Beer, very rose, and welcome to welcome.
We are so happy to be here with you tonight.
I see that we have got people tuning in from San Francisco, Jesse from Connecticut, Bay Area, Amsterdam, potentially our producer, Linda.
Wow, I mean, we have got a range from east coast to West Coast.
Alexis, Douglas, Detroit, Danielle and San Diego.
Wow, this is great.
Nashville, and I am here in hot sunny desert Las Vegas.
So what's so awesome?
Is that all of us?
Oh, there we go.
Got the are horde.
So what would so awesome is that all of us are getting the opportunity to cook together tonight?
We're sharing the same ingredients.
We have got these kits and were all across the world.
And so we're excited to have all of you here.
On the panel to your right, you will see the chat.
And so, feel free to drop any of your thoughts, your feedback, and there's a Q&A tab as well.
So, if you click on it, feel free to drop any questions in the meantime, as we have right there with a fire Moji.
Let us show some love.
If you have got, your laptop in front of you drop an emoji and show us some of your love.
There we go.
What's up, Linda?
Hey, Andrew Dylan in the house.
Um, anybody else?
If you have got some love, just keep dropping it.
Thanks, Sean and Alex, Jesse Lauren McCoy.
Here we go.
All right, let us do this.
Okay.
So before we jump into some tacos and margaritas, let us do a quick poll.
All right, so Linda in our Green Room, I can see her.
Maybe y'all can't see her but I see you.
Linda.
Do you mind putting that pole?
There we go.
Have you cooked with a virtual Chef before?
If yes, today's my first time drop in your votes.
If you haven't already, it looks like for majority of you.
This is your first time, so, oh, we got some other folks who have done this before.
All right.
Okay.
Well great.
We have got a packed out agenda, an amazing Chef that I see in the Green Room Chef Giovanni who I will introduce shortly.
Let us pull up that agenda here.
So today what we're going.
Do is we will also introduce you to the chef.
We will start with our cocktails mocktails, then we will go through the overview of tools.
Protein prep, do a taco.
Check in with one another garnish tortilla prep.
And then we will do the Tocco assembly.
Have the party at the end, final remarks.
And then there's going to be a photo winning up.
So be sure to take those photos, and we're going to share it with one another.
Now with that.
I would love to introduce the chef, he has worked in the Austin restaurant scene for over 10 years.
He's made relationships with some of the most popular restaurant groups in Austin.
On, if you're from Austin, you would know these names Bryce Gilmore, Mark, bewley Sam, Hillman Mass.
These are really big chefs out there.
So Chef Philip Speer who runs assembly.
And he's had four nominations with the James Beard Foundation hired, Chef Giovanni to come to become a key member of the His kitchen management team and their chef Giovanni serves as the sous chef for the Commodore.
And this is allowed him to expand his knowledge and his skills within modern Mexican Cuisine.
And so now, he operates as the executive chef at assembly kitchen leading the team with menu creation and talent screening.
So with that Chef Giovanni.
Join me on stage.
Hello.
Taco Tuesday.
Yeah.
Yes, I am excited.
Hola como estas.
Hi, muy.
Bien, muy Brent.
Yeah, super excited, Taco Tuesday, officially today.
We're going to have a great time.
We're going to eat some really delicious food and enjoy each other's company.
So let us do it.
Perfect.
Well, I think especially the best way to start off.
Taco Tuesday is with a God, dang, Margarita.
So let us get right into it.
Right?
Y'all, I would like to mention.
If you have any questions whatsoever.
Unfortunately, I am not able to see you guys on my end of the screen.
But please throw those questions right in the chat.
I can see it on the right of my monitor, and we can definitely get you, those answers, right?
So, the best thing about this Margarita is that it's going to be ready in 30.
Against.
All right.
So all the items we will need for this Margarita as follows here, when Empty Glass, beautiful lime, our Margarita mixture here and I just have this little plate with my lime salt in it.
Alright.
So here we go, guys.
This is a quick trick.
First thing I am going to do is, let us go ahead and cut this line right down the middle.
Like so, Then we're going to go ahead and grab a little wedge from this lime.
Slice it in the middle.
Just going to score it, allowing us to place it over our glass and really Rim it with this fresh lime juice.
More flavor from here.
We're just going to tip it right onto that glass.
Sorry for the scratchy's sounds not pleasant.
But here we go.
Fill it up with ice like that.
Beautiful.
Good healthy, Shake.
Everybody get that.
Taco dance already started.
This is where we're getting that move-in ready.
Getting ready for it.
Pop, the cap.
Fill her up extra.
Squeeze of lime.
Quick Trick, there we go, guys.
Beautiful.
Margarita right in front of you.
Cheers y'all.
Beautiful.
How's it tasting?
Everyone like the margarita?
Cheers, I love the chairs.
Perfect.
Super Fresh lime juice, is exactly what makes this Margarita, really pop?
I like a little strawberry floater on my margarita.
Someone asked do we like floaters here in Austin, Texas?
That's a hell.
Yes.
So beautiful.
So now that we got our drink settled in front of us.
We can finally get to relax, you know, get our drinking on, it's only makes us better chefs and the end of it.
I think it's also going to make us a little more confident.
So when we are cooking these tacos, everything is pre cooked for you.
We're really just looking to get those garnishes on the plate.
We're looking to heat up this meat or vegetables depending on the kit you get.
And then so it's really simple trick.
We got our super nice tacos.
It's going to feed a lot of people.
Tonight.
So if you have anyone in your house with you, please tag them along and let us get on with the show.
So we got our drink out of the way, right?
Let us go ahead and talk about utensils and tools.
Okay, super, super simple.
The most things we were going to be needing is actually pans, right?
Because we have got three proteins.
We got a Carnitas, we have chicken tinga, and we have our Koji marinated skirt steak.
If you did get the vegetarian, you're going to have our much.
Shroom mixture, some miso carrots, and also a butternut squash to saute.
Super, super simple.
So like I said, it's going to be a majority of pans.
But let us go ahead and talk about utensils.
Got our chef knife, right.
Beautiful cutting board, of course, and then just now near me.
I have a little spatula.
Definitely going to need that for our homemade tortillas.
I love to have these little tongues as well.
And then I just have a small amount of spoons here.
Is it going to help with pulling out any ingredients out of those packaging and just kind of make our life a little easier when we're saucing when we're putting some, you know, Salsas and ramekins, super simple.
Of course.
I have a couple Linens as well.
Now you guys, if you don't have a tortilla holder too warm to keep our tortillas nice and warm.
While we're eating our tacos.
The linen will definitely work as the trick, right?
We're going to use It as a steamer once we have our hot tortillas.
So make sure you at least have an extra clean linen.
Alongside.
I am going to go ahead and bring you over to my stove here.
So you will see, I do have a decent amount of pans right now.
The saucepan in the middle here is going to be for my chicken tinga.
So make sure you guys have a small sauce pot for your chicken tinga and then I have to cast iron pans here just for my other proteins, my Carnitas and also my steak.
So for the vegetarian out there, I just like to go ahead and use a sheet tray with a little bit of foil on it, because we can actually go ahead and just roast our It's alongside our butternut squash.
Okay, alongside that sheet tray for my vegetarian.
Vegan friend.
You will need at least one cast, iron pan.
And that's going to be for your mushrooms.
Now, you will notice I have this really large, kind of flat top attachment on my stove as well.
Now for me, this is the best thing you can possibly use to heat up tortilla.
It's right.
We don't want to go ahead and heat up one towards he at a time.
Letting it get cold in the You know, after we're cooking it, so for me, I love to be able to cook at least six tortillas on this flat top.
Now.
If you guys don't have a flat top like this, just having another large cast, iron pan will definitely do the trick.
All right.
Beautiful.
How's the margarita going?
Hopefully, no one went ahead and chugged it.
It is only Tuesday, but no, shame.
Perfect.
Other than that, guy's if you were had your box in front of you, feel free to go ahead and pull out all the ingredients and just kind of neatly lined them up in front of your cooking station, makes your life a little bit easier.
And other than that, I think we can go ahead and is it is only Tuesday?
I know it looks like Friday outside plus we got it is Wednesday.
Oh my God, you guys are totally, right.
We're going to act like, it's Friday, even though it's Taco Tuesday on this Wednesday.
If that Sounds.
All right, beautiful.
Thank you for keeping me in check over there.
McCoy.
Definitely with the knowledge great.
So we do have a little protein prep just to get started beforehand.
I also would like Zachary that my loan vegetarian not to section you off, but go ahead and pre-heat your oven to 375.
All right, Zachary only for Zachary.
He is a special person in this entire group.
Group, and we all love him for them.
Great.
So back into our small amount of protein prep.
All I am going to do here.
And after the protein prep will go ahead and jump into our side rooms, but just a couple steps before we do that for my protein prep.
I really just want to go ahead and start getting all this meat out and be able to breathe especially the stake here.
Okay, so just getting a steak right out of our compostable packaging here.
I am going to go ahead and just lay it on a linen.
Just to kind of soak up some of that liquid.
If you don't want to use a linen just for this, we can go ahead and just have a paper towel.
Will definitely do the trick.
Okay, I have a thousand of these Linens though.
So I have no shame in using that beautiful one protein prep down.
And as I did mention, these bags are 100% compostable.
So if you guys have little home compost, compost at your house, please, just throw them in there.
They will buy generally degrade.
Next up.
I am going to go ahead and just get my chicken tinga in the sauce pot.
Okay.
Now I don't want to turn on that sauce pot.
I just want to get it in there.
Okay, just like we said this is just a small amount of prep work before the fun really begins.
So right into my pot, make sure you get all of those sauces from this packaging.
They're so delicious.
Just like the squeeze out with your hands, just like that.
Fantastic, and then just going to put the lid back on.
Like I said, we're not turning on that pot just yet.
We're just getting it ready.
All right.
Now that leaves us with our Carnitas, the Carnitas can actually stay in the bag here.
But I am just going to go ahead and open them up.
I like to open the entire packaging up just, so we keep a nice flat surface for the Carnitas, and we will go ahead and show you why that's important a little bit later.
But as you can see, just opening it up like a book.
Beautiful.
That will do the trick.
Here we go.
So now we got all our proteins, nice and prepped.
Chickens in the sauce, pot, steaks, drying out a little bit on a paper towel, Carnitas are opened up getting ready for that cook along.
Okay, so we will go ahead and just make sure you hit except on your break rooms here and I will see you guys back here in about seven minutes or so.
So you guys enjoy that margarita.
I also have a dog.
Yes.
You guys are in my house today.
So welcome.
She knows.
She knows that guy that she ever belong here.
I love that poll.
By the way.
I also voted for whiskey.
So, great job everyone.
You guys got the right answer.
Beautiful.
Love.
Seeing the photos as well.
Everyone holding on gripping.
Tight to that Margarita.
Beautiful.
Love it.
What's I would love to see some of y'all's favorite whiskies in the chat.
I personally love to drink Booker's.
Booker's is my drink for the most part when it comes down to Whiskey.
Sneezy.
Good straight.
Sipping Wild Turkey 101.
Okay.
Hi.
Hi West.
He's just a simple man.
Love it.
Great, guys.
Well tonight.
We are drinking tequila.
So no one should be mad about that.
The Margaritas are really fantastic.
So let us get kind of down into the grittiness of setting up our clatter.
Right?
So this is going to be called armies and place.
Does anyone know what Mason pluses by chance?
Has anyone watched the Food Network and heard that?
Put your answer in the chat really quickly.
Let us see if I get any Put in place.
Yeah, pretty much.
That's exactly it.
So, we're getting everything in its place.
That's mise-en-place.
Right?
So what to means in place for this taco event is going to be, is getting are those little garnishes all those beautiful colors right on the plate first?
Okay, and the very first amazing plus, I think that we can essentially do get our prep ready is.
I have our 2, beautiful Salsas here and all I did was put them right into little ramekins.
Now, this is sounds like a really small step but Actually adds a lot of value to the perceived value of this ditch.
Right?
We took the time to went ahead and separate our Salsas.
We can use them throughout the night.
It looks beautiful.
Just nice off into their ramekins.
So let us go ahead and start by doing soap, right?
I am looking for a nice plate skills tonight.
Okay, and we can actually do that with just using our vision.
Having these beautiful colors that were about to display on our plate, is actually going to be kind of the plate up of this platter at itself.
Other than that, I am going to go ahead and grab my platter for this evening.
This is beautiful, nice white large plate.
It's going to have plenty of surface area for me to work with all my garnishes have all three of my All-Star meats, or All is right in the center.
So go ahead and find yourselves a beautiful, nice platter like this.
Okay, and the first thing I am going to be adding to this platter.
We have those pesky lines from that Margarita.
So I think, let us go ahead and just finish the job.
Right?
We have about three quarters of a margarita.
We have our knife and let us just go ahead and create the rest into wedges here.
Like so beautiful.
No, Taco is complete without a nice fresh Spritz of that line.
It's right there.
And I am just going to start playing with colors here.
I think we should go ahead and do for the most part.
All of our knife work.
Now here.
I have my market vegetables.
These are going to be just fresh seasonal, vegetables, that freshness of the vegetable actually gives a lot of texture to a taco.
I love the little bite of a radish and between some carnitas.
So let us go ahead and attack that.
So just slicing off the top of the package.
These vegetables have already been pre-washed for you.
So you can see I have a little yellow carrot and also this just beautiful cherry bomb of a radish are so using my fingertips here.
I am going to actually claw the item.
Now.
I don't want anyone.
We're going to do a little pre lesson on how to properly cut something as you can see on a professional chef and I have all 10.
And my fingers, still tell you, I know what I am talking about, right?
So when I cut anything, I am always clawing the Mmm, usually, with these three fingers here.
Okay, so I am gripping it.
And as you can tell, when I grip it, my Knuckles kind of protrude out word, which allows me to kind of rest, my knife amongst my Knuckles.
And as you can see, my fingertips will naturally kind of push inward being hidden from my knife blade itself.
So let us think a little smart here as well.
This thing rolls around like crazy.
So let us go ahead and give it some nice.
Flat edges.
Nice flat surface to work on.
This looks like a nice little heart.
Let us hear you guys.
There we go, beautiful.
So now we have a, we have a flat surface radish.
My fingertips are gripping.
The item Knuckles are, protruding outward firm grip on my knife.
And I am just slicing right through and a rocking motion, until I meet an apex in which my reddish is no longer.
A safe kind of on this Edge, so I am a tilted back down and then just attack the other side.
Definitely not a race.
We want nice thin slices a vegetable here, okay.
Beautiful.
Now, we kind of made it a little easier ready for you with the carrot.
It's got a nice flat surface.
And for me, I like these to kind of mimic the size of the taco.
So I am going to go ahead and cut them at a diagonal bias.
So they're a little larger, and they just fit nicely onto my taco.
So just like that.
A nice little sweetness from the carrot, alongside its texture.
And the crunch makes her a really nice little taco garnish.
So here we just have our beautiful little bundle.
Showing off those knife skills.
Everyone's got their finger tips.
I hope.
And we're going to roll.
But look at that already.
The color of these to the grain from the line, the beautiful carrot alongside the radish, makes this look really beautiful.
Now, let us go ahead and finish off a little of this knife work here and I think we're going to do some of this charred onion here.
Slicing it rights?
Open like that.
Now you will notice on this onion itself, the root system is still attached.
So just this little button, has the roots still attached.
All we want to do is slice that off.
Don't want to eat that.
Using that same technique.
I am gripping these onion, this onion here, and I am just going to make small little ribbon, so I can go ahead and put this throughout my taco of my choosing.
Beautiful.
Fun.
This right back to our platter.
Love the translucent color.
Fantastic.
Now I am going to go ahead and reach for my chili Tori.
Ah, do so, anyone know what a chili Tory Auto is Can anyone guess what pepper this is in this package?
I know there're some Californians out there.
So they definitely know what this is here.
I just got a nice, beautiful charred jalapeno and which we then quick pickle with a little lime juice.
Okay, so it's got that dark bite from the grill.
It's got that acidic punch to it from the lime.
And I am just going to strike off the stem.
Now, if you guys don't like the spiciness of this jalapeno, all too much.
We can go ahead and de-seed it from the inside.
So, just slicing the center open, not all the way through, but just enough to expose those seeds, you can use the back of your knife.
To just scrape nice and easily out like so.
For me, I like the chili.
So I am going to go ahead and put them right back in, and I am just going to slice nice, beautiful wedges of this jalapeno.
Fantastic, nice hatch, stick.
And I am going to rest that directly right on top of my onions.
Let us see where you guys are at.
Okay, beautiful head on a swivel.
Love it.
Someone's thinking on their feet.
That's a true.
Chef move.
Great job.
So here, just to show you what I am working with so far, have a couple of my garnishes.
Now.
Let us add a little more brightness to this, right?
It's kind of getting a little mold down with these charred, vegetable garnishes with the onion and the jalapeno.
What I want you guys to go ahead and reach for next is what's called.
Need pack that you need.
Peck is a very traditional Yucatan style garnish.
You often find these on tostadas and Tacos, but the thing that's so special about SHINee, Peck is the pickling liquid, which usually tends to be vinegar, has been swapped out for citrus juices.
So, in this, we have pickled it with orange juice, lime juice, and a little habanero pieces, just to give it a nice kick and it's got some good sweetness from those juices themselves.
And you can just see the color of it is just absolutely stunning.
So, just using your fingertips, we're here to get messy.
Kind of drain.
These onions?
Right out.
These are some of my favorite garnishes for a steak taco.
So beautiful.
It's like that.
So you can see how I am actually using the rim of my plate, to really set the boundary for all of our garnishes.
Right?
So we're thinking the little smart here and then next up.
I am going to go ahead and reach for some fresh cilantro.
Let us live in this thing up with a little more fresh herbs here, okay.
Now just a couple more steps before we do break off into your breakout rooms once more.
So really take the time to set off these garnishes really beautifully.
Feel free to take a couple of those photos once you guys are in there, but just grabbing the cilantro.
It's already been picked for you.
We did the hard stuff.
It's already been washed.
So just give it a little volume, right?
But something's nice and Tall on a play.
It just speaks so much louder.
Look so much more beautiful.
And now, pair them with our house bar herbs.
This is just from a local hyper local Farm here in Austin Texas.
That grows these beautiful little field herbs.
Now, not only do they just look gorgeous.
They really do add a lot of different flavors.
Now if you have any large pieces like this, Malabar spinach here, feel free to just pick it with your fingers, tear it up into some bite-sized pieces.
Those flowers are edible.
They just give a nice little beautiful.
Look to your plate.
Here we go.
Now, I am starting to get a little more green on my plate.
So, let us go ahead and lighten up the mood.
We have this beautiful quesillo.
They will.
Haka that we get imported at the restaurant.
Every single Friday, from Oaxaca.
This is the most insanely delicious cheese you have ever had the way that it's made is that it's stretched and continuously stretched and balled up into a nice large ball.
So here we have those Strands of it.
So just pick it with your fingers, definitely snag a little piece for the enjoyment, pre taco.
But this on top of the chicken tinga just makes it so delicious.
So here we go.
And then that leaves me with our last garnish here, which is this avocado.
So, the avocado is bagged because we went ahead and just slice the avocado down the middle, just to make sure you guys are getting a nice, beautiful, non bruised, avocado.
So once we slice it, we sealed it right back up as if it was brand-new and it is absolutely fantastic.
You will notice the seed is still in the avocado that helps.
The my stay oxidation of it.
So for the last kind of knife work prep.
We have we just have to deep it.
This avocado seed.
Gently striking the center of the avocado with your middle of your knife.
Get in there.
Counter twist both hands.
Beautiful.
Thing is right out.
Now.
I love to cut this on The Cutting Board.
You don't ever need to buy an avocado Spooner right?
Or what?
I don't even know what it's called.
I just have this nice antique spoon here that I found perfect for my avocados.
So I am just going to use the spoon to scoop out that beautiful flesh.
Bright and vibrant green.
This avocado.
It's one of my favorite garnishes.
Fantastic, and I am just going to go ahead and cut little wedges on a bias like so, For Allah, you can press down, give it that nice fan.
Look at that beautiful green eggs, just like that.
Clean up the station, just a little bit.
I know.
Hey, we're here to prove you guys wrong on that shipping of avocados.
It is possible.
We have the technology.
We can ship avocados, worldwide, love it.
So hopefully your platter looks just as bright and vibrant as mine, take a quick look, definitely can get this done and I will see you guys here in a minute.
So go ahead and accept those breakout rooms one more time.
Show us your beautiful platters and let us go Ready to fill them up with some great taco fill-ins.
See you guys soon.
Welcome back, guys.
Hopefully, you will have a little Margarita by the end of this cooking experience.
Definitely encourage drinking while we're eating these tacos.
It really sets off the mood, right?
But with that, welcome back, let us do a quick cheers.
Last confidence booster because we're about to get into the actual fire of things.
Alright, so here we have our garnish tray set up, right?
It's beautiful.
Hopefully you guys, I definitely piqued.
A couple of these breakout rooms and look stunning.
Shouts out to cheffy boy, Zachary Smith with the wood board.
Platter looks freaking fantastic.
Absolutely.
Love it.
Follow him on Instagram.
He went ahead and put we're trying to post up his Chef Instagram here.
It's going to be great.
So we have our platter here.
It looks beautiful.
I saw everyone's super amazing job now.
It's on to the cooking part, right?
The very most important thing about cooking is proper.
On our pans or oven, right?
So we need to make sure these pans are nice and hot.
This is why I love to use cast iron.
It retains its heat much, much better than most pans, and it's also really simple to clean out.
You rinse it, wipe it out.
With a paper towel.
It just keeps on getting better.
The seasoning on the pan itself grows with you while you're kind of cooking.
So the first thing I want to do come with me to my range here.
Zachary, you got your oven on?
Yes, sir.
Great.
So our oven on is for our vegetarian option.
Mr. Exact.
Everyone else should be working with this.
These pans here.
Okay.
So for me, the very first thing, we have our chicken tinga in our sauce pot.
I am going to go ahead and start that first, and I am going to turn it on very low.
I just want a nice simmer on my chicken tinga.
I don't want to reduce my sauce.
In there all that much.
I just really want to warm up this chicken.
Okay.
So the very first thing we're going kind of reverse, little Seer here, chicken tinga on low heat with my other pans.
I am going to go ahead and turn on my tortilla pan.
So this will be your largest pan.
And I also want this on low.
So by time or mates are nice and Cooked.
Our tortilla pan will be nice and ready just to warm up these House made Tortillas, okay, and that leaves me with my two solo pants here.
One for my carnitas, one, for my steak, now, Zachary with a vegetarian option.
One of these pans will go ahead and be for our mushrooms.
Okay.
So here we have the mon.
I am going to go ahead and start preheating.
My pans to just under medium heat.
I want a nice and hot.
But I don't want to really burn down the place, right?
So let us just get that going, beautiful.
This is a nice little Pro tip as well.
As you can see that, I have a bunch of items cooking.
Now.
I am always very cautious that I have my handles of my pans, kind of facing the same way.
Right?
And I never want those handles to be in front of the stove.
Just in case you got a kid running around that dog.
Is maybe pulling up here.
They're going to knock this thing.
I am always having my pans, just consciously in a single Direction, okay.
So now that our pans are starting to warm up.
Once again on that Medium.
I am going to grab that neutral oil that we sent you and I want half of that neutral oil and to each of your pants.
Okay, just like that.
Now, this neutral oil has a higher smoke point.
That smoke point is going to allow us to get a hotter temperature on her oil which is going to have us have a better texture on our Carnitas are Steak, right?
So I want you guys to keep a close eye on your pans.
Not looking for a billowing of smoke, but just a small little faint hint of smoke.
That's the pan saying hey, I am here to party.
Let us get it going.
Okay, now for Zach with our vegetarian, I am going to go ahead and jump on that for a moment.
I am going to go ahead and open up our me so grilled carrots.
Right here.
We have that and then I have our sweet potato.
That's been part roasted.
Okay, both of these packages are now open.
We're going to go ahead and grab my sheet tray.
Now Zach feel free to go ahead and salt Tay these vegetables instead if you want a little more live action, but for me, I just like to kind of continue to roast them.
So one side is going to have my beautiful.
It's on there.
The other my sweet potato.
And now that neutral oil, instead of using it on the pan, Zachary go ahead and just sprinkle a little bit directly on top.
Beautiful, and I am going to go straight into the oven with these vegetables.
It's like that.
And on that last three minute cook for these vegetables.
I am going to actually switch the oven to the broil setting which is going to cook from the above.
Point of the stove.
It's going to give a nice color to those carrots and those sweet potatoes in there.
Okay?
Back to my mate folk garnishes on our plate, polish off to the side.
I am going to probably start with my stake here because it's going to need to rest after we cook it.
So we have the oil in the pan.
It's on medium Heat.
Going to be there in about 20 seconds, for sure.
Now, when I grab my piece of steak, And this is the pan.
Imagine.
This is the pan here.
I am going to lay the steak, just the tip of it.
In the pan must hear the sizzle.
And if you're not hearing the sizzle, pull it right out.
Just wait a little bit.
Let us see.
Let me answer a question really quick.
That grape seed is not olive oil.
Olive oil is not actually the best oil to use for sauteing items because it has a really low smoke point.
So when you're sauting something really hot and olive oil, you're burning the olive oil.
And we have all probably seen, how all of oil can get $25 a bottle.
You're kind of just wasting money when you're sauting and olive oil.
Now, Italian recipes, I am Italian, do call for sweating things and olive oil.
And that's just a really shallow kind of low heat.
So this is actually grapeseed oil.
But what we got going on with the steak, want to hear the sizzle, and then we're going to drop away from us.
So that oil doesn't potentially splatter on.
To us.
Do you recommend turning on the vent Hood?
It might get a little hot in here.
And my pan looks nice and ready.
So, starting with that steak can see the oil, the viscosity is, it has totally changed?
Great Sizzle, definitely get that mic in their beautiful.
And I am setting it away from me.
Now.
We're going to cook that steak for about a minute to two minutes on this side and flip it.
Okay, so get those tongues ready.
Now, this steak is to be prepared, kind of medium rare, which is the best way to enjoy it in my opinion.
Now.
If you do want to have a medium to, well, steak go ahead and add a minute, to a minute, and a half on that cook time on each of these sides.
Okay.
So, our steak is rolling.
Which means we're about ready for our Carnitas.
Now, we left our Carnitas in this nice Flat state because we want all this surface area to caramelize this layer of Carnitas before we really begin to represent Italians.
Yeah, then, you know, sorry reading the chat.
We want this surface area to carmelites and really fry in its own fat.
So going to remove that plastic.
Back to my pan, viscosity of the oil is beautiful.
It's going to lay it in there, and I am not even going to touch it.
We're going to cook that for about two minutes and allow it to really fry and its own rendered fat, okay.
Beautiful.
Now Zachary with your mushrooms.
Here.
We can do the same with the pan and getting it, nice and hot.
And then we're really simply just going to saute these bad boys, okay.
So sauteing them should hear the sizzle.
Once the oil is nice and hot, add the mushrooms and then kind of just let them cool out and cook for about a minute before we really begin to stir them.
Right?
Because we want that caramelization.
We want that color on those mushrooms.
Let us see, any other questions about neutral oil.
Nope.
Neutral oil is just really cheap.
Honestly, for me personally.
I use neutral oil for every cooking, pretty much procedure.
And that's like I said, it's for like a specific recipe and which I am using olive oil to kind of sweat and embed those onions and baby carrots with some of that olive oil flavor.
But yeah grapeseed oil which is the neutral Oil.
We're using super cheap and it gets better product out of it.
Yep.
High Point.
So, smart used avocado as well.
That's also a great neutral oil.
Beautiful.
So just showing you guys my stake here.
It's been about 2 minutes.
I am going to go ahead and flip it over.
It's got this nice dark caramelization on it that dark Amber red.
And so another 2 minutes on this side should do the trick.
And then once that two minutes is up directly from my pan.
I am just going to come and rest my steak on my cutting board, right?
Fantastic, so it's been a couple of minutes.
My Carnitas are quite literally popping off right now, which is a great, great sign.
If they're popping a little bit too much, you can go ahead and turn down the heat, but let us look at some of this great color.
We got.
Yeah, the caramelization definitely happening.
Beautiful.
Going to go ahead and mix in that kind of fried.
Consistent Carnitas.
Let us take a look at our chicken tinga, beautiful.
Small reduce just give it a good stir.
So that's been another minute or two on my steak.
So I am going to go ahead and turn off the heat on my steak going to bring that over to my cutting board.
Let that thing, rest.
For exact Curry's pleasure.
I am going to go ahead and just saute my mushrooms in that cast iron pan.
It's got some great color.
Beautiful.
So, the mmm does anyone know the importance of letting?
The steak rests.
What do you guys think is happening, you know, cooking is so much for me.
I really begun to excel in my career when I began to really observe quite literally what's just happening.
This is an applied science in my opinion, which makes this entire, you know, room of your house.
A living laboratory, which makes it so much more fun to really get in the kitchen.
Get your hands on some ingredients and cook.
So let us say yeah, the juices.
Exactly.
So think about it, right.
We just expose this meet a lot of heat, which is opening up pores, right?
Ladies.
And I mean my skin routine at nighttime jump out of the shower.
My pores are freaking size of pepperonis that heat is just expanding them open.
So all that poor in the stake.
Here is expanding, once we take it back to that cold State outside of the pan.
It's going to shrivel.
Back up sucking in all those juices, right?
Beautiful.
So sauteing some mushrooms, getting some great color.
These pork carnitas definitely popping, which is great.
Got some great caramelization.
You can see all the extra fat that's just been rendered from the pork itself.
I am actually going to go ahead and turn my pan off just because they look nice and golden, but I want these Carnitas to go ahead and just remain in the pan.
My chicken tinga looks nice and hot thoroughly all throughout.
So, I as well, we will turn that off.
And at this point Zach, let us go ahead and probably turn that oven to that broil State just for about a minute or two.
Just to give it a final color on our, our mushroom or excuse me, our carrots, and our sweet potatoes.
So let us do that real quick.
Perfect.
Do a little wipe down at the station.
Now, our meats are nice and hot.
They're beautifully caramelized.
Our steak is resting.
The last thing we need to be doing our next thing, we should be doing preparing our tortillas.
So through the company to MOA.
We buy literally about two tons of dried corn every 6 months and this corn comes from different areas, all throughout Mexico.
Absolutely, beautiful.
You will notice here.
I have these Pink House made Tortillas.
Now the elevation that all of these different pieces of corn.
Growing really alter the change in the way you cook these tortillas in general.
So just taking them out of the bag.
I am going to separate the tortillas from the paper recyclable.
Just like that.
We're letting them breathe.
And we already was smart enough to go ahead and turn on our tortilla pan.
Some really warming these things up, should take no time at all.
Beautiful, and just want to mention, I did turn off all of my heat sources on my pans, and I am letting those items stay in the pan just to stay warm until we really hit the plate with them.
Okay.
So I have my clean linen here.
Wrong one here.
It is beautiful.
So I am just going to take this over to my workstation are my Kamal.
I have this beautiful little tiny spatula.
Absolutely.
Love it.
Thank you, Central Market.
And nice and hot pan already just nice and warm.
No oil is needed whatsoever.
There's plenty of natural oil in this tortilla.
Now.
The only thing that should ever be in your corn.
Tortilla is dried corn, obviously, water and salt.
So this is a natural gluten-free, you know, vegan option for tacos and it makes the best tacos in the world must be made from fresh.
Massa, I am just going to go ahead and cook these for 30 seconds on each side.
Beautiful.
Definitely have my dog started to come and circle around like a shark.
She's psycho.
She definitely her favorite.
Taco is probably the steak carnitas.
Yeah.
She's looking at me like she said and hasn't eaten dinner, but she got well-fed beforehand.
Beautiful.
So as you can see my tortillas 30 seconds on each side, this is Master Level Kemal work.
When you can do it with your fingertips here.
And like I said, these are already totally cooked for you.
So all we got to do is really warm them up.
So right into my Fresh Linen, it's going to act as a steamer, right?
So here just going to place my Fresh Tortillas.
If they inflate on you.
That's just a really amazing great sign that it's a Fresh Tortilla.
And then redo the steps here.
Make sure you close that linen.
We want to keep that heat Source inside, right?
Do you guys smell the natural kind of oils being released from these tortillas, as we're cooking?
It's kind of like toasting bread, right?
We don't necessarily so proud.
Jesse.
I am proud of you.
It should be smelling amazing and everyone's house right now.
Take a look at my vegetable Zack.
We don't want to forget about that.
That Broiler does work fast.
Just a small amount of color tortillas or coming too long.
Beautiful.
So add to our pile here, people are start to be coming out of y'all's house.
Like y'all didn't even know was there right?
Y'all guess this past weekend watching, some footballs guarantee at they're still over waiting for some tacos.
So right into my stack, some more hot tortillas going to just fold over my tortillas and put them on a nice plate.
Remember this presentation is everything.
I mean, how beautiful is it when we just have a nice little blanket of sleeping tortillas like that.
Fantastic guys, so close to that final and first bite of heaven.
So now we have our station, right?
All our Foods hot here.
We are getting ready to Plate.
Now.
We have our code, you steak on the counter, aren't on our cutting board here.
Looks nice and delicious.
You can see all those beautiful juices being sucked back in.
Now, you can see the striation of the meat, right?
And here's a pro tip for you guys.
We always want to cut our meat against the grain.
We don't want to chew with the grain.
We want our mouth to, you know, cut through the meat itself.
So find where those long strands of kind of caramelized meet go, and we're going to cut opposite of it.
So here, I am just cutting nice, beautiful, traditional little fajita ribbons.
This will be the first item to hit our plate here.
Like I said, beautiful medium rare.
Absolutely beautiful for me.
I like to just use my knife and kind of hatch.
Stick them like that.
We're going to go right in the center.
Our platter.
Maybe for you.
Zach.
This is the carrots to match kind of the length, beautiful already.
And then next up.
I am going to go ahead and divide it with my chicken tinga.
For having one of these spoons here.
Super Saucy.
This adobo Chipotle blend.
That just coats.
All of this chicken just makes it.
Absolutely amazing smells so good.
Make sure you get all that sauce from that pan.
And I am just going to finish with my absolutely beautiful Carnitas.
Now, for me.
The best tool is going to be the tongs because there is a decent amount of that rendered fat still.
So just give a nice dripping on top of your plate.
Oh, yeah.
Guys, I am salivating so bad right now.
It's hard for me to talk.
Oh Lord.
This is unfair that we get to eat this way.
Seriously guys.
Fluff up some of those herbs.
Let us get our beautiful platter coming back together.
Strong.
Introduce these beautiful Salsas.
Look at this spread, good Lord.
Here we have it.
He will even get a little Margarita left.
Look at that.
So guys.
Once you're at this point, we're going to jump again into another breakout room.
Of course.
I want to hear.
I am going to eat a taco with you guys.
I want to hear any questions.
You guys have.
Oh my God, Emily.
Can we get Emily hired for assembly here?
I need some help on these events.
All right, that looks freaking amazing.
She's got my vote.
By the way, if there's a winner for this, I am sorry, everyone else.
She beat ya will to it.
Emily seems to have won this contest.
Are you food?
Are you actually like a food stylist on Instagram or something or no?
But you missed and we all did beyond that.
It's giving you guys a hard time for not having all the like plating, but I think it turned out.
I love The Cutting Board.
It looks amazing for that Final Touch.
No, Emily here.
I want you to do this live with me, right?
Go ahead and grab them.
Maldon salt.
We sent you yet.
We got to get our salt day on.
All right.
So maldon, salt is going to be a larger flake salt.
Right?
So, the reason we put this on at the very end is because we want to tie in all these intense flavors at the very top-level, right?
So when we get that salt just on top.
Oh wait, use your hands.
There we go.
Yeah, beautiful.
So we're always seasoning from above because we want to capture as much surface.
This area right as possible.
We don't want real small pinches of salt, all over the place.
We want to sporadic almost like a shotgun blast, right?
All of that, seasoning, right onto the plate.
Fantastic, everyone do yourself a, get it going on.
All right.
Amazing.
Hopefully, it smells great.
All these plates are looking fabulous.
Fantastic, we're definitely going to have to post some of these on our Instagram and my Instagram is well, I would love that.
Producer throwing on Instagram in the chat.
Hopefully everyone's coming to the fruition of their platter being assembled Zachary house.
The house the vegetarian coming along.
Should get some nice color on the butternut squash or excuse me in this, sweet potatoes as carrots should have a nice Grill touch to them as well.
Perfect out.
He's already finished.
Those mushrooms are, I wish everyone could have those mushrooms.
So, in the mushroom mixture, we add with called wila coche.
Now, we get this also weekly and this is going to be a raw corn truffle.
Unfortunately.
We don't get this raw beautiful product in the States because of our corn being so genetically modified, which is a whole other issue.
That's the whole thing, but you're able to enjoy that real authentic.
Fresh probably a new ingredient that you have been having fourth, which is amazing.
Man, all right.
I am a dive in on a Taco.
This is been staring at me too much.
What's the consensus?
What is everyone?
Starting with carnitas steak Tanga?
Let us see what they got going on.
I think I might I am just it's probably eating right now.
So they can't take things in, right?
That's fair.
Everyone's Max are going to be all greased up.
Yeah, right.
Wow, Lee.
That's a gorgeous plate.
Look at that.
Andrew.
Very nice.
Jesse beautiful, man.
These plates are gorgeous.
So let us start dropping in some questions.
We have got a few questions here in QA with Linda's.
First question.
Okay, Chef, what is neutral oil?
Yeah, so neutral oil, as we said before, is a neutral oil.
It doesn't have a very Bold Flavor like olive oil does, right?
Because olive oil is made of Olives.
It tastes like all this neutral oil is just kind of plain Bland Flavor now, I don't want to say Bland and a negative term because to me, it does technically have a flavor for instance.
I use it to pop popcorn and I really love the flavor of grapeseed on my popcorn.
Which I guess I am just weird about that.
I am not sure but this oil allows you to heat up your pan a little higher than other oils, like olive oil allowing you to get a better texture on your food without burning that oil which could potentially, you know contaminate and make your food taste a little bitter, you know an onslaught of things.
Good question though.
Gotcha.
So is are there particular oils that are considered neutral?
Yeah, so I use grape seed oil, grapeseed oil is my favorite oil to use for cooking when it comes to sauteing our, you know, like shallow frying, something olive oil more, so for salad dressings, or finishing a pasta, so you're not, you know, really abusing the oil on its temperature, but we're actually using it for the flavor of the oil itself.
And then of course, like shortening for frying, even higher smoke point, so, Able to you know, fry things at 400 degrees getting that super text crispy texture on wings, you know, tater tots things like that.
Is canola oil, considered neutral and was Askin?
Yes, technically I use canola more.
So for frying, just because it does have a higher caloric intake, right?
And if you're frying, something like might as well just take it all.
Anyway.
So yeah, I use canola a little bit more for frying, really, really love grape seed.
Oil for my main use of personal cooking.
Good to note.
All right, we got a question from Ali.
Could you remind us which toppings are supposed to pair with, which proteins?
Every year, every topping goes with all of these proteins, honestly, we're inviting you to kind of figure out your own blend, right?
So for me, as you can see, I really love the salsa verde with the Carnitas and just avocado, but that's not to say that you shouldn't try the salsa verde with the chicken and, you know, carrots.
It's all really just for you to explore.
We give you a decent amount of these tortillas.
So you're really having a full deck to play.
But yeah, just figure out what your favorite combination.
Like.
I love the steak and the SHINee Peck together, but that's not technically the exact way.
We encourage you guys to eat it.
So play along, feel free to dive in on different garnishes until you figure out your favorite.
Another question here from Danielle.
Do you prefer a flavored Marg or a classic?
A flavored.
Yeah.
Here in Austin, Texas.
I feel like I live on that Tex-Mex aisle off South First Street here.
So for me mango frozen.
Margarita is just like, you know, just hits it a different spot than a, just a traditional line, but I really love just a nice traditional one on the Rocks.
Yeah.
Nice.
Emily's all about the spicy bars.
Honestly, that's the thing for me is, I don't necessarily like The Salt Room.
Interesting.
Alright, well, we're opening it up.
If anyone wants to jump on stage and show us your plate or your empty playing or just come on up and ask a question to Chef.
You're welcome to Joey.
Yes.
I agreed Sean.
That plate, looks amazing.
I hope half of that is gone already, but this is a video to delicious everyone's off chowing down there.
Down anyone who wanted to shout down with us on stage?
I am only a taco by tense.
Okay.
If not, oh, here we go.
Andrews.
He's intrigued.
Alexis is getting right off the stove.
Got it.
That is the my, a professional chef move.
You can possibly do.
I do that twice a day, three days on our three times on Sunday.
I guarantee it like that is such a chef thing.
So wait and be right in line with me.
Good job.
Alexis you want to come on stage?
He said you're confused about how people were plating.
Well, we will invite you with totally up to you.
If you want to join us.
I in the meantime.
Andrew, is down to jump on up.
Hello, Andrew.
Hey, how's it going?
I have got my tortilla.
Nice.
I am gonna get this one.
Is this?
This is the Andrew song special here.
Yeah, so I am going to try to make a Korean.
Taco, because I am Korean love it, ingredients.
Little bit of a talk.
Okay.
Talk to your right.
What are these leaves again?
Yeah, so that in particular the bundle that we do send you is just a field medley of herbs.
But that one in your hand was a Malabar spinach leaf lettuce.
Got more kids coming on my side.
So you will start hearing some kids screaming, but I am going to top this off with some salsa.
Love it.
Nice.
That sounds like my taco.
Cheers.
Cheers Alexis, so how's it going with plating?
I mean, you're just diving right in the drink.
I didn't know the artistic plate was part of it.
I was like very much building, right into a taco in my mouth, kudos to all providers out there.
That wasn't me.
What's yours do you Alexis?
It looks like Zachary Smith is down.
Eat on stage with us.
Yeah, take me off.
I don't want to see me anymore.
You're welcome.
Today.
We're all just hang it right through Andrew.
Thank you Chef.
That was wonderful.
Thank you.
I would love to ask.
What's everyone's favorite.
Salsa.
You guys lean towards the Verde like myself, or do you like this month pregnancy or bit more?
The answer is yes, Emily.
You have a fourth Taco.
Maybe even if it.
All right, I gotta say, my favorite.
I think out of the three meats, I have here, the fork with the soft rubber dogs.
Yeah, it's clutch.
Shelby boy, gets it.
I really eat.
One of the meat straight up.
Probably go for the steak.
But when you put the toppings with the Carnitas, that's the best.
It's a magical feeling.
It's a Magical pair.
That's what we're here for, right?
I felt all my good brain controls released.
Once I get into that when we got to feed the Sous chefs to, so make sure you feed your for making some shots.
Swallows it, they do the sweeping, you know, they have come through and especially my line in my kitchen is always nice and clean my little Hoover vacuum suit sous-chef over here.
Keeps it tight.
Yeah, whenever she's not around, they drop something on the floor.
What do I do now?
I know it's like, so I do I have to pick this up?
This is not fair.
Starting work, Chef.
Great job.
All right, so we're going to move to lounge and Continue the remainder of this time together and lounges are there.
Any final thoughts?
Chef that you have for us any like tips, best practices, a Twitter, quote, anything, keep those fingertips tucked in?
All right.
Next time I see you guys.
I better see all everyone with 10 fingers.
Keep on cooking.
It's, you know your own expression, and we're here to eat.
So Enjoy the food, guys.
It was really such a pleasure cooking with all of you.
I am looking forward to the next one.
So I will see you then.
Thank you, everyone.
Enjoy your food idea.
We grow primarily Greens on here and I wanted to have more land because gardening was a hobby that got out of control.
So we practice permaculture principles out here.
The way you can Define permaculture is that get is a way to design an ecosystem that is beneficial to plan.
Soil and humans.
One of our primary missions is to lead the land in better shape than when we found it.
A lot of farms, don't practice that we have these tunnels.
We have hundred-foot tunnels.
We have five of them on our farm right now, and they are great.
Protectors from extreme weather star Greenhouse.
And then we transplant by hand, all of these letters, heads that we have grown in our Greenhouse from seed.
So, everything we grow here, we have grown ourselves.
I love, love, love growing lettuce.
What you'd be enjoying at your event or lettuce is from this bed and most likely this bed for the folks who are going to be part of this event.
I think you're going to really like this lettuce.
One of the things that I really love about Austin is how food-centric it is.
So many great restaurants in Austin by local and local farms.
There's a really nice healthy diversity of farms.
And that wouldn't exist if restaurants and school districts, grocery stores, weren't supporting those local farms.
The more you keep your money local, the more you're growing the economy and the more you're Growing the future health of your own community.
And that's, it's great to see, Austin.
Not only talk that talk.
I really walk that walk.
She knows what's coming.