Put it in all caps so that I hear it better.
That's that doesn't make any sense.
Anyways, that's what we're going to do.
We're going to use the chat for any questions.
If I need to slow down, please let me know.
I am going to go ahead and try to like, slow it down.
Come back checking on everyone and give everyone a break to make sure we're all caught up.
I do want to go ahead and let you all check in with each other.
A little bit of connection.
Just a moment.
We're going to see that pop up.
That Linda was telling us about appear on your screen.
Inviting you to the breakout room.
Just hit except and I will see you back here in about seven minutes for the plant-based kit.
Remember before you go on that.
Breakout Ro room.
Turn your oven up to 400°.
Now do that now so that way we're not playing catch-up.
All right, get your plates ready.
Get your knives ready.
Sharpen those knives up.
We're not going in the microwave tonight.
We're going on the stove or using fire.
Okay, okay.
Owner of Olden, Food, Forest a sustainable Farm in Rogers, Texas, we grow primarily Greens on here, 2016 started, Urban farming in South Austin, and I wanted to have more land because gardening was a hobby that got out of control.
So we practice permaculture principles out here.
The way you can Define permaculture is that it is a way to design an ecosystem that is beneficial to Plants soil, and humans.
One of our primary missions is to lead the land in better shape than when we found it.
A lot of farms don't practice that we have these tunnels.
We have Hundred-Foot tunnels.
We have 5 mm on our farm right now, and they are great.
Protectors from extreme weather star Greenhouse.
And then we transplant by hand, all of these letters, heads that we have grown in our Greenhouse from seed.
So, everything we grow here, we have grown ourselves.
I love, love, love growing lettuce.
Well, you'd be enjoying at your event or lettuce is from this bed and most likely this bed for the folks who are going to be part of this event.
I think you're going to really like this lettuce.
One of the things that I really love about Austin is how food-centric it is.
So many great restaurants in Austin by local farms.
There's a really nice healthy diversity of farms.
And that wouldn't exist if restaurants and school districts, grocery stores, weren't supporting those local farms.
The more you keep your money local, the more you're growing the economy and the more you're Growing the future health of your own community.
And that's, it's great to see Austin.
Not only talk that talk, don't really walk that walk.
Awesome, and that's Austin or whatever Community you're in.
We have truly believed to support your local food community and to keep the food economy, booming that you must put your dollars back into that and enjoy the freshest, most delicious foods because I guarantee you wherever you are.
I saw some cities, you're in San Diego.
Has one of the best farmers markets in the world.
You're going to find these great products and it really great that we can bring this Central Texas.
Mostly Austin Centric, But Central Texas ingredients to you.
Now, you don't have salads out.
You don't have that lettuce.
That lettuce is out of season until early next year.
However, and that there's a small part of the video where the onions are sticking up and those onions, take about eight months to grow.
And we're actually using those sweet Texas onions today that were growing.
When that video was filmed pretty cool.
Alright, so at a certain point, too, Two or a few points this evening.
I am going to break away and say, okay plant-based kit standard kit.
This is one of those moments.
I want to be really clear about that.
Alrighty.
So here we go.
Plant-based kit.
I had said earlier to go ahead and heat up your oven a little preheated 400 degrees.
One thing I like to do just for cleanliness sake because I always like to kind of line my baking dishes casserole, pan, cookie pan with foil.
When I am cooking these Foods, you Savory Foods.
So that when I am done with this, I can use my agrees.
I can just pull that foil off, give it a quick rinse, and my pot is now clean.
I am going to go ahead and put this in the oven.
I have combined.
Both the sweet potato and the carrot.
But I have not put those mushrooms in there.
Again.
This is for the plant-based kit.
There's about 10 or 12 of you who have that kit, the carrots and the sweet potatoes are in the oven.
Your mushrooms are sitting next to your stove.
All right, you are taken care of for a minute.
I am now going to go over to the standard kit and talk about the proteins that we are going to cook in those pans that I told you earlier to have on the stove.
I have already heated them up.
Because I like to get a little bit of a jump start.
So go ahead and start heating your pans up at this point.
And for the plan base, we are also going to do a little sauteing.
So you two will have a saute pan for your mushrooms.
But let us get your pan heated up.
Now.
One thing I like to do is I like to take my three proteins back to the standard kit.
I am going to take my three proteins.
I have a chicken tinga.
I have a pork carnitas and then I have some carne asada made with this delicious pea, Loretta.
Strip steak.
So I have those three proteins.
I have taken my knife, and I am cutting this almost like a book.
So that I can open my compostable packaging up all the way.
I am going to use this packaging, not only as a tool, but when I am finished with it, I am going to put it in my compost, and I am going to use it to go back into the Earth.
Okay, we're very proud of the fact that we have figure out a way to Source.
All compostable, packaging.
I am moving to the stovetop now.
All right, I have my chicken team.
You're going right into the pot for the little lid on it.
Would put this on low heat.
This is my Kamala talking about earlier, or my flat top or griddle top.
Sometimes it's called a Plancha.
I have this on a very low heat.
I am going to cook some tortillas here.
I am also going to heat up my chicken.
Get I have chicken in there.
My sauce pots.
Now, I have started my cast iron and then for those who have the plant base, I have a saute pan here.
I am just going to put a little bit of fat and you have a package it says new.
True loyal in your kit, and we're going to put some of that neutral oil onto our heating up pans.
Well, hands aren't super hot yet because I just asked you to turn them on, but they're going to get there in a minute.
You're going to start to see some of this oil start to smoke.
That is good.
We're at that smoking point.
A little bit of white or gray smoke or light colored gray.
Smoke is great.
We're scared of black smoke, but we like gray smoke.
Okay.
First, I am going to eat see here, my carne asada.
Am I pants since I saw that smoke?
I know it's hot enough to do what I needed to do here.
All righty.
Now my other saute pan, I am just sort of waiting for that when that oil, when the viscosity of, it turns into more like a water texture, will know where they are.
All right.
After the sear on this.
I am going to use the same pan to heat up my carnitas.
So that's just going to go for a minute.
I have that at about a medium to medium-high heat.
Yes, you can.
It's a home packaging compostable it.
Is it takes a little longer, right?
I wouldn't like, lying here rose with it, but you can put it straight into your compost.
I am going to go ahead and open up my tortilla packaging because I like to get a little bit of air in those tortillas.
All right, I am starting to smell the aroma of that steak.
I am going to come back over here.
Let me grab my tongs.
Now remember, this steak is already fully cooked.
All we're doing is we're getting a sear on it.
For a little bit of texture and flavor, and we're heating it through.
I also see that my own oil now is this shimmering around the pan?
So I am going to put plant-based kit, my mushrooms in here and start to saute these Now, these are mushrooms with a mixture of aromatic.
Some of those delicious onions from Bolton Food, Forest and Wheeler coche.
Does anybody know what we look on chairs?
No, takers on the wheelchair.
Will it talk to an is a fungus that grows on the outside of corner?
So that is correct.
Chris.
It is a corn fungus and it is a delicacy in many parts of the world, especially in Mexico.
And some of the other Latin American countries.
All right, when we come back over here and give this a flip.
If you see, I have some nice caramelization on my steak.
When we go ahead and lower my heat down to medium-low.
Let that heat through.
I am also checking my mushrooms here.
Giving them saute with your cooking.
Those mushrooms are going to get also very aromatic or going to start to smell.
This is not a pepper in there.
The garlic, the onion.
Now, there is a little bit of chili in there, some salt and pepper, but it's not too spicy.
I promise.
We're probably at about a two or three on a 1 to 10 scale.
Okay.
Now I am going to check my chicken.
Give it a little stir.
Make sure that's heating up.
I see some steam coming out of there.
So I know it's doing what it's supposed to do.
Again, that chicken is fully cooked.
So I know that all I have to do is get it warm.
All right.
I am going to go ahead and pull my Stakeout.
Looks.
I love good.
Caramelization on both sides.
I am gonna let that rest.
We nearly didn't need to cook it for long since fully cooked.
And now I am going to put my pork carnitas in that same pan.
There's already enough residual fat from the stake, plus the Carnitas themselves are cooked and a delicious aromatic flat.
So we don't, we don't need to add anymore.
It's going to do what it needs to do in this pan.
Give another saute on these.
Flip of the saute pan on these mushrooms.
Got my steak resting.
My Carnitas a pop in here.
I have my chicken tinga heating up, and if I am a plant-based, I have carrots and squash in the oven.
Now.
I am going to slow her down.
Let my Carnitas pop and cook.
I am gonna put my mushroom pan on very low, and I am going to check in and make sure everyone.
MK, would you not put the Carnitas in the pan?
The mushrooms were in because you should not have both.
Yes.
The one that steak was in.
So pull out that stage.
Let it rest Carnitas go into that pan.
That is correct.
Rachel.
M'Kay.
You are good MK.
I am curious.
You have mushrooms in your kit.
Okay, good.
So that's why I would have been confused too.
Okay.
So the next thing I am going to do is I am going to start to grab my tortillas, and we have sent you a lot of tortillas.
This Taco kit makes 12 different tacos for of three different kinds of finding out how you want to build them.
Now, if you aren't going to eat 12 tacos tonight, what I would do, little Pro tip, the save about half of your tortillas and eat them maybe with breakfast.
Bones, some of you, especially the Texans may know what breakfast tacos are you, you few people in California.
There are a lot like breakfast burritos, but smaller the burritos aren't really a real thing.
So yeah, 12 Spencer.
I am eating 12 to, I am right there with you.
All right.
I am going back to my stovetop.
My Carnitas have been going for about 2 minutes.
I am going to give them a flip.
Look at that.
Have caramelization.
I have crispiness.
That is exactly what we want.
I am going to drop for tortillas on my flat top or my go Mal.
I am going to check my oven.
You know, I am going to turn my oven off because I know.
That my veggies are done and they look awesome.
I see some delicious.
I have a delicious Aroma.
There's some steam coming off of them, and I am now heating up tortillas.
Alright, the next thing I am going to do is I am going to lower my heat of my Carnitas to a very low.
Now, I have everything on low heat except for my tortilla and my chicken, which I have on a medium heat.
I have turned off my oven.
Okay, we have gotten through the hard part.
We have gotten through the cooking part.
Let me heat up a few more tortillas, and we're going to start doing the garnishes.
I am going to slow down, just slow it down just a bit.
See where everyone is.
There're any questions that need to be answered Eileen.
Look at that.
That looks amazing.
Breakfast.
Tacos on the bottom.
That is correct.
And okay.
Where do you live now?
Actually, if you have your sous chef working for you, smart, that's what we do to.
Wow.
You just went for it.
Andrew from Dallas, okay, in case oh, you know, you know about breakfast tacos.
Okay, I am going to bring my steak over got my chicken over.
I am flipping.
Tortillas that's going.
Well.
I have got my veggies.
I have got my mushrooms, right?
We're on the same page.
I am going to go ahead, and we have my tortillas this first round of tortillas is hot, which is awesome.
I am gonna put them in my tortilla warmer.
Remember if you don't have a tortilla warmer and you just have some linen, that works very well.
What's happened is that linen?
The steaming of that is going to continue to cook the tortillas.
Alright.
Now, we're going to build our Taco plate.
Does anybody have any questions before we start going on this mise en place?
Yes.
How do we save the tortillas?
Good question.
I would keep some of this parchment paper that we have between them and if we're just going to save him for a day or two just put them into like a nice pork side, zip lock bag and kind of just try to get most of the air out of there.
The less air or oxygen in the packaging, the better.
If you don't have a Ziploc bag that these will fit in, it's best to keep them flat.
Just use some plastic wrap and wrap them very tightly, then put them in the refrigerator.
You want to save them in the refrigerator.
All right.
So before this meat or veggies get cold.
I want to start building out my taco plate.
First things first.
We have this oaxacan Cassio, this cheese that is made for us, in Oaxaca by a family that's been making the cheese for generations.
And you may see a hawk and queso in the grocery store and the markets.
But I guarantee you, when I can say this with complete certainty, none of it tastes like this.
Mrs. The most delicious.
Well, how can Castle you Had I promise next, I am going to open up our chili Diablo, which is a grilled.
Jalapeño.
I am going to leave mine.
Well, you may leave your toll because I like to do is take a bite of my taco and then take a bite of my pepper, but you can also cut it into an aha, which is the shape of roasted peppers like this.
When you come this way, put that right in the middle.
Next.
I am gonna open up my schnee pack which are these pickled onions.
These are pickled, the red onions that are pickled with habanero.
So there's a little more heat to this element.
There's some fresh garlic and Mexican oregano in there.
These are delicious.
Addition.
Next, I am going to open up my avocado.
Texans.
The avocados and Texas are out of season.
So these are California, avocados.
Thank you, California.
I don't know what you would do with avocado without avocados.
I don't know what I would do without our kados.
You're welcome.
All right, I am gonna put take a spoon, and I am going to just four separate this from the skin like to do that and kind of flip it over, and we will show you a fun little trick here.
So you do that, do the same with the next avocado.
Just take your spoon kind of scoop it out.
Like so, flip it over.
Now.
You have two nice habit, avocados, right?
I am going to take my chef knife.
And I am just going to slice them like this if your knife sharp and you can move your knife pretty quickly on this go in and out like that.
And then I am going to take my hand and go like this and create this little avocado spread here, which looks really beautiful on the plate like this.
And that is a trick that's pretty easy to do.
If you try a few times.
I am only going to do half my avocado to start, getting to the next piece later.
I have some of that charred onion.
We were talking about earlier from the farm.
I like to put that right next to my grilled.
Jalapeño.
I will take my fresh cilantro.
If you see, I am kind of building everything on one side of the plate right now.
That's intentional.
We will take some of my mold own salt, give it a little sprinkle of the over the avocado because we love salty avocado, and we cut some lime wedges.
Just cut them.
However, you want the build some more of the plate with my line, like so right?
Okay.
My steak is rested.
It's still warm.
My chicken is still in the pot on the stove.
So I know that's warm by Carnitas are on very low heat, then their cast iron pan getting nice and crispy.
So I know those are warm if you have, if you have veggies, and they were still in your hot cookie tray.
We can go ahead and start placing your veggies here like to do is the mush mushrooms here.
Maybe the squash, the carrots.
Okay, let us go back to the stake.
If you see here, I am slicing Against the Grain.
You can see that national natural thread Asian of grain of the meat.
If you slice against it, you will get a month, tender much more tender bite of meat and if you see this should be cooked.
It's nice and crispy on the outside and cook to a perfect medium-rare medium.
Say that again.
I was fully cooked when you got it.
We're just heating.
It's Ruth.
I am gonna grab some carnitas when we put these on the plate as well.
These have gotten crispy textured.
They're so anxious and flavor.
You see little pockets of fattiness.
And then I am going to take my chicken tinga.
Because with an adobo Pepper marinade that will put that right here.
Now.
I have all my proteins.
Maybe you have all your veggies on your plate like, so I would go ahead and stick your finger in there and get a little case because it's so delicious.
I am gonna go to my last few ingredients.
All right, I have some of these Market vegetables, which are also grown in a local Farm, not the food force that you saw on the video.
These are grown at government Acres.
Then I am going to slice my radish.
You may have radish, you might have turnips.
Maybe Abby.
It's all seasonal.
All depends on which Farm.
It's coming from might have carrots.
They might be yellow.
The might be, or I am just going to use these to garnish here because I know when I built my tacos.
I like to have this fresh peppery crunch of radish.
Maybe this fresh crisp, textured of carrot.
So I am going to slice these really thin.
On a bias like, so, If these Cuts aren't available to totally cool, you can do a die, you can do a julienne.
You can take a mandolin and slice them really thin.
If you have one of those at home, let me again, I am just building.
I am building the taco plate.
I want to eat.
I am thinking about putting meat in my tortilla or vegetables.
Maybe some cheese, some jalapeno, some avocado.
Some of these, nice fresh crisp vegetables.
I am gonna take I was might have my lime wedge that have this package of fresh beautiful herbs, and we're just going to garnish more of our plate with these.
You may have some chrysanthemums flower, maybe some diaphanous.
I have here some kale Leaf.
You might have mirror gold.
Everyone has something a little bit different, and I am just putting those beautiful garnishes on my plate.
I have already put my smoke.
Fresno, salsa into one.
My Verde sauce into another.
Your avocado didn't go like that actually.
That's alright.
You will do it again.
Your avocado money Bells.
Perfect.
Awesome.
Cool.
I have my tortillas my salsa verde, which is made with tomatillo.
It's also made with some aromatics and garlic and onions, how the finial, sodano then we have our smoked Fresno.
Salsa.
Make the to Fresno pepper.
Grilled tomatoes.
How's everyone else deal with their taco place?
Are they coming along?
If so, I would love to build a taco with you.
Anyone want to build a taco with me?
All right, I am gonna grab one tortilla.
We're going to build a taco then we're going to go into our taco party lounges, right?
All right, Elizabeth looking hyped up.
Danielle Ashley.
Hello.
Actually, your avocado didn't go this way.
Yeah, so my avocado doesn't look anything like that.
I will give you some footage here.
You can 300 pretty close.
That's what do you think?
It's close?
You did a much better job, but I definitely don't think it has some work to disclosure.
I browser working on a sushi restaurant.
So we have done a lot of that I did too.
So that's even more embarrassing like with the plastic wrap on the top of the Dragon Roll.
Yeah.
Yeah, right.
Never for me is what we're learning.
Thoughts of well, I like the effort.
How's yours?
Come out Elizabeth.
Hey my avocados.
This Con Neal not slide.
You know.
This stays just came off.
So I am running a little behind but this is awesome.
Maybe you're going a little fast, but you have everything hot.
It looks like your everything ready to go.
It's all going to come together and have been a delicious Taco hard to you.
All right, I am gonna go out and have my first taco from then.
We're going to go into our taco party lounges, but anybody who's available to make their Taco now as well.
Let us go ahead and have a bite a toast, a taco toast, if you will.
Oh, yes material, that looks awesome.
Aaron.
That was great.
What's up, bro?
Stock of you build.
I built carnitas.
Did you guys build the charger Carnitas and somebody build their veggie tacos, or they love those?
What's a salsa that you like on that?
I like to smoke.
Fresno with my car meet this, the red one, put in the chat, your favorite salsa, red or green?
That's a very good point.
Spencer.
You don't need this first.
You're not going to anything else.
We got green red all day.
Verde green.
Yes.
Yeah, the red is so Smoky, right?
That smokes.
Fresno.
Hmm.
Save some tortillas for your breakfast tacos.
That red salsa goes so good with eggs.
All right, so we're going to move to the taco party Lounge.
If you look at the top of your window at Taco party, will be opening momentarily.
Click on the tab and join the party.
See you back here by clicking kids to the top of your window in about 10 minutes ago.
She knows.
Hello.