And then, so hold on.
Let me just get familiar with intro.
Good morning.
Good afternoon.
He will CDA members.
So, okay, so great to be here with you today.
My name is Oleg told the CEO co-founder virtual platform you are today.
Okay.
Yeah, I will mix up some Spanish Spanglish in here.
We're super excited for your two amazing days with you.
Here at welcome.
We have built a virtual event platform that skills production, and human connection.
So glad that you're here today.
I will show you around.
Let us jump into some housekeeping notes.
Okay, got it, and then we will go into public.
Check you a help.
Let us just run it back and see.
Do a couple tanks.
Hey folks.
Good morning.
Good afternoon.
LCD, a members Bienvenidos.
Welcome.
It is so great to have you here today.
My name is Roberto Ortiz, and I am the co-founder and CEO of the virtual platform that you're on.
Here.
Today.
We're super excited for the two days that you have ahead of you.
And here at welcome.
We have designed a platform that enables human connection and production at scale.
So, so glad to have you here, but first, I will To show you around and dive into some housekeeping notes.
Let us run that back.
Was there?
It was that intentional.
The stop to the music.
No, it's muted.
Now.
What have you just bring it up?
Just a tad.
Let me bring it down.
Attack.
It's muted.
Want me to try on my side?
Okay, why don't we stop the track?
So start from the beginning.
How, how long is the track?