Hi everyone.
My name is Linda chew.
I am with marketing here at welcome and welcome to welcome.
I am caught, I am joining you all.
I am producing this event as well, Live from Paris France.
It's late at night, but it's time for tacos and somewhere.
It's Taco Time and it's time to have a cocktail.
So let us get started.
Okay, first things first, gotta go through some housekeeping notes.
Excuse me, as you can all see in the public chat.
Please drop in any questions that you have.
If you have any reactions share photos, as you can see, Pete has done of your progress and show us your taco photos.
We'd love to see them.
And then the next thing is, if you have any questions for the chef, please drop that in the Q&A tab, which you see to the right of your screen right over this way.
In addition to that you might have seen some really fun polling like this.
Really cool one that I put up.
How would you rate your Chef skills?
5, MasterChef 432 microwave show.
I would count myself at a three.
I don't know about other people, but if you have any more selections that you want to contribute to in the polling, please do so on the screen here, or you can actually do that in the pull column.
Last but not least, you will see help tab in the Tap tab button, scuse me.
If you have any questions about your experience, please drop some drop, but note right in there and one of our team members will get back to you as soon as possible.
Okay, so we have got some fun stuff cooked up for you today.
And we are going to be making some pretty cool tacos.
We have Chef Phillip here, who comes from us from assembly.
He has four nominations in the James Beard Foundation for outstanding pastry chef as well.
Is Starship not comms Rising Star, pastry chef in 2012, and a listing among zagat's, zagat's, National Power players, 2014.
In addition to that, he has National recognition in bone Appetit, food and wine Cook's Illustrated art Culinaire, thrillist eater.com, and you name it without further Ado.
I would love to introduce Chef Philip Speer.
He's been amazing with us, and we're so excited that you get to meet with him today and cook with him.
So, please let me introduce chef.
Back here with you an experience, welcome, and I am jealous of you being in France, but happy to be here to make tacos with all of you.
As I was introduced.
I am chef and owner of assembly also come with a restaurant here in Austin.
The first thing I want to do though is I want to start this evening with a toast.
So each of you has received the kit.
If you open up your kit and your kid, I am sure most of you have already opened your kits, but that's my experience.
At least, is that up to this point?
Everyone opened it, they want to see what's in the box, and they have already organized it.
That's great.
We're going to go through all those pieces, but first, I want to have a drink with you.
So I am going to use a rocks glass.
I have my RTD that's a little assembly slang that we have right there.
That is a ready to drink.
Margarita from of you have non-alcoholic version, which is my favorite version, but they're all delicious.
I have some lime salt.
So you do have a package of lime salt.
There are two packages of salt in your kit this evening.
The lime salt is the one we're going to use first.
Then I like to use a little plate so that I can Rim, my rocks glass.
And then I am going to use a line here.
To complete this whole process.
I have gotten some Iced Out.
And now we're going to begin making a drink.
And then we're going to have a toast first.
Let us go ahead and dump that line Salt right on there.
Next, I am going to take a little bit of this line because I am going to use this line throughout the evening.
I am going to run my glass like this.
Now, I am going to take the moisture from the lime juice and I Rim the rim with, and I am going to put it through the lime salt.
So I have myself here, a nice, beautiful rimmed glass.
Now.
Remember, this is two drinks worth.
Although, I am not going to judge you for how you drink your drinks, but I am going to put some ice in a rocks, glass saved my limes, salt, for my next dream.
Finish this drink, the pour about half of this in here.
Save the other half for later on in my meal, maybe even for dessert.
And there we have our Margarita the ready to drink made famous by our restaurant here.
In Austin called comedor.
All right, and I would like to go ahead and have a little bit of a toast with you.
Two beautiful evening, wherever you may be.
I think we're all over the country.
I am here in Texas, and I am happy to be here and grateful to be in your kitchen with you toast.
All right, that's pretty delicious.
How's your margarita?
I hope it's so good.
Alright next I just kind of want to go General like overview of our buddy, a taco kid that you have in front of you.
This evening.
This is actually kind of multi-course experience.
So while we have a drink in our hand, and we got our palate, nice and wet.
I am going to quickly, pull, pull a snack out so that we can munch on this snack.
We're going to go to breakout room in a minute.
After I go through the rest of the contents.
I want y'all to have a drink and some chips.
Or the top us to snack on, you know, for the 78 minutes.
We're in those breakout rooms, and we're gonna come back, and we're gonna cook our meal.
Okay, when we come back, it's going to go fast.
It's going to be fun right now.
Let us go ahead and let us pull out our bag of it says on there to topos which are our tips made of Masa, which is a corn flour that we grind every day from corn that we have sourced from different small farms in Mexico.
They come to us in the US.
Yes, we pay a premium for it.
That money goes right back into those small farms and in their communities, and then we have this delicious heirloom errant or Heritage corn that we see our process of mixed to Malaysian, which is a soaking calcifying process a little scientific.
It's pretty simple though, through that process.
We grind it into a corn flour, and then we make these chips, Ortho post, and I am going to pour those into a bowl.
So grab yourself a bowl, won't take long.
You should I trust you and your kitchen right now.
Reach out for a bowl.
I also have a little bit of a little salsa cup here that we're going to use.
Ramekin will salsa Bowl.
Anything will work.
If you have like a nice classroom can like this, it will work.
I like this for my salsa.
It's a perfect size, and I am going to put my salsa divorcee Otto's in there.
All right, just like so it's the only salsa that is in your kit.
You do have some broth in your kid, but this is not that because this the salsa divorce Shadows right here, and we together go to have a little bit of a chip.
So dipped the salsa.
What time?
When I crunch so good.
I just want you to keep these for your evening.
You can snack on them.
You can save them from the meal a little bit of texture when we a tacos, but just right now, enjoy Margaritas some chips and salsa as I walk you through the rest of the kit.
And we're going to break out in this room to get to know each other a little bit.
Let me go ahead and walk you through that process.
I have separated the ingredients.
I have a bowl here.
This is going to be for our bean salad.
The ingredients that bean salad or A package of beans and hominy here in are compostable packaging of a package of Rebel tomatoes.
Some pistachio oil and just dark red oil made from the pasilla pepper some honey.
Do queso fresco.
Onion and some herbs.
And that was just say herbs.
You also have a package of cilantro in your kit.
This is for a different part of the meal.
We're just using the herbs and there are two onions.
This is the Red Onion.
This is the ball.
I am going to serve it in.
I also need a mixing bowl.
Okay, that is The tools that I need for that being salad.
Next just so we get a little bit ahead.
I am going to walk you through this process.
I am gonna pull out my tortillas where we utilize that same corn today.
I have some blue corn.
Tortillas.
You could have any kind, you might have white, you might have yellow, you might have a red corn tortilla.
We're going to just pull those out.
Let them be a little life into them.
By take him out of that compostable Packaging.
I have some short rib video, short rib.
Now.
If you have a plant-based kit, this will be mushrooms.
Don't fret.
We're going to cook them the exact same way.
Okay, but we are going to use short, rib or mushroom.
I have cilantro.
I have some white onion and then some of our guests sealed that Oaxaca.
Okay, or oaxacan caps on beef, broth or mushroom broth.
Okay.
I have the rest of my life.
I am going to use a cutting board.
My knife last but not least my platter that I am going to use these.
Do these tacos are now?
Remember.
We're going to do eight.
Small tacos.
So, you want to play big enough for the tacos to fit around?
We also need another container for vessel for the consomme, which we will pour into this.
Once, we are finished building the tacos, right?
Large platter, couple, consummates about 6 ounces of consommé, if I start putting numbers out there and that means nothing to you.
That's fine.
That's going to hold about half a cup to a cup.
Okay?
Now I just want to walk over to the stovetop.
Tell you what we need here?
I am going to use a small sauce pot.
It's got about a 3 inside.
It's got about a 3-inch side here, and I am going to fill this is one thing.
I am going to use.
I am also going to use A saute pan here, or I am going to use a cast-iron.
I am going to use this to heat up our beef or arts or our excuse me, mushrooms, and then I have With me at the mall.
Now, you may not have one of these, that's fine.
We're going to do on that is we're going to heat up.
Our tacos.
Are for p as we're going to, like melt the cheese into the tortilla.
So if you don't have a Kamal or a griddle top or something of that sort, just think about something that you might cook like eggs on or pancakes or bacon like a nonstick.
Something pretty large cause we're going to cook multiple Tacos on that.
At the same time.
I am going to cook, you know, two or four to time.
You could do.
Depending on the size of your pan, you can you all?
I ate it once, but you likely don't have a pan that big unless you have maybe a built-in flattop.
We will just do a couple of the time and it's going to be super fun and super easy.
All right.
So one more time, when I go through all of that, we have our chips and salsa.
We have our poor drink.
All right, we have all the ingredients in a bowl for being salad.
We have our platter Consul make up here.
We pulled out the ingredients for a tacos.
I have here one pan to heat up my Beef or mushroom one pot to heat up my broth.
And then I have my Surface in which I am going to continue to cook the tacos.
Now, if you don't have multiple pans, you can actually make one pan work.
It will take a couple extra steps of pulling the meat out, putting it into a container and then wiping that pan out, but that's totally fine.
If you want to kind of cut down on your dishes.
All right, so they're going to give everyone a few minutes to kind of In fact, going to a breakout room.
And from there, we're going to come back, and we're going to start cooking.
All right, so you will see a screen inviting you to your breakout room?
Just hit except and I will see you back here in about seven eight minutes.
All right, they all get out of here.
Do you have put me into the big homes?
Alrighty, welcome back.
I hope everyone was able to connect a little bit, the breakout rooms.
Enjoy your Margarita and have some of your to do post and your salsa.
Need a little bit of smokiness from that red salsa.
It's so delicious.
And you have tanginess from the Verde sauce.
It's in there as well.
Maybe forger, second drink.
I don't know.
Again, not here to clock your drinking, but if you have it.
Now might be a good time to do.
So, we're going to make this salad.
What I want to do with this salad, those I want to give it a little bit of a marination period?
So we're going to start the salad.
We're not going to finish it all the way yet.
We're going to let the beans marinate for a little bit as we heat up our tacos.
Okay.
So the first thing I want to do is I am going to take my mixing bowl.
I am going to take my beans and hominy and before the package right in the bowl.
Just like so, super simple.
Okay.
Next, I have some red onion here.
I am just going to slice thinly, right across the grain like this.
I like to use about.
Half of what you're probably had in your kit personally with this amount of being.
So, you see how I have very seen that ratio.
I am going to save this onion for some stock or something.
Alright, next, I am going to take our Tomatoes these Rebel Tomatoes.
It comes from Marfa, Texas, and I am just going to cut the bigger ones in like third recorders.
Maybe the smaller ones and just halves like.
So we have some nice, Red Onion.
Excuse me.
You do have the red onion.
You also have some nice, red, tomatoes, and yellow tomatoes.
Some are sweeter than the other.
The yellow tends to be more.
Heart, right.
I am just going to start to give that a toss.
Next, I am going to take so you should have most of your line left.
You take a bit of that.
Give this some lime juice.
This is going to help the marination process.
I am going to take some of my mulled own salt.
You may not have open that package up yet.
That is the other package of salt.
You have.
I am going to season my salad a bit.
Now.
There has been some seasoning added.
So we're just adding a touch more really to taste.
I just have a pinch and I season from hi.
All right, so it gets nice and Incorporated, and then we take about two-thirds of my Paseo oil.
I am going to put it right on there.
I am only going to use two-thirds of it or so because I am going to use the rest of it to garnish when that time comes.
I have a kitchen spoon, give this a nice stir.
So what's happening?
Is that Smoky plescia.
All right, which is the Smoky lockable pepper.
The Red, Onion, the black beans, and the harmony.
With those Tomatoes, the salt, the lime are going to marinate and really impart a bunch of flavor.
Just going to put that aside.
I do have my herbs and my queso fresco and rest assured if you have a base hit York as a fresco is also plant-based.
We're just going to save that for when we plate our salad.
Okay.
It's just going to marinate for a bit.
— I would put my bowl back on my side, put the spoon and its place.
And now we're going to start cooking.
All right, step 1.
Let us take our beef broth, or you may have a mushroom broth.
Let us pour that into our sauce pot.
We nice and thick.
There's some good viscous bone broth in there.
You have the short rib broth.
Well, I am going to turn my burner on.
I am going to put that at about a medium-high heat, and we're going to let that heat up till it gets to about a simmer.
Now.
I am going to take my cast-iron pan.
I am going to put that on a low heat.
I have already done so personally so you go ahead and do that.
Put on a low heat.
We're just going to use this to heat.
Up our, our beef have that on a low heat.
Now.
I have my coma which I sorry about earlier or my flat top cooking surface here, which I am going to heat my tortillas and sort of do the finishing of my tacos on now.
This works very well-to-do multiple tacos.
If you do not have something like this cool.
We will get through.
It will use something else.
I do encourage you to buy one though.
If you cook often, it's great for bacon pancakes.
All To do eggs on it like to fry potatoes on it.
They usually on the other side have like a griddle, like a grill marks, you can grill fish on it.
So I am going to sort anyway, if you don't have any like this, a large pan, that you would cook Crepes or pancakes anything like that.
And we will work like a big non-stick pan works really?
Well.
This is cast iron.
It's nice and seasoned, but I am going to like take a little bit of my neutral oil and just give it another little seasoning oil so that when that time comes, I was ready to go.
So this is already on a low, to medium Heat.
I am just letting that heat up and get ready.
When the time comes we're going to turn the heat up a little bit more to a low medium to like a medium to medium-high, but for now, it's just heating slowly.
This pan is heating slowly.
My stock on my Quantum, an is heating slowly.
I am gonna check the chat and make sure that I am not missing any questions if we can go over to the chat.
Most Wanted.
Awesome.
I see a big dog.
Well as a cute dog.
All right.
It doesn't look like we have any real questions about the food.
So that's great.
But I do love that.
You're sharing your hearing your photos, showing your dog picks.
There's your canine sous-chef if you will.
Okay, so we have that on going up there.
Any questions, please, ask them now.
Next.
I am going to open up my short rib video.
And what I am doing is I am giving this three nice cuss like this, and I have kind of opened it.
Just opens up like a book.
So I am going to use this packaging to help you.
If you have the mushroom.
You cannot really do that with the mushroom.
Just give it one cut, but if you do have a short rib, this is a great way to do that.
Kind of put it aside.
We're not going to use it quite yet.
I have my guess, you know, that Oaxaca oaxacan to co which is made by hand from a family Oaxaca that makes us this cheese, and we get it at all of our restaurants a couple times a week.
It is amazing.
It is delicious.
Look how much that breaks up.
I would give it a little bite just to taste it.
It's creamy.
It's tart or Tonight, it's a rich and cheesy and also like that perfect amount of like funky cheese taster.
I am going to put that there and I will give up that are a little bit.
I am going to open up my white onion.
All right.
This is going to be to garnish our Taco.
So, often a street Taco, this video Taco sometimes like it's Aqua past or like a good carne asada.
You will see like a typical accompaniment or Darkness to that will be cilantro or, and lime wedges and diced up onion, white onion.
And so, we're going to prepare that typical.
Mint right now, so I have the cilantro.
It's already picked for you.
So we're not really have to do anything with that.
Besides things on the package.
We have the line we're going to make lime wedges shortly.
And then I am just going to give this a nice Dice and I like to do a small dice because I don't want to bite into too much onion.
Okay?
And again, I am going to use about half of what I have here and save the rest of this onion for a nice stock layer.
And that's what I am going to use.
Now, depending on what your tastes are, what your flavor profiles.
You love is.
You may want to be more.
You may want to do less, totally cool, Choose Your Own Adventure and that one, go ahead and open up my cilantro.
All right, and let us keep this lime and give ourselves some wedges.
Well, I just do a little wedge, maybe one wedge for every couple tacos or Doom, really small.
I am going to put that aside.
So basically this is going to be our garnish and that time comes.
All right.
Bye.
Now, pot is hot.
Looks like my consomme or my beef stock, or maybe a mushroom stock is heating up nicely that congealed Ridge.
Bone marrow in there as it's often doubt.
Give it a little taste of this.
Very delicious.
It's nice and hot which is how we want it.
So we're going to put that down to a low heat and then I have my Kamal heating up Now's the Time when I am probably going to put that on a medium heat because we're going to cook on that.
All right, I am gonna take about 5 Seconds, 10 seconds.
Check the chat.
Make sure there are no questions.
Make sure that everyone has confirmed that everyone has hot heating cooking vessels on their stove because once we get going, we got to go pretty fast.
I don't want anyone to fall behind.
All right.
Cool.
Good evening.
I am glad Pieces.
Good.
Yes, the cheese is so goofs.
Pete agrees.
We can good.
All right, looks like we're ready.
So, enjoy and chips and salsa.
Yeah, you can have you seen that mean?
It's like, what do I do?
Do I just keep beating them or do I die, right?
That's how I feel like substance also to cool down my plate.
We're ready.
I feel good.
You feel good.
Yes, yes.
Alright if you have just the regular traditional kit with the beauty of short rib tacos, we're going to do a little bit of oil in the pan.
If you have the mushroom kit, you will want a bit more oil because it is more liquidy.
Whereas the beef is more fatty.
I am going to open up the flip that down like that.
Remember, this is all compostable packaging that goes into my compost.
Now, this short rib and as well as the mushrooms fully cooked.
So we're really kind of just heating this up.
We're not really, we're not, we're not looking to get a sear.
Let me a little bit of a Sears, always great because it imparts some texture and flavor.
But this is cooked.
We want this heated up enough, to be able to break it up into are eight different top of.
Remember, this is enough for a taco.
So keep that in mind as you're building the tacos, now, there may be some pieces of the body.
Short rib.
That is, you know, that fattiness really just needs to be broken up with a spoon or spatula.
Go ahead and do that.
Now, a pair of tongs will work.
Right, let us just break that all up now, so that we go to build the tacos, ready to go.
Okay.
Now I am going to turn my heat off because I am hot, that's all it took.
If you see here, Mike, Lonesome a, let us come to a full boil.
I do not want it that hot because inevitably, I am gonna stick my fingers in it, and I am gonna burn myself.
So let us turn it down.
Hot me or if you have mushrooms?
It should look about the same hot stock.
I have my hot Kamal from now.
I have my tortillas right here.
I brought the cheese over.
And we're going to start building tacos, you already.
Okay, as you do have we seen the video Taco on the internet, the Instagram sensation or tick-tock?
Yes, doc.
We have seen it.
Oh, I see what you're saying about talking to me.
That's fine.
Yes, but he had tacos.
I will give you a little background.
We go in the big breakout rooms of where but it came from traditionally, but now this internet sensation is like this.
Ew, e, gooey Taco.
You dip it in the sauce.
You needed some food trucks all over Austin.
I don't have my blessing country because you haven't been traveled as much as normal, right?
But they're delicious.
They're made with here.
They're going to maybe be made with these delicious scones with you.
Is that we grind.
Yeah, super, super stoked, okay.
I am going to take one tortilla.
Just going to let me I would be counterintuitive to some of y'all.
I am a dip it into my consomme.
This is one of the reasons that it's important to have a seasoning or a fat on your cooking surface because when we put this 40 on the cooking surface, we don't want it to stick.
See what it's doing right there.
That's great.
That's perfect.
That's what we want.
I am going to do for tacos to start.
Again, we have give me enough for eight depending on how hungry you are, or who you have there with you, you can decide how many to cook.
Want to make sure?
Free and then let us go with the fourth one.
Okay.
Now I am going to go back to my first one because it is now ready for slip.
We hope that we have enough fat so that it doesn't stick you see.
I have a little sticky notes here, but that's okay.
I am gonna use.
Well today.
I am going to use the spoon but if you have a spatula you can use that too.
Get up off.
Give it a nice flip.
I am going to find a spatula real quick.
You should as well.
And you give the second one, the flip.
Again.
This is why it's important to have a decent amount of fat on your pan.
But if you have a little bit of a rip like I do, I am going to show you an incredible way to incredibly delicious way to fix it.
Even some of you may already know what I am going to do a tour to fix it.
All right, and I am going to give this next flip on the last one.
Like so cool.
These look great.
I am totally cool with this little bit of a rip here.
I am just going to throw some cheese over it.
Remember, this is enough cheese for ate tacos.
I know you're going to want to put so much of this delicious cheese on there.
But a little goes a really long way.
And if you have the Basically, you do have a plant-based cheese.
Alright, so we have now our meat.
Okay, when you put that right over the cheese again, this is enough for eight.
So each one is just a little bit of really rich meat and really rich cheese, okay.
I have another four tacos ready to go.
I have my mean I have my cheese on my garnish.
Ready, will take this spatula.
I am going to go ahead and fold my first Taco like, so again for my full my second Taco, like, so and you see right where I have that.
Rip.
No Freddie.
No worries.
I tacos are coming together.
This is not one of those like super.
This is, I mean, it is beautiful.
It's delicious.
It's not one of those super like high-touch fancy meal things right?
We're just making some delicious food.
Here are making sure that cheese is not kind of binding that taco down, and then we take some more of that consomme.
I am just going to put it over my tacos.
I want to keep that taco.
Nice and gooey.
Right.
Look at that.
And you see the heat is just making that evaporate.
You got the cheese coming off the side.
That's exactly what we're looking for.
Let that cook for another minute.
Even split.
Give a flip.
Another flip.
You got crispy cheese.
There we go.
I am going to start with my next tortilla.
So I can do four more.
Put these tacos up to the side of us.
Lower heat side of my Kamal.
Make sure have some more fat down there because I didn't have enough to begin with.
If you remember, that's fine, less and learn can always fix that.
Take my soaps for Kia.
Remember this consomme we're going to end up using it as our dip.
All right.
All right, we're going to pull that first few tacos off.
They're going to stay nice and hot and start putting them on my plate.
Like so.
The first one here.
I told you this part.
We're going to start moving a little bit fast.
But again, we're just making tacos.
This is fun.
This is not rocket science or super fancy food.
This is delicious and miliar.
Homey style Homestyle food.
All right.
Where to go Keys down on that?
First one, I flipped.
Put into that meat in there.
Go to the next split.
So let us get a little bit of color on it.
Like a little caramelization.
That's great.
We want that.
Please rest a cheese for the last few tacos.
Make sure evenly.
Throw s***.
A couple tacos in the meat.
Or mushrooms.
Now, I will get let you in on a little secret.
I actually this means great.
This is from a local Rancher here in Texas, high quality delicious free-range beef and I just, I love eating it.
I have no, you know, have no aversions to meat or beef.
But this kit, I actually prefer the mushrooms are so good.
So if you ever offered an opportunity to eat, Mushrooms in this way.
I highly recommend it.
I give a little fold here.
The fold on my next taco.
And then my last fold, I am going to let that cook for a minute.
It unfolds, go ahead and come back and just kind of force it uses that cheese to help find it.
Okay, see that perfect.
I give it one more spoonful of consomme like so, Make sure that these are nice and gooey.
It's almost like, you know, into ladas aren't super common in Mexico.
And the way that you see them in the u.s.
You're more actually more like this.
We just have a fold over a little bit of sauce and some filling.
Okay, cool.
All those last few cooks.
Let us go ahead and finish our bean salad because this will just take a minute.
We have that marinated Bean that's going to go straight into the bowl.
We have some of our honey do queso fresco, which is a local cheese will go to Austin.
We have our fresh herbs here.
Let us hear some of them up there.
Different herbs in here and there might be some frilly mustard.
You might have some amaranths wood.
Sorrel, even all these are grown just for us at our farm.
Okay.
What Charleston, dianthus Leaf Samara gold leaf, and then we just want that to look really beautiful to take a little bit more of that Paseo oil.
We had just finish it.
This number, that's a fully compostable bag.
And that is finished, and we go back to wear the clothes.
They did great and turn all the heat off on my stove.
Now.
I am going to finish building out my taco platter here.
Look at that.
Nice crispy side Bowie.
Let us just Yes, I am right.
And she's here, and I am going to take you as my consomme looking for it, right in?
Think of if you want to compare to something think of like an Azu sandwich, right?
Where you take your sandwich and take a bite and dip it in your broth.
Take these onions.
So she long throw?
How to fold the tacos?
Now, you can't really you're right.
Danielle mess up a taco too poorly.
How to fold the taco.
I just, you know, I use the tongs it's bad.
So I am sure we're past that point now, but I just saw that in the top here.
I have some lime wedges.
Take the rest of this onion.
All right, we have it.
Like so.
Even a little bit into the consummate is how I prefer that, because some of that onion flavor, starts to come out, oil starts to come out like that.
And there we have it.
The Vessel Margarita, we have already eaten our chips and salsa.
You probably you may have drank and had a drink of all your Margarita by now, too.
How does that look for y'all?
I know.
Are you enjoying it?
Are we?
All right.
I would love to have a first bite with you.
But I want to make sure that everyone catches up who everyone who's cooking tonight.
And if you're not cooking tonight, and you do have your kit rest assured.
There are instructions in the kit are super clear.
You have a little bit of some structural video on our part.
And so now you have a good idea of how it's supposed to go.
And yeah, you can just follow those instructions, but I am gonna go ahead and have this first bite.
So I like to use like to grab the taco.
Okay, I have some lime, make sure I have some of that cilantro on there, some of those onions.
And I am going to dip it into that consomme.
Get that.
This is a little messy.
That's okay.
This is how we do it.
That's so delicious.
What do y'all think?
Is he one having a bite yet?
Yes, you can drag and drop a picture into the text.
I am gonna go have a bite of my bean salad.
Now sometimes a bean salad may seem kind of boring, but I show you.
This means I was really delicious.
I encourage you to have a bite now.
What do y'all think?
Danielle.
Did you do delete all your tacos?
I sure hope not.
I hope they left some for you.
Awesome.
So I assume there're any questions because everyone's still cooking when I hope that everyone's having a great experience with the cooking or you're eating and enjoying it so much.
What I would like to do is know if there's no more.
No more instructional questions.
Let us go into these breakout rooms to have a taco party.
And I would love to come in and out of those rooms and check in.
And you all, maybe tell you a little bit of story of how this came about, maybe share a chocolate with you, because, you know, I am ready for dinner as well.
All right, now to go into the breakout rooms, you're going to have a little prompt.
On your screen will say join.
Join the taco party.
Go ahead and click on that and join that taco party.
Yeah, I think that's how they want to do.
She knows.
Booster, you know, stuck out.
She knows that guy.
Does he ever belong here?
Baby, I omentum and no doubt.
Cuando me outside your so don't chose a Bulgari.
Not by your the what I do anymore.
Is he do my dear to permit, the September of daughter?
I am using gonna look into a mirror.
I am 42 years old, but that is impressive.
She knows what's coming.
You know, Stackhouse.
She knows that guy that she ever belong here.
McConnell owner of bouldin food Forest, sustainable Farm in Rogers, Texas, we grow primarily Greens on here, 2016 started, Urban farming in South Austin, and I wanted to have more land because gardening was a hobby that got out of control.
So we practice permaculture principles out here.
The way you can Define permaculture is that get is a way to design an ecosystem that is beneficial to plan.
Since oil.
And humans, one of our primary missions is to lead the land in better shape than when we found it.
A lot of farmers.
Don't practice that we have these tunnels.
We have hundred-foot tunnels.
We have five of them on our farm right now, and they are great.
Protectors from extreme weather star Greenhouse.
And then we transplant by hand, all of these letters, heads that we have grown in our Greenhouse from seed.
So, everything we grow here, we have grown ourselves.
I love, love, love growing lettuce.
Well, you'd be enjoying at your event or lettuce is from this bed and most likely this bed for the folks who are going to be part of this event.
I think you're going to really like this lettuce.
One of the things that I really love about Austin is how food-centric it is.
So many great restaurants in Austin by local farms.
There's a really nice healthy diversity of farms.
And that wouldn't exist if restaurants and school districts, grocery stores, weren't supporting those local farms.
The more you keep your money local, the more you're growing, the economy in the You're growing the future health of your own community.
And that's its great to see often.
Not only talk that talk.
That really walk.
That walk.
Awesome.
Well, I hope that you have all had a great experience.
I know some of you may come from the breakout rooms, and he may be cooking still in front of making into your room.
I am sorry.
I am here.
Now for any quick questions.
You may have or anything that goes into the chat.
I would be happy to answer.
And if we rather just enjoy your food, put your, put your kids to bed.
Totally great.
But I hope you were able to pay attention that last video.
One thing that makes what we do, I think so special is that we are fully committed to using.
You know, obviously I said over and over again Nico packet and go friendly packaging and you have some literature in your box about what that Eco packet, eco-friendly Packaging.
Entails, but we also Source locally everything we Source other than the things that we get from Mexico, which one we get two things from actually make sure that we're all so.
Thoughtfully sourcing getting organic making sure that our dollars are going back into communities.
That better those communities and it's very, very important to us.
But also when we do Source locally, which is probably the other 70% of what we have, it's always, you know, thoughtfully grown in a thirty to sixty mile, radius of the front door of assembly from the beef to if you have any of our kids that have seafood, we get everything from the Gulf from day boat, Fisher's, as well as all the produce is grown locally.
Obviously, if you have a kid that has pineapple in it, we do that.
Sometimes we don't get the pineapples locally, but for the most part like again, it's always thoughtful practicing?
Or make sure way we are getting those products is somewhere that we know.
We're not only in the best product of Using the best practices.
Awesome.
Yes.
Thank you, Amy.
I agree.
Doc.
This platform is awesome.
We love being on.
Welcome.
It's fun.
There's a lot of features, a lot of amenities to it, and it's super definitely, super fun.
Thank you, Angela.
Appreciate that.
Everyone.
Thank you so much for joining us today.
Hope you had a wonderful time and you ate some delicious food.
Thank you so much, Chef for a wonderful evening.
We wanted to say thank you, or going to open up the lounges in the case that you want to continue the conversation and keep talking or just have finished your cocktails together.
Those will be opening momentarily.
But, thank you so much.
And we will see you soon.
And yeah, that's it.
See ya.
Bye.