Hello, everyone.
Welcome to welcome.
I am Gina the head of marketing of welcome, and we are so glad that you are here joining us today for a very special acoustic session with American Idols.
Top 10.
Finalists Joven web.
So, I am looking in chat right now.
Wow, it's so great to see all of you.
We got Jennifer from Frederick.
Hello, Florida, California, Berkeley, San Diego, Portland.
In New Jersey, Puerto Rico Chicago, this is awesome.
We're all going to be experiencing this together.
No matter where you are Coast to Coast.
We're hanging out, and we're excited that you're here with us.
So before we jump into a special interview with jobin and his session note that you are on welcome.
This is our virtual hybrid experience platform, and we are powering both buyer journey and A journey events.
And so, we hope that today, you will be able to walk away to experience what we get to experience and enjoy every day here on welcome.
So with that note that you have got the help chat to the right.
If you got any technical issues, feel free to drop them there.
And if you have got some specific questions that you want to ask Joven, then drop them in Q&A, and we can upvote those as well.
We have also got some amazing giveaways from our partner.
Lupin tie will have MK up in a little bit at the end, but they're giving away a hundred dollar, a 75 dollar and a fifty dollar giveaway.
So if we're going to raffle those off, at the end of the event, go ahead and click on the tab above where it says, giveaway and feel free to fill in your information.
And we're going to do a random select at the end of the event.
All right.
So with that lets actually bring up.
Oh, here, the pull.
Thank you, Jessica.
Jessica is my amazing.
Producer in The Green Room.
Let me give it up for you because she's making it happen on the ones and twos every event.
So everyone put place your votes.
What is your favorite style of music?
And I know we have just got a select few here, but Blues Jazz country rock.
We got a lot of folks that are vibing with the rock.
Okay?
Shift it up.
Equalizing here with jazz and Country.
All right, with that, I want to bring up.
Joven web because his sound is a combination of all of those nouns.
So Joven, join me right now.
Come on up.
Hello.
How's it going?
It's so good to see you.
Sam.
To be a very happy to be here.
Yeah, and I suppose.
See that?
Taylor say something about?
They look awesome.
Well before we jump To the awesome tunes that you're going to be sharing with us today.
You know, some of us are just curious about your story.
Now, both of you are singer-songwriters from Louisiana, right?
Yes.
Tell us a little bit about your roots, you know, like Joven.
How did you get into music?
And we would love to hear the story of how you crushed American Idol auditions through the pandemic.
I mean, come on out.
That is it.
Incredible.
So, give us a little glimpse of your path.
How did, how did you get into music and how has Louisiana influenced you and Taylor feel free to jump into because I know you're from Louise, Louisiana as well.
Um, basically my biggest influence would be Church.
My parents kept me in church when I was very young.
So just that's sold and culture of that from just Louisiana and general Inspire my soul to do the music I do today.
Awesome.
How about you Taylor?
Yeah, for me, just being surrounded by the blend of country music and Soul music and gospel music, and southern rock music and all that things.
Just kind of came together into an amalgam of what I am doing now, rich.
So rich, we're excited to hear that.
So job and tell us a little bit about that.
Experience, auditioning for American Idol, through the pandemic, how, how that happened and have you been always trying to go after American Idol, like, we're their excellent amount of auditions that you had submitted before even getting to this.
Or was this your first time?
No, actually, I sent in an audition.
The year before is actually the year that lane Hardy won, and I was a little bit nervous to going from the judges or what the executives of that they had set forth.
So I sent in the video, and they actually liked it.
But at the time I wasn't really checking my email, so I missed that opportunity, but God had a plan to set me up for the next year.
So, I went in and just sing my butt off sweating, like I am doing now.
We're thicker email folks.
Basically check emails.
Well, yeah, that would that was not fun to miss that email.
I am sure I was crushed.
So then in 2020, how did you do the auditions?
Where you capture iPhone footage, selfie footage of yourself and submitting those like, what was that process?
Like, they sent those home from La.
Once they got the notice about the pandemic stuff, and they say, There's on the next day soon as we got there.
They start sending us equipment and start sending phone.
So we filmed the whole thing from three iPhone pros and that's how the show's made.
So I had to have family friends there just to help me do that.
Awesome about how many auditions did you do before you got in front of three, judges?
Oh God, I was like, at least for like six, at least.
Wow, so I did look, do a little traveling to went out to California.
First time.
I almost got left there.
That was interesting story.
What happened?
Basically my audition lasted longer than we were supposed to and I end up missing my flight and I had like a hundred bucks left to get home.
Yeah, that's another story.
Wow.
Okay, and what kind of tracks do you think?
You know, what was it about your sound that kept on advancing you through the auditions?
I don't know.
Thank you.
I guess everybody just kind of seen an and in heard of the pain in my voice and now he was authentic and it came from someone real, so they can relate to it.
So I am pretty sure everybody's been through a breakup.
So that's what the song was about.
Wow.
Yeah, I mean as a songwriter you have to pull from those deep experiences and emotions.
So with your sound that's what you have been able to.
Pull and really bring it out.
Well, that's awesome.
Are there any other questions from anyone in the audience?
Yeah, bring up some questions.
If you have any for jobin and throughout this event, if any of you, oh, who's the meanest judge?
None of them?
None of them.
They were, is that like you were dealing with Simon?
I mean, you did it with Katy Perry.
And she's like, bubbly, did see you got Uncle on an oh, that's kind of what it feels like to me.
Uncle Lionel.
Right?
Right.
You look at Luke.
He's like, just a southern boy like us and feels like so, it was very a home feeling.
It wasn't like, I was meeting famous people even though they were megastars.
Yeah.
I mean, Katie had some pretty nice things to say about you.
And I mean, Lionel did to that one audition that you did in front of them.
What was that?
It?
What does that feel like just Going on to the American Idol stage, you have that, you know epic American Idol signage behind you?
How does that feel that whole experience?
It was a pretty nerve-wracking for what made the trip for me.
So crazy, just a whole journey.
I did the whole thing by myself.
So, when I traveled, I was by myself.
When I had to, you know, I was nervous.
I was by myself.
So, I was confiding myself.
Everybody else had somebody else.
So I was literally in a nutshell, freaking out, to be honest.
And something that didn't quite make.
The show was a I was outside a little nervous and I smoked the cigarette or something like that and I came in and I sing and I hug Kate, and she's like you a smoker.
I was like and Luke was that guy?
I think we need a smoker.
So that was like my biggest memories is like them asking me that it was like I was gonna need that grit that roughness.
So I don't know.
You just lied emotion that came out there one time and kind of blacked out for a minute.
Wow, that was a powerful audition.
Think a lot of us have seen that on YouTube.
All right, some questions here sod has asking what's your favorite City to play in?
Oh cool.
Is New Orleans.
Alright flavor it?
Yes, the face is asking.
Who would you like to do?
A duet with and why?
I think we both can agree.
It will be Chris Stapleton.
Because Chris Stapleton is kind of like that guy.
That's helping bridge, the gap between country and blues, and soul rock and roll thing.
So when I, when I see him and somebody doing what he's doing, is almost a reflection of myself.
That's beautiful.
How about you Taylor?
Honestly, if I can do a duet with anybody, I wanted to do it with it.
Would either be Susan Tedeschi or Brandi.
Carlile.
Nice choices.
Wendy is asking.
What was the biggest life learning from this experience with American Idol?
It's a good question.
Um, The basically where I took most from it was to start believing myself.
You guys don't know who I am.
I am a very known to be kind of timid and laid-back and shy and introverted.
But when I am on that stage, I am different and it's kind of thing.
I need to balance.
It's like I need to just learn to believe in myself in.
And that's where that show has.
Taught me is like up all hours of the night learning stuff and just pushing yourself to the limit.
So, Basically, I learned to keep going jover Duty.
So then I think all of us could take a little note, a tip from that as well as to believe in ourselves, you know, especially in such a time as this where there's uncertainty there's volatility and you know around the globe and you want.
One thing we can do is believe in ourselves and you know, be thankful for each day that we have and get after it.
So, I love that.
Christian is asking, what do you feel keeps upcoming musicians and songwriters for making it interesting question, what prevents them from making it?
Just I guess not being able to relate.
I mean if you don't have anybody that.
So the thing I learned singing gospel music and being in church is that you can have a really good singer sing a song.
But if they don't feel it, if people don't receive it that way, then it's not going to go over well basically, so if you're not writing something that's going to touch somebody, so make them cry or whatever that emotion that your time, projected ain't going to work.
It's good.
It's got to be authentic.
Yes.
That's why I think when you said pulling from a deep place and a an authentic experience like that, that shines through when you do that, when you tap into that.
All right, our last question here from semenko, how has your family loved ones and Friends, reacted to your newfound success.
Oh God, they love it.
But I am sure they over at this point.
I am sure the old a whole thing is like we can't.
I mean it's his home.
So I am very happy that people notice who I am but it can't get a little nerve-racking especially when they just try to enjoy our family time and somebody comes up and say something like this is what I signed up for.
So I think they love it.
They just like I broke.
Hmm.
And you have a little son.
Yes.
Name, how old is he?
Jayven will be Jamie.
Did Shane will be six years old.
He was born on my birthday.
Sal's my present.
Wow.
What a special kid.
Does he have?
The same pipes?
Are you?
We don't know yet.
We're going to find out because you know, what are you doing in Rome?
I am not going to work with them.
We'd love to have the daddy son duet on one of our events.
One of these days.
All right.
Well, Everyone's waiting for this moment.
So Joven if you and Taylor could take it away.
It sounds like you guys have a few tunes that Taylor's going to be doing.
And then a few tunes that job and you're going to do.
So, we're super excited for this, take us away.
You made a killer point about, you know if you're not feeling it, it's not going to be real kind of whole thing about people resonate with something.
If it's, if it's something you lived in, you know, and you're singing from a Place.
And so this first song is called lion.
And it's about when you're being cheated on and, you know, it, but you can't prove it.
I have been there.
I got a feeling that something's wrong.
Once you're kissing me reeling.
But lately the magic song, I think there's a problem.
I can't seem to find that look in your eyes baby that I used to see all the it's cause you didn't.
I am here, she been lying.
Even lying next to my new Bridges to do.
Everything is alright, but I know something's wrong with you.
Even lying next to somebody new and you're lying.
It don't take a genius, just see things to change between us and never will Hangzhou girl.
Something's missing love is not easy.
Hey, you gotta know where some levels, but somehow I feel like I am.
Yes, you have been lying even lying next to somebody.
And you're lying.
Somebody new and you lie to me.
So yeah, that's definitely a song.
I have lived through singing from that place.
Where you know something dirty is going on and you just can't prove it, but, you know, it in your gut, it's not a good place to be.
And this next one?
Is another one that I didn't live per se but I watched it.
I watched it being lived and it hurt deep to see it.
It's a song about my brother.
I got a little brother who's been in and out of addiction for a long time, heroin and different things and it resulted in him being homeless and I never know where he is most of the time.
And I wrote this song, kind of trying to put myself in his shoes.
And so what y'all think it's called water under the bridge?
I am through the smoke and I have drank my last bottle.
I have spent 15 years old on this road because sometimes you choices and burn down your own, but that's what I have made my bed now, I will sleep in it when it rains it, pours.
It is what it is under and be it's a hard place to be.
Begging for change selling newspapers and who I am?
Sometimes the weather can't mess up.
You plant.
That's what made my baby sleep in.
Is world.
It is the rain pouring down.
I try to drown out the sound under ayat.
I can't.
That's what water under the bridge time.
Made my bed.
Now, I will sleep in the when it rains.
It.
Pours.
It is what it is.
Under the wreath.
Now we're going to do one together.
Now.
It's another one.
I wrote in the kind of like my message to the world.
If I had just one thing to say to the world before I died.
This would be it and I think it's the vices and I love the way he does the other half of it.
And he just learned this like yesterday, like today last night, and he's, he did it.
He did a great job.
He nailed it.
So this one's called, just like you.
They all come into this world the same way.
We have all got Mama's to think when we were kids.
We'd play with anyone now, rage.
Didn't matter what Rings somewhere along the way.
We left things, people tell me more than people themselves.
If we don't turn off the news and find better things to do, life might be more like heaven.
If you say, we're all gonna die.
I have learned from the time cuz he — in the dark never way you do.
If you love me.
Yeah.
Jeremy.
I mentioned my love for Chris Stapleton, so this next song is about him.
Kick it off.
Say my share of broken a Lowe's told you we that used they were gone wherever they go f****** hate it.
And just come down from the heavens.
Just to help her come to teachers and it helps a mother.
See myself walking a lows.
So, did we?
If I go wherever they go looking Halos, that you don't go looking.
And for the reasons, why don't you lay eggs in diesel and I miss, you know, the answer they belong.
The Whitney.
Rockin a knows that he's working.
Late knows that he used to A little homage to the late great, Stevie Ray Vaughan, but I feel it.
If I could just talk about the soul and a route to this song is definitely a southern born and raised.
So let us keep some of that from the barbecue sauce.
I love and giving sight to the blind.
My baby love and causes Sunshine.
She's my pride and joy, she must be little baby.
I am her little lover boy.
Let us meet the man.
She's my pride and joy.
Dig Me Up.
My sweet little thing.
Yeah.
Yes.
He is.
My pottinger is my pride and joy.
Little baby.
I am her little lover boy.
So we got one more tune.
Of course, you know, they're doing all covers.
This is Into the Mystic.
I guess what, I get from this song is just talking about it.
We won't buy one for the win.
Awesome.
So, younger than this house?
With everybody bows, one sitting into the mystery of my here.
The city's smell the season at Isola spherify, still into the mystery.
And that far gone, blows coming home?
That's all I have to feeling now.
I could even win in the days of old.
There are souls.
Beautiful sailing Into the Mystic.
Coming home.
Then if you feel really nice.
Jabra.
There's always more song with you always moves to split it.
Yeah, I will do the first verse you.
The second one sounds of that ain't no sunshine.
When she's gone.
It's not warm when she's away.
And no sunshine when she's gone.
She's always gone too long anytime.
She goes away.
Wonder if she's gone.
Let us go too long.
Darkness everyday ain't no sunshine.
When she's gone, and she's always gone too long.
One in this time when she's gone.
Wondering if she's gone to stay, ain't no sunshine when she's gone.
And this house just ain't no home.
Anytime.
She goes away.
I know, I know.
No, I know downstairs are when she's gone?
It's not warm when she's away.
Ain't no sunshine when she's gone.
And this house just ain't no home.
Anytime she goes away.
Anytime.
She goes away.
You guys goodness bring it on this improv heat?
Hello.
Wow, I mean you got some fans.
So hopefully you can drop your Instagram handles or something so that we can all be tracking with you both of Joven and Taylor.
You guys need to keep doing Duets together.
Keep it up.
Thank you so much.
Thank what?
What a delight, and a breath of fresh air for all of us.
All right.
Look at that.
There is love in the chat.
It's not stopped with stupid.
Thank you so much.
All right.
Well with that, it doesn't stop here.
We have got some amazing.
A ways from Loop and tie.
So I would love to invite to the stage CM o MK jump on.
Hello.
I gotta say, I think all of us are Grand Prize winners because that was a phenomenal experience, Taylor Joven.
You are incredibly talented.
Thank you for sharing your gifts with us today.
Thank you very much.
Thank you guys so much.
Thank you.
All right, with that MK.
Here we go.
Jess.
We got some Grand Prize winner Grand Prize winners.
I am we want to do massive Shadows to Angie foxy.
Was our first place winner who gets a hundred dollar gift from Loop and tie Danielle King.
You're right there in second place as our second place winner with a seventy-five dollar gift from Loop and tie and last but certainly not least.
Alexis Todd, congrats.
You are a third place winner with a fifty dollar gift card.
Again.
I think all of us can walk away as winners because this experience was truly something remarkable.
So thanks for keeping Loop and tie in Mix, your welcome.
And thank you again to Joanne and Taylor.
Awesome.
Thanks MK.
So, you will follow up.
She will follow up with you the three winners and with that Joven Taylor.
We thank you so much.
You know, we're on this platform right now?
Welcome this, you know, welcome Powers Keystone employee experiences that build connection culture and belonging.
This includes like Town whole howls, onboarding zei, T, groups, kickoffs, and events acoustic sessions just like this.
So, imagine doing this for your own team or your own company.
Let us know.
There is a tab at the top says book a demo talk to any of our employee experienced Specialists today, and we will help you out in figuring out how to create these jaw-dropping experiences for your employees.
All right.
We will check out our events page.
Thank you all so much.
Follow job and web on Insta.
Taylor will Drop your Handles in an email that will send out to all the registrants.
So there's going to be a recording in there.
And follow up with us and connect with us on LinkedIn.
Thank you so much.
We send our love from all of our cities to you and thank you, Joven, Taylor for sharing your love and your tunes your stories with us today.
Thank you.
Have a great rest of the week.
Y'all.
Take care.