Hello everyone.
I don't know what part of the world you're at, but I am in Hawaii and so tuning in.
It's 7 AM over here but it's so good to be your police drop in chat if and let us know where you're tuning in from Gina head of marketing with welcome, and we're so excited that you are here, and we're able to chat about a really interesting topic that I think is very relevant for this time.
Volunteering and really having purpose.
LED Purpose Driven alignment with your company and with your team's, all right?
People are beginning to drop that their locations.
We got Kelly from l.a.
India.
Toronto, India.
Wow.
Okay.
Puerto Rico.
Very nice New York.
Hey Lena.
Okay, good.
Good.
Well before we jump into the panel discussion, we have also got a really cool.
Cool lgbtq+ affirmation.
While activity that we're going to do as a group together, which is going to be awesome.
Hey, Kristen, a Brady Colorado, what's up?
Whoo.
So let us jump right into this poll.
And we want to know how many of you have ever participated in a virtual volunteering before just drop your votes.
Let us see.
For me, this is going to be my first time, actually.
So I have not yet.
Anticipated.
How about you all?
Okay, well, I am not seeing the numbers come in.
Oh, there we go.
I see him now.
Alright.
Alright, so a good chunk of y'all.
We have got about half-and-half but majority have not yet.
Done a group virtual volunteering activity.
Okay.
Now, that's starting to increase a little bit more great.
Well, we have got some experts today to talk about engaging employees in a really meaningful way.
With this transformative time of how we work.
So, I would love to invite to the stage.
If Abhishek CEO of gaudreau, please join me on stage along with our CEO, Roberto.
Hello.
Hey, Deena idea.
Good to be here.
So even right here where represented all over the world where are you Abhishek and Roberto?
I will kick off, I mostly on the Eastern time zone right now, I am in Puerto Rico but you know in a couple weeks I am going to be in Philadelphia.
And so this is a beauty about remote, work could be wherever in the world Yeah, I am in Bangalore in India, but I am working on PT time zone.
So welcome everyone and great to meet with you.
Awesome.
That's cool.
It's truly distributed represented here and even in our audience, which is amazing.
And that's why engagement is.
So, top of mind, takes a lot of intentionality, and I am excited to be able to dive into that a little bit more with each of you.
Can you tell me a little bit more about your company's?
And how you all are solving for the Transformer, formative work place today with distributed teams.
If you said you weren't, you want to take that one first and then I will jump in.
Oh, so you know very quickly about good ERA in very simple, terms could areas like an know what?
We call an Airbnb of volunteering, where we work with nonprofits, thousands of nonprofits across, more than 100 countries globally.
Understand their volunteering in requirements on board them on good errors platform and offer it to employees of our customers.
So that Employee across any part of the world can volunteer in a very, very simple Manner.
And the reason why we started that was, you know, it's just so strange that in this world volunteering is just so difficult.
You know, it's so easy to get a pizza delivered home or get a cab but it's just so difficult to volunteer and that's what we wanted to Saul.
And, you know, currently work with the hundreds of companies with 16 Fortune, 500 with 7 million employees volunteering with us across.
Asset globe and, you know, great too great to be here.
And you know, as soon as I heard about the topic and I know this was been in the works for a little while.
I was just intrigued because I think that volunteering and I know I am talk about welcome here in a second, but I think volunteering is so important in connecting people together where I like when you can work side by side with someone for a good cause Beyond like your day-to-day job, it does something pretty special and income and uniting employees for a bigger.
Cause I have been Pretty Hands-On with volunteering.
Like, in the real world virtually though, I haven't really experienced much of it.
And, so I am looking forward to learning what this is all about, as well.
So guys, my name is Roberto Ortiz.
I am co-founder and CEO of welcome.
Welcome is the platform that we're hosting.
This experience on.
What we do is we help companies that have distributed teams bringing them together in more intentional ways.
And so employee experiences actually draw Drive a lot of connection belonging amounts of months of work force and our technology makes it.
So it's much easier and engaging for everybody that's participating.
And so we're serving customers from the startup that has a remote team to accompany a five, ten thousand people that have employees around the world.
And so that's what we did.
And I am glad to be here.
Thanks for being here.
Awesome.
Thank you.
Both for those intros.
You know, I would love to kick it off, actually, with this survey.
That Abhishek your team had conducted with your own customers.
And so if we could pull that on stage, it actually gives some really good insights into why orgs are opting into virtual volunteering.
So as we're seeing here, 33% care about Community impact, aligned in our cause areas, 33% care about Employee Engagement, 25% employee well-being, and mental health, and 9% care about the employee Learning and Development.
Mint Abhishek, could you elaborate on this a little bit more for us?
Yeah, absolutely.
And you know us, as we all know, the pandemic has, you know, had a huge impact on everyone of us across the world and the need to do good or you know, help or contribute to the world is higher than ever before.
So everyone feels that urge and need to do good, but because of constraints in a bit What's the pandemic?
It's extremely difficult to go out there and help and contribute but you know, how do you then convert this intention and the need to do good and it's just not, you know, from a healthcare and education perspective.
But you know, things like Racial equality and climate change and now her whole bunch of issues, especially the younger folks are extremely motivated to do something, and there needs to be a channelization of these energies and this need and Motivation in a positive manner and that's where virtual volunteering comes in is how can companies effectively channelize, the need, an urge to contribute in a much more engaging and effective manner than that's even the alignment with social causes and, you know, it's just not a greenwashing kind of thing, but it's actually very, very meaningful.
It's not top down, but a very inclusive, very Democratic way in, which employees can come together to do good, another same time, it's probably the most meaningful Employee Engagement.
You know, in today's world where we talk about, you know, the great resignation or the great reshuffle and every companies trying to do something around engagement which is very you know check the box kind of thing with just seems.
Okay, why am I doing it versus doing something?
Which is actually meaningful something, which is helping someone in need something, where you use your time and skills, effectively is just so much more satisfying for you individually, and that's where the meaningful employing.
A judgment comes in and the last piece is around this mental health and well-being.
And you know, we all know that when you volunteer there is something called as oxy toxin that's a hormone which gets released which, you know, makes you feel happier.
And, you know, everyone wants a lot more happiness today and this is just a beautiful way of doing it.
Where you know, it's your helping someone and feeling happy and as you do something for someone you also learn by using your skills.
You know you might be an intern somewhere but you are helping.
Nonprofit are really, really big way and that's the Learning and Development.
So these are just some of the different ways in which, you know, volunteering is.
So, so very powerful, and we have customers seeing the direct benefit of it as their employees volunteer across the world.
Mmm, that's really.
It's actually, I think, I think I just go back to, you know, when you were just, again, my experience in volunteering typically when you're volunteering, you think that?
Hey, I am gonna go help a group of people or, you know, I am going to partner with my friends, are going to go volunteer all day or take a trip and help clean this up or go.
He will be Hands-On and the school and go ready to And you do that with all the right intentions and typically people go to do it because they want to help people in many ways.
Just like you're saying you walk away from that being helped so much more profoundly yourself and your team walks away with the better scent of accomplishment, not just because they help somebody.
But this something within them I remember going to one trip I thought that hey we could just we have to go help me schools we have to help put the plumbing inside these Schools that don't have Plumbing.
We have to go figure this out and I went for like two weeks, and we're working in the Sun and doing all of this work.
But it was the most rewarding thing for me like fine back home.
It wasn't that I was hoping people but it was the appreciation for the people that are on the ground that people that do this every single day, the people that are inside of these, you know, like these volunteering.
Hubs that are dedicated the entire lives to go make a difference, right?
And then you get to an Of that purpose that they do every single day.
And that just, you just walk away just more much more impacted, than anything else and so, I just, I don't know.
I am just a big fan of doing things like this.
I think, remote, we may be good to kind of talk about, like, what are the opportunities in doing this remotely?
And what are the challenges in doing a remotely?
Like, I am curious to say like what are like, at a high level?
I think that, you know, some volunteering things, you can't do, because you can't go pick up.
Paint brush and go pink or school.
Right.
There is probably a ton that you could do that.
Even like if you think about like us as many ways like knowledge workers, there's a lot of things that we could do that.
Maybe what you and your company do is unlock that and really start to catalyze.
Those kind of things, I would be curious to learn like from your perspective, what are you seeing being some of the common things that companies are doing remotely?
Virtually that you really can't do, right?
If it's in the physical world.
So absolutely.
And I think the first thing is I we have seen teams being distributed across time zones locations languages and how do you bring a team together and do something, which is Meaningful?
One of our most popular volunteering activities, is recording, audio books for blind, kids, you know, we're a team comes together on a virtual call.
There is a good are a host, you know, someone like Carla would be hosting you today where they do some fun icebreakers to an orientation about the nonprofit.
And then there are individual audio books, which are given to employees that they can record, and these audio books, once recorded and Q Cedar given to a local nonprofit, which works a blind kids, and these nonprofits is spread across the world with good error.
So if you're a team in the US and the East Coast, a non-profit in New York or in California or in Dubai, or Singapore or Bangalore, They are local nonprofits who benefit from it.
It's a very simple activity.
Takes just, you know, one hour to do it.
It's very fulfilling.
It's also something where you don't require a lot of preparation.
It's really, really fun, very engaging and you feel really, really happy after it.
So it's something you know really wonderful and there are volunteering activities across different cause areas of its stem education, climate change, you know, Pride accessibility dni, and we work with a lot of these what we call employee resource groups, or ERG is our communities within companies to help them further their cause that they care about.
So, so that's just one example of activities in other ones are reviewing resumes for you.
In a lot of you don't have access to high-quality resumes, you could review those resumes, make it high quality, and they might get a job, which is just, you know, they would never get access to Talent like this.
So we work with an apple or an Amazon or an Airbnb.
And, you know, I would have loved to have someone at Apple review my résumé.
You know, when I was a kid and that's something, you know, only possible through volunteering.
So, it's really amazing, the kind of value that you could add remotely in just an hour together as a team and also have fun together.
I mean, just by you even talk about this, it makes me feel good.
How many?
I mean can we do some hands in chat and you feel you feeling good?
Now, do you realize you're volunteering yet and the thought in the thinking about tearing makes you just feel?
I feel so much better.
I, first of all we have to figure out how to do one of these things internally here at welcome.
So in the Green Room which apart talk about like getting hooked up at figuring this out but at a high level I just, I don't know, I just, I just feel pretty bought into this whole opportunity of volunteering remotely.
So and we do now set up because I will get us off.
Try, these are good questions.
Yeah, I know.
Thank you.
Thank you both for leaning into it.
So, I kind of dig more into the challenges because engaging employees is hard remote.
Everything feels a little bit extra.
You know, we don't have those water cooler moments where we just run into the office, and we can have, you know, a quick little chat, connect even solve problems in those asynchronous informal manners, right?
We don't have that and I think about volunteering Robbie were touching this bit being there in person.
And, like, Really solving for whether it's like building the house for somebody or feeding somebody like you don't really have that virtually.
So I do see how the things that you're calling out.
Can help bring that oxytocin but I have since you know there's a little further intentionality that's needed.
How do you guys solve for that in this evolving?
Virtual District distributed world that we're in right now?
You know, you constantly have to innovate Constant.
Had to be creative.
How you guys solving for both of you solving for this, for your customers, and for your own employees?
So I will jump in and give it back just a broader one and then I mean Abhishek and you can bring it home with like you know the work that you're doing I think high level.
So for us and I will just speak about because a lot of people here that are working remotely or hybrid type of setup or are trying to figure out and pull engagement at their companies as well as.
So for us at welcome we're we were born a remote, we're staying remote, that's what we do, and then we huddle people upright regionally or yearly For in-person activities, just from a cultural perspective.
I think something to just acknowledge is that throughout the last two years we were all forced to go remote and being forced to go remote, meaning means that you necessarily then, I mean you didn't opt into it, you're just figuring it out as you go, and we're all honest, we have been trying to figure it out as we go.
But I think the companies that buy into being remote first or 100% remote or Embracing remote and distributed teams.
I think it starts at the onboarding of bringing employee in and saying like your part of remote culture, that means that the way we operate the way we function is X y&z the way that we connect is a b and c versus this sort of hodgepodge that we have been in.
We have been forced to figure it out and have a lot of questions and I think, honestly, like organizations.
Haven't really figured it out because they have been sort of stuck in the Person only being forced to go remote hoping that we can come back to in person.
And what we're finding is that there's tension and pool where employees don't want that and people want flexibility, but the processes and practices have not been matured in a lot of organizations especially organizations that didn't start with remote first.
And, so I think organizations that have already been functioning remote.
We have figured out how to have an amazing culture and how to drive connection among their employees.
So it's not that it's not possible, but it's actually something you have to be very intentional about Can and just to add to that, you know what you have seen amongst, the team is, sometimes the remote is tends to become very transactional that okay, this is a meeting, this is a call, this is the agenda, and we don't know each other as humans or you know, who are we as people?
And you need a platform where you could be in a vulnerable where you could be sensitive, very could share stories Beyond work and that's where you know, to an extent volunteering comes in where You know when you see nonprofits when you see, you know folks on the ground having so much more problems and yourself, you tend to become a lot more emotional.
You tend to become a lot more sensitive, you become more resilient and you start sharing a lot more and you feel safe sharing in the in that you know group or in that time and that builds connection and that bills, you know, empathy and that bills, you know like a family feeling where you feel safe to share things with each other and that Pins.
Only because that's atmosphere gets created during a voluntary experience.
Very learn about the nonprofit about the cause about things which people go through about in all the good and bad things happening.
I was in the world.
And when you as a group and as a team come together and go through that, emotional experience, share stories in a work together, create something, which is Meaningful.
You feel a lot more connected and that builds human connection.
And we were on a volunteering call.
Where there was a CEO there was An intern and there was a fire old kid and the kid didn't know that this who is the CEO and who's the intern and, you know, just talking as normal people and that created such a great bond between the CEO and the intern, which was never possible earlier.
So I think it brings every human to the human angle rather than designations and titles and roles.
And that makes it a really beautiful experience and that creates something which, you know, we sometimes gray for in the virtual world and That's what we try and do is also build connections, you know, create empathy, and emotions in a very structured environment through the volunteer experience across the year.
And it's just not about doing it once a year during givingtuesday Thanksgiving.
But doing it frequently, you want to build connection and everyone is passionate about different things.
You know, someone likes to work for pet, animals for climate change to stem education for women and girls and across the year.
There are moments where you could do it and it creates, you know, communities.
Within the company that become really strong and connected and that's what you have seen happen at good area as well.
That's awesome.
I totally agree on that human to human connection and being able to be intentional to enable those very human real authentic, moments virtually with your remote teams.
I think that is the challenge of what we're figuring out.
But these are some great ideas and insights.
We have got about a few minutes left before we jump into our volunteering activity.
So I didn't want to open up.
If there're any questions that you all have for our panelists, feel free to drop them.
The Q&A tab.
In the meantime, I have got here.
One last question, about mental health and well-being, this is top of Mind top priority.
You know, Roberto.
You recently just signed a pledge with Thrive about mental health, and wellness, and the accountability that you along with 80 other companies and gadara, hope you all sign that pledge as well.
You know, a lot of folks are beginning to see the value of this, for their organizations?
How are you all thinking about mental health and wellbeing for your employees?
And are you seeing any great best practices across your customers?
You know, would love any inputs here.
Yeah thanks for teeing that up Tina.
Yeah we signed a pledge and a partnership with Thrive and a bunch of other organizations as well and I think just kind of like put a like just whole space for that I think it's we're all in this like continue a journey of how to want support our employees support our customers and also as Leaders figure it out ourselves right?
I think well-being and preventing burnout starts at the top.
And so, we're burnt out as leaders, and we're not showing it and exhibiting it, and taking days off and, and practicing the things that we need to practice being.
Well, there's going to be hard for us to try to support our employees and doing the same.
And so for me, I say that, like, for me to hear myself speak that because I need to do that more often myself, in terms of the Pledge, you know, we're just committed to just, you know, mental health is a core, a core requirement for all of us to show up.
Up while and do our jobs.
Well, if our employees are well then they're going to do their best work.
Now, the challenge that typically has also is like when you're in a start-up and you're running at 100 miles an hour, being able to know when to pull over and take the rest stops, it's super important.
And I think that the hard thing for companies that are growing companies that are moving, fast is the balance of hey we're running a hundred miles an hour.
So how do we do?
When we understand that this is a marathon, but it's a marathon of seven minute miles, meaning that we're running constantly.
How do we look at well-being and mental health, in that demanding type of environment?
And that means that we have to be really intentional.
It doesn't happen by mistake, right?
So for us even signing the pledge, is us saying that really continue to invest in this stuff and yes, we have, you know, we basically have some things internally that support the balance of Mental Health.
Health and just being well, one example of that is every Friday of the first Friday of every month, we take off as an entire company, and we dedicated to just well-being, we call it Wellness, Wellness weekends.
And so that means that every employee has a three-day weekend, every single month.
That means that almost two weeks, out the ear because you Des 12 business days, out the year, almost 2 weeks out of the Year.
We're shutting down.
And we're seeing go do what recharges your As an employee at that, meaning spending time with your family.
And that means taking your kids to the park.
If that means to sleep in it, for the whole day, you go do that.
And so that's one small thing that we have decided to do at the top of the year.
And it's been phenomenal, but we can do so much more, right?
And so the pledge is really a pledge of continuous Improvement for us.
Yeah, and just to mention from a site in the interest of time.
I think one thing which we do very intentionally is that in a good area for us as a family and you know you find a safe space inside your family to share a lot of things from a mental health perspective is that you know, you don't or you can't share and if you can't share, things don't get resolved and that leads to more issues and concerns.
So, think the spirit of family Is that you can share and that comes from, you know, starting off in India, where it's a very strong connection that you build with the family and get a very strong sense of a safe space to share anything about anyone and problem solve together without being judgmental.
So, I know we are out of time but just wanted to share as to how do you think about a company as a family and, you know, create that environment that everyone is there for everyone for, you know, during all ups and downs.
So good.
Wow.
Thank you, Abhishek.
Thank you, Roberto for sharing your insights experiences.
Best practices we're grateful for this time.
All right, so we're now going to flip the switch here and move into a virtual group volunteering activity for the lgbtq+ community.
And I would love to bring Carla to the stage.
Each will you join me?
Awesome.
Okay.
Hey, thank you so much, Gina.
What a great conversation and what a great segue into our gadara volunteering virtual volunteering event.
I should say.
And again, happy pride month, everybody, my name is Carla.
Curtsinger, I am a gadara Ambassador, and I am joined by my colleague Deb who be helping me out in the chat window.
We're so excited that you're here today for our virtual volunteering event activity.
We're going to work together to write and decorate messages of love for the lgbtq+ Elders of color.
This is a really unique opportunity.
You think about the world as it is today, think about being a person and a person, a lgbtq+ person Generations ago right?
A much different world back then.
Those people are now our elders.
And so you get the opportunity to create virtual Nation walls to tell them that we support them.
We know that the journey they have been through and now they're their elders.
And obviously their communities may feel like they're shrinking as well.
So you get the opportunity to say that we're there with them, and we want to show our love and support.
So what a unique opportunity, thank you so much for sharing your time today and working on this activity with us.
So why you'd expect with this is a short activity today, we're going to start out obviously we're doing the introductions now.
We're going to do Quick Icebreaker.
I am going to test your knowledge during pride month.
Then I will tell you a little bit about the nonprofit that you're serving today.
Give you some quick, a quick instruction on the activity itself and then you will have some opportunity as you can see here.
It says make some notes, it really is creating a wall of affirmation for these lgbtq+ Elders that our nonprofit serves, and then we will take just a couple of minutes to get together and say what was that like What was your feeling?
What did you learn about yourself and about pride month working on this activity?
So there's a lot to do a lot to learn and hopefully a lot of fun to be had.
So let us start with those icebreakers as we celebrate love during pride month and this is, you can say is a bit of a trivia contest, and so I am going to start out.
We're going to guess the rock star because we have musicians Among Us, who have really played a part in promoting queer culture.
We're going to focus on one, and we're going to give you a pole here.
Are you to guess now?
This is one of the greatest singers in the history of rock music.
He was known for his flamboyant stage Persona and four octave vocal range.
Oh my goodness.
I think this may have been a little too easy for you.
I see that everybody has guessed correctly and again, you are right.
This is indeed Freddie Mercury.
Shown here when he appeared at Wembley Stadium, I believe that was a Live Aid concert.
Look at him there and so sad that tragically.
We lost him a little too early but good for you for knowing your pride trivia.
Now we're going to kind of switch gears here.
This may be a little more challenging we're going to guess.
There's many different Pride flags and each one kind of represents a different identity in our lgbtq+ community.
So you have to match the flag to the community.
So maybe this will be a little bit harder.
It will see you seem like a smart Bunch.
Okay.
Here's our first.
Like this is the more commonly known for a pride flag, so which identity goes with this pride flag.
I don't know, I don't know if this is really that hard.
I am going to give you a second to answer this one.
What?
What identity goes with this pride flag?
I mean, you have to admit, some of these guesses are pretty fun.
Oh, my goodness.
Wow.
I am so shocked that you got this one.
Right.
Very good.
Yes, this is considered again, you got all got it, right?
This of course, goes with the homosexual, orientation.
And you have to admit, some of those choices were pretty fun.
Okay, let us take a look at another flag now, that's why I may not be as well-known, but I think the answer, I think our hint is going to help you with the answer.
Let us take a look.
Guess the identity.
That goes along with this flag that was designed in 1998, which identity goes along with this flag.
Oh hey, we had a couple of, we have actually a little bit of dissension.
This makes this more exciting for me but indeed those of you who guessed bisexual got it right now, so that's kind of new flag, isn't that?
That was, that was a new one to me.
So good job.
Those of you who guessed bisexual, okay, I have got another one for you.
Here's another flag that was created for this.
Immunity and again, introduce just a few years ago in 2018, so which Community go identifies with this flag and I think the colors are quite lovely.
Okay again, so again we have a little bit of back and forth on this one, but for those of you who guessed lesbian, you are created correct.
So, again, whenever you go to a pride parade, you can look for that black, and here's our final flag of our trivia contest.
Now, this is again, the, the origins of this flag are not known but it was introduced in the late 2000s.
What flag?
What community is this flag representing?
Okay.
So ghetto, look at this.
We have a 60/40 split.
This is exciting who is right?
And who is wrong, it is the straight Ally, okay.
So again, I am so excited.
There was a little bit of dissent there because I thought maybe our trivia game may have been a little too easy.
So excellent.
Thank you so much for participating.
Again, a lot of knowledge in our welcome room.
So now I want to tell you a little bit about the nonprofit.
Drop it that you're working for and because I don't know if everyone is familiar with degree out Circle again.
This is I want to tell you what, griot stands for its gay reunions and our time, and it's the only organization that's dedicated to serving the needs of the elders in the lgbtq+ people of color.
And you can see that their mission is a great one there, just trying to eliminate all forms of Oppression, especially if you think about it, as I mentioned earlier, Elders, already deal.
With ageism and racism and sexism and misogyny, and all these things.
And then you, and then you include those of course, who are part of the lgbtq+ community.
So they have to deal with a lot, and I am so happy that today, we can serve them by volunteering in this activity, so, I luckily, we have a video and that will tell you a little bit more about both the organization and the work they do.
And we will play that for you now.
Come a long way, but we still have not reached the top of the mountain as Martin Luther King, with Junior say.
Sprint, older adults, especially LGBT, when we get above will be get up age, we sometimes become invisible, our issues become invisible, our challenges become on your dress.
So we, the purpose of our organization is to put that visibility back on our community and to show, you know, communities at.
Hey, not only are we still here, but we still have the same challenges that, you know, other individuals that have Grill single carry on in my life at a time.
When I was really lonely.
I was just watching TV and saw the thing on we're circling and can remember and it gave my life a purpose that I didn't have for a while.
So again such a worthy organization and these affirmation walls, these digital affirmation walls that you will be creating two are really again to just send out notes to this community these Elders to let them know that we are thinking about them that we understand.
As you can see here, they face dual discrimination.
And that we want to know that there are people out there that are supporting them and it's all of us collected here today.
And, so I am so happy that you have the Community to take part in this activity.
So how is this going to work?
Because we want to make this as easy as possible.
Well, first of all, is to think about what you're writing and of course know your reader.
So again just to remember these are elders and their lgbtq+ so they again that's important to know who your audience is.
So you want to avoid any trigger words.
And one of the first things you will notice is we called them Elders because there're many things that you can call people who are of a certain age that they do not appreciate it.
Elder is one that we have found.
That is it gives them the respect, they deserve without some of the negative connotation and then of course, we want to use the neutral pronouns, which is so important to this community.
So we want to use the, the appropriate pronouns so that we don't run into any triggers there as well.
Now again this just reiterates.
What I just said again, you want to make sure your language is sensitive.
It's simple.
It's supportive.
It's warm.
It's positive.
This is an affirmation wall.
So everything there should be positive upbeat and supportive.
Now here, just some sample messages and I like these because they tend to be concise you see everything from.
You know the very first one.
I want to tell you that love has no gender.
Love is never wrong.
You are more than your queer and gender identity.
All the way to the one at the bottom hope is never silent, right?
So there's a, there're many things you can say that will make them feel seen and supported and loved.
And that's what we really are going for today.
Now, these are things, they recommend that you avoid, you can see again, they reiterate that you want to be positive but you don't want to be glib either.
Like, don't worry, be happy.
It's a little flip, a little glib.
And also if you are an ally as I am, you don't want to say, I Understand what you're going through because as someone who is just shy of being an elder and who is an ally I don't, I can never understand what they have gone through.
And so, you want to make sure you're supportive, but you don't try to grab their Journey as your own because none of us truly can grab.
Can understand truly understand what they have gone through.
So just make sure you're supportive.
But, you know, don't try to appropriate what they have been through either.
Now here are some basics do's and don'ts.
Again, we ask that you avoid Any messages directly about religion or faith because again you don't know exactly who this is going to.
Again we say positive and supportive but maybe the fourth or fifth time.
I have said that and again try to keep them concise and short and you will see once my colleague dep.
If he hasn't already in the chat window shares, the templates that were working with really, short messages are going to work really well.
Now, another thing I want to mention in the template, you may see that we tried to make it as easy as possible for you to work on these, but you may feel like you want to add something to the designs, we have already given you.
You may want to add an image, but we want to make sure you don't run into problems with copyright sharing.
Copyrighted images.
So these websites.
And again, I will ask Debbie to share these in the, in the chat window as well.
So you can refer to them is that these are all open source web sites.
So anything you find on these websites, would be copyright free?
So I just want to make sure You have your own list of these that you can reference.
So you make sure that you don't run into any problems with potential copyright issues.
Now again, how do we do this virtually?
Well again, we have developed a template, it is a slide deck and you can download it to your local computer.
It should work with whatever slideshow program you prefer to use.
You just download it locally, open it up, and each slide is its own little template, and you have a few to choose from.
So you pick the one that you like, and then you start adding Words, adding copyright free images and really think about remember your audience.
They are Elders with elder eyes and even at my age, I have trouble reading.
So you want to think about, I want to make the text I use as high contrast as possible.
So, think about if the background is like, the text should be dark.
If conversely, if the background is dark, the text.
I may have just said that, but you want to make sure that if you have a dark background, white text on a white background, dark text.
Now, what does this look like in the end?
Well here's a sample of the templates.
One of the templates.
You have three or four.
I think to choose from.
If you fill it in, boom, right?
So you can add text, you can add copyright free images, you can see here, there's some of these are quotes, some of these are just, you know, little messages that were written themselves.
So that's what your affirmation wall can look like.
And then of course this is something we will also put in the chat window.
You will want to name your affirmation wall which would be one slide.
You would save that slide or wall individually named it you see here and then you will upload it to the link.
And you can see here, you don't have to finish today because we know we're all going to have, you know, maybe less than 10 minutes to work on it.
You can get started here, you have up to two weeks to complete this activity up to two weeks.
So you can brainstorm Get started.
And then after our sessions over today, you can finish and you can send it to us when you're ready, okay?
And again, devil set will share this in the chat window where it will be a link that you can click.
So, I want to start designing, I want to take a second though and see, if there are any questions that have come in and do our Q&A window, or Q&A panel.
I don't see any right now, but if anything has come into the chat window as well.
I see all the information that Deb has shared which I appreciate but I want to see if anyone has any quick questions.
What I would like to do is let us start designing, and we can spend probably the next seven or eight minutes designing, and then we can come back together and talk about it really, really quickly.
Before we close our, today's session with, with Gina, I don't see any questions now but if you want to just start designing now and if any questions come up you can share them in the Q&A window or the chat window, I will be checking both, and then we will come back together.
Like I said in about Seven minutes.
Such a great exercise.
Now, welcome back.
Everybody.
I am just really curious to see, I know this.
That was a short period of time to work on our activity and some of you may have just gotten started or be halfway done, but I wondered in that in the chat window, if you could describe the process of working on your affirmation while in one or two words, how would you describe it?
What was it, like, working on this affirmation wall for our lgbtq+ Elders at the, at the garrote Circle, what was it like You may still be working, you may still be in the middle of your PowerPoint slides going.
Not now Carla.
I am working.
What was it like working on these?
Enjoyable Janet says it says fun.
That's you know that's exactly what I want to hear.
That makes me happy Valerie.
I see that you mentioned.
You're trying to work on your text boxes and PowerPoint.
Yeah that can be sometimes.
Yeah Janet see Janet is giving you a that's what I was happy to get some advice on that double clicking the text in the text box and I think that power points allows you to like rotate them and that way you will be able to get it in the box at that we provide in the template.
So hopefully And it's Janet advice will help you.
Yeah, we really want these to be enjoyable and fun and like I said, you have a couple of weeks to work on these, so I know that all of you are, probably if you're like me, you want it to be perfect.
And I believe we might have someone that wants to share theirs.
That's in process.
Do we have someone that wants to share theirs?
Look now here's one.
This is actually, our producer Jessica was working on her.
She really wanted to get hers going.
This is amazing.
Jess.
Sakura, for such a short period of time.
So she has love has no gender.
You are loved.
Just as you are thanked you for being you.
You're the reason why so many can be their true selves.
Wow, that's amazing, I hate nothing about you and then thank you.
That's beautiful, what a great job.
Wow a lot of I need to get, so I need to get some claps on that one.
So again, everyone out that if yours is still in process, keep working on it again, you have two weeks to go this.
And all of the links that Deb provided will still be viable.
It was such a pleasure working with you.
Today, I am going to turn it over to Gina, and she's going close out the meeting for you Gina.
Thanks again for letting all of us at coderre be here today.
Thank you so much Carla.
That was an awesome exercise and I could see how it just brings that.
That the oxytocin as what Abhishek Was saying earlier, but what a powerful exercise, and we'd love to hear more from each of you.
I know, some of you are probably still working on it, which is all good, but feel free to join us in the lounge.
So click on the tab above and you can jump in there, be camera-ready or camera off.
We just would love to meet you.
And if you are ready to share, we can also screen share in the lounge.
And there's a photo booth option.
So we'd love to take a picture together with all those.
Who are here with us today?
Alright.
So with that, we're going to move from our main stage Auditorium.
I would love to see you in lounge and see you in a few seconds.