So, excited to see you here today.
I see in chat.
We have got folks, joining us from Lansing, Michigan, Puerto Rico, Sacramento, Tampa, Arizona.
Okay.
Wow, we have got a really nice group of folks, here represented, California to Seattle.
I am Gina, I am head of marketing at welcome, and I am actually tuning in from Ewa Beach, Hawaii, which is on Oahu.
So it is nice to be here with all of you today as We're going to dive into a really relevant, awesome topic.
We have got lingle live with us.
Our CEO Roberto with us.
And we're going to talk today about skills based coaching and how you know burnout is at its all-time high.
As we know, and in fact, forty-seven point four million people voluntarily left their jobs in 2021, and we're finding that, you know, 78% of Industry professionals found that Group coaching could very well be extremely helpful during a lot of the Chan change management that we're all going through.
So I am excited to dive into this topic.
But before we do, so few housekeeping things to note.
You have got the chat right there that you're seeing.
You can also throw in GIF.
He's at any time /, giphy enter the name of what you want to do and just throw that up there, QA.
Anytime there's a question that you have, please drop that in the Q&A tab.
And if you got any technical issues, you're experiencing click on help.
We have got closed captioning at the bottom of the screen as well.
Alright, so before I introduce our panelists Jessica, who's in The Green Room?
My producer.
Could you throw up our poll?
We're going to start with this quick question here?
All right, let us get a pulse.
Do you know what skills based coaching is?
So, go ahead and drop your votes in.
All right.
Okay, throwing those votes.
And then Jess if you want to reveal to us.
How many folks know what skills based coaching is, how many of you don't and it's okay if you don't because we're going to dive into that.
All right.
Okay.
Well, I am not really seeing the results.
Are you, are you got them up?
Jess.
Okay, all right.
Well, let me go ahead and introduce our panelists to the stage.
So Tyler new CEO of lingle live and Roberto feel welcome join me on stage.
Hey, hey, hey.
Hey.
Gina Good morning.
It's 7 AM for me here.
What?
Yeah, yeah.
Where are each of you tuning in from and what time is it?
Go ahead, rip.
So, okay.
Yeah.
So I am tuning in from Puerto Rico.
So, Gina is on the island in the Pacific.
I am gonna Iving in the Atlantic.
So, my time is 1:00 PM Eastern, and I am on the opposite of an island.
I am in the Prairies of Texas in Dallas, Texas, where there is nothing but flat land and nope, beautiful weather to be singing and it is 12:07 PM here.
Nice, I love that we can all tune in and be Completely different time zones like this and have such an amazing conversation together.
So I am really excited to dive into this before we jump in.
Could each of you provide a quick little introduction of, you know what you're solving for today with your organization's?
What's top of mind, even?
Sure I am happy to go first.
So as you mentioned, I am the founder and CEO here at lingo live and at lingo live.
Our mission is to connect the world and Empower people to contribute their unique potential at work.
And so we do that by unlocking that potential through the transformative power of one-on-one coaching which I know we're going to talk a little bit about how we do that coaching skills based coaching.
So I won't kind of ruin that surprised now but at a high level that's what we do.
Thanks, Tyler Roberto good.
Fantastics yet.
My name is Roberto CEO.
Co-founder of welcome.
Welcome is the platform that you're on, so welcome to welcome.
What we focus on is helping companies gather and Inspire their distributed Workforce right now.
More than ever before, folks are located around the world.
Hence, even the intro of this conversation and what we're doing is partnering with organizations that are driving more intentional, Gatherings across their employees.
Life cycle from onboarding to town halls to Learning and Development to social, diversity and Community groups as well on the platform.
So that's what we do on our side.
Awesome.
Thanks for weirdo.
Okay.
So Doom Loop, you know that was part of our title here where we want to break this corporate Doom Loop, and I am just curious as in chat, have you all heard of this term ERM Doom Loop.
If you have just, just let us know.
Because Tyler could you help?
Explain, you know, what is this Doom Loop cycle?
And why is it affecting?
Oh, no, not really.
Okay, Joe hasn't heard of it.
And anyone else, if you have heard of it, let us know.
That's okay.
Joe, I hadn't heard of it.
Either until our marketing team, came up with it.
I thought it was a really brilliant way of putting it, which is so basically, what's the Doom Loop?
The Doom Loops.
Is this idea that As you mentioned before the voluntary, turnover, that happens?
So, what's happening there?
Why are people leaving companies?
They're leaving companies?
Not because of their role or the company, they're leaving companies because of their boss.
So three out of four employees who leave a company voluntarily, they do that because they basically have a bad manager and so what that leads to is you know obviously a cost and a drop in revenue for the organization which then prevents those companies from being able to invest in management, which then starts the cycle all over again.
So, that's the concept of the Doom Loop bad managers lead to Employees leaving, which drops Revenue hurts.
Your cash, prevents you from being able to invest and improving those managers.
Gotcha.
Okay, I didn't know.
It was a marketing term that I thought it was actually like an industry term.
Well, I think it is, but I hadn't heard of it.
I am saying to Joe like I, yeah, I hadn't heard of it.
Put that watch.
Uh, it totally makes sense.
I mean, if you even layer on the post, pandemic burnout that everyone is experiencing those.
Managers may also be burnt out themselves And, you know, could result.
So, it's like, how do we come around?
That manager is, is the big opportunity here, Rob?
Did you have any other thoughts to know what you're seeing with doom loops?
And you know, the management eating this support?
Yeah, yeah, no doubt.
So yeah, Doom Loop was new to me as well, but it completely makes sense to describe.
I think that cycle of like what's happening right now and I just now in the industry but for a long Time like folks are, you know, Sister pandemic.
People have just really started.
Taking inventory of the work, they do who they work with, we're doing work from.
And in that inventory, they're making decisions to change, right?
Organizations that are not invested in those employee experiences and invested in the key managers who drive in pole experiences.
A hard time, have a hard time retaining talent because of that, I think one of the things that we're going to find, and I am looking forward to this conversation, is the important of even middle managers, like folks that are in chat folks that are joining us as we were streaming here, managers are having to not just carry the weight of an organization because they understand sort of the mile markers that benchmarks of goals that they have to go ahead.
And then have to drive and coach your team to get there.
But they were also dealing with employees that are going through hardships.
And over the last few years, it's been really hard for all of us.
Right?
Personally and professionally and even given the certain the current like market conditions.
There's a lot of thrashing.
I would say right now just at the employee level at company level and the middle manager that manager not just has to show up to get results and I have an outcome but also to show up in coach and drive culture for their team.
And so that middle manager, I think if we had a focus of put a focus on people within a company middle managers are carrying a lot of weight today.
And, so I am glad that were talking about how this, how do we support managers and Leaders with coaching?
What is this coaching actually lead to?
What kind of outcomes can actually drive for the organization and so yeah, I am looking forward to the combo.
Yeah, just to add to that Roberta.
I think it's really important to, to capture the scale of the problem.
Like, I think everyone can buy into like yeah, that's an issue.
We should solve it.
But you know, when Gina mentions the statistics around voluntary, turnover, this is last year alone.
It cost the US economy.
A trillion dollars, a trillion dollars wasted due to voluntary turnover because you have to spend money often times as much as 2 times the salary of the person who left.
And so, if you're a company with 100 employees, He's the Bureau of Labor and statistics, going to say, you're going to lose, 26 of those employees.
Every year.
That's 2.6 million dollars that you're paying as an organization to replace those employees.
Like, most of us that are working at companies with 100 people, you can't afford to spend 2.6 million dollars so it is a very big, you know, national issue.
So let us jump into skills based coaching.
How is that different from regular coaching?
You know, I think there's, like General coaching that people are aware of.
But when it comes to skills based coaching, how do you define that Tyler?
And how do we see that as possibly a huge solution to some of these problems were talking about?
Yeah, so basically you know the way that companies are solving this problem which will get into like dif what is skills based coaching.
So companies acknowledge this issue trillion dollars And so the way that they're solving it is their Learning and Development.
Teams are putting together training programs to say.
Okay when we have got to upscale our managers let us figure out what skills really matter to be a leader at lingo live or welcome.
Like what does that mean, leading effectively at this company, so they codify some skills that they want to focus on, and then they train their managers on those skills.
And usually that happens in like a group setting where it's kind of like instructor-led training.
Maybe there's some coaching circles where people kind of Share what they thought about.
But unless you can provide the kind of safe space for someone to work out what these things mean for them and how they can actually embody these skills, you're not going to see meaningful Behavior change, you're going to get people who is a kind of learn some things, and they keep it in the back of their head.
But they're not really embodying this.
So, if you think about a skill like having difficult conversations, that's like such a classic skill.
You can run a training around crucial Relations you can train people on Frameworks for things like Behavior and the impact of that behavior and then asking someone a question, right?
Like you can give them these Concepts but unless you provide the environment for them to be able to practice those things and really contextualize, what does this mean for me in my job?
And who I am as a person?
It's not going to become ingrained and how they show up.
And so that's what skills based coaching is, is the idea of Partnering with you as an organization to identify?
What are the skills that you're training these leaders on and giving you what, you don't have the scale to be able to provide, which is personalized coaching.
It's catered to those skills.
So that these folks can actually contextualize them and start to embody them as a regular part of their identity as a leader.
And how that's different from traditional coaching is a little bit more open-ended, where it's kind of like you.
Every single individual might be working on their own things.
You show up when you need the coach, you kind of talk about what's top of Mind.
Our skills based coaching is very much focused on a specific goal that you're trying to tackle skills that matter to your organization.
That's going to help you achieve that goal in the accountability that we put in place through our applied learning model to make sure that you're actually applying.
Things in the workplace.
That's really good.
Thank you for waiting, Tyler.
I just want to hit on the last point you mentioned.
There are around accountability, how many of us get something done?
When there's a deadline most of us do, right?
Or we have to show up to a meeting and present something because somebody is expecting that you're going to have something done by a certain point in time.
I think one of the most powerful things about coaching is the accountability that comes with that, right?
Not just like meeting.
One mapping out the gaps to go work on but and then it's like, hey, in two weeks, we're going to huddle up again for 30 minutes, and we should review that plan which will review that strategy we should check on the progress that you're making.
I mean, I think that even Beyond managers even like employees, everyone that's listening to the call here, like there is something to be said around just accountability in general and mapping out the gaps that we want to go with.
Steve individually right at work or in life.
And I always found that accountability when it comes to coaching is one of those key is one of the most part.
Most powerful things about that.
Dynamic, within coach is, hey, we're in this relationship.
I am here to learn.
I am here to grow, your helping me, figure this stuff out, but also you're holding me accountable to get those things done.
Which, which I think is a big part of the how, how do you see that play out, you know, in the work that you're doing?
How important?
Is not an ability that can you just like set it goes?
And it's kind of, leave it lofty.
And how effective is it when you actually have the follow-ups with someone on the team?
Yeah, so we have actually caught a fide that as a part of our learning methodology, in a part of our program, you're going to meet with your coach, you're going to work on some skills, like, again, it's a difficult conversation.
Maybe your company train, you on some Frameworks.
But now you have literally got a difficult conversation tomorrow Friday with one of your car for two weeks.
Yeah, right, you're going To practice this thing with your coach, but then what we have codified is like homework in our program is an action step where the coach is going to say, Tyler.
We practice this, you know, we noticed how your imposter syndrome flares up when you're in this situation, take note of that, that's your homework between now.
And next week, when we meet next Thursday, I want you to take note of like when that imposter syndrome flares up, I want you to write that down and next Thursday, when we meet, I am going to ask you about that.
So that gets Put into the system, you get that as an email, as a homework assignment basically.
And then when you start your session with your coach, the next week, they're going to check in on that and be like hey did you do that thing?
What was that?
Like so that's where we're trying to use technology to kind of codify what the accountability is that you need to own and empower the coach to remember like oh yeah, because they have many coaches.
He's like, oh yeah this is what Tyler's working on.
I am going to hold them accountable for this.
Can you sort of break down the process of even how you would go about, to start a skills-based coaching program?
If you will with a manager like, how does that the goal from the goal setting to the accountability that you're describing?
Can you just walk us through some of those phases?
Sure.
So the first phase is working with your organization to really understand what are the skills that you're training your leaders on.
And why what are the There's their showing up in your organization today that you don't like what are the behaviors?
Give us some examples of that.
Like what is that?
Yeah, looks like common example.
Common example we hear is hey we're growing 40 percent year over year, and so we're promoting a lot of people in the management who don't have experience in management.
So a lot of the behaviors are showing up, are you know, they're nice, they're really nice to their team, but they're not really good at holding them accountable to Performance and outcomes, or they're telling their team what to do instead of coaching and developing them to allow the team to figure out what do they need to do.
And so we do that kind of alignment at the organization level to understand some of the themes and the trends and create a custom coaching program that's going to address those themes.
But then what happens for the manager when they on board is we have 20 different leadership skills in our catalog that we built with leading experts on leadership development and you go through that and start to indicate what do Thinker some of my biggest strengths and then some of my biggest growth opportunities.
And then we also asked you to ask your team, so you send a survey to your manager and your direct reports in your peers to do the same thing.
So that you get this holistic perspective of how people see you as a leader, both strengths and weaknesses.
And that's great context for when you connect to a coach.
So obviously, we have a matching algorithm, you can find a coach that aligns with your availability in your skills.
But when you meet with that coach, they have got This context, not just from you but from your team around kind of what do, what do you and your team, feel your strong at and what our growth opportunities so that you can kind of talk through that.
And then set a very specific goal that for you is going to be meaningful in the next four to six weeks.
I will pause there.
I mean that's just scratching the surface, but does that make sense?
Like how we get kind of program launched in the managers?
On-boarded, with a coach?
That's really great and to hear that you have identified.
You said 20 different common management, themes, what are some of those examples?
Yes, a we categorize these.
And by the way, I would be happy to share these.
Like, for any managers that are on this call that want to figure out how to improve their own self-awareness, which I know.
No, you're big on.
We're probably going to talk about.
We're happy to share our skills catalog.
Which I think as a manager one of the best things you can do is that exact same process where you survey your teammates and your manager to find out.
Hey, here's these 20 leadership skills.
What do you think I am strong at and what our growth opportunities?
I think that's something that is hugely impactful for you.
It just really turning the lights on outside of how you perceive yourself and kind of how your team perceives yourself.
But the skills themselves, I won't go into all 20, but there's basically five categories of skills.
The first is communication skills, so things like active listening, I mentioned before managers are telling your team what to do instead of coaching them stop talking, ask questions and really actively, listen to what the answers are.
And why this person saying that the second category is emotional intelligence.
So, being open is an example of a skill in emotional intelligence, being curious, being empathetic, like, Our emotional intelligence skills.
Probably the most important category, to be honest, the third is people skills.
So having difficult conversations, is this skill in the people skills, the fourth is performance.
So ensuring accountability or planning and directing work is an example of skills in the performance category and then the last is thought, like actual critical, thinking stop so much time.
We spend so much time, just working banging on keyboards or opening.
Google Docs responding to It was like, you need to think you need to set aside some time if you're really in a leadership position to stop doing and start thinking about kind of what is it that you need to be doing.
So, those are the five categories of skills.
That's great.
I just dropped it in chat as well, and we would love to see that catalog.
So if somebody could drop that in chat, or we will have a post-event follow-up email, so we could drop the link in there as well.
Perfect, that's great.
Rob.
Did you have anything to add I am just taking notes over here now.
It's all right, it's just stuff.
I think, I think one of those, you know, when we talk about Communication in general and I think, when you think about perform, all of them, all five of those, you know, for a manager to be able to show up and say, like, how am I successful?
Like, how like my role as a manager?
What does success look like?
And a lot of times, you know, we get caught up in the attic, Tyler you mentioned As well.
It's like, well, I want to drive culture, which is amazing.
That's a, that's a big priority for team at the team level.
Make sure that there's a healthy Dynamic within, within a team within your team.
But then I think performance is one of those things where if we're not really clear on the expectations of what an employee success looks like, then it's hard to actually see progression and have good conversations and feedback around those things, right?
It's something that For me, it's like one of those things.
Like when you're running so fast, You intentionally are because you're running so fast.
You intensively dismiss the importance of sitting down and check it in and asking the questions of how are you doing?
Are you be clear?
Do you understand what we are expecting XYZ?
Because sometimes, you're running so fast and high growth company that you take those things for granted.
And as a manager, you might think that's okay, but at the employee level, they're craving, that they're craving.
That level of feedback, you're craving that level of clarity, they're craving.
Even the growth that comes from the performance that the output that they're having.
What does that look like for me a year or two years?
Three years and a lot of times we're so caught up back to your point.
Tyler, we're so focused in the now that we don't take a step back not just on the Strategic level, but also just on the manager level and checking in on our people, to make sure that they're good right across all.
Those spectrums.
And so, yeah, I will put it on my side.
I am just like taking notes on my side so, you can we yeah, like, taking mental notes here.
I will probably watch this recording over and over again.
That's right.
It's really hard work like for anybody.
That's like okay, it's easier said than done like I am with you, I run a company that does this and I struggle with it.
So, like to be clear, it's not like, okay, cool, there're some skills, you just need to like work on those skills and then you're good like know, you spend your whole life trying to get better at these things because we're not hardwired as human beings to do things like the naturally inquisitive or to, you know, not view a threat when there's just conflict.
And it could be healthy conflict but you perceive it as a threat like we are.
We are not hired are hard wired this way.
And so you have got to work on it and you got to be patient with it and know that it's a marathon, not a Sprint and view success as the progress that you make, not as being this like Exemplar leader that, you know, everybody looks up to because it just it's going to take forever to get there and that's okay, it's either one thing just to follow up on that.
Like, if we go back to tough conversations, that was an example.
For that.
You put forward managers and leaders always have to have tough conversations, no doubt, and then any employee on the other side is trying to make sense of those conversations as well.
What are some, some key things that some folks can if someone is having tough conversation next week, Both from a manager perspective and also from employee perspective, what is a healthy structure or dynamic to go into those tough conversations with?
Well, I think the biggest thing is self-awareness like how are you doing?
As you go into that conversation as a manager as an employee whatever, self-awareness in terms of understanding the energy that you're coming in with.
So I am a, I am a big fan of meditation and mindfulness.
I think that's really powerful and helping you kind of tap into what's going on internally with me and you can do that for five minutes before.
One on one, we're about to have that conversation, just put away the slack, close the laptop, breathe for five minutes and just kind of take stock of where you're at.
I think that's super important.
The other thing is then to, when you're delivering feedback, I mentioned this before.
There's a framework, and we have partnered with the team at Life Labs learning.
They kind of launched this framework that I think is really helpful, which is behavior impact and then a question biq.
So, here's a behavior, I noticed.
Here's the impact, That had and then a question that you asked them, so an example of that could be and it can't be a you know, subjective thing and has to be like an actual thing that happened in a meeting.
So in a meeting I noticed that you cut off Roberto think the impact of that is that he felt like his input wasn't very warranted.
How does that make you feel?
Hearing that feedback for me?
That's Behavior impact question and I think the questions probably the most important part because you're opening the door to the fact that like, this is my perception.
It's not a fact.
It's not like stamping you with this and you are bad, and I am good.
It's like I am it's my job as your manager to give you feedback but at the same time I am open to hearing your reaction and your thoughts on this.
I think questions really important figuring out.
However, you're going to say it.
Make sure your objective and then make sure you end with a question instead of a definitive statement.
So that you Make the other person feel free to kind of share how they feel and what their reaction is to it.
That's good, that's really good.
I like that quite a bit.
It's one of those things.
If you don't have a framework, you go into those conversations and, you know, it can get personal really fast.
We're both for you, and the individual versus I am being focused on.
Hey, this happened to this is the impact.
Let us have a conversation around it.
It removes the person personally from it, but the actual thing that happened, right, right.
But what you just touch on Roberto, I think is really important, just because you prepared and you got Mindful and you followed that framework doesn't mean that things aren't going to go off the rails.
They totally can and it can be emotional.
And, so I think that's important too is to when if and when that happens be comfortable to saying hey let us pause here.
Like this is not right, we're not heading in a healthy direction and that's okay.
Let us pause, let us just kind of, you know, leave it for later.
Let us come back and revisit this.
But I think, you know, let us move on to the next topic.
That's okay.
We don't need to get into this kind of back and forth where it's starting to get toxic.
I think that's another key part of being aware of That's good.
If anybody has questions again, feel free to drop them in the Q&A tab as well.
Y'all have never been in these situations, right Roberto?
Yeah.
No it's real.
It's real.
I think that self-awareness point is really good and at as managers How can we improve in making sure to take that inventory?
Pulse check of where we are at, as we're running really fast with the things that need to get done and driving on performance so on and so forth.
Not only for our teams of for ourselves everything that Roberto had described earlier, the pressures that have manager could be experiencing how do you have any Frameworks or any ways that a manager could just like paws?
And take a self-awareness inventory.
Check You want me to tackle this one Roberto or I mean?
Yeah, I will follow on from you.
Just, I don't have all the answers here.
I just know that, you know, for me, it's, it's really interesting, right?
So if we look, if I look back at my career right, working as an individual contributor for a long time, then stepping into manager Rose.
And then now running a company like thinks changes at every step of that Journey quite a bit right.
But I think the going back to the self-awareness Gina you teed it up in?
Tyler.
We talked about this before, I think it's really and also just considering personal versus professional, I think we take inventory and say, look, if I am growing, as a manager, if I am trying to drive my career in this way and grow, that means that I my responsibilities are going to drive different skills that are required.
You know, one of my mentors said, hey, you know, a company can be growing exponentially like this far enough to the right, but people don't grow that way.
People don't grow that way at that speed.
Is much more gradual, right?
And so there's going to be a gap of like, hey my job or this season that we're in the, the company, the organization is requiring.
This I am here.
Now, self-awareness is saying there are some gaps between here and getting to this point of wearing.
To be functioning.
How do I fill that Gap?
But if we don't take inventory and say what is like, what are those gaps going back to self-awareness?
That we're going to continue to be here where the need is up here and that's a problem that's where conflicts in because at that point now it's like well you know my team needs me to be much more clear about performance objectives, feedback Cycles, all these different things because we're running at the speed and this is what it's required.
Word versus where we were a year ago, two years ago, three years ago and that's how I think about it.
When it comes to self-awareness is like, okay, if I am growing and developing, my responsibilities are going as well with that.
What are the gaps in order to keep up with the responsibilities that I have?
So that I can drive the right outcomes.
I just for the organization, but from my team as well.
And if we don't do that, then I think it takes an ever toll on ourselves because we can feel there's a gap.
But if we're not stopping to address the Gap, we're just continuing every single day.
Carrying the weight of that Gap with that Gap.
Brings to not just your team for yourself and the company that you're working.
Like so that's what I think about when I think about self-awareness is like there is a lot of times you're just gaps that we're not aware of.
We might feel it.
Our managers might tell us about it, our employees, my signal it, but we don't stop and take inventory.
Then we can't fill the gap.
They might signal it, but they probably won't like that's again then we're not as human beings wired that way.
And, so I think vulnerability is which gets talked about a lot and I think a lot of times people can hear vulnerability and think it's this kind of woo thing where you're going to be holding hands singing Kumbaya frying.
I know vulnerability is like what I said like, Sending out a survey to your people and saying, hey, there's these leadership skills that I think are good embodiment of what a leader is.
Can you share with me things that you think I do well and things that I could do a better job at like that's huge is to open that door 20, I am allowed to do that.
Like not only are you allowed to like, I need that to become a better leader.
I need your input.
That is huge, but I think the bigger thing is that kind of what you're talking about, Roberto like that.
Duration that self-exploration and I think you need another human being to help you do that.
Obviously, I am biased like a coat as a guy who built a coaching company.
Like I think someone who has a vested interest in helping you figure out what these things mean for you, and how you show up and why you show up that way, is really, really important.
And so coaches can be really impactful there, but if you can't get a coach, like, you know, you can work with those employees to say, Hey, you gave me this feedback.
I really would love your help.
Help like what are you seeing show up?
When you say I need to get better at you know being open let us say like can you share more about how am I showing up?
Can you give instances this week and then shut up?
Do not try to defend it, do not try to explain why you did the thing, right?
Like just ask questions understand what they think that's going to help you build your self awareness.
Your goal is not to solve problems and help people really understand where you came from.
Or what your intent was.
Your goal is to In the impact of your behaviors and your actions, both positive and negative.
So I think if you can kind of Orient, Orient yourself around that is like understanding not explaining or problem-solving, you're going to be in a good spot.
I think that's key right there in Joe.
I see that you're also reinforcing Tyler that's like right on, you know, after the question it's like you can't come in with a solution already.
You have to literally just, listen and Like you said, shut up and let the employee share, that honest, feedback.
Sarah Brown is asking, what are some other examples of questions in your framework?
I mean I think it really depends on the scenario.
So my cinerea was like where someone you know, interrupted someone else during a meeting which I think is that example that I have heard before, but I will try and think of it.
Another example, a question could be, I would say if you sense that the person is, you should, you know, speaking of self-awareness, be aware of, like, how is this Landing?
When I talk about the behavior in the impact?
Do I feel like this person is kind of leaning in And if they are, then the question could be something?
Like where do you think that comes from right?
Like, why did you feel the need to do that?
Where do you think that comes from versus?
If you feel like their like, you know, getting their knife out then it's like a question might be, you know, how's that Landing?
When you hear me say that or what's your perspective on the situation?
Because I know, I am only giving part of the story.
I would love to hear your perspective on it.
That's great.
Okay, looks like we have a question from Sal.
Jessica, if you don't mind pulling that on stage, what are some actual steps practices?
One can take to improve empathy and general and workspace in specific?
Yeah, I mean I think with empathy this has been a battle for me personally and professionally like I am somebody who is a problem.
Solver, I am kind of in a way a classic entrepreneur.
Like you give me a challenge.
I am going to figure out how to solve that challenge.
You give me a fire.
I am going to put it out or help.
Get the team together to put it out.
And, so I think acknowledging that's not always your job.
And Bethy is about just, I heard this quote, I apparently the Dalai Lama put it Sways is the difference between compassion and empathy is if you're on a hike and you see a man trapped under a boulder feeling their pain, right?
Versus compassion is getting the boulder off of them.
You know, it's like feeling their pain but at the same time, like solving the problem, and so I think understanding when you need to use each of those because sometimes they don't need their problem to be solved, sometimes they need to be heard, and they need to They need you to feel their pain with them but sometimes it's like, hey, this is not healthy for you or the organization.
So I am going to feel you.
I understand why this is, you know, painful but also let us get the boulder off you and let us figure out how we solve this problem.
And so, I think figuring out which one is which comes down to trust and building a really solid relationship.
Where, you know, this person and you kind of understand what they need, which is your job as a manager, like your job.
To get better outcomes from a group of people working together.
That's, I have literally was looking at this today.
If y'all haven't read this book, The Making of a manager.
Yes, Julie's book, yes, Julie's book.
This is fantastic and she defines a manager.
That way your job is to get better outcomes out of a group of people working together and you can't do that if you don't understand these people and who they are and what they need when it comes to kind of empathy versus Passion in the different circumstances that they face until you got to get to know them as people.
You can't just view your job is showing up getting status updates, telling them what they need to do.
And then ending you have gotta like cultivate a relationship understand what their biggest challenges are, why are they facing those challenges?
And then you will be able to figure out.
Does this person need me to get under the boulder with them or do they need me to get the boulder off?
That's a really good distinction between empathy and compassion.
Kareem is actually making an interesting point there.
The mere fact of asking rather than telling, and listening is a first step to building empathy, you know, making it about that other person and not about yourself.
So I think there's some great points, shared awesome.
So we were talking about that process.
I would love to jump back.
Into, you know.
Now once we identify okay these are the goals and these are the things that we can improve on and the coaches identify to work with the manager.
Now, what does that look like in accountability?
Hmm.
What is?
And today, let us say for those of us that are here, we don't have a coach, right?
And let us say we need to solve these problems today.
So what are some real practical things?
That we can do today to start, you know, you have helped us understand the identification process.
The self-awareness and vulnerability requires to ask the right questions.
Get the feedback.
Now how about accountability?
Yeah.
What is that?
Look like at a one-on-one level at A Team level, you know, the different touch points of interactions.
Sure.
So I shared the skills catalog.
I have seen some people are coming into it and I think Marines point is spot-on, like the mere fact of asking rather than telling what you can do after you have gotten that, even if you don't have a coach, let us say you have gotten that input from your team about things that you're strong at and things that our growth opportunities and how you can improve on the, on the on both really is you can come back to them, you should come back to them and ask, that's that accountability.
Gina's, hey, you told me this for weeks ago that I need to get better at this thing.
Here's some of the things I have been trying.
And what have you noticed?
Like, be honest with me, don't just tell me.
I have gotten better because you want to root for me or whatever.
Like, what have you what are you saying?
Have I gotten better at this or not?
And do you have any feedback or advice for me as to how I can improve?
So, we build this into our product, that's part of the coaching is, right?
We do that Baseline Where We Gather that data, and then we will come back and Survey the team and provide data that shows that people are actually improving in these skills, but you can do that again.
Like, if you're, if you're really invested in, This and you have got, you know, you feel good about this skills catalog and you're getting feedback from your team.
The worst thing you can do is get all that feedback and then never come back to them and share anything about like you know, they were vulnerable with you and they told you what they thought you could be better at and like, man, that would be such a shame did not come back to them and say, hey, I worked on this and I would love your input as to like whether or not you think I have gotten better.
And I am going to keep working on these areas.
So what do you think I can do about the next?
Just four weeks to get better at this.
That's huge.
It's great.
I am going to open with a question on just I know we're talking about managers a lot, and she would have coaching that supports managers.
How does a manager be a good coach for their teams as well?
Like so managers that are not you know, coaches professionally, but we know that the best way to you get results for your team is to coach them as well.
What are some of those things that managers can take home with you?
Teams to say, no, I am gonna have a team of five people.
What are some of those best practices that I can take to my team?
My starting tomorrow right?
From a coaching perspective?
Yeah.
So I have got a I mean at the end of the day it comes down to asking questions.
I have a five-year-old and I think she's a really good model for what this looks like, we're right Gina.
I saw your kid popped in the other day when we were doing the prep, they asked why they ask why all the time, right?
There's why is it that?
And then, Why?
So, the five wise is a great model.
But something happens where we lose that from kids, when becoming adults.
And it feels like conflicting.
So, I think, again, as a coach, if your job are, sorry, is a manager.
If your job is to coach your team, one of the biggest things tactically, I would say is have your team.
So I have all my direct reports and me kind of like an update each week.
Here's what I worked on this week.
Here's what I am working on next week, and here's the support I need from you.
And what That does are when we have our weekly one-on-ones.
I don't have to spend any time getting status updates from you, I can just dive into figuring out what do you need?
So I think that's a tactical thing.
You got to do like you got to take the Tactical status update things, which you need is a manager to do your job out of the synchronous kind of one-on-one time that you have with your direct report and Reserve that time for asking questions.
So you know, I noticed that you're working on this.
Thing.
But you're running into this challenge.
Why do you think that's happening and the might give an answer right?
Oh well so-and-so just you know, isn't prioritizing this for me.
Well, why do you think that is?
Right?
Well I think he's, you know, prioritizing this other thing because he thinks that's more important.
The business like well why do you think that he thinks that's more important than this is?
Like, it feels weird, feels unnatural.
But you get to the root of like this is what's going on?
Actually, maybe I failed to articulate.
Why what I need is more important than what he is working.
Hang on to him and him being successful.
Like I never thought about it that way.
I am going to change the way I make the ask so that he understands that.
This isn't just a thing I need for my team.
Like, this is something he needs and the organization needs to be really successful.
Let me reframe it, that way.
That's your job as a manager.
The other thing I would do and again this comes from this book as well is so you should meet with your direct reports once a week.
I think, for sure at least a half hour every week, but what she does is once a month, the one-on-ones are about your career, they're not about the kind of tactical things that you're working on right now.
At this company it's more figuring out where do you want to be going with your career and Reid Hoffman?
The founder of LinkedIn has this great framework which is called a row Alliance.
He wrote a book about it.
I don't know if y'all heard about this but this idea of like you know we don't live in a world anymore where somebody works at a company for 40 years, and they get the role Watch, by the way.
This is not a Rolex.
Well, I am sorry, you know, like that's an outdated model people tend to work from, you know, three to five years, and they can they move.
And, so I think acknowledging that as a leader that like, this is an alliance, it's not a power Dynamic.
We're like you work for this company and you need to do what this company needs.
It's like no, we need to also give you the skills and the critical experiences you want to gain to kind of get you to that next level in your career.
So, let us Check, let us document what that looks like.
And then once a month, let us revisit that document.
Like, what are, you know, what zoom out like, hey, you're trying to become a chief marketing officer.
Like, here's some of the things you were hoping to get done this year.
Does that align with the types of stuff that we're working on right now, like why or why not do we want to shift things around like does that make sense for the business to do that?
So I think those types of conversations are really important to avoiding the staff that you mentioned Gina at the beginning of the call.
Because when you look at that, voluntary turnover I was Looking at this stat over half of the exiting employees who left a company, say that in the three months before they left, neither their manager, nor any other leaders spoke to them about their job satisfaction or their future with the organization.
So, you have got to do that, like, you have got to acknowledge, it's a two-way street, it is not just this person's job to do the job description, you have laid out.
It's your job to set them up for a really successful career in the time that there with you.
So good.
So we need to check out those two books that you recommended.
You said it was making of the manager by Julie and then there's a Reid, Hoffman one as well.
You know, I think mentions it's like Tour of Duty or something the alliance by Reid Hoffman, the alliance.
Okay.
Awesome.
Well we got some questions coming in.
So let us tackle this first one here or second question for today.
How do you get someone resistant?
20, I just lost it.
Here it is.
How do you get someone resistant to coaching self-aware enough to get the help?
They need.
Mmm.
Such a good one.
I mean, I would love to tell you that 100% of the time.
You can do that.
You can get someone to buy in and say like okay I get it I got to be vulnerable, I got to acknowledge what my blind spots are and what my gaps are.
I was talking to a coach, but the fact the matter is, you can't, everybody is going to get there.
And I was talking to a coach about this and saying, kind of like, what is, what is the landscape of people who are Capable of actually, like getting there and doing this, and he said, there's a small minority of people who are literally for psychological reasons, like, incapable of doing this.
Maybe it's because of how they are raised, or how their brain is wired.
They just can't do it.
They're not willing to be vulnerable.
And so with those folks you have got to figure out.
Do you have one of those?
The odds are.
You don't like the?
He said the vast majority of us are.
Just are his words Garden variety neurotics.
And so with those you can through coaching and through feedback, you can get them there and it's got to be in a way that's, you know, as objective as possible and is clear and specific as possible.
But there are going to be people who just resist and are not able to get there.
And in those situations like it's a way more difficult conversation is like is this person going to be successful in this company or in this team?
But I would tell you like small minority.
The vast majority are just Like the rest of us Garden.
Variety neurotics.
Yeah, one what one thing I would add to that Tyler and I think going back to like personal professional.
I think if folks are tied to Performance being all personal versus this is a job that I have to get done and the job requires a b c, and d and self-awareness, would say that there is a gap between me understanding how to perform those ABC.
And he's, then I need some support.
I need a strategic partner.
I need a plan in place.
I need the Milestones to hit the books.
Read the coaching, the program, whatever it is, so that I can grow and hit the mark, on those things that are required.
You know, for me, I resisted coaching for a long time.
I have a coach right now, but my wife is a coach.
And so, I have always I have at home, we know the power of coaching, but there was a part of me for some time that said, I don't know, I don't want to sit down with someone to sort of like I am leaving to go figure it out.
I am gonna figure it out my own XYZ.
But when you Understand that the job your growth and your growth trajectory is going to require you to learn and adapt at a much faster rate likely than you have before.
When you separate that personal Thing versus the job to be done.
And when there's a separation there and you look at it tactically and say I have to go do this new job.
Therefore, I need a new manual.
Therefore, I need a new skill.
Therefore, I need to sharpen.
This other thing that I haven't done before or I haven't done it in a long time.
It makes it easier to engage in the support and strategic partnership that a coach can bring where I or peer can have.
But if it's, if the person is not able to get to a point of self-awareness, and say, this is the thing that I have to go do, there's a gap here, and I need support, and it's a really, really hard thing to get done.
Yeah, yeah.
I think demystifying, what coaching is, and what I often say is, what we do is we help people have uncomfortable conversations Say that to anybody any Walk of Life.
Any industry, any level of leadership?
They all go.
I need that.
I could use some help with that.
Like of course you can we all deal with it all the time.
They're like, I could use that my personal life too.
So I think when you kind of just get to a something concrete, it's not this.
Woo self Explorer ation.
I mean, there is going to be some of that.
But like, when you get to the problem that's sitting in front of me today, which is like you have to have uncomfortable conversations, would you like some help with that?
I think a lot of people go.
Oh yeah, because if I could do that better, After we can, we could grow so much faster, we could spend so much less money on an attrition all this stuff.
Then it comes solidifies for people like okay, even though that's not an accurate reflection of the totality of what coaching is, I think that's made out of a taste for that, but I think that's a really important.
Tyler is like getting as tactful as possible because then that makes it like, oh, okay, these are five things.
I have to go work on because I know that there's a gap there right now.
Okay, so how do I drive a better performance for my team?
Right now, we have been performing here.
I need to get them to hear.
How do I do that?
Well, I am having tough conversations, how do I do that better?
Or I am feeling burnt out as a manager because I am feeling all this pressure.
How do I fix that right?
I am versus making it these ambiguities ambiguous sort of like conversation with someone else.
Yeah, yeah.
That's the Doom Loop.
Thanks so much negativity.
Without that Clarity and without that structure You know I think it you get into those cyclical do lips.
So all right we got two other questions.
Pull up this next question.
Can you share with us, a personal experience where you struggle between choosing compassion versus empathy?
Which one did you end up choosing?
And why I got one.
This is a friend of mine who She processes stress (differently) than I do.
And so it took me a long time to realize she doesn't need compassion.
She needs empathy.
When I process the way I process stress is, I am I go boxing.
I go play tennis like I don't need to talk about the thing.
That's stressing me out that actually makes it worse.
It stresses me, more talking about it.
So I meditate like, it's not like a bottle it up.
Like I just I process internally but what helps me is more compassion.
Like, hey, help me solve my pride.
If I am coming to you with something like Because I want you to solve my problem.
So I think personally the relationship with this person improves significantly, when I realized all I have to do is just listen to her talk and think about how hard this is for her and articulate that and like you know try to build her confidence up but not solve the problem and that was like Game Changer like for that relationship.
So that's one.
Yeah, I have 128 you know, for me, I am always trying to be Mr. Fixit, I am attack in the motor, like this is like, like somebody that I really care about where I work with them or someone and my family, or friend, they're having an issue.
I am like, I am going to fix the thing that's causing you.
An issue that will fix the situation, or, you know what, like, I have to be strong it in a personal situation, when families going through grief for The grief and you like, you know what, almost, I am not gonna show my sentimental side.
I am not going to show my emotions because I need to be strong for that person that I care about the reality.
They want you to sit with them in De grief, they want you to sit with them in the sorrow and just be there.
And listen, and be vulnerable with the person getting under the rock, getting under the boater with the person and just sitting there and say, look, okay, let us just be in this together versus just attacking the boat of the entire time.
There's been countless times, I think in my personal life, that's been a learning lesson for me, because I have always been Mr. Fixit, you don't have to go fix the problem versus just sitting with the person going through the problem.
Not feel you, man.
You and I are very similar.
Next, that's a game changer, and I am probably like, your friend Tyler, where I am like, Hey, I am Sport Boulder.
Can you just be here next to me and cry with me?
And I actually talked about Coach helped me realize like that doesn't, you're not solving the problem like you're a problem.
Solver your Mr. Fixit, it's not working.
So like when you get under the boulder, it actually solves the problem.
So it's scratches your itch, too.
That's really good.
Wow, this has been such a rich discussion, and we're literally at time right now, so we made it all the way up to the top.
Thank you so much, Tyler.
Roberto each of you just sharing your vulnerability, even in this kind of discussion for any of you that have further questions?
Feel free to we have got AC, welcome link above.
We're also going to follow up with an email with lingle lives links as well.
So, You know, feel free to reach out to any of us.
So in the meantime, thank you all.
Thank you so much to our panelists and note that we have a really exciting event coming, this Tuesday with Arianna Huffington and Joe Thomas, who's a CEO of loom.
And it's all about the changing way in which we're working today.
These new rituals Tech practices and creating a more human workplace.
In this remote distributed time.
So please join us.
We look forward to seeing you there.
And we will follow up with a post recording.
So, keep up with our events.
Hope to see you at our next one.
Have a wonderful rest of your day.