Hello and good afternoon.
I am Gina head of marketing with welcome.
And today we have a special treat as we are kicking off these Spotlight series, and I am so excited that we have Sophia Chang in the Sophia, jeg in the green room, and she and I go way back.
So I am looking forward to kicking up the story and here and unpacking a little bit more about her journey, but in the meantime, just Some housekeeping notes.
If you have any technical issues, feel free to click in chat and one of us will be there to help you out.
And if you need some closed captioning, there is a volume bar, right underneath this stage that you can adjust the volume and hit the CC on.
So with that, we want to start with a poll.
So those of you who know Sofia she is an entrepreneur and illustrator a designer, a creative leader.
She's an influencer.
ER, in our day and age today, and she's worked with probably every shoe brand possible.
So, let us take a quick vote of all of these Brands.
Which one did she not work on?
Okay.
So we're seeing Nike and Reebok.
All right.
Well, let us bring Sophia on.
Come on in.
Join me, Sophia.
Hey, hey Gina.
How you do?
I am doing great.
How are you?
I am good to see you.
I just noticed a little welcome logo behind you.
I love it.
Nice.
We have turned it into art as well.
So, so of those logos, which one did you not work with?
These are some pretty close answers or know people did their own research, but the fog New balance is the one brand that I actually haven't had a chance to be able to work with gotcha.
Okay, but it all, those are some pretty phenomenal brands that you have had the chance to work on and Sophia.
I am so excited to be able to have this moment.
Even honored to be able to have this moment to do a little Spotlight on you and hear your amazing journey of how you got to where you are and even doing the work supporting these brands.
And it's quite a fantastic Journey.
But let us go all the way back.
If you could take us back to even your roots.
Like where did you grow up?
And what were those roots like?
Because I know it's all about those roots that shape who you are today.
Oh, yeah.
Absolutely.
I definitely have a lot of credit to give to my groups.
I have been very fortunate and grateful.
I had a chance to be able to grow up in New York City, born and raised in Queens, and that definitely played an Into just my identity, you know, being able to be immersed in this environment of a lot of stimulation from noises defense.
I literally would listen to the sound that fall asleep to the sound of car alarms going off.
I can literally can remember the exact order of the sound and, but, yeah, I mean, I am just being around so much stimulation, and I am pretty sure I had a TV or something, but I haven't been officially diagnosed but that Definitely contributes to just this Lively energy I have and just always looked for an outlet.
So, in terms of present day, you know, I would say I am an illustrator and designer by trade, but I am also very much, a Storyteller work on a number of different types of mediums.
Everything from t-shirts to print, magazines to branding and design to selling prints of my work to get having a chance to be able to collaborate with a lot of Brands and also create a parallel.
I don't think sneakers to websites.
So really, I am just a Creator, a Storyteller, and loved working on different types of canvases, surfaces platforms, be able to tell stories, that's amazing.
So take us back even further to your upbringings.
Yeah, so I mentioned, I am originally from New York, born and raised in Queens and some of my really early influences were, you know, just growing up in the 90s.
You got hip hop, music was really Sneakers was really inspired by the street art.
That was around me.
We can go to the next Slide.
By the way, the street art that was around me.
Obviously, taking the subway, the overground subway.
You just see all these graffiti around you all the time and just, it was just so much stimulation.
So that's definitely played a lot into.
Just my early years, early influences.
We can go over to the next slide where you can literally see.
I am not kidding when I say and listen to a lot of (hip-hop) and rap music.
New Jersey, by the way, is actually a jersey dress.
You can't tell him that and that photo, that's a little Polo sport bag to bring you know, throw about.
I am doing a lot of it.
Like I was able, you know, I used to work part-time jobs on the side just to be able to get sneakers.
So that's a pair of patent Air.
Jordan are Jordan One's classic, you know, just with graffiti and all of that was really inspired to just create my own little tag that I would go to the Post Office, get the sticker draw, a little The situation, I would even die cut it.
That's how it has that shape.
And then I was just like, stick it all around school and stuff like that.
So he's just take, take us back.
Give us a little bit of notes on SC.
Like, how did you come up with?
Is that your name or?
Yeah, so my name is Sophia Chang and my initials RS.
See, so growing up, you know, especially in the graffiti World street art World.
Everyone kind of went by this Alias name, and so I just went by this one just because it was just phonetically sounded like my initials.
And that's what I ended up landing on and then you know, AOL Instant Messenger people made screen names.
I would just do a CES, why?
And I am backwards.
So Ma I so and then you know, I went to college at the buyer website domain.
Do you know what to do?
So just use my screen name.
Same thing with started Instagram.
Everyone's draining, Instagram couldn't think of anything else?
Oh just went with that.
But yeah, that's the story behind.
He ask.
Oh, that is so cool.
I didn't even know that and I know there's like a sc.
And am I right?
And yes, what am I just I am backwards.
Wow, of course.
It's super creative.
I love that.
And these pictures are awesome.
You had cornrows.
Did you play sports to um, not really, but Sports culture, you know, which is so deeply intertwined with Arts and Music anyways, right?
General, like sense of style, you know, I was obviously really into Street where before they were, it was coined a name, you know, obviously into a lot of them.
More 90s inspired types of clothes from wearing a lot of Jordans to, you know, Marc Ecko baby fat.
A lot of these breaths.
Our backgrounds.
Yeah, and then my best friend growing up the girl who's in the photo next to me her older.
Sister would braid hair.
So literally after school and Elementary, I would just go over to her house, and we'd watch music videos and her sister would just bring my hair for fun.
So I am just walking around with these cornrows all the time.
I, I think there were there was a certain point where I had my whole head done too, but it was just, I mean growing up in Queens.
It's so extremely diverse as well.
Like we have we're all like how I explain to people as in elementary school, everyone packs their lunch, kind of And literally have like the Indian kids meeting Indians when you're like to know what is that, you know, people are looking at the food that I am eating, you know, an American, you know, the white kids have their own thing, you know, Spanish kids have this stuff.
So we're all kind of all tasting, each other's home, cooked meals, and you go to your friend's house after school.
And it's just, it's very different.
You know, I grew up in a Christian household where we have to pray before we eat you, go to someone else's house.
It's a whole nother situation.
So it was I was very fortunate to be able to grow up in an environment.
Moment where you know, so deeply inversed amongst so many different types of cultures.
Yeah.
Wow, and would you say a lot of those cultures all of that?
Now that it is sparking your creativity in your early years and all of that sort of has influenced the work that you even do today.
Yeah.
Absolutely.
It was just like extreme overstimulation.
I guess that's another way to put it.
Wow, like sight sounds cultures people, you know languages holler languages.
Yeah, you take the 7 train.
That's like one of the primary trains that brings you to Queens every person that says sitting next to each other, the speaking a different language.
So it's just like it's a lot all at once all the time.
Wow, that's exciting.
So all of this, these are your roots.
And then what like what happened, how?
Did you get into doing what you do?
What you do today?
Which are.
So obviously being just someone who had so much energy always had a lot of interest in the creative arts, you know, shared a little bit about my roots.
So I was really fortunate to be able to go to college and attend Parsons School of Design.
You can do the math and, you know, really valued my four years in undergrad.
I majored in illustration and, you know, really learn about the professional side of things.
This a lot of time.
People would think, oh, drawing is just a hobby.
But how can you actually turn your hobby and passion into a real career into a source of income?
And so livelihood a big part that played into just the early days of my career was definitely the internships that I was a part of.
We can go to the next slide.
And, so I had a chance to be able to work with complex magazine, which is no longer magazine and mainly like more of a media platform, but just again, applying my route to my interest into areas where I can apply my Skills and education that I was getting.
So beyond just your usual undergrad courses and art school.
I also did internships with the find artist named Ron McKenna's.
I had a chance to be able to work in the art Department, as an intern for complex magazine, where I learned about publishing.
How does advertising work?
How does, how does the advertising Department work with the editorial department, will put the, you know, design Department?
I had a chance to be able to work with a graphic designer that did a lot of work.
Graphics for Street Wear brands that I admired.
So, again, looking underneath the hood and being able to be a part of the process of some of my favorite Brands, how do they make their clothes or products?
What does that exact process light?
From research to inspiration, to actually designing it to getting it ready for vendor, picking colors figuring out sizing.
And really, like I really was fortunate to be able to work with other creators that were fortunate enough to, you know, give me a chance.
Chance take me under their wing and really show me their way to help me craft my eye as well.
When it comes to just like General design, which is really just Priceless.
And then, you know, fast-forward the next slide.
We kind of look at just exactly how my work my or a lot of my artwork looks like now some of the commission's I have had over the years.
So a lot of it is very colorful Lively lot of Storytelling.
It's very busy, a lot of times and a big part of how I would like to describe.
My work is very much again inspired by my roots where, you know, in York City, you're on like a subway car and there're sounds, there's people doing all sorts of things.
And then you have all these colorful advertisements all around you or you're walking down the street and Fifth Avenue.
And there's just so much stimulation.
But what is actually a poster or a sign on a bus?
Or something that actually makes you stop in your tracks and catches your attention.
And that's always a moment that I always valued even just for myself as someone who lives in a city, a busy City.
And I think that General mentality contributed a lot to my general style of work and along with, you know, a lot of, I guess just being involved in the just a, New York scene and being into fashion and music and so forth.
It's been able to just open doors for me to be able to On a lot of different types of projects in that space.
So what's the coolest project that your most proud of that you worked on?
And what was the most challenging project that I have ever learned a lot from?
Well, let us see the coolest one.
Well, I can say that the easiest one in the most fun one in the one that you know always gets people excited is definitely having the opportunity to be able to work with Anthony Bourdain.
So that was really my big break shortly.
After college.
The story behind that project was and I had a friend of a friend, you know, someone was looking for an illustrator just on Facebook, and they Kind of referred me to someone who happened to be another friend, you know, all around the same age group of newly grads and, you know, not really having much access, but someone did work at the production company that handled a lot of the Travel Channel shows, including No Reservations.
So they had asked me to do an illustration.
It was totally free.
It was just an illustration.
We posted on Facebook, just as a flyer, to be like, hey, make sure you check out the Boston episode tonight.
It aired.
It looked great.
Apparently, you know people at Travel Channel loved it.
So I actually got called by them don't like directly, and they signed me on for an entire season.
So I had a chance to be able to watch every single episode ahead of town of time and work on a custom illustration for each episode, which do they then produce those posters and the heat signed.
And that was their giveaway on Facebook.
It was a very early days.
We want, I want to say like 2010-2011 before.
Major companies are really using social media platforms as well.
Communicate to Their audience.
So that was very exciting because you're very easy client to work with it.
He would obviously I think we're doing is a very well-known person and it and as a budding creative to be able to share that.
Hey you had a chance to be able to work on a project like this that was very valuable and helpful to be able to you know, just again continue to build my portfolio and share the types of the type of work that I was getting.
And then to answer your question of what was the hardest Most challenging and biggest lessons.
I feel like I am always learning lessons regardless.
I love new challenges.
While I was going to leave you fast-forward on some slides, but essentially a big part of what I like to do today is I take the skills that I have learned over the years, the skills of illustration design print working with people just the whole 360 like 15 years of experience being in this space, you know, just building my On platforms.
So I guess it's a marriage of the skills that I have with my own personal interest.
So growing up, you know, loving sneakers.
I started a sneaker platform co-founded a speaker platform called common.
Ace where people get to shop from multiple sneaker retailers at once.
Because as a woman who loves to collect sneakers, it's very hard for me to find things in my size is a lot of issues when it comes to accessibility.
TV variety.
So we really wanted to create an aggregator that allowed and empowered women to butt.
And honestly, it's marketed to women, but men, women kids, everyone can use it.
It's just another online, aggregator for you to be able to find the product that you want, really, just trying to present ourselves as a One-Stop shop.
And there's always challenges there.
You know, I had to work with a team of people to work with different personalities.
Majority of our team members were women.
So it was a team of women, and I was like, oh my gosh, a lot of I usually work in a more male dominated space.
So working with different types of emotions and personalities, and especially being someone who's the co-founder and a leader in this space.
You know, I definitely had to invest a lot into communication skills and delegation and, and yeah, just a lot.
I started to read a lot more into leadership to just learn more and, and how to empower myself as a leader in that space, but that was where just definitely lots of challenges.
But Yeah, I kind of really like to tackle challenges, head-on.
I think it's exciting.
It's always an opportunity to learn, so I am all for it.
Wow.
Okay, so touching challenges leadership, you know, some, some of those things, you know, right now.
I hear you're the VP of brand of an up-and-coming brand in the tech Fitness space.
Could you talk to us a little bit about that?
And, you know, you're leading a creative team remote?
And yeah, there's I am sure there're challenges there because you know, because you meetings all day can lead to a lot of burnouts and exhaustion.
So absolutely.
Yeah, so I have had about you.
10, 10, 15 years of just freelance.
And as of November of last year, I accepted my first like full-time role in a really long time.
I had a full-time job when I first graduated from college, but it's been a long time since.
And so it's my first time, you know getting back into direct deposit every two weeks.
I was like, oh my gosh, this is amazing and it doesn't help benefit for so long.
We just, you know, Describe freelance.
So it's been really exciting.
So as I mentioned, my title is VP of brand.
So I have had a chance to be able to work with this company that I deeply admire.
It's called myo detox.
We actually have a slide for them as well, and it's actually a physical therapy and Chiropractic practice.
We have about 11 locations in Canada, and three, and Allah.
We're looking to expand, you know, within the u.s.
Very soon, a big part of why.
I will tell you, kind of the whole story of how I kind of stumbled upon my oh, but just like anyone.
I know, I just quickly recapped my journey as an illustrator, but that all of that, and all of the amazing art, you saw was a lot of hours behind a computer on a desk Urban.
Ah, McCleary really offset and in my very early 20s shortly after college.
I was getting shooting pains in my neck and my lower back and my wrist just from drying and using a mouse and, and I am hours at a desk, even though I loved drawing and I still do to this day love what I do and it definitely really took a toll on my body and plus, you know living in New York.
You carry your whole life on you all day.
Every day.
You just got it.
You can't have a car to stop the stick, your things in.
So, you carry this heavy backpack.
It's cold.
You're physically very tense.
So just takes a really big toll on your, on your body.
And everyone has their set of, you know, different types of injuries that their bodies kind of held on.
Over the years, some syrup over time and so forth.
So my story is not that much different and I had a PT person.
I was going, you know, Clinic I was seeing on and off, maybe a chiropractor when I was living in New York.
When I had moved to LA.
I had to find a new PT and a new place.
So I stumbled upon my oh and I had one session was completely life-changing.
I think what makes them extremely different for me at that time.
Was, I have never been told that there's hope I never II thought that.
At the pain and discomfort that I experienced was normal.
And that relief was temporary.
And a big part of our entire mission is really just getting the world moving helping people understand like moving every day.
So I started investing in my 0 in terms of just for myself as a customer, and I was going there once a month over the course of three years.
I was, you know, work was really, really busy lots of hours.
The desk.
I was flying once a month.
I was going between LA and New York.
Very often.
This is pretty covid.
And that was really the one relief that I found were it.
It future-proof my body.
Meaning allowed me to continue doing what I love, which is drying working.
I never want to stop doing that.
And now, you know, obviously, I am an active person as well.
But this was just that additional supplement.
I needed in my routine just like how someone flosses their teeth every day, you know.
Brush your teeth that it's just part of the maintenance or you have a therapist that you speak with that supports your mental health.
This was my staple and my everything in terms of just caring for my body.
So the same type of treatment that a Superstar athlete would get you know on the Courtside during a game of physical therapy treatment.
We get we package that for everyday people like you and I whether you're a plumber or a lawyer or a celebrity Superstar singer or whatever it is.
I will have a one body for the rest of our lives.
How can we continue to care for it?
And essentially, you know, learn more about it because my body is different from yours.
Are not their anatomies different.
We have different habits.
So, I always had this feeling of what guys, you would love to work for this company one day and I kind of got to place with my freelance work, where I had some really good years.
I started working like seven days a week with freelance and started to get really crazy.
And you know, I in many ways also felt like I work with a lot of amazing Brands and kind of reach it.
My own little ceiling and wanted more of a challenge for myself because Beyond just illustration design.
I also have more of a knack for strategy as well.
So I have been very fortunate to be able to join their team and, you know, support on their creative Endeavors and support on some of their marketing and strategy initiatives, which Just been so fulfilling.
But yeah, I highly recommend if you're a budding ones over and LA to definitely check it out.
Yeah, just it's great.
And I am so excited to be a part of, you know, their mission and I truly believe in their business and would love to see them at in major, every major city around the world because everyone should know what.
Glenn actually feel.
What this type of relief feels like.
Yeah.
Let me know when they're in Vegas.
Yeah, we could do that too.
That's true.
Okay, next trip to La.
So, you know, you're leading this creative team remotely.
How are you yourself?
Preventing burnout and from getting fatigued from meeting after meeting.
And how are you keeping your teams engaged and inspired?
Yeah, so I mentioned earlier that Our companies also Canadian.
So a lot of our team members are split between US and Canada.
There's a lot of different technical laws when it comes to.
Like how people house just to Medical Physical Therapy field is in Canada versus u.s.
So there's so you're almost working with two different companies.
Plus you have different people who are in different countries with in different time zones.
So, you know, obviously, especially since, so we have kind of been working very virtuous.
So, for a while, we never actually had a home-based office, but with that obviously comes lots of challenges.
So covid-19 a huge shock for us.
But yeah, like I think, you know, all of us definitely use your usual platforms to be able to communicate.
And, for myself, personally.
I am obsessed with productivity.
So I read a lot into productivity with some of my favorite Outlets are like to do this task to do it as a great blood.
So it Close blog that I love to use.
But I love to read their blogs, just to learn like little tips and tricks, big fan of Cal Newport as well, the author of deep work.
So I am always looking into ways to be able to optimize my workflow, and she's ways to be able to improve how work of course, burnout is very common in a big part of how I like to manage.
That is again, like through that education and awareness by researching and learning more about music.
Lots of resources for more than anything, you know, you have to remember you're in control, and I am always all about calibrating.
So I don't know if you're into productivity, but there's you know, Cal Newports, deep work.
There's also getting things done by David Allen.
There's a new show at the Pomodoro Technique.
There's so many different types of techniques and sometimes it's for me, it's more.
So just exposing myself to all of them and then testing and trying and seeing which one's work for me in certain times and certain phases of my life and my career.
And work mode and that helps me protect my time.
And, you know, for example, blocking out, certain type of whether there's everything from, you know, time blocking today, theming to there's so many different types of day.
Theming is if you dedicate specific days to different parts of your work, so Mondays are specifically for accounting.
Operational stuff.
Tuesdays are for me to do deep work, creative work.
He think, no cause that day is great and days for me to do any type of marketing Social Media stuff.
So that doesn't work for me as well.
But, you know, again, to each their own, there's no like one answer, everyone's different, and they have different circumstances, especially in their home.
So, it's just so great to be able to expose yourself to these resources.
So, that's definitely something.
I bring into the way, I work with my team, and I am also always thinking about ways that I can support them on prioritization specially when you're trying to fulfill Creative needs for such a, you know, so pretty large company to some extent.
There's a lot of different clinics, a lot of locations.
Lots of people needing things from you.
How can we build?
This is kind of the productivity part again, how can we build proper systems and infrastructures so that there's efficient workflow?
So I am really into notion.
I am really the Trello and asada and basically, I love all those types of apps and building a healthy Foundation that helps manage the entire.
Fire massive amount of workloads that are coming in.
So I am always, I don't, I always kind of, I am constantly doing but General, like, business, hygiene housekeeping.
Cleaning up my own house is nothing to be honest, but I am from a business perspective.
I am always just, you know, pruning away and cleaning up because it's like doing your laundry.
It's like, you know, just general maintenance and I know that's definitely like helps to support our teams.
And I think when we can Speak of where way, where we lead by example as well.
And also share those resources.
It definitely helps to create a paradigm shift and also creates has shifted being just a general culture of your team because you can do everything, but you can't do everything.
So how do I?
Like I never say any ideas really bad.
I kind of just shelf ideas sometimes, but I always keep a little record of it.
So then we need to like refresh and revisit the, it will be there.
You can't, you had Idea for reason, we can always revisit it at a later time.
But yeah, I think, you know, just, I myself and just a huge advocate for productivity.
So, definitely tried to bring that into conversations as much as I can with my team.
I love that.
Well, we're almost wrapping up at time here.
But for any of those that have questions for Sophia, go ahead and drop your questions either, even in the chat, or there is a Q&A tab up there, you know.
Feel free to ask any questions in the meantime.
Sophia.
I am curious.
You know what's next?
Like, I know you have got the VP of brand thing, but you always got something else too.
You know there.
What's next for you?
What is what's your next like North Star that you want to accomplish?
Yeah, I think as many as different hats that I have worn over the years.
I feel like the North Star has always been Present, you know, using the skills that I have finding, you know, speaking in a very passionate authentic way, that's always true to myself and my own personal interests, and I just really love storytelling.
I think what's next for me is always just learning new skills, and continuing to harness those skills.
I think like definitely building in this Rule, still pretty recent, you know, it's only been like, 7 months, but I love it.
And I would love to be able to see my sin, and I think the most exciting part about my role, and, We're positioned out today is I really see the company's growth and actually see my own skill sets being a part of that company's growth and that's the most exciting part.
So I think I will be here for a while.
I am still freelancing on the side.
I am actually going to be doing, I am going to be painting at like a football game tomorrow.
Wait, this is really tomorrow evening.
Yeah, so it's called secret walls.
They have artists kind of battle each other.
So, so you team up with an artist, and we each get a side of a wall.
We created look so that creative outlet and need to draw a great will always be there and thankfully the opportunity still come about, and I am still working on some fun collections with some sneaker brands that are going to be coming out next year.
It's all, it's all happening and it's all doable.
And yeah, I would say like right now freelance is fine.
And then fighting I am still doing it on the side by my biggest focus is just to really make sure the whole world knows about While detox, love it.
Okay, and it's a challenge.
It's always a challenge.
And I feel like my, I am always telling myself, like, could I be doing more?
And I think it's because it's not as easily fulfilled as like me, getting a great job, getting all the Press.
It's like I have to work in a whole different way, and I am really enjoying the challenge.
Mmm.
We will all the best to you.
Sophia.
We're so grateful that you went to go.
A little sliver of your time to be with us today.
And we wish you all the best in your journey and painting and illustrating and all the fun creative things you get to do so beautiful.
Thanks so much Gina.
Thank you.
Well, we will catch up later.
Alright.
So again, thank you, Sofia, we have in this next portion of this event.
We have got our de Cocktails.
So we had a little Spotlight and now we're going to do a little bit of a drink piss.
Hip.
Pat skip Josie on stage.
I am here.
Hey, what's happening?
I am wonderful.
Good to see you.
Jim.
How you do?
Great to see you.
Is that Snoop Dogg right behind you?
Yeah, I got Snoop Dogg with me.
I got David Bowie.
I have got Jeff Goldblum.
Willie Nelson, you know, come on.
I got a whole cast of characters.
Nice.
They're all kicking it with us, huh?
That's it.
That's great.
All right, so, what drink are we making today?
So we are going to make bubbles all day because anytime is a good time for bubbles, and we love it.
Easy to make easy to recreate.
Make it home.
Have it any time of the day?
So good.
All right, we will take it away for us.
Awesome.
Thanks, Gina.
Good to see you.
What's up?
Everybody?
I am pip.
I am a Creator bordega.
Cocktail Club and author.
Of Raise Your Spirits cocktail book all about crafting a good cocktail at home.
You don't have to spend hundreds of dollars on equipment.
You probably have everything you need right in your kitchen to craft a good cocktail part of a Hospitality Group in Asbury, Park, New Jersey, and we created this Cocktail Club.
When we had some free time over the past two years when our restaurants and our Bars were closed, and we wanted to reach out to everybody.
In the virtual land that we couldn't, we couldn't connect with on site and just talk about Cocktails.
So yeah, thanks for having me today.
Hope you guys are been making some good cocktails at home.
But like I said it's easy to do and you have everything you need right in your kitchen.
Today.
We are making bubbles all day.
So this kind of good cocktail you can make as a mocktail or as a, you know, just a regular cocktail as well.
It is very versatile.
This by switching out a few different ingredients.
Yeah.
So we like to go over what we have behind our bars when you can use at home.
If you don't have the right equipment.
Like I said, you probably have everything.
You need right next to you.
We're going to shake up this cocktail.
So I am going to use a Boston style Shaker set, but more popular homes Shaker is that cobbler style?
That's got that top with the built-in strainer.
You don't have anything to shake with, it's fine.
You just need something that's going to lock in your ice in your ingredients.
We use a protein drink Shaker that's collecting dust in your cabinet.
If you use a mason jar, just want to get that proper chill and dilution.
And yeah.
You other things that you need some frozen water.
Make sure you have some ice handy.
When we're making drinks at home.
I like to keep our ice stored in some freezer.
Eggs, just to keep any aromatics, my refrigerator off of our ice out of our cocktails, but always having some new ice from Cocktail very popular.
So if you're having a cocktail session cocktail party, sure you get enough ice ready and good clean Spirit.
What's great about this cocktail is that it's very versatile?
If you want to use vodka you can use Jin.
You can wrong news wila.
We love tequila, but the original recipe calls for vodka is very Kind of, like I said, versatile cocktail, but you can always just lean on whatever spirit that you like best.
Of course.
We're going to be adding some bubbles to some sparkling wine.
We have got a kava root.
So a little dryer.
Not too sweet, not to overpower the cocktail.
Now, if you wanted to make a cocktail, all we have to do is, you know, not, add your spirit.
And substitute your champagne or sparkling wine with Soda, the nice little bubbly cocktail, some ingredients that we will be using as well is a honey syrup.
Now instead of using just raw honey.
Honey tends to like stick to the Shaker.
Even stick to the ice.
You make a honey syrup, which is just equal parts of honey and water.
This to dilute that honey.
That makes it much easier to aerate and dilute in your cocktail and mixes much better and you still get that nice sweetness.
We're also using some fresh.
And squeezed, lemon juice makes all the difference in the world.
Make sure you have fresh Citrus in your cocktails.
Don't use it against us, controlling the ingredients not using any artificial mixers or filling up on a ton of juice.
You want to get some fresh Citrus in there and not even have to use that much to get that nice tart flavor in there.
We're going to be using lemon juice and what I like to do, with our lemons, you know, whether using hand juicer for juicing, it by this hand.
Am I like to keep the peels for last-minute Expressions on a cocktail?
So there's a lot of great flavors and fragrances that live in the oils of our citrus fruits.
So what I would do is just grab a peeler, as a y-shaped.
Peeler great for citrus.
Fruits can use any kind of Veggie peeler, or just a paring knife?
No, just taking off a nice P, like that.
I am going to keep it to the side and I will garnish my cocktail with this.
But using all those great oils for fragrance and for a little bit of zesty flavor.
So we're making a cocktails all about balance.
So we want to have our most important tool is are measuring utensil few things.
You can use.
We use a jigger.
This is a Japanese cone style Jigger, has different volume denominations and even has some nice etchings inside from a half ounce, three-quarter ounce and so on.
But if you don't have a jigger, use a measuring spoon, tablespoon is equivalent to a half an ounce.
So easy way to play.
A along.
Make a cocktail this by using a measuring spoon or if you have something small measuring cups, but either way, if they seem most important utensil just so you can consistently recreate that cocktail, no matter how we like to, you know, whatever you're using, and then tend to your palate.
So if you like things a little less interesting, little more sweet.
You can manipulate those flavors to make it the way you like it each time.
Then switching out some ingredients, but following these template makes you know, just a little better at going off and crafting, your own cocktail, but all the cocktails and our bars are our own recipes that we want to make.
Sure that guess has that same experience, no matter who bartending.
So we're always measuring at hot.
Yeah, I guess let us make the bubbles all day.
Shall we one thing to note?
You know that club.
So, Soda that sparkling wine that never goes in the shake.
Okay, just like we don't shake up and a beer or a bottle of wine or anything carbonated.
We don't shake so that will go in after we strain out our cocktail.
We also like to build our cocktails dry so high schools in last.
Once, your ice in your ingredients, meet clock starts.
Ticking.
Ice will start melting.
It could over dilute your cocktails.
We only add ice once.
You're ready to start shape.
Also, kind of flavor up this, not do with different ingredients.
But if you want to model in some different berries, for a little bit of spice pepper, we can reach to your liquor shelf and grab a different lock or Louise, only use like a little bit at a time because a little goes, a long way with these different reporters.
And editors.
We're going to use some a parole.
An hour cocktail, it's completely optional.
But I like the after all very popular because the Apple s grits, it's a red bidder from the Amore family, adds a nice little kind of Bittersweet component and a nice little pretty cute tour cocktail.
You're not familiar with the after all.
This is its a nice kind of way of introducing yourself to the mares are red bitters that go into our cocktails.
It's older brother.
I would say Campari very better, very aggressive.
After all is a nice little softer way, go bad it.
But this only would be using a half an ounce just to kind of give a nice little balance.
All right.
So first I am going to add our honey syrup and same thing with all the cores are syrups little goes a long way.
And I am just going to have a half ounce of a touch of Sweetness in the cockpit.
So I have got my honey syrup ready to go.
I am just going to measure out a half ounce.
Go right in the shaker.
Notice, I am also using my least expensive ingredients first just in case I have a little spill precious booze isn't going to go to waste just yet.
So I have my sweet with my honey syrup, and I am going to have my Citrus, and I am going to add three-quarter ounce of our fresh squeezed lemon juice .75.
So making a traditional sour style cocktail first similar to like a bee's knees.
You always want your sweet, your citrus and your spirit, the main components to your sour style cocktails.
Bee's knees Margarita's Daiquiris gimlets.
Those are also our style cocktails all that same template with those three ingredients.
So I have got my sweet.
I have got my Citrus now, my spirit whatever is Andy that you'd like to use.
Like I said, very versatile, I am going to use a silver rum in this and with this, we're going to go an ounce and a half.
Now you can make this as low alcohol as you like to just want like a, you know, low ABV.
We call them loaf on top sales, and she don't want to go too aggressive.
So I mean, it's just a Thursday.
Thursday is new Friday.
Let us go one and a half ounces.
I am going to go, 1.5.
Now cocktail just like that is good to go.
But I am going to add a little bit extra little, you know, pop to this cocktail.
I am going to add some after all and just going to use a half ounce.
Now, if you have something like an elderflower liqueur, Ginger liqueur, maybe a berry liqueur again, just use a little bit half hours, just to give that little extra pop of flavor.
So, This doesn't want to come off.
All right, so in cases like these, when you can't get the cap off of your bottle, just run it under some warm water and that will lose.
The sugars that are keeping this from coming off the top of my bottle.
Live TV, anything can happen.
So I am going to opt to not even have the after all my cocktail this time.
Good thing.
That's an optional component.
So cocktail is ready to shape.
I am just going to add some ice, just enough, ice the top, the components in my shaker.
And then once we lock in our shaker, if you want to get a good Vigor shake for about 10 seconds, that's just enough to aerate.
The, all your components, all your ingredients, you get that good.
Chill.
And you always want to add a little bit die.
Lucien.
You want to get a little water to into the cocktail as well.
So lock it in.
No, don't shake it at somebody, you know, I don't want to weaponize these cocktails.
Always try to get your hands on it and Get away.
So, check it out, guys.
Ice hope.
All right.
So check it.
However, you want to.
Yeah, go ahead the Shaker if you want, but any kind of glass eight-year at home heirs, have it out of the coffee, mug, have it on the rocks and rocks this.
If you like, I have got this nice Coupe glass that I would like to turn it into just been begging to be used.
Now.
I am going to use a Hawthorn style strainer.
This just says, he's flexible coil sits right on top of my shaker.
You don't have a strainer, you know, you can use a couple Forks that would Finance training at your cocktail.
The Strain this out first.
Notice the drink right now is great to drink on its own, not a ton of volume, not filling up on a lot of artificial mixers are, you know, ton of juice?
It's a much easier to drink another one, but I want to add some bubbles.
Now if you just made it with lemon and honey, and no booze and you have a nice little kind of funny lemonade, which is fine.
Just want to add some club soda.
I am going to be adding some.
F****** wine and use about like 2.
Oz.
You don't have to measure it.
You can kind of just give it a little lift.
Now.
You don't want to add too much.
Big can't take away.
You can always add more.
So I am just going to give it a little lift.
It's a nice little effervescence.
For the cocktail.
Now the last piece I am going to use that lemon wedge, or I am sorry, lemon peel that I would save and by pinching it a holding it over.
The cocktail with a bright yellow side, down the release those oils on top of the cocktail that's going to help with the your the aroma and just a little extra of citrus zest and might not be able to see it here, but it's little fireworks will shoot.
Tick-Tock tell just by pinching it.
So, put it in there.
Those are fireworks.
BBB over your cocktail.
And you can either leave it in there as a garnish or get rid of it.
Here's there.
We have it.
We have got bubbles all day.
Here's everybody.
Oh, yeah, dangerous cocktail and just about cocktail time.
So it's a perfect timing.
Come on, Jimmy made one with me this time.
I know, I know didn't quite have all the ingredients this time.
But I do enjoy learning all your tips and tricks so it's fun to watch.
Thank ye sometimes things.
Don't go as planned.
You just, you know, it's all about balance.
It's all about having some good ingredients in front of you.
So, you know, that's what we offer in the bar, dega Cocktail Club.
And as we offer in our classes, I love it.
Okay.
Cool.
And people could go to your site to get some more information.
Absolutely bordega cocktails.com.
We have got all your home bartending needs and any kind of tips and tricks there and coming up on Cinco de Mayo.
So we have got, that's wonderful.
Margarita, kits.
Margarita salts, things, like that.
That is a week from today.
So, we're, we're psyched to celebrate that because we love our Margaritas to tequila is life.
That's right.
All right.
Well, if anybody has questions, feel free to drop them in chat, and otherwise, I see.
There's a few folks here, Francisco, Michael Raquel.
Ym.
Thanks so much for joining.
Meaning us and you're obviously here on welcome, and we are a virtual event platform that can support both your internal events such as these kind of experiential events for team members, but also external events as well.
So let us know, there's a book of demo tab at the top and you can connect with us and get to know and see.
Welcome and also for a day of cocktails, so great.
Well, thank you all for joining and have a wonderful.
Awful afternoon.
We have another Spotlight event taking place.
It's going to be a coffee with Spotlight with tam-tam who is head of global de I had envisioned.
So we will be doing sort of like this 30-minute quick Spotlight and coffee experience on Tuesday.
So feel free to sign up for that one.
As she used to be a former Winter Olympics athlete from with Salt Lake City 2002, and She was the first woman in Ireland to be in the Olympics.
It's a really big deal and that whole experience of being a woman athlete, actually spurred a lot of the passion as to why she's leading D EI and doing the things she's doing globally today.
So it's going to be a really riveting conversation and I encourage invite all you join.
So with that, thank you again.
Have a wonderful evening.
Wherever you are afternoon.
If you're on the PST time, and we will catch you next time.
See you later.