Hello everyone.
It's so great to see you all happy August First Tuesday of the month.
I am Gina head of marketing of welcome, and we are happy to be with you today to talk about a very, very important topic on getting effective and communicating feedback before.
We jump into our panel topic discussion.
We have got folks tuning in from Helena Montana, that's where Claire's at Janet.
Hello from Mendocino.
Now to Pennsylvania Dallas, Texas.
San Diego.
It's so great to have you all here.
I am doing it from Las Vegas.
All right.
So today we have got some, some questions that were submitted in advance.
So, feel free to go to the Q&A tab to the right and check out the questions that were submitted, feel free to upvote them.
And at any given time through this event, drop your questions.
If you have any Cuz we're going to pull those on stage and Claire and I are going to have this Rich dialogue around the feedback, and we can answer them real time now.
Employ feedback surfaces issues in the workplace which we all know can improve morale retention and feelings of safety.
But the problem is there're barriers to giving feedback like fear of retaliation or fear of not being believed.
So in order to create a thriving, engaging work culture, it's critical.
To hear from your employees about what's going.
Well, what's not?
And then here's the kicker, take the action to fix it.
So I am so excited.
It's one of my favorite topics because I need to learn a lot from it as well.
But I am so excited for this opportunity to chat with Claire.
She's the founder and CEO of all voices and employee feedback management platform.
We're going to hear a little bit more about that when she comes on stage and you know, on March 20 21 all voices survey Paid 800 plus individuals from the US who are fully employed and ask them about the free feedback programs at their workplace and check this out.
79 percent of employees have shared feedback with their employer.
41% have left a job because they didn't feel listened to 37 percent.
Have left the job because they felt feedback.
Was it being taken?
Seriously, in the workplace and said, Four percent would be more inclined to share feedback if it's truly Anonymous.
So those are some real staggering statistics there, and I am looking forward to unpacking that a little bit more.
Thanks, Katie.
She's the producer right now in The Green Room.
Hello?
Y'all feel free to say hi to her.
Thanks for dropping that guide that all voices just put out.
So we're going to kick off with this pole.
We have got two poles.
The first question at your company.
How comfortable do you think?
Employees are giving leadership.
Positive feedback.
Feel free to drop your votes right now.
And then we're going to ask the flip side of it.
Very comfortable.
Oh, that's good to see somewhat comfortable.
We got a fairly uncomfortable, extremely uncomfortable.
Okay, we have got make sense, very uncomfortable.
All right, next question at your company.
How comfortable do you think?
Employees are giving leadership negative feedback?
Go ahead and drop your votes.
All right.
Okay, I am not fully seeing the votes.
There they are.
They're coming through.
All right, somewhat comfortable, 35% fairly uncomfortable, 35% and then 25%, extremely uncomfortable.
All right.
So this probably isn't surprising to Claire.
I would love for you to join me on the stage.
Hello.
Hello, it's great to be here.
Thanks for having me.
Absolutely.
Yeah it's great to see you, and I am so excited to have this conversation with you around feedback and really tap into your expertise.
Can you tell us a little bit about all voices and even if you have any thoughts on that pole?
Yeah that pole was really interesting.
I will share my thoughts in a second but first all voices, like Gina men.
And is an employee feedback management platform.
And what that really means is that we help employees speak up about anything.
They want to at work positive negative neutral in real time, and we have built a two-way Communication channel.
So that HR leaders legal leaders, CEOs.
Anyone in the leadership role is able to have a back and forth conversation with that employee, and then we provide a bunch of tools on the back end for the Teachers to help them take action, understand, patterns, and Trends, and ultimately resolve.
The things that are being brought up in one way or another.
So it's been a really fascinating Journey.
We have been doing it for five years and I think just to touch back on those poll results.
One thing that's really interesting to me when I started all voices, it was really in response to the me to movement, that was emerging and my hypothesis was that Would be extremely hesitant to speak up at work, about really serious issues, like sexual harassment, discrimination mistreatment, and what we found in the first, like, six months was that employees were using our platform to share all kinds of feedback positive negative anywhere in between a lot of questions, actually.
So what we realized was for one reason or another many employees have hesitations about speaking up about anything.
I am at work and so making sure that you have some way for them to speak up anonymously, which goes back to that statistic, Gina that you shared about employees, wanting and preferring to have an option at least for anonymous feedback, that was really one of the things that I took away from the first six months is, like, no matter what's going on with an employee.
It's good for them to have multiple different channels to share that feedback.
Hmm, ii-i'd love to tap into that more.
I know we have some other questions going to, but like what are all those channels?
Like if we can get into that later on, that would be great.
What I would like to kick it off?
First with a question that came through.
How would you define good versus bad feedback?
And I think we can start with the ladder on bad feedback.
I know Claire when you are you and I were chatting earlier, there's probably a lot more bad behavior that occurs around this in a workplace.
What are your thoughts?
Yeah, I mean I think look having a company is just challenging, right?
And I started a company and I have seen this firsthand, but you're bringing together a big group of people who all come from different backgrounds, have different experiences, have different communication Styles, you're bringing them all together, whether they're remote, or they're all in the same room.
And you're saying like, Okay, let us all work together toward the shared goal, there are always going to be conflict.
They're always going to be miscommunication.
There are always going to be challenges personality clashes Etc, right?
There's no like perfect company culture or Utopia and so the question in my mind is how do you make it possible for employees to speak up about what's going on about what their reality is early and often?
And if you do that, what you will find is that you have the information that you need to take.
Action to make things better, right?
You so in terms of like bad behavior versus good behavior, bad feedback versus good feedback.
I would say in general, it's just about needing to first, to sort of start with listening and understanding what's going on and making sure that people actually feel safe speaking up.
And like I said, even if let us say your company is perfect, let us say it's this dream company.
Where everyone?
Everyone feels 100% comfortable being transparent.
Being honest, you're still going to have issues come up and people come to your company with baggage from their previous rules.
And so even if you as an HR leader are incredibly approachable, and you have built relationships with every person, they're still probably a lot.
That is not being brought to you for one reason or another.
So I think of all voices, as kind of like The Back-up Plan, like In case someone's not comfortable coming to, you just have another way that they can speak up, just to make sure you have all your bases covered.
Mmm, that's good.
That's good.
So, when you know, you were mentioning something about how bad behavior has been part of companies for a long time and, you know, it's been a broken system that a lot of us are used to operating within where the proper channels aren't in place and Managers may not have the training knowing how to have a constructive conversation around feedback with their employees.
So what are your thoughts to this?
And you know what, what does that look like for?
And I think this goes into the next highest voted question is, you know, what is the best way to provide constructive feedback to your leader to your employee?
This goes both ways.
Yeah, so when I was doing research to into this space right into employee reporting an employee feedback and how historically employees have spoken up at work.
I looked at a really interesting report from the EEOC and what that said was that I was specifically looking at harassment at the time because we were sort of the me to movement was emerging.
And I was thinking about solutions to people not Harassment in particular and I found some really fascinating data and what it said is that 75% of people who experience sexual harassment in the workplace, never report it, right?
So they don't share that information with someone who could actually take action and address it out of that 25%, who do report it according to the EEOC 75% of those individuals face, some type of retaliation Ation for speaking up.
So to me, I looked at those two stats and took them together and realize like these data points, really represent a broken system, like you said Gina.
So I think historically like preemie to movement pre 2017, we as a society, basically, just that Okay.
Employees like speak of or nobody will help you.
And those are kind of your two options and employees for the most part.
According to that data, just stayed quiet and maybe they became disengaged unproductive.
Maybe they quit their jobs.
You know, even during the Great resignation, I think there was a stab at 57% of people who left their jobs during the Great resignation of 2021 left because they felt disrespected at work.
So these are solvable Issues, right, but someone at the company needs to know what's going on in order to take action to try to help resolve it.
So I think just to go back to the beginning, like we have had a broken system for a really long time and for so long it was just like, okay, deal with it.
And I think what happened in during the me to movement is that the public took great interest in how employees were being treated and started to make it okay?
For employees to share their experiences publicly and to actually hold companies accountable in the public eye for the behavior that was happening within their companies, even if leadership wasn't aware, it was sort of like, it doesn't matter.
And the fact that you're not aware is the problem.
So, that's kind of the evolution that I have seen since then is that there's a lot more accountability for companies and there's a lot more required of them.
And so, to this question about, how is the best way to provide constructive feedback?
I really think companies need to create multiple options or multiple channels.
Like I said, before for employees to speak up, so have an open door policy.
Make sure they know who on the HR team or the employer relations team for the executive team to go talk to if they're having a challenge or an experience.
Give them tips for having actually conversations with their own direct leadership.
But also, make sure there's a secondary channel for employees.
Speak up that feels a lot safer to them where they can be anonymous, where they don't have to fear retaliation just for having spoken up.
I mean, you see companies put out those annual surveys, you know you could like Google search the questions and drop them into like a Google form and send it out.
You know what I am saying?
Are those effective and you know, that is that a channel as well?
To be considered or what are your thoughts there?
I don't think they're effective at solving the problem that we're talking about today.
I think they solve a different problem which is at a given point in time and over a period of time, right?
Year over year what is the sort of overall high-level cultural health of my organization?
And is it trending in the right direction or not?
That I think is what those annual culture, surveys are good for it, and I think they have a role.
It's great to, it's great to measure that what it's not great at is, let us say you send that survey out in January every year.
And in February, I have an issue and I don't know who to talk to.
It's an issue with my manager.
I am nervous.
Bringing it up to my manager.
I don't feel like I have the tools, maybe I was retaliated against at a past company and so, I am especially scared or hesitant to bring something up.
And I am, Receiving a culture survey until next January.
So am I supposed to you as the employee?
Just stay quiet and gut it out over 11 months and then put something in a culture survey that I am not even sure will be followed up on.
I am not even sure if it's possible to be followed up on.
I am not sure if it's Anonymous or not, I don't know the difference between Anonymous and confidential.
There needs to be a real-time solution in place for those types of issues so that they can get resolved now and not in 11 months or, you know, possibly never.
So if you were to break out the different types of channels, you mentioned, you know, having an open door policy and being able to have that conversation, both ways and police should feel that openness and their one-on-ones with their manager and vice versa.
And then you mentioned, you know, maybe it's quarterly or annually annual surveys to gauge patterns of Health but then there's the ongoing that you're talking about and what are some recommended channels that we could tactically use today for something that's a little bit ongoing outside of the one-on-ones that you may have with your team member or manager on a weekly basis.
Let us say.
Yeah.
So a couple of those, a couple of solutions we have built right?
One is all voices Anonymous feedback Channel letting employees be kept in.
Real time, anonymously sharing feedback and then communicating back and forth with that employee.
Another one we have that we think has been really valuable to our customers is pulse surveys.
So, let us say that, you're so not a big annual culture survey with 50 questions, right?
That needs like a data scientist to analyze all the Service for you.
But let us say you're hearing about a specific topic, like, oh, I don't like our new PTO policy and you're hearing that through all voices.
Maybe some managers are hearing whispers of that.
It's starting to kind of like Ripple through the organization.
You could send out a pulse survey that day and say hey wanted to ask some questions about our new PTO policy.
One is this better or worse than our previous policy to?
What are the things you would like to see that?
The policy includes that it doesn't include three Etc.
Right?
And you're, you're pulling information in real time.
And then you're pushing request for more information back out about a very specific and actionable topic, so that can be incredibly valuable to.
And then, the third tool that I have started to hear more and more about leaders using is stay interviews.
So, I think those need to be conducted in concert with some of these other sort of measurement tactics and tools but stator Use earn opportunity.
So we all know about exit interviews, right?
Which is like when someone leaves you conduct an exit interview to find out why they left and that's helpful.
But it doesn't help you in retaining that employee, right?
They have already left.
So, it's a little bit too late and hopefully you use the exit interviews to prevent others from leaving, but it doesn't help with that.
The ones who have already left.
So stay interviews are sort of the inverse of that, which is leaders from within the company set up time to You just talk one-on-one with individual employees about why they're stay right?
Why they're not leaving.
So it's an opportunity to say like what's working?
Well, what do you like about your job?
What do you like about the company?
Also, what's not working, how can we better support you?
How can we meet your needs better as an employee?
How do we make sure that you're still here a year from now?
And I think the combination of all of those different practices can be incredibly valuable at painting like a Comprehensive picture of what's going on with employees at is really interesting, the state interviews.
What's the frequency?
And do you recommend leaders that are not the direct manager of the employee?
I do, yes.
I think, I think it's actually a great role for HR.
I think HR business partners, and HR leaders spending time talking to employees about just how they're doing it.
In general, right?
Not around a specific incident or investigation.
But just like, how are you doing?
Conducting a stay interview.
Anything that's not working.
Well, how is your relationship with your manager?
Like all of these things are helpful and, and to go back to my earlier point, there might be hesitation in those conversations, right?
There might be fear from employees still, but at least you're giving them the opportunity to speak up and showing them that you and the organization are receptive to feedback and want.
Feedback and hopefully by having additional ways for them to speak up.
Like I said, the stay interview in combination with all voices reports in combination with, you know, the poll surveys and the annual culture survey that together paints a more comprehensive picture.
Gotcha?
Okay.
So one of the other thoughts I have is being able to create a culture that feels safe to conduct these ongoing pulse surveys.
And you know, you're asking its listening a lot of Information from your employees but then I think from an employee perspective, you know, my employers asking all this stuff, what are they going to do with it?
You know, and I think there needs to be proven ways to demonstrate that their that on her door, that actions be taken.
So that goes to one of them.
There's a question that's been submitted here.
It's got four up votes.
I have seen many organizations struggle with how to share and act on employee feedback.
How can Relations execute action around feedback better?
Hmm, I got a great question.
So basically, I think we're starting to get to a point where companies know, they have to provide ways for employees to share feedback, but I think sometimes the missing piece is then converting that feedback into action.
So one of the things that I mentioned, right, the pulse survey, that's actually a great example of showing employees.
So let us say, let us say four employees submitted Concerns about the PTO policy.
And then a week later, you the HR leader are sending the entire company.
A survey about the PTO policy that's actually actioned that's showing that you are looking into something that is being brought up and trying to continuously improve, whatever it is, that was raised as a potential issue.
So the pulse survey itself is a form of action and then in response to the pulse survey, there's additional action that can be taken.
So maybe, At an all-hands meeting you share the results of the poll survey.
You say 75 percent of people in the company feel good about our PTO policy.
And the number one Improvement that was requested was bereavement leave.
So we are going to add bereavement leave since that's something, we have never had and something that the majority of you wanted.
That's all and that's not rocketed science, right?
That's simply being responsive to the feedback that you're getting and then communicating the responsiveness, which I think is sometimes the missing piece.
Another example of something we have heard from customers, is that communication piece is sometimes just missing like leadership knows something, but they haven't yet communicated it down to the rest of the organization.
So one of our customers was getting a bunch of reports about Space issues.
Like we're all, you know, the pre-pandemic but like we're all, you know, elbow-to-elbow, I can't even like breathe in my space.
Like, what is going on?
Meanwhile, leadership had been looking for a new office space for the last like, four months so that search was underway.
But employees had no idea because oftentimes leadership as leadership, we don't announce things until they're done or at least more solidified.
But sometimes it's just a matter of saying we heard you.
No, this is you know we are all crammed in here and this is untenable, we are in the search for an office space.
We think we will have One Secured in the next three to six months.
And in the meantime, we're looking into, you know, getting some satellite office options, right?
It's not always about having a fully baked solution to roll out and announce with a perfectly executed, communication strategy.
Sometimes it's just communicating that you're working on something and that, you know, it's an issue.
So that yes, I think Paula just mentioned here, the positive energy you got from asking for feedback can be negated if there is a lack of action on that feedback so it is very critical and I guess one of my questions would be, who is there a point person that should be responsible to handle the surveys?
Make sure it's properly being communicated out like what team generally is responsible.
And if you know, like It's a I would assume HR right?
But what if you don't have an HR room?
Yeah, I was just going to say it really depends on the size of the organization.
So let us say you're a 10-person company, right?
We have been a 10-person company, and we didn't have HR at that time, but we still, but you still want to create opportunities for people to share feedback.
I think it's an initiative that in the earlier days or in the smaller days needs to be led by the CEO, I think creating a healthy culture is ultimately a part of the CEOs job.
It's not just about delivering results.
It's about how do you get those results and part of that is hiring recruiting retaining key emphasis on retaining employees.
So, you know, in the early days like I let all of our culture initiatives, I am still super involved in our culture initiatives, and we now have almost 40 employees.
So I think it has to come from the Top down, it has to in order, especially in order for people to feel like action is actually going to be taken, right?
Because if you pass off the initiative to someone who then doesn't have the ability to take action or you're not providing a way for them to take action on the feedback received that can actually to Paul is point that can actually backfire and have a negative impact.
That's good to know.
Okay, we have got another question with some pretty high up votes here.
Before closing a feedback conversation.
How do you best ensure that the feedback has been understood?
So I think that miscommunications always happen or can happen and so it is really good to clarify the information that you're receiving.
So I guess this answer would differ a bit depending on the context.
So in a state interview I would actually say repeating things back to the employee.
This is kind of what you're saying, let me make sure I understand it.
In rephrase it back to them, and then they have the opportunity to say.
No, not exactly.
I am actually saying more than this so that you really both leave that conversation with complete clarity about at least what was being said, you don't have to solve the problem in the meeting, right?
You don't have to come up with all the answers in the meeting.
This is really an opportunity to listen and this type of listening if it's done, effectively would mean that you both walk out of that.
Conversation with the same understanding of that person's experience and what they share.
So how do you, you know, we have built a software platform?
So how do you kind of like mimic that experience through a digital communication Channel?
There's a couple things one, you can still repeat back digitally like hey this is what I am hearing.
Does this make sense?
You can clarify what you think as the HR leader?
What the next steps are and how you know how that works for?
Other person.
But then actually we have built into our product and additional data point, which is after the employee and the employer and the conversation, and that conversation gets marked by the administrator as resolved, so they can track like, how many open issues do I have versus closed?
We actually all voices.
Send a follow-up survey to the employee.
And it's just, it's still an honor.
Amos and it's just like two questions.
How satisfied are you with the way that was handled, and we're any steps taken to address the issue that you raised and then that data goes back to the HR leader.
So maybe the HR person thinks that something has been totally satisfactorily resolved, but the employee does not feel that way.
Then they can reopen the conversation and say, hey, I saw that you didn't feel like this was quite handled.
Now to resolution.
What else do you need?
What am I missing?
What else can I do for you?
Where do you think you know the gaps are or the opportunity to improve this further?
So that's another sort of like tool that helps make sure everyone is on the same page.
What were those two questions again?
How satisfied are you with how it was handled?
And what else?
So, it's basically been you aware of the company taking steps to address the issue that you raised and how satisfied are you with the way?
It was handled on it, that's good.
So, that's sort of guy this question that can be asked after the one-on-one session that a manager may have with their employee.
And then, you need that third party, though, to probably be filtering through that.
And then providing you need that system to have that conversation and feedback.
Go back to the manager, you know, that the invoice.
Now, what about the other way around?
As an employee, you know, going back to those poll results.
It is very challenging to provide negative feedback to your manager to the leadership.
So let us say we don't have all of those channels that you have identified Claire Where did you start as an employee to have a constructive conversation with your dirt direct manager?
Yeah, I mean, I think, you know, the way I think about this is that the best way to build trust with employees, is by listening and taking action.
So you have to build trust over time.
And I think in some ways all voices is kind of shortcut to building that trust Is it gives you the information?
You may not be getting and helps you show.
Like, it's okay to bring things up, and we will actually take action even if we have no idea who you are in the absence of a tool like that, you have to do a little more heavy lifting yourself, right?
You have to have you know, many opportunities for employees to share their feedback, directly with you as a manager.
You have to ask a lot of questions, right?
You have to get an in-depth understanding of what that employees experience.
Are there any like roadblocks for them are there do they feel good about their career path?
You know?
And these conversations are most likely happening between a manager and their employee and I think over time if you show them that when they share feedback even if it's constructive or negative feedback that they're not fired, but they're not demoted that they're not shut out of projects continuously just asking for it and showing that Want it and then having no repercussions or — you know retaliation or anything like that happen as a result that can very slowly build trust as well.
Because they will say okay, two weeks ago, I told my manager this thing, and they actually thanked me for my feedback, nothing bad has happened.
Since then, I think I can bring up another issue so it's about like building the trust via two-way communication to start to make employees fill.
More comfortable.
So let us say you're in a culture where That trust has not been built but as an employee I still need to voice certain things to my employer.
How would I even start that conversation?
Where it wouldn't get to like maybe subjective or emotional?
Like you have any Frameworks of recommendation of how an employee can even approach a manager with you know, the feedback I think it's really hard when there's not trusted.
I do.
I think, I think people are scared, you know, part of it is our jobs are not just like something we do for fun, right?
Our jobs are how we pay our bills.
It's how we take care of our families.
It's how we pay rent.
It's how we buy food.
And so when evaluating kind of like the cost benefit of bringing something up, that might be difficult in a context where you haven't built.
Us with someone and you don't feel trust in them.
It can just feel too risky and a lot of employees and up just staying quiet because they don't want to bring up something difficult with someone they don't trust in, you know, two months later, find themself fire.
So it's about you know, as an employee.
I don't want to give employees sort of like false confidence that no Matter.
What if you bring things up, it will all be, okay?
Like I don't think that's true.
Is that where we should be heading as a society, is that the kind of culture that?
I am sure everybody on this call wants to build at their companies, of course, but there's a gap between where we are today and where we want to be.
And so that's why I started all voices to bridge the gap.
But over time, what I would love to see is that there's a ton of opportunity for It healthy candid conversations within companies between managers and their direct reports between employees and HR between employees and the CEO and that it's in an environment free from retaliation.
That's where we want to be, but we're just not there yet.
Okay, I appreciate your honesty in that and, you know, we're hoping that everyone on this call here if your Eating an organization starts at the top.
So there're opportunities to start building trust today with your employees and creating a nurturing that kind of environment.
All right, we have got another question here that I think relates to what we were just talking about.
How do you communicate to your CEO that their behavior and reaction to things is making people leave It's really hard?
You know, in a situation like that, unless you have a really strong relationship with the CEO and you have built a lot of trust with them, you know, maybe you're their director Porter, you have known them for a long time.
It's really tricky to do.
I think some of that has to come anonymously?
Maybe your company has a 3D 360 feedback programs where people who report to someone get to also share?
Their feedback like as a performance review, that's like one opportunity potentially or it's through some type of anonymous Channel.
But you know, I have tried to build like incredibly transparent culture healthy candid, like we really walk.
The walk of what we're trying to do?
We use our own tool internally.
I also have like an open door policy, like put time on my calendar.
Come talk to me.
What's working?
What's not working?
I still No, it is really hard for people to speak up to me even about challenges, they're having with someone else at the company, let alone challenges, they're having with me, right?
My behavior.
I think that's just incredibly intimidating.
So I think CEOs need to be doing a better job of asking questions of getting to know people of building trust and Rapport of even saying like hey does everyone Here, feel comfortable sharing feedback directly with me and if not, like, what could I do to better?
Encourage that like, even one step removed from actually setting up a system where the feedback can be, shared is asking like, is there a feeling of safety of psychological safety, right?
Because I think this question really indicates, like the structural challenge that exist today, which is that, I as the CEO or any CEO, hot have more power in the organization than, like, a junior employee or someone who might have feedback for me.
And so, just by definition in that hierarchy, it is challenging for the person who's more Junior to give critical feedback to the person who's more senior.
So, we have to, And workarounds to that.
So at the very least, we have to figure out ways to provide Anonymous feedback.
Maybe that's the way.
Absolutely back to whoever Point person it is but figuring out just a way to get that information to them.
And actually, there's a related question here.
What are the words one would use to tell the owner CEO?
Hey, you are our biggest problem, the CEO is not going anywhere.
The owner, you know, So the choice becomes one of improvement versus losing the employee.
Yeah.
It's tough.
Just like we were just talking about.
Like, I don't recommend someone on this call, go to their CEO and say you're our biggest problem or I can't even think of a great phrasing that would make that message go over well.
But what I can say is that the CEO does need the information in order to improve sometimes.
It's just about self-awareness, we hopefully all like ourselves.
And sometimes we don't see the gaps in the areas of improvement that we have.
So, hopefully, the CEO is working on themselves.
Hopefully, the CEO has a coach or hopefully the CEO Is.
Talking to advisors, right talking to their board?
Getting that feedback from someone who is more of a peer and not someone who is Junior to them.
But ultimately, at the end of the day, the people who report to the CEO or the people who report to the CEO are the ones that have the best insight into how the CEOs, you know, style personality, whatever are impacting the business's ability to succeed and that's why Needs to be some type of anonymous channel, for this, exact type of situation because I think in some cases with awareness CEOs and leaders can improve.
So it doesn't have to be, you know, you can't speak up to the CEO.
So you just have to leave your job.
There has to be a third option, but they have to get the information first.
And if you give them the information through an anonymous Channel, and then they still don't improve.
Then it's a really tough situation then I would potentially start looking for a new job.
That's unfortunate.
It's real.
I think it's real for a lot of people I think working remote or distributed also makes it even more challenging to be able to communicate in general and then communicate such sensitive information back to a leader.
You know, as you were talking about power dynamics, and I am seeing Clarissa and Christina plus one that I am wondering if there's certain key leaders around?
On the CEO who and employee could feel safe to speak to and hopefully get a message relayed through you know the powers that be in the leadership team to the CEO.
What are your thoughts about that?
And, you know, I am really curious to hear a little bit more about the power Dynamic aspect as well around feedback.
I just think it's tough if you're trying to get a message to the CEO and you talk to someone whose close to them, there is the chance that it could backfire.
Right person is close to them.
It just depends on the CEOs personality.
It depends on the organizational culture, but just being really honest here.
Like, the person whose close to CEO could say, hey Gina like was speaking really badly about you and suddenly The CEOs.
Like this is a disloyal employee, they aren't on board with the mission.
They don't value me as a leader, whatever it is, they could misinterpret.
Like there's kind of game of telephone sometimes with things like that even if you were trying to be helpful which I am sure most people are but it can backfire.
So I just don't want to sort of sugarcoat, you know, I truly believe in feedback but I still don't think the systems that we have in place are set up to protect people enough that they can just freely share feedback with anyone at anytime and I don't want to encourage people to just go for it and then have it backfires.
Like, even on this call, I don't want someone to leader email me and be like, hey, I followed your advice about being really candid and I got fired because the reality is that can't happen.
Now, of course, we hope that never happens.
Of course, I think things are shifting to the point where organizations are more receptive to feedback, they do view feedback as a positive thing.
Even if it's technically — They know that they need to go above and beyond and to do more to help employees and to keep employees, it's still a really competitive job market.
So there is an interest in making sure that companies are doing everything possible to retain employees.
But I just wouldn't want that strategy to backfire on someone.
And I would feel bad if that happened.
So I really can't encourage that.
You obviously are the expert on your Company culture, the power dynamics, the relationships between people.
If you have someone that you really trust and feel safe with I would recommend having the conversation if you want to have it, but framing it less.
As the CEO is our problem and is causing all the problems to like, you know, I feel like a, you know, a more neutral way of phrasing it.
So, I feel like, you know, sometimes the blunt Is of the CEO is off-putting to employees or something like that and then maybe that feedback will get back to them in a constructive way.
But I can't, I can't say go for it.
Yep.
That's good.
And I think there's something to you know if an employee is still on board with the mission and believes in the team there, despite these things that they're experiencing from seat the CEO if they're able to Provide the feedback with the best intent, then wouldn't that get received hopefully better with the leader versus just like, you know, getting really hard and maybe there could be some bitterness and even resentment.
It's like behind some words, it's like be very selective of the words to make sure that you're always in the best interest of the company.
And then it's almost like the sandwich effect, right?
You give some of your best intentions and positive aspects, feedback of the company.
And then you question it with some of the constructive feedback.
You know.
That could be a way to provide that feedback directly to L.
Yeah.
We have a couple more questions.
Let us get bees.
Use question up there.
It'd be great to get your thoughts on how companies can ensure psychological safety while soliciting candid feedback from the org.
Yeah, so psychological safety is critical.
We talk about it all the time and all voices, one of our advisors is Amy Edmondson.
Who's a professor at Harvard Business School, and she's one of the foremost experts on psychological safety in the workplace and the way She defines psychological safety is the ability to fail or make mistakes without being punished and that can include the ability to speak up without being punished to.
Right?
It's not just failing, but it's doing something and not feeling like you're going to be punished for it.
So I think the best way to create it is to show it, right?
Not Tell people, so if I go to an all hands, and I am like, hey we have a psychological psychologically safe environment, if you fail, it's okay those are just words.
It doesn't really mean much to people to hear that.
At the end of the day, they have to see it.
I think in order to really internalize it and so what might be more effective for me as a leader or for a manager right on our team is to talk about the mistakes they have made talk about the places where they made the wrong decision, or they focused on the wrong.
Initiative or, you know, they shot for the stars, and they missed, but to use it as an opportunity to show people that, it's okay, I am still here.
We're still here, right?
The organization is still doing well.
We learned a ton from it, and here's what we learned.
And here's how we might do things differently in the future.
Because I think you want to encourage people to take risks at work, you want to encourage them to try new things and to learn as they go.
And I think the only way to do that, Is to show them that when they do it.
It's encouraged and that they aren't being punished for when things don't work out.
That's key.
That's really good.
That's a great.
Great definition of psychological safety.
We have got another question.
Okay.
Sorry, one, last thing I would add the same thing goes for feedback, so someone gives constructive feedback.
You say.
Thank you for the feedback.
Here's what I am To do as a result.
You know, they don't get fired, they don't get demoted, they don't get, shut out of things.
They don't get Scolded by someone right?
Then the next time they feel more comfortable giving feedback.
So that's kind of like the feedback version of psychological safety.
Mmm.
So good.
And I am seeing Clarissa and Bijou spots here.
Thank you for the FEMA.
Yes be the example show not tell and being vulnerable transparent As Leaders.
There's such power in that When leaders can actually let down their guard.
And constructively, you know, share that, and also a follow-up to what they're sharing.
All right?
We have got another question.
Our final question and just a few minutes left.
So if anyone else has questions, drop them right now.
How do we help staff?
And managers who have had negative experiences with feedback, you ready and open to feedback sessions.
Who?
Well, I think one question that I would ask that question is, what does it mean — experiences with feedback?
Right.
So I would really take a look at what's causing that person to feel like their experience was -.
So one thing that happened a lot when I was starting all voices, I would talk to people.
I would talk to HR leaders and lawyer Then sometimes most of the time they were like, this is a great idea.
I love the idea of you know, easily accessible Anonymous reporting and feedback for employees.
It's so needed some people were afraid.
They were afraid.
This was quoted to me many times of opening Pandora's Box because they thought if I let people share anonymously, I am going to get so much negative feedback that I am not even going to be able to handle it.
And then I went to all these people responses and it's going to be really stressful and What's really interesting is I almost never hear that feedback anymore from customers from people and talking to from experts.
I think one thing that's happened is that there has been a major shift over the last five years, in the value that we place on this type of feedback, getting to the people who need to hear it.
So it started with the me to movement, right?
It was like, all of a sudden, it was not an excuse, it was not a good excuse for a company leader to say, oh, I had no idea that was happening, right?
Ignorance was not an out.
People were being held accountable for the things that were happening in their companies.
Whether they knew about them or not, and the only difference is if you know about it, you can do something about it.
So I sometimes use the analogy or like the symbolism of like the ostrich with its head in the sand.
Like you can be the ostrich but you're also not going to know what's actually going on.
You're not going to be aware of reality and that's actually riskier.
Knowing, and so I think having some type of conversation with staff or managers, who are afraid because I would say it's less about having had negative experiences and probably more fear of what's going to come up.
And just tell them, at least if we know what people really feel, at least if we're aware of what's going on and what our employees reality is we can do something about it.
If we don't know, we can't do anything about it and that's a much worse position for us.
Us to be in.
Knowledge is power.
So good.
Wow, Claire, this has been a rich conversation.
I am curious to know.
So one, last question and maybe even point of advice that you would give to all of us here.
How should we, how should we show up?
What do you see for the future?
You know, what are things that we could be doing and implementing today?
In our circumstance, even if it's a mindset shift and you might have just been talking about that, you know what would you advise to us?
Because obviously, people who came here to this event, we care about providing good feedback and making sure that the loops are there.
What do you advise to us?
Yeah, I think.
I think, like I was just talking about, like, starting with this humility that, like, we don't know what, we don't know.
It sounds so obvious, but there's information out there that we aren't aware of that someone has not felt comfortable bringing up to us and I think about this every day as a leader, there's definitely stuffed that I don't know about my organization about my team about specific team members, right?
I just don't know.
So the More that I can show up to make people feel comfortable, giving me that information sharing that feedback doing it in real time.
Not doing it when it's already too late, and they have already left the organization.
The better and, you know, going back to the pool that was shared at the beginning.
What's really interesting from what I have seen anecdotally?
People are almost just as scared to share the positive feedback directly.
And if you open up an anonymous Channel, I think you'd be really surprised by the amount of positive feedback.
You will get two people who, for whatever reason, just don't feel safe sharing their opinion at all and the more that you can open up another.
Channel, the more you can say like okay I have the feedback that's coming to me directly, I have the feedback that is coming to me through these additional channels.
I really feel like I have a more comprehensive understanding of what's going on with my employees and as a result, I am going to be better able to take care of them to see around corners to anticipate their needs and ultimately to build a healthy culture that really is Logically safe, and inclusive and welcoming for all employees.
Thank you so much, Claire.
We receive that word.
And we thank you for your time.
We're going to have a post event recording sent to everyone who's registered.
So feel free to re-watch parts of this and you know you're here on welcome.
And this is an employee Gathering platform, and we can do webinars like this as well.
And For All Hands, sales kickoffs and all sorts of internal type of gatherings.
If you want to see more, check us out, there's a tab of, and then we got our next upcoming event already.
We got a great lineup actually this month every week.
We have got an event.
Oh, check this one out.
So this is our August 17th event with culture amp and oyster, and we're going to have a feng shui consultant from Marco experiences and also a real Ali, strong panel with some behavioral scientists from culture and speaking about leading with compassion.
So there's that and then just go to our website.
Check out our other events, we got another one next week on top predictions of remote distributed leadership for 2023.
And another one with torch on coaching and the power of relationships in the works workplace.
So we hope this was helpful and insightful for you all have a wonderful rest of your day.
Our next event, take care.