Hey friends.
Welcome, welcome.
Welcome and Bienvenidos.
It looks like you have representation from around the country, even around the world.
Joining us this event, we have a fantastic time and line up for you guys today.
So my name is Alberto Ortiz, and I am the CEO and founder of welcome.
Welcome to the platform that you're on here today.
So if you haven't already, please drop inside of chat where you're tuning in from, we love to see that.
We love to see that.
Presentation today, I am joining you from Boston.
I was born and raised on the east coast in Philadelphia, but I live in Puerto Rico.
And so in true remote fashion, we are dispersed around the country joining you guys for this, for this.
See that.
Now a few housekeeping rules before we dive into the meat of our program, you know, we're going to be having a good portion of our time with Q&A with Ariana and Joe here in a second.
And so as you Have questions come up.
There's a Q&A tab on the right-hand side.
Please go ahead and drop questions there throughout the conversation.
Will try to get to as many of those as possible.
Also, if you're navigating the platform and you want to learn a few other things, there's a help tab on the right-hand side and somebody can actually answer any live questions that you might have.
And so guys, I have we have been looking forward to this event for a long time.
The team has been working behind the scenes and pulling all the details together and so First of all, just want to give a thank you and a shout out to the team behind the scenes.
We have people in the green room right now, they have been working around the clock to bring this together for you guys.
Now, we're going to jump into some q and A's and the topics are going to be very relevant for the time that we have right now.
So why don't we go ahead and set the stage and set the table for the conversation?
So why are we here today?
You know, when you register for this event you probably register because Ariana and Joe are phenomenal leaders that you want to learn from.
And so we're going to get to that in a second.
But also you know, we're going to be discussing things that is really relevant to everyone.
That's on this event today and that's changing how we work.
And when you look at the landscape of where we are today, it's a very, very relevant content relevant.
Relevant content is being shared, across social media, news articles, every week, every two weeks you see different headlines being announced about the challenges of Shifting to remote.
The impact that has on employees, the impact that has on tension.
And so we want to bring leaders together to have this conversation of what's fueling, the change of work and how do we do it in a positive way?
What are the opportunities that also invites for us?
So we're going to be discussing the fundamental changes that we're seeing the Technology that are being shipped and develop to address the support this change and more importantly how to make sure we adapt well.
So we take care of our mental health, and we're not sacrificing it at the expense of the work that we're doing.
So talking about mental health.
Why don't we go ahead and pull up a pole on stage to just do a quick post check here?
We have a lot of people here, joining us, and we're going to talk about mental health and this is something that I have been working on, and I am just curious on how Often are you individually taken time on a mental health, practice to really fuel your well-being.
Is that daily?
Is it happening once a week?
Is it happening once a month?
Or is that honestly not happening often enough?
Because we don't want, we don't prioritize these things we're left out on the other side of it, fully burnt out and then it becomes a bigger problem, not just for our employers for ourselves but also for our family.
So it looks like we're we have a pretty good mix of folks here.
Here we have people that are doing something daily and I will be curious to learn what that is as we're in conversation.
If you want to share some tips and techniques, please drop that in chat.
Now, let us go ahead and dive into the core of our time together.
And quickly, I want to touch base on the speakers that we have, and I just get myself out the way again.
My name is Roberto, you can call me Rob.
And I am based in Puerto Rico, the co-founder and CEO of welcome and welcome is on a mission to gather Inspire and engage employees that are distributed.
We believe that the times when you bring your employees together, you have to make them count and you have to drive engagement and our technology is built just for that.
Now, we have two very special guests and these are friends.
And I have been building relationships with both Ariana and Joe over the last year or so phenomenal leaders on the Forefront of the topics that were discussing today started with Arianna, Huffington founder and CEO of Thrive, Huffington Post and off the roof.
If teen books.
In fact, you know what, I meant, Ariana few months ago, she carried a book with her.
We're talking about the importance of sleep, and she took a book out of her bag and gave it to me.
And I so have It's all my nice day and when I am trying to go to sleep, I am bussing that book open and reading a couple lines but it's 2016.
She also launched drive a leading Behavior change, technology company with the mission of changing how we work and how we live to put an end to the burnout epidemic.
So, we got the right person here to discuss, mental health and Burdock and then Joe, Joe Thomas is the founder and co-founder CEO of loom.
We just talk to Joe inside the Vroom of how much my team uses loom.
In fact, there's a leaderboard at my team of common.
Who's the leader at welcome using loom phenomenal product.
And so, he's on a mission to empower everyone to at work to communicate effectively regardless of where they're located, and we go to dive into that the importance of a sink and what that means in the future of work.
But not only is he leading a phenomenal company with phenomenal growth.
He also became recently a father to a beautiful baby girl.
I can attach to the title of founder and CEO comes way down the line, so the title of father.
So congratulations.
Joe, love to see it.
We're going to talk about that here in a second.
Why don't you guys put your hands together?
And so inside of chat for Arianna Huffington and Joe Thomas.
Hey sup.
Joe Ariana get to see you both.
Hello, Roberto.
This is the I love the name Roberto.
Don't you Joe?
Yes, it is rolls off the tongue, as I said, require some practice.
You guys, you guys get it, get it.
Get it done.
Well, good to see you both Jill.
You're joining us from Atlanta, right?
We're just talking, and Ariana, where's were you located today?
New York, okay?
My apartment in New York which is literally two minutes from our office.
Fantastic.
Well, first of all, thank you both for take your time.
I know that time is the most valuable thing that we all have.
And you guys are taking time to join this topic, this topic and conversation.
So, so thank you for that.
And I want to jump.
Yeah, you say quickly that all of us are thriving, passionate users.
Sirs of welcome and of loom.
So I am delighted to be with both of you.
You all are what I would say.
The bleeding edge, Ariana Ewing Thrive have built an Innovative Company products, and we love to hear it.
So, thank you for sharing that.
Yeah, and I think there's a I think it's something as it were pausing on and just talking about, you know, the importance of the work that you guys are doing.
I think that there is something to be said about building a company built for the future and where we're going right now.
And this is why I want to jump it to both sides of that conversation.
One is mental health and the importance of that and the reality of where we are today, but also the technology that we're building to equip a distributed Workforce, we can work more efficiently and this, You world, right?
And so, I want to jump right in, and I am going to kick off with Just Around burnout.
And I know that there's a quick poll and looks like we have an audience that's being very attentive to that and doing some daily practices and some folks are not doing enough and not taking care of their well-being with the rituals.
So, Ariana, you know, all of us feel the importance of burnout, we feel the weight of it as well, but it's not just us, the market is reacting to it.
The headlines are acted to it, you know, both on the employee side, but also leaders, you know, you shared an article.
I think it was last week that quote, 68 percent of employees and their leaders 81% of the c-suite says that improving their well-being is more important than advancing their careers, you know.
And, and to take that even further a few weeks before that you and your team got ahead of that as well and kicked off a mental health.
Pledge I got picked up.
The New York Times hundreds of companies have supported it and it's good to see this on both sides right initiatives to address it and the reality of what it actually is.
So I want to take some time and just set the stage on, you know, I have we have heard of burn out, you know, through the years but I have never felt a more tangible than it is today.
How do we get here?
How do we get here to this point where it's like top of mind for everybody, what are the drought driving Factor?
Hers that you guys are seeing that's leading to this big problem.
Well Roberta, first of all burnout has been with us for years.
I was personally diagnosed with burnout in 2007, two years into building that cause when I Collapse and built and broke my cheekbone and the diagnosis was burnout at that time, as you implied, most people were not aware of Burnout, but it's been existing for decades.
The silver lining of the pandemic is that now it fronts and center and it's not just front and center for the HR department.
But for the c-suite for boards, we have finally recognized that employee well-being and mental health are fundamentally connected to business metrics, attrition retention product.
Tivity health care costs.
So the reason why I am optimistic despite all the Dreadful numbers you cited is because finally we're acknowledging a problem, and we have a once-in-a-generation opportunity to fix it and the fact that the majorities of employees and the c-suite, executives think that their life is more important than their career, it makes me feel like saying dada Shouldn't have known that for a while.
We love our jobs and know the three of us really feel very blessed that we are doing jobs that we are passionate about but our jobs more important than Joe's little girl or your child or my children or the rest of our lives.
And for many, many years people acted, as though climbing the career ladder was more important than Anything, including their own health and withstand the skyrocketing increases in mental health problems, diabetes, obesity, Etc.
You know, Ariana.
I just want to follow up on that and like, 100%, I think that there was a point in time, when burnout working till 2:00 3:00 in the morning, was a sign of honor.
It was like, I work hard, I work hard at all expenses.
Like, especially when you work at a company that's growing and thriving and trying to run after the opportunity.
Many times it was like, honored, like this person is working hard and what I have realized as a leader with a family.
Now, and my priorities are changing is like that actually isn't worth at the expense of all these other things in my life.
What are you seeing that change happen?
Like within leaders today and realizing that.
Okay, this is a burnout, I Am shifting.
Is there a shift you feel to prioritize mental health versus just like reporting that it's an issue?
Absolutely.
There is a shift and the shift is actually based on a scientific Foundation, which is that actually, when we take time to recharge to refuel to renew ourselves, we are more effective at work.
So there is no trade-off which is what we believed for years and Elite.
Athletes are at the Forefront who have Tom Brady speak about how prioritizing his sleep and what he eats and his recovery time has had Made it possible for him to win Super Bowls in his 40s.
And so, the connection between well-being and performance is now clear.
We have really left behind, although we're still in a period of transition, the idea that downtime is a bug, and we realize that it may be a bag for software, but it's a feature for the human operating system.
No Doubt.
Appreciate that Joe.
I mean, your dad now and I know we opened up with that, and I remember, this is what podcast recently, by the way, with juban, which is a phenomenal podcast.
If you guys haven't seen a grit from kind of Perkins, and you mentioned, like the importance of taking PTO, especially even as a leader, even as a CTO and taken parental leave, what was that like for like beating up to taking that break with a debt due for you and sort of the inner workings of that at your company.
So first Want to say something back to Ariana really quickly, which is like the book you put out thrive in 2015.
I really do think as accelerated.
The common lexicon that we have to be more preventative and how we kind of approach things like burnout, right burnout wasn't really a word you were diagnosed with it in 2007, you're like, what is that whereas in 2015 or 2020 to it is actually a commonly understood term.
And so if you just even understand what the concept is, you can start to be more preventive with it.
And so, I think that's where it really does tie in well, with paternity leave because to me I was very nervous about taking extended time off.
It would be the first time and six and a half years that I took longer than a week, long vacation.
And ultimately, I came back on the other side of paternity leave feeling like I had recharged the tank in a way that I hadn't since the very beginning of Bloom.
And I have been a significantly better CEO, even with having a brand-new born.
With in my household day in and day out for the last three months.
Since then, like you would think that I would become a worse or less productive.
CEO knows like the opposite because not only was it.
I had the time off that allowed for me to recharge the batteries.
It's also allowed for me to kind of be what I would say in terms of being a father.
I talked about this concept of like Ambien anxiety.
Is like how am I spending my time outside of work?
And, you know, that you can't work 24/7.
So it's like, what are you for down, time to go like workout and exercise?
Do you sit down and have dinner with your spouse?
Do you end up doing the lazy thing, which is Doom scrolling on social media, like all of these sorts of things that you may spend your time?
Obviously, some of those are stacked ranked, very differently.
But any time that I spend with my family, while I do my wife and my daughter, there's none of that no anxiety, no guilt and so the recharge that I get since having a child and then being able to come back and show up at work, the like my battery is recharged.
Is better than it ever has been before at Loom.
And so taking time off, spending time with family, enables me to be a better CEO and I have 3 months of data now, so I will check back in a year to be like and it's still true but like as of today it is definitely true.
Fantastic.
You know, you know what's interesting.
Joe, I think you know, we always hear about Lee from the top.
So like what you sort of like, do you know, your employees follow as well?
And I think this is one of those things, right?
Like taking a month, off taken, three months off, whatever.
I mean, whatever.
That looks like it's important.
All right.
So as something balanced armatures on a Segway into that, right, like, let us talk about thriving at work.
And I think, you know, as Leaders, we all want each teammate, at our companies, to thrive, to be, well, to do the best work.
But saying in actually supporting it is two different things.
We can say that all we want.
And then on top of that, we're in a remote first world.
And this is brings a lot of change.
What does that look like?
How do we be more attention about supporting our employees?
For now, we may, we may never see in the office or it's going to be much more or less frequent than ever before.
This is these are the screens that we engage with them on.
Why have you seen work on like empowering employees, to take care of themselves?
Outside of just like, showing by example?
Ariana.
I think that first of all, what you said about all these new practices starting at the top is incredibly important because we are still in the middle of a cultural transition.
And so, a lot of people feel they need cultural permission to take care of themselves.
And when we launched with any company, we like to bring into a blood from stories from their leaders about how they are recharging, even small things that we just launched at Paramount and Bob Beckel, their CEO told the story at the fireside chat that we launched with of how he used to go straight to his phone.
And now he takes five minutes.
He lives by a He makes a cup of coffee.
Go sit on his porch said, saying that his intention for the day and remembers what he's grateful for and then goes through his phone now, that small and in fact, I drive, we talked, we talked about micro steps.
Small daily incremental, steps that become gradually healthier habits.
And that way, it's not overwhelming.
Me and that micro step of how you start your day and how you end your day?
By as Joe said, instead of Doom's crawling doing something that connects you with your family or recharges you before you go to sleep, are absolutely key micro steps.
Now Ariana like let us talk about how do you bring that into the workplace?
Because we talked about a lot of mental health, for you, the individual, and we talked about humanizing the workplace and what that looks like.
And I love to segue right into Thrive because you talked about bringing your personal self, your host self and sharing a glimpse of what really matters to you as an employee of a bigger company.
Why don't we can you?
Can you just T up?
What, what, what our Thrive resets?
And then got a little bit, surprised I have a reset Ricky said I have my reset and it'd be good to kind of give the audience a glimpse of what resets our go.
I would love for you to introduce it and talk about the science behind it.
So I thrive our Behavior change methodology is based on meeting employees, whatever they are on teams on slack, on welcome, whatever medium they're using.
We want to meet them.
They're both with this micro steps around, sleep Food Connection, Ian Focus, but also with the 62nd interventions that we call reset which are based on the Neuroscience that tells us that while stress is unavoidable, cumulative, stress is avoidable and it takes 60 seconds to move us from the sympathetic to the parasympathetic nervous system.
And therefore interrupt that cycle that, if it's not interrupted can To high blood pressure or binge drinking or binge eating to be able to wind down.
So my favorite feature in our platform as Roberto, you know, is reset because you bring together things that you love about your life.
And whenever you are stressed, you played.
Also, we believe that the we played at the beginning of meetings, to build social capital who literally spinning wheel and One of us plays there reset and it gives us a glimpse as we're going to see now into a colleagues life that helps us build the social capital that we lose when we are not all physically together.
Bumping into each.
Other asking each other more intimate questions about our lives are weak and Etc.
Fantastic.
I mean with that if we can roll the clip of Ariana's, and then we will switch over to my reset as well.
We just saw a little bit of a glimpse Ariana to your reset.
I love seeing that let us play minds, and then we will talk about it here in a second.
There it is, there it is.
Joe.
Yeah, I mean do we gonna have to get yours going next time and would love to see your family?
But Ariana that's I mean I just think about that was pooling photos last night together to kind of get the reset going.
But yeah, talk to us about that.
How has it been received who companies that you're working with your team?
What's what changes?
People love it and you know you can have multiple resets share them with colleagues and friends and you can build research for your children, your family.
It's a very simple way to start this journey of well-being or to add these well-being practice into your life.
You know, in the Paul people said that they have these little well-being Rituals once a day or once a week, or once a month, but you can have them once an hour and if you bring them into your workflow and interrupt the stress cycle, and it can be incredibly effective and Thrive we bring them into call centers.
We bring them into the lives of Frontline workers.
It's not just for people with desk jobs and the I can't play this resets on the phones and also everything comes pre-loaded with, with ready-made resets where thing over play one at the end that helps us take the breath.
Remember what we're grateful for etcetera?
Fantastic.
Now, I love it.
I mean I just saw Minds come together for today's event, and I am looking forward to it.
I just I want to keep it shortcut on my phone because you guys know things, get pretty tense at the top and it's good to Anchor back to what's important.
All right, so I want to jump into Switching gears here and Joe, you talk about something, which I think you wrote, You have right about this.
You talked about this and it's talking about the change of what's happening with remote and employees that are now distributed.
And the importance of us understanding that work is fundamentally changing.
You know, I think if you look at work being no longer a place you go to But it's something that you do now.
If we just anchor on that for a second, right?
Work is no longer a place.
You go to, but it's something that you do.
Historically, you would think generationally, you know, Dad goes to work.
Mom goes to work, like they're going to work.
Now you're literally, you are where you are and you do the work and the tip, the question becomes, how do we do that?
Well, you know, our friend Stewart Butterfield over a slack says we only have about 10% of the tools.
Needed to do this well and serve this shift in the market.
You would argue that slack all of us use slack and it's the thing that connects all of us but even the leader and the CEO of slack says, we're just scratching.
The surface is only 10% of the tools needed to do the job.
Well, and then as we talk about the headlines, you know, there's a headline every single week company is announcing their own remote.
Other companies saying, you have to show up or else, right?
And there's like that.
A war happening right now.
And some people think that hybrid might be the worst of Both Worlds.
And some people are like, no, like in offices where it's at, some people are very Progressive, and they're saying, we're going all in on remote where do you stand?
This is open.
Question for both of you.
Where do you stand, what's your thoughts on like hybrid and remote is remote more Equitable as hybrid?
What's your current take?
As I know you guys are on the front lines of that yourself.
So I will do a little preamble.
Room.
And one of our original thesis for building what we were building because I do think it's relevant just in terms of thematically what we're all navigating, which is when we built a synchronous video for the workplace, that was what we launched in June of 2016, right?
So this was three and a half years in advance of covid and everybody being shelter in place.
And really, truly understanding, what is feasible with remote work.
And so are, we always said that we're not necessarily a remote.
Only tool, although we are very valuable for those who are communicating in a remote context because we were growing really well.
And folks were using us, even if they were in office because you know, it's hybrid as a full spectrum, right?
It is you're a hybrid company.
If you have every single person in office, but one person decides to work from home for per day, or you are still a hybrid company.
If everybody is fully remote, but then we get to people who go into the office once or twice per week.
I like that.
That's still technically a Hybrid and so for us when we, when we were thinking about, what is this change, that we are all navigating in the first and second quarter of 2020, when we were all just thinking about, what does this mean for us as individuals?
What does it mean for our company's?
What does it mean for potentially the products that we're building in order to help facilitate distributed and remote teams in communicating with one another?
I kept reminding the company that this is a multi-decade change.
Like we're not going to Of the wand and figure this out.
Because when we go back into office, when we go back home, how often receive one another?
Like these are really big long scale and large experiments that were generally running right now and Humanity doesn't necessarily change overnight when we're talking about the global population and how they think about the intersection of work and life.
And so for us and Loom, the way that we personally think about it right now is we want to live the idealistic of version of this like we It to push for what is what we believe that Ideal World is where, like work is not what, like, where you are, it's what you do.
And so how do you end up enabling that?
It's that you enable individuals to have as much freedom and flexibility as possible because you actually fundamentally trust that individuals are going to adhere to whatever is best for them.
If that means going into the office, once a quarter, then and working at home for the rest of the time, like, I Mean please do that.
And how frequently do you want to get together with the broad company?
Or your department, or your team?
Like, we're all figuring that out right now, but ultimately what that is fundamentally rooted in.
If you treat the individual with trust then you can enable them with freedom and flexibility, and we will figure out how to do that over the course of time.
Now there is a whole host of hairy challenges that we gotta tackle over the next couple decades, like I was saying and Stewart Butterfield is also talking about the fact that like we are at 10% of the tooling that we potentially need to.
Be able to solve this, what we wanted to live, the ideal version and what we want to help pull that potential ideal future into the present as quickly as possible.
Fantastic well-well, put Ariana.
Okay, Ned one thing.
If it were not just a 10% of the technology we need, I think we are a 10% of the humanity because one of the things that we are realizing is that we are not going to be able to figure it all out and deal with his hairy challenges.
If we think everything is going to be solved by technology, I think technology can help us ironically Rico.
Act with a deeper part of ourselves as we are doing with reset.
So, you are doing with them, welcome platform or the loom platform.
But we need to reconnect to a deeper part of ourselves where we can find our creativity, our empathy, our peace, and strength, and resilience.
And if we don't do that, the future is going to be very difficult because we are living in extremely uncertain, and turbulent times, there is absolutely nothing.
Thing that assures us that's going to change.
So resilience is more important than ever but it's a human quality, and I am a big believer in technology, helping us get there.
But we need to realize that this human upscaling has to be part of the future.
I couldn't by the way, in terms of resiliency, I think that we all kind of like see and feel it right now where we just came out of a multi-year global pandemic.
And now we're about to go into potentially a multi-year global recession based off of like all leading indicators at this point.
So, when it comes to resiliency, like another, we feel like we just got sucked through something so big.
But on the other side of it, where, like, potentially facing another major change will impact our day-to-day.
Lives as well.
And so resiliency just wanted to like, triple emphasize with Arianna said is, I think it's so important.
No doubt.
And I think, you know, I think the conversation we're having here about work, but also the people side of it, just goes hand-in-hand, and I feel like over the last few years has become so much more important about employee well-being.
Like the person that you provide space to come to do the work, not just like the skills that they provide, but the individual and Joe, I think you put it really well.
Well, around optimizing for the person when you optimize for the employee, when you optimize for the person, if they want to come in once a quarter.
And that's the best thing for them than having to trust that, that's the best thing for them.
And the question is, how do you support that and make that habit?
You know, one of the biggest arguments that we see or might be, might be fading away now since data showing otherwise, that going remote, having folks choose nice, Lisa and If impact on connection and culture within a company, right?
That's one side of the argument is like, well, if I don't have, I built my coaching because there's a good micro kitchen because, you know, we got all these perks.
You can take the slide from the third floor.
Down to the first floor, you can take a cool bike from one office to another office when that goes away.
And this is the beauty of I think about like, the shift that's happening.
Because when that goes away, leaders and companies have to think very differently about what matters to the employee.
Lee.
And I think also, when you look at all these circumstances that were talking about pandemic War recession, if we're all honest, we have taken inventory of what's important for us in our lives.
And data is starting to show that as well.
What do you guys think it's possible?
You guys think it's possible for us as we're going more remote, more distributed to still build amazing, cultures, amazing companies and enable people feel connected.
Absolutely.
Yes.
I think Joe said it best that it's not really about where you work.
I think it's really how we show up at every moment in our lives.
How present are we?
How fully engaged?
Are we?
You know, in something you said, Roberto you have one of my favorite quotes by Maya Angelou, you should add it into your next reset.
The wisest thing you can do is be present in the present.
Gratefully.
That's a very different way of experiencing life.
Find work.
Then we have been used to, which is Being not at all.
In the present breathlessly you know living life as though we're always running out of time and that's been the experience that I grew up with.
You know, I am older than all of you but I don't think yours has been that different and now we are changing that.
So this is kind of incredible Catalyst.
You know how someone said that Christ is a terrible thing to waste.
So let us not waste this crisis and last, let us be incredibly optimistic about what we are building because who wants to go back to the past?
Fantastic.
And I was just going to say really quickly, that, you know, we're a lot of folks say that time is the most precious resource, which I agree, but I would like argue that we should extend it to.
It's more like attention and intention of where you end up, allocating your focus.
And so that whole being present in the present is such a gift that I think that in terms of building connection and community in a largely distributed world, I still think that were humans and biology.
Like, it takes a very long time for like biology to evolve and so there's a very real half-life that comes from getting a group of folks together.
Like, I was fortunate enough to get to spend time with Ariana at the loom off site a couple weeks ago, where we got everybody together for the first time in two and a half years and it was 30 minutes into the welcome kind of like happy hour horderves time that illuminates were just head over heels in terms of spending time with one another Either, but I think that what's really exciting about things like off sites when you're primarily distributed is that you have the intention of creating what I think is like, accelerates.
Building of relationships, which is unique shared experiences.
If you can have a unique shared experiences with another or group of other people, then you can build really accelerated connection and Community across a group.
So even if you only get together within your team or Department once every six months and then a company, once a year, the half-life of the value of that is so strong.
A digital actually can enable you to build connection and community in a way that I think that we're just scratching the surface onto its Shameless plug a sink video is an unbelievably powerful way to build connection and Community.
I could show you our Loom work space where somebody was sharing a video from Loom, a couple of years ago that now has gone viral.
In our workspace.
That a bunch of folks is watching where we make it a hot wing challenge together and like that is then getting a bunch of other illuminates to talk about.
They have done the hot wing challenge together and so all of this connection and Community is being built asynchronously.
So I think we're just scratching the surface there, but I really do think that intention around unique shared experiences, you're going to absolutely do both and digital and physical worlds.
No doubt, no doubt, loves this conversation.
I do want to shift over to the audience.
It looks like we have a lot of questions, queued up in the audience.
We're going to start shifting gears on that side.
And so, I think for the next few minutes, we're going to start taking some questions.
So why don't we go ahead and bring question up on stage?
I love to hear ideas on how we encourage employees to build and maintain those connections when several are remote or hype.
I think this goes back to, you know, like I don't see all my peers, I don't see all my colleagues all the time I used to bump into them, you know, at the micro kitchen and now people are distributed, or I am working from Boston and you know our team I have one of my leaders is in Hawaii.
Another one of my leaders was in Poland last week, I am in Boston.
Now what does that look like?
Are you guys seeing like effective ways of building that connection?
I mean Joe you talked about, you know, async videos and sort of The building connection, can we expand on that?
Because that feels like a good segue into this one.
Yeah, I mean I think that it starts from the very beginning of an employee life cycle where a very popular use cases that instead of somebody sending an introductory like two or three sentence note, somebody is that true required on day, one to record a loom introducing themselves, and we have lumet intros and so that sent a bunch of people leave reactions.
They're actually like know where that person lived over the course of time.
And like, do they have a dog or a cat like what's their General interests?
And so, watching a video of somebody walking through that with, like, Men passion about what they are, what are the things that they genuinely care about?
I think is super, super powerful, and then from there, if you kind of create the opportunity for people to bring their whole selves, to work and sharing things of interest to them, one of the things that Ariana really did want to, we have to follow through on a loom specifically, but one of the things that you shared when you're up on stage, is the fact that you ask employees what matters most to them and it was crazy when you were hiring a certain employee at I have where they had said that they weren't able to do that for six months and at Thrive you're like no, no, you're doing this like every week right in.
So like, understanding what is generally interesting to an individual is so important.
And so what we need to follow through on with loom is that I said at the off-site you need to pick one other person to be your accountability partner to make sure that you check in and making sure that individual is doing what they're supposed to be doing over the course of time.
Like, Josh when is an engineer at Loom, and he and I decided to partner up, and he said She wanted to spend time talking to every single one of his family members each week, because he feels like he's drifted apart over the last year.
And so like that, brings him a lot of energy and joy if he just gives them a call.
So this is one where I think that to me, I said that my practice was meditating for at least 15 minutes per day because it's my leading indicator behavior.
And it's obviously, you know what to do.
But do you do it in practice?
And so, if you understand what's really important at an individual level, than you can build deeper relationships with them, over the course of time, I am 100% I want to follow up on that because Ariana you told me the same thing and I can't shake it from my head.
It was I remember when we were having a conversation couple months ago, and we're talking about the importance of getting to know your employees and the first question you ask you flip it around and is not what can you do?
But what is most important for you in the season?
And we went off and talking about examples of that and let us say, for instance, you know, you have a mom who was a busy mom, and she's the most important.
In her life right now is her daughter's recital and the practice that happens for the next three months.
For that to happen, which means that I can't really attend, you know, Friday, 2:00 meetings.
And so now as a manager, I know that for Samantha, that is the most important thing that matters to her in the season.
So, I am not going to require.
I am not even going to book a time on a meeting, on the front, by the way.
Friday meeting shouldn't exist, but I am not going to book a meeting on a Friday afternoon for Samantha because I know that's the most important thing.
NG for her, but it seems like Joe's taken that advice as well, pretty tactically Ariana.
Can you expand on that a little bit more?
Yeah.
Actually it's going goes back to a Joe said about the need to be much more intentional in a hybrid world.
And for us, it starts with onboarding with all the companies who work with, whether they are Walmart or a small, high-growth startup onboarding is sacred.
Now.
It's the opportunity.
We have to embed the culture from day one.
So we interview the entry interview starts with his questionable.
If you both mention which is quite important to you, I don't work and how can afford so it can be What's important to me take my daughter to school every morning at 7 or to go to the my daughter's recital on Friday after whatever it is make it even larger.
You can actually And the way you interact with that employee, and if you also have an accountability buddy, then it makes it much more likely that you're going to achieve your goals.
And then you're going to be much happier at work and much less stressed about navigating this intersection between life and work.
And what we do on day, one is also helped each new employee create their own personalized reset And that way that's a tool that we have to play a team meeting to play individually by feeding it into slack or team, so or any method of communication.
And these are two of the small rituals, there are dozens of others that we can embed in the workflow to interrupt the stress cycle.
Fantastic know.
I think that's, that's a such a powerful question.
So, simple, Joe is such a simple question, right?
But when you like dissect, it was like this game-changing, like just starting with what's most important to that individual.
I want to segue into this next question which is a real good one.
Especially in the tension of remote and hybrid from Howard.
He says, curious as to how ad-hoc hallway and water cooler conversations can be recreated in this hybrid world and I remember My time at what time I Google I you know, how always goes our micro kitchen because it was a fantastic place to load up on snacks, but also make coffee or whatever it is and you do bump into people, right?
And you do get the sense of like Community because you see the folks that you're working with.
How are you guys handling that at your company's?
So this one I think is like, really challenging specifically because, yeah, in the sense that what are the very nuanced human engagements and interactions that happen in office.
That I think that like we were saying we're two years into a multi-decade change and so what problems are being solved today, it's the biggest ones that are lined to the most direct Roi for a business, right?
So like, can I communicate Directly uncritical work streams, can I actually drive a project forward?
But some things like, the Nuance interaction around water coolers or hallway, talk.
I think is one that will absolutely be solved.
I think that, you know, I could continue to talk about Loom but like I will talk about a few other ones where slack built something called the Huddle's, right?
So that makes it very easy to potentially like jump into a quick call.
There's other software's out there like team flow or tandem or uncheck gathered at Town.
Town that allows that tries to make it a little bit more 3D where you can walk around and be in an office setting to like run into folks throughout even if you're engaging in a digital space.
And, so I think that there's a long way to go to potentially solve on this front and that we don't necessarily have it today.
The way that Loom is doing it specifically is that we're asynchronous by Nature so folks can record and share a video, but then we built this concept of trending within a workspace.
And so depending on what Loom is getting Emoji, reacted With and comments, right?
And a lot of times the loons that Trend are not directly work-related their actual cultural related so illuminates decided to start doing plant tours around their home.
So they're like two or three minutes where they'd show off the plants at their home.
And now we have 40 plant tours across the loom workspace and a genuinely became the interesting thing about culture as like the remix component.
So at the beginning it was a full five-minute Plant tour by the Yen.
People were doing the fastest plant tours east of the Mississippi, and so they were like running.
Earning around their hive and like this plant, this plant.
And, so I think that to me, there're ways of you would an asynchronous way, but ultimately I think that those like creative Innovative bouncing conversations off of each other.
We still got a long way to go to solve that problem but I do see software's that are trying to tackle it, and they're really, really interesting.
So just a little bit more time.
Yeah.
No doubt, no doubt.
Joe I live.
I love the long term perspective to the problem that you're bringing here, I think it's really important to understand that we're just in the very beginning.
It's of his big Monumental shift in the way that we work and that is really important, right?
For all of us, not just as Leaders, but also employees in the workforce that we're adapting we have to change.
This is part of it.
Yeah.
The two things I would share is like give ourselves a Grace and feel like every idea doesn't work because that they're not going to work and it's like an experiment mindset, just be willing to try things.
I didn't like, don't get to turn by if it doesn't work because they are hard problems.
So like just keep that.
Experimentation mindset and keep testing things.
That's actually one of the paradoxes, we need a long-term mindset, we need Grace, but we also need a sense of urgency because the Mental Health crisis is real, and a lot of people are suffering, and so we need to address it.
That's why I am so grateful.
You both signed the mental health pledge which was basically put together by Thrive and Society of Human Resources management to protect their mental health advances that we have made in the last two years at a time.
When we know companies have to make tough decisions layoffs, hiring freezes and cats to protect cash.
Let us not cut on Mental Health offerings because that's been one of the advances of the last two years and it's Now, more important than ever because the Mental Health crisis is being described as the second pandemic.
I mean, with that, I think I want to bring that up, start kind of getting us to a close Ariana.
I mean, what you're bringing to the conversation is so timely, so meaningful.
So human is so anchoring as well, right?
It's like kind of shaking it off as I guess I have a meeting.
Yes, I have a to do.
Yes, I do.
I am always going to have a meeting.
I am always going to have a to do.
But that person that's waiting.
On the couch.
But I am choosing to Beyond another meeting.
Another call another slack.
Another document that person is waiting for me to go have dinner and that's more precious than anything else.
Right?
And I think that as we're in this shift Ariana, I think what you said is really, really important, we have Technologies, we can figure things out.
Technology will get better.
We will solve a lot of these issues, but I think us as humans adapting to this new change and us take an ownership as well of our mental.
Oh, health and us as employers taking ownership of it as well for our employees, is really where the magic is going to happen.
I want to before we close out with a reset and Ariana would love for you to kind of introduce a reset.
This is more like a collective reset.
And this is part of us is exiting from today with a little bit more peace with a little bit.
More being grounded before we go back to our families.
Am I do want to remind everybody that in a few weeks?
We're going to be hosting another event here on.
Welcome.
Even the conversation going on.
Changing how we work.
And just featuring, Tony Jamis is the co-founder and CEO of oyster, and Chris heard founder.
And CEO of First Base.
These guys are on the front end of remote, and building companies that support that and making that happen.
So please join us there, Ariana.
And Joe again, thank you for not just spending your time, but also the intention of your presence here with everyone on the, on the call and on the ENT Ariana reset.
We have a reset here for all of us to do.
Why don't you bring us home?
Will play the reset and I will see you guys in The Green Room.
Well, first of all, well Robert, I want to thank you so much for bringing us together.
This has been a wonderful event and I would go anywhere to be in conversation with Joe so that made it doubly wonderful.
And you said something beautiful about those a person waiting for us beyond the to-do list beyond the meeting.
I also want to remind us.
There is another person waiting for us and that somebody inside ourselves and sometimes we forget that and you know thick not hand, the Buddhist monk said something beautiful.
He said it's never been easier to run away from ourselves.
There are so many distractions.
It's so difficult to find even 60 seconds to be with ourselves.
So that's another function of reset that we are going to play now and there are hundreds of them on the Thrive platform.
Take this moment to really just stay fully present gratefully, as Maya Angelou said, with ourselves and reconnect with ourselves, which makes it much easier to reconnect with anyone else.
Thank you, everyone.
Thank you.
Breathing.
Breathe out.
Time moves quickly, especially when we are so busy.
But At this moment let us pause and take it slow.
Bring your attention to the rising and falling of your breath.
Appreciate the slowness.
Notice how your body feels when you allow yourself.
This moment of calm and quiet.
Throughout your Day.
Let Yourself observe the world around you.
And remember that each moment is a gift.
Breathe in.
Breathe out.