Aloha, how are you?
So great to have you all here?
I see you tuning in from all over the country and even across the globe here from Puerto Rico, New Jersey, Seattle for a lottery, Danielle Valerie from Texas and YC, Vancouver Detroit Baltimore.
Hello Kelly Moore from SoCal and Dana Schultz and Ontario Canada.
Thank you for joining us today.
I am Gina Marketing a welcome hope you enjoyed those jams as you were coming in to this event.
I am so excited about this panel.
We got a two-part event today.
It's part panel.
We're going to be talking about how you can lead distributed teams with compassion with empathy and some very tactical ways in doing that.
And then the second part of our event will be drumroll for real.
Real a feng shui virtual feng shui event, so we have got Suman from Marco experiences.
Marina who is also in the green room I see you all and Rob Kim and Bobby here to be able to be part of this event.
I have also we who is our event producer, so she's the one that's hitting the ones that too.
So I always like to give kudos to our producer.
So with that note, that there is A Q&A Tab, and at any given time, feel free to drop in your questions and upvote any of the questions that you are most interested in hearing answered.
All right?
So jumping into our panel topic today, you know, as we all are feeling this, you know, we're dealing with remote work.
And on one side, there's an amazing upside of the quality of life, but there's also the challenge, Challenge of eroded boundaries between work and personal life.
And, you know, there's this need right now, the craving that employees have what whether your remote weather, your hybrid, whatever your situation is that you're working.
The common denominator is that employees are seeking that support and that connection that value, like I value you.
And I value that you're here part of our organization at as you're navigating these Teas with a distributed workplace.
There's some key ways in which we as leaders and managers and even individual contributors can show up and support one another.
You know, there's this statistic here that shows employees who work for compassionate manager.
Their 25% more engaged in their jobs.
20% of them are more committed to the organization and 11% are less likely to burn.
Burnout Katie's going to drop in chat the research there so you can double-click into that a little bit more.
But you know the research shows it rights there that compassionate managers and leaders do make a big difference.
So with that I would love to introduce our panel today.
We have got Kim who is the head of employee experience with oyster Bobby, the regional director of people.
Science with culture, amp and Roberto are co-founder and CEO of welcome.
Please join me on stage.
Hello.
Hello?
How's it go?
Alright so hello Kim.
Hello Bobby.
I don't see it Roberto but I know there were some challenges he was having with his video but it's all good.
Kim.
Let us know what boy stur is about and what do you get to do every day with them?
Well, hello.
Nice to be here to see you all.
I am with a company called oyster.
We are Employment platform that helps companies to hire people anywhere in the world.
So that you are not a cure not limited to the talent pool, that happens to be within a geographic radius of your office.
Or if you don't have enough, it's like oyster, you can hire anyone anywhere in the world without the legal administrative, HR headache.
That comes with anyone on this call who is part of an HRT, more people obscene those that it's very complicated to hire people outside of your, your space oyster is over 600 employees now, and we're going Now, over 70 countries.
So we are an extremely globally, distributed team, and I get to spend my days building and trying to make sure that we have a consistent employee experience.
No matter where you are in the world, no matter whether you have overlapping time zones with anyone else on your team, trying to ensure that everyone feels a sense of inclusion on belonging and has a really seamless and great experience being a part of the oyster team.
And I am calling in from my home office.
Which is About one square meter of the corner of my living room.
So, welcome to my, welcome to my home.
Thanks for letting us in love it.
Bobby, how about you?
Tell us a little bit about culture.
Ab and what you get to do with them?
Yeah, thank you first.
Thank you for your enthusiasm and your excitement.
You're getting a lot of love around your energy in the chat there and also Kim, a lot of love for oyster to.
So, It's great to see as it was mentioned.
My name is Bobby Malloy.
My role at culture amp is as Regional director of people science.
As Kim was saying, she helps cultivate an employee experience, and we are an employee experience platform that helps users.
Like Kim cultivate that experience in your organization.
So, we are a software platform sort of end to end in terms of experience.
So from candidate and onboarding through engagement and performance.
And development all the way through exit and alumni.
We have you covered there and so in our role in people science we are a group of people with backgrounds and Industrial organizational psychology and organizational development.
And we help you design tools in our platform in service of cultivating, your experience strategy.
So whether that looks like actually designing those tools or helping you interpret, some of the data that you get back, when you send out employee surveys, or you go oh, through a performance management process or you have a development cycle for your employees, were there with you, to help you kind of craft that strategy and then ultimately take action.
So ultimately, it's all in the service of improving the workplace.
Happy to be here.
Love it.
Well, we're glad you're here.
So, you know, we're talking about this research that I just pulled up on how employees who work for compassionate, managers are likely to be more engaged.
They are more committed to an org, they're less likely to burn out.
Now each of you are seeing the data or creating the experience to further encourage this.
Now there's a lot of going on right now in the world, you know, you go on LinkedIn.
There's a new Said that just got laid off and you're just like, ah, gosh.
This is a very unstable uncomfortable time.
And so how do you create engagement and motivation within a workplace particularly, if recently, somebody's gone through substantial layoffs, how can we do that as Leaders managers?
I have you to start work about, we both like jumped in at the same time I will give it a start on a pass it on to you.
I think the thing to remember about all of this as is that as much as we desperately need data and metrics and thus like people science that we're all here, we're all so culture, a I am a decade-long culture, a superfan, if we need, all of that data to help build the business case, Says, I am and build and an objective viewpoint on overall holistic Trends, but at the core of it, we're dealing with people, we're dealing with humans.
And so taking this human Centric approach to realizing that everyone has stuff going on in their lives.
Everyone has a life outside of work and that's something that and depend on McCrea, Lee brought to light in a way that maybe people were able to hide or create a line between their home lives and their work lives pre-pandemic in a way that we just haven't been able too lately.
And so creating that level of Engagement is it's not about saying, well what do we need to do to increase our engagement score?
It's what do we need to do to support the whole human that showing up to work whether that's showing up in a co-working space, showing up in a physical office showing up on a call with their toddler hanging off of them because their school had a closure like these things.
All Impact how we can show up at work and how we show up at work is how we experience our engagement Network.
If people feel supported, and they feel heard, and they feel like their full life experience, Eiffel lived experience can be represented in their workplace then that will translate into higher level of Engagement.
I would say the example that you use of the outset was around layoffs and ultimately that's under the umbrella of something that we might consider to be a hard time.
There're a layoffs there's the pandemic.
There's Any number of examples that you could use but ultimately it is an example of change.
And so when you're thinking about, how do we either lean in or lean out, think about the fact that whenever there is change, you should be leaning into helping to make sure that change goes smoothly.
Now, you do that with number one, like open acknowledgement, so don't put your head in the sand and acknowledge when there is a layoff acknowledge when there are hard times going on in the world around us and With creating the space, to give people the grace to express how those challenges might be affecting them but then also solicit feedback from your employees.
So, get a sense for what's going, well during this change, what's not going.
So well during this change so that you can focus your efforts on improving, the things that are not going.
Well, I would say in terms of layoffs, think about it from three levels.
Think about it from the organization level acknowledge you know you can Get feedback in aggregate across the organization, but it's probably a little bit demoralizing to communicate, a layoff to your employees and for your employees to hear that about their organization.
And so you need to understand how they're feeling in order to tailor your Communications in ways that are going to get them remote abated and re-engaged.
For managers, you know, really help employees understand why these decisions were made and how these decisions were made giving.
See to the process.
Can help people really feel like there was fairness and equity in the decisions that were made so that they remain motivated to continue working for you and then employees, you know, you might have something like survivor's guilt, which tends to be pretty common as a result of layoffs.
And so if that's the case, acknowledge that to your mentor, to your manager, but also really acknowledge when you're overwhelmed or overworked because speaking up is what's going to get you, the That you need so that you're not oppressed by, you know, the lean way of working now that other people have been laid off.
And I would just like to add one thing to that, which is this idea of acknowledging, the pain, the pain of it.
And acknowledging, the hook, the difficulty of it, I am not saying that you should say post a selfie crying about how hard it was for you, to lay off your staff.
But acknowledging, especially for the people who are still there that like this is hard, this is a hard thing for us to go through as a business.
It's a hard thing for us to lose people who we love working with.
This is the Why we had to make this decision and how we made this decision, and we just want to acknowledge that it's painful and it's difficult for all of us, and we want to move through this together, but we're not going to jump straight to action.
We're not going to jump straight past your grief for your struggle or challenges.
Here's the safe way that we can talk about this.
Here's might think about providing counseling services or reminding people about the Mental Health Resources, you have available, you can't just gloss over You see that a lot from leaders during layoffs, if they want to jump straight to but it's all going to be okay because here's our strong team that we're left with and that doesn't acknowledge the emotional experience.
That people are having as they're going through it.
Wow.
That's totally.
Right.
Right on a very human in approach.
How do you see that actually happening?
As far as the communication touchpoints?
Like, there's the company level, there's the one-on-ones, there's the team seeing Inks.
And there's may be other types of gatherings in between.
So how do you, you know, in change management and these transitions?
Like how, how do you communicate with transparency yet also have compassion?
And what does that look like cascaded?
You want to take it?
I was going to let you speak first this time.
Okay, great.
So there's a couple different angles that you could take especially with communication and some of which might not be obvious.
So with strict communication, yes of course, leaders top-down, org-wide Communications, that's important.
What I tend to see across organizational data over, let us say the past like eight months or so.
Communication is become one of the number-one drivers of Employee Engagement.
And part of the reason is that people are using Communications, to understand what the future is for the organization, both in the near term and then over the long term, they want to know, coming out of a covid era.
What's our plan, what's our vision and our mission and has that changed from before covid and or from, when I signed on for the organization, And with Communications and for organizations that have seen declines, they have audited their Communications, and they have realized that they have over index toward financial and other types of metrics.
And in those Communications they have really tried their thinking was, let us communicate how our profits are the highest.
You know, that they have been in five years or, you know, all of these great numbers, but they have not Incorporated.
It sort of humanistic perspective to those Communications.
So people are not necessarily seeing themselves represented in the success of the organization.
And there is a little bit of a lack of acknowledgements.
For those organizations that the burdens that have been placed upon people through the covid era.
Now, coming out of it, that the employees have carried in order to make those metrics as good as they are.
And so, the I think the misalignment and perception is that, hey, we're doing this really great thing by showing all these great numbers, but we're not actually acknowledging that it was sacrificed that helped contribute to those numbers.
And so injecting those Communications with a more humanistic perspective, is, is one action?
And the other is a little bit of a signal, not necessarily an overt communication, but even in your performance management process, if you have a self-reflective opportunity for employees, To sort of reflect on their experience over the past.
Let us say six months.
Having within that, a question about what are some challenges or blockers?
That you faced either in work or out of work?
That might have affected your job performance, allowing the Unseen especially in our remote work World, allowing the Unseen or the unheard to have a place for a manager, or a mentor to acknowledge that in a performance.
Evaluation can be really powerful and I meant that is a signal, it's not an overt communication but it is a signal that the organization cares about, you know, how the world or how those contextual factors are affecting you.
Absolutely.
And I think there's a piece of communication to think about, which is that At the end of the day humans are inherently selfish, right?
It's a survival mechanism.
Have to think about ourselves.
So any communication to make, think about how the person reading it is.
Going to look at that and say, okay, but what about me?
How does that impact me?
How does that affect my job?
How does that impact my career growth has that picked impacts my work?
If you talk about a shift in the product roadmap whoever's working on that project or adjacent projects are going to think.
What does that mean about my products?
That mean about the thing that I work on your talent?
Doesn't even wonder does that mean we have to hire different?
People your sales team is going to think it's that completely change our sales cycle so thinking about how everything you communicate is going to be interpreted at least you know not by every single one of your employees that would be a very big task but think about the kind of different personas within your company.
And how is this communication going to impact?
The person who is a live-in, caregiver for their elderly parent?
And how is it going to impact those employee?
Who is about to go on, Parental leave?
And how's it going to impact this employee?
Who just joined the sales team?
On the team that is now being restructured.
Or, and like, thinking about, who is this going to impact the most?
But then also people who are not directly involved with it, how might they interpret this communication?
And how can I touch on as many levels of inclusion as possible?
That's really great.
I am seeing the question start to pop up, and we have got about 10 minutes till we have to transition over to the part two of today's event.
So let us pull up marinas.
Question servers question on to Stage here, Katie, okay, is compassion a learnable trait.
If so, how do you prepare, new leaders or Future Leaders?
To be compassionate.
And I guess I have a question right above this.
It's like, how do you define compassion is Different from empathy.
And then you can answer this one as well.
That is a good question.
I don't, I am not a psych.
I was not a psych major, I was a theater major.
So in terms of defining compassion versus empathy, and we're like, where's the Venn diagram of intersection and the terminology?
I don't know.
But I think it all relates back to this idea of EQ or being able to put yourself in someone else's shoes.
Think that is empathy that is compassionate is looking at someone else.
And thinking about their experience, sometimes above your own, but sometimes in addition to your own looking at how is this person going to be impacted by what I say and do.
And that is coachable.
That is learnable.
I think there are people who are inherently who have more of that in them inherently based on how they were raised or their brain chemistry, or whatever it is.
But there are definitely people who see that as something that's like this is a skill, I need to learn and it's a foreign concept to me.
Not because I don't believe in Fashion, but because emotional breath is not part of my natural skill.
Set, depending on if you're looking at companies and neuro diversity, as a part of your, your inclusion thinking about, how can you include people who have varying levels of neuro diversity, that don't allow them to inherently connect with the emotions, the emotional response and you know, it's not just a neuro diversity.
Also, as to how you were raised paying it?
So what kind of experience you had in previous companies?
It's what you are allowed to be and how you're allowed to show up in a previous workplace.
There are people who believe compassion and empathy are just completely separate from your work life and that's something you might have in your personal life, but it worked.
It's like all business and so really defining what that means at your company.
What does it mean to be a compassionate leader?
What does it mean to be human Centric?
What does it mean to be empathetic, whatever language you used to define that part of your Culture?
Anyone, regardless of their, their personal proclivity is towards empathy and compassion can learn how to participate in your culture because you have defined it really clearly.
As we want to be, we talk about it.
Always starts being human Centric, but it's not enough to say we're human Centric company of say this is what it means to be human Centric at or Easter.
So whether you live your life in a way where you would describe yourself as being human Centric, you know what the expectations are here, and that's what you Teach people, you might not be able to teach them like how to be a compassionate person 24/7 in their lives, but you can tell them how to show up compassionately at work and teach them what that looks like.
Well said, Bobby, did you have anything to add to that?
I do think it was well said we typically consider we sort of my background is in sync in Psychology and emotions, and we consider compassion to be an emotional response.
Whereas empathy is the feeling of another's, kind of emotions.
When we have empathy, we can then have compassion and so compassion is an emotional response with a desire to help.
And, so I think It was well said that we might not necessarily be able to teach people how to have an emotional response, but we can in train within them the behaviors.
And also at an organizational level policy wide set, the expectation that people should be behaving in a way that demonstrates compassion doesn't necessarily mean, they have to know what it is to behave in that way.
But when this happens you As a mentored respond in this way, you send them to this person or you provide them this resource or you work with them to overcome their goal or to overcome the challenge to their goal.
There are all kinds of like work-related within the scope of control of the organization behaviors that we can do that are compassionate.
Even if you know we don't necessarily have to get to the point where we're just having an emotional skill.
Training.
That notwithstanding is also something new A do.
But yeah, I think focusing on the behaviors is right.
We have got another question.
That's getting a vote voted right now, more and more.
I see companies measuring commitment, instead of Engagement curious, as to your thoughts on this alternative approach.
Would you mind if I jump in here first?
So that's a great question and actually, so I culture amp our engagement index the way that we measure engagement includes commitment as one of three components.
So we measure engagement with five items two of which are around commitment.
Now, that's important because in this, in this conceptualization, which is consistent, with all of the research and scientific literature on engagement.
Commitment is one part of what it means for an employee to be engaged.
They cannot be fully engaged unless they're committed.
But there are also other things that indicate an employee is engaged.
And commitment is necessary, but not completely sufficient.
And so if you think about just measuring commitment, there are a hosts of reasons why someone might be committed Beyond Simple Beyond them.
We enjoy their job.
I might be committed here because I have nowhere else to go.
We saw this pretty strongly at the beginning of the covid.
Pandemic commitment increased because other organizations were laying people off or downsizing and people became they sheltered in place was I think the popular phrasing at that point.
And so there are all these external factors, and they're all these sort of contaminating factors that might contribute to why someone has committed.
But it doesn't necessarily mean that they actually want to do a good job for you.
So we continue to measure engagement because it considers commitment along with the emotional, Affinity or investment that people have for your company, or your organization are they proud to work there, are they motivated to go above and beyond and to the extent that they're engaged, they would tend to do.
So, would they recommend you as a great place to work?
Those are the kinds of things that would indicate that someone is committed to you.
They want to be with you for the long term.
And while they're there, they will want to do good work.
Those three questions I think are really key which would you mind it?
Would it be okay if you drop that in chat for us because those are very clear questions that we could be asking or you know serving out to gauge that commitment.
All right.
Thank you, Bobbi.
We actually have a couple minutes left, and so I do want to get through at least another question here.
Let us go with the anonymous question.
I have read that engagement.
Is the bare minimum.
You should expect from your employees.
Disengaged employees equals reduced ARR with this in mind.
What are some benchmarks for an Engaged Workforce?
I am not, I am not exactly sure.
What we talked about engagement is the bare minimum, you should expect from your employees, and not sure exactly what that is, referring to, maybe Bobby if you want to take this and it's benchmarks for an Engaged Workforce.
We look at things like our culture and thank you, Sherman scores, across a bunch of different categories.
In addition to the primary engagement score as well as things like attrition and retention and There's a lot of factors that we look at around our Workforce but in terms of Engagement specifically, yeah.
Three seconds.
I don't have a great answer for the beginning part around engagement, as being the bare minimum, you should expect from your employees.
When I think, Potentially, I mean, so if you think about what we used to measure engagement, it's whether your employees are proud to work there, they would recommend you, they're committed to you, I almost would reverse it and say, I think engagement is the bare minimum.
You should expect from your employer that they should be engaging.
You it's at least insofar as you believe that having an Engaged Workforce as a competitive Advantage.
So if you want to be an employee or employer of choice, we go through this work because in we want to act upon aspects of our culture and Experience that drive that in emotional investment, that commitment from your employees, to get all the downstream benefits that we know the increased AR are the reduced turnover, the higher job, performance and productivity.
Thank you.
All right, I am going to squeeze in one question because this one's a good one, but keep it as fast as you can Kim and Bobby its release a hunter with a fully remote team.
How do you cultivate team culture and facilitate staff?
Getting to know each other outside of work focused meetings What does be a short answer?
I think you have to recognize that the team culture is going to happen whether you're paying attention to it or not and that everything you do cultivates, your team culture.
So, it's how you run your meetings is how you assign work, it's how you promote, its how you terminate.
It's like that is all culture is not just Gathering Together outside of work focused in meetings.
So your team culture is part of your work, Focus meetings as well.
You can't separate the two.
I think that's first thing that people.
Tends to where they pretend to kind of separate.
But in terms of people getting to know each other outside of work, Focus meetings, I think well one of the things we do is Affinity groups on slack and those groups we have a pets group and a parent's group and a we just have we have a new channel called social yell where the Only Rule that you have to type in all caps and it's great for just like shouting because we don't really encourage shouting in all caps in the rest of our Slack.
But creating slack channels and creating opportunities for people to find their people, whether those people are near them or not, and then building in and a suggested mechanisms and letting people take it their way, we suggested something called Loom pen, pals.
It's like you can connect with somebody on the other side of the world and you just send Loom videos back and forth to each other like Uncle pen pals, I am doing things like doughnut, social check, Enzyme just like brand name-dropping now, but people are the other thing to realize is the last thing I will say, is that people are going to experience the social side of Team culture, which I think is what you're talking about here.
Lisa, they're going to want to experience that in different ways depending on how they like to show up at work.
How introverted or extroverted?
They are how passionate they are about their Hobbies, how much time they have to devote to kind of social things, outside of the regular work day.
And so not Adding any sort of expectation that every single employee must engage with X number of social chats, otherwise our team culture, sex and kind of removing those expectations and realizing that for some people.
They feel totally.
I am one of these people feeling totally Satisfied by the five minutes of social engagement.
We do at the beginning of our team meetings, where we do a 5-minute social kind of check in with each other.
At the beginning of our meetings, my brain is so busy with two little kids and full-time job and everything else going on in my life.
I feel like I don't at this stage in my life and career, maybe it will be different six months from now.
Like I don't personally feel the need to create extra social opportunities in my workday or outside of my working hours.
Forget about it.
I am like in full-time kid mode but I have like where I am in my life.
I have this kind of cultivation outside of work largely.
So I find ways to do it within my work.
Other people on our team are really looking for that, social connection and are very active.
In our pets channels and are meeting up when Traveling to take their pets on walks with other co-workers.
And so just, you really have to be flexible and inclusive of a lot of different styles of socializing.
Love it.
Not a short answer.
Thank you, Bobby.
I agree.
I won't belabor the point by going too much more in-depth but I do think that changing the nature of what that looks like.
Depending on understanding that you have different audiences and abilities to be engaged with some of those outside of work meeting.
Social engagements is one of the best things that you can do to get more people involved in outside of work, meeting social engagements.
So, at the beginning of covid, you know, that the virtual happy hours or something with All the Rage.
But recognizing the fact that people who are at home, caregivers, working all day, trying to juggle both things, don't also have the, you know, the next hour or two after to spend, you know, doing a happy hour but recognizing that sometimes in those instances, when those informal connections are made and so standardizing, I think is a great idea, the fact that you're asking the question means that you're hoping to Sigh what that virtual culture looks like and standardizing it ensures that it's not left up to those like really informal, you know, informal Gatherings that some people can and can't make more consistently than others.
For we're actually a lot of like the to take an extreme example where like you know, performance evaluations happen or promotions or made, you know when people are just find that they like each other because they shared a beer together means that I am going to Put you up for that promotion, or I am going to tell you about a career opportunity.
I just saw in a different slack Channel but then not communicate that out more structured or more standardized in a one-on-one or a team meeting.
That's great.
Wow, thank you.
There's so many notes.
The recording of This will be shared to everybody, so we're probably going to rewind this and watch some of these Key Parts.
But Kim Bobby.
Thank you so much for sharing your insights with us, your presence alone, just radiates sunshine, and it radiates so much love.
So I am grateful for it.
And I feel that our attendees here today are also grateful.
So, thank you so much.
And with that corn Transition into our feng shui experience.
So I would like to introduce Suman who is the CEO and co-founder of Marco experiences to the stage and tell us a little bit about Marco.
And you know what, we're going to go into today.
Well, I think it's pretty timely with Lisa's question just now actually.
And their recent discussion which is an amazing discussion.
So appreciate you facilitating that.
Yeah, so I am assuming I am the CEO and co-founder of Marco.
The problem we're solving is, it was just discussed, which is that the way we work and live, his kind of fundamentally changed, and while we have more flexibility, there's Now new challenges, which is how do I attract and retain the best talent.
How do I create?
Obviously culture is very complicated, but perhaps some of that, social fabric, fabric, around culture, and connection, and that's kind of the problem, we're solving.
So we do that through experiences virtual in-person multi-layered.
It's, and then we help proactively kind of plan that partner with companies for that.
We have our product that helps manage kind of employee sentiment and also understanding the ROI of your investment in kind of Employee Engagement or a portion of Employee Engagement.
And so we have our amazing host for the Fung shui experience, but that's kind of what we're solving.
Appreciate you guys having us and feel free to reach out.
If you have questions around how to build kind of employee experience and that connectivity in a proactive, it kind of structured way, we have a Marketplace that you can kind of Used to book events, but we also have what we call Mark of memberships which is a more kind of embedded offering where we partner with amazing companies.
They're trying to solve this pretty complicated problem here but appreciate you having us.
And with that the main event which is Marina and this beautiful fun, shui experience that were in great.
Spirits are going to embark on awesome, thanks Suman, Marina, you look forward to learning from you.
Hello everyone, welcome to my office.
I am so delighted to see you all here today.
Thank you so much for joining us.
I wanted to ask you all before.
I tell you all about the wonderful world of funk shui, how many of you have heard of Fung shui?
Right?
How many of you and just put it in the chat?
Tell me.
Yes or now if you have heard a function way.
I love that.
So Shelly saying yes Danielle.
Yeah, so many people have, and I am So Lisa.
Yes Mindy.
Okay, perfect.
So I will tell those of you who might not be familiar with it a little bit about what it is.
But I am also going to tell you how I got into function y right, didn't just wake up one day and say, hmm shui.
What I did was it's a little bit.
Long story but it makes sense.
So I worked in the New York City Art world for many years, and I started my own company that helps artists navigate the art world.
And when I started this company, I ended up working out of my kitchen.
I was in this tiny, New York City apartment, and we had a little Nook in the kitchen where I could work.
And here's a picture of the meat in the kitchen.
You see the room divider behind me?
Behind that is like the stove.
It was a true, you know, from the ground up in the kitchen moment.
And when I did this, I Googled Fung shui, I wanted to have everything set up as nicely as possible, and once I really do deep into it, and set it up in a way where I was really activating as much good energy.
Fung shui as possible, my business went full time, I got featured in major Publications and since then, I have been helping so many people work with the principles of feng shui to help them, take their business to the next level.
And while this may not be fully, you know, conventional here in places like Asia, there are major corporations that higher Hire Consultants to double-check and actually guide them on the layout of their offices on the layout, for their Executives and their homes and everything.
So, I wanted to ask you right now, if you could put in the chat, where are you guys working from right now?
And as you could see right, as you could see, I am Not in my kitchen office anymore because the business worked and now I have a beautiful, big office and my desk is on the other side of the room.
Okay.
So we have Tara says, she's working from the kitchen table been there, done that Jenna says, in my or Gina, sorry, my home office.
Katie says my kitchen.
Let us see one too, many dogs and husbands and here too.
You know, dogs are actually wonderful for Feng shui because they hang out where the energy is good.
So if you have got dogs hanging out near you this is a good thing.
So we have someone working in their corporate office, which is wonderful.
So if you say the office in San Francisco right by the bay gorgeous, I bet it's beautiful and Kenny says my office.
Chair has a loose screw.
So I have been a victim to a living room and dining room table.
Okay.
All right.
So we have some off.
Says, in some sort of unconventional work from home situations, like Emily.
She's sharing an office / bedroom with her work from home co-workers, who are her husband and her dog, isn't it?
Funny how much our dogs are?
Just totally working.
Alongside us nowadays.
Also tell me what kind of dog you have?
If you have a dog because I absolutely, I am trying to get my dog to hop on here but I have a little pomeranian dog.
Who I would love to say hi to you.
Well and caps.
Yes! Jessica you have a cat.
Okay.
Gosh.
It's a miniature schnauzer.
I love this.
Okay, so when you are working with Feng Shui, so many of you have heard a lot about this, there are three types of luck when it comes to function way, okay?
And the types of lock are as follows, there's the lock that you're born with.
So in our Kind of society, we think of maybe like our Karma or astrology.
So, that's the luck that you're born with, and we can say that the lock that were born with because we live pretty much in the lap of luxury.
I would say compare comparatively, it's pretty good.
And then we have the lock that we create with our hard work and all of you I am sure are working very diligently.
So you can say that you have a lot of luck that you bring in with your hard work.
Now the third type of Lock and mind you, all of these are divided evenly.
So it's 1/3 the luck, you're born with 1/3 the luck that you create with your hard work.
And then 1/3 the luck that funk shui brings you.
So the luck that your environment brings you, the flow of energy and your environment.
And so today I am going to share with you three small quick things that you can do too.
Uplevel your space, right?
So let me get into it.
Number one, okay?
Is the power position.
So where you are sitting, okay?
So how many of you are sitting facing the wall where you are?
So if you're sitting facing the wall, put a number one in the chat.
Okay, Sonic Christian lore.
Dana Caitlin.
Okay.
So many people are sitting facing the wall and you know what?
When I first started I was also sitting facing the wall.
I am going to tell you this really quick trick here and it's actually going to help with your engagement and your company, right?
And it really helps with Employee Engagement because it helps you focus.
And that is sitting in the power position.
So when you are sitting in the power position, what happens is you feel more powerful, you feel more focused.
So you're asking me Marina, what is this power position?
You're talking about, how do we get there?
So there is might have some illustrations pop up on the screen for you but basically when you are sitting not facing the wall and you have the door in sight so you're not sitting.
Right in front of the door, we're going to have some not right, power positions but when you are sitting with the facing a wall or where you see the door, right, you're not directly in front of the door, but you see and it's not to the site side.
So Lori says, dead center of the room that's actually wonderful as long as you can see the door.
And the reason for this is a little bit psychological but it's also very powerful when it comes to function way.
So punctual actually goes back, many, many centuries, thousands of years actually.
And originally, it was to find the right land, formations to bury Emperor's and China, a little Macabre.
But today, it has evolved into amplifying, the lock, right in your life, in your relationships, and your health, and your business.
And so when you are thinking about your space, think of yourself as the royalty in your home, okay?
So if you are the Royal person in your home, whether you're the king, the queen Emperor, the empress or whatever, right?
When you are doing that.
You are in a power position and that Royal person would never sit in a way so that they do not see the door.
What a king ever sit with their back to the door.
If you think about it in movies, villains always sit with their back to the door and what happens to them, right?
Okay.
So we have someone's who's sitting facing so pakalana says she's facing the window.
A door behind me.
So I know it's beautiful to look at the window and it's actually great lighting to sit facing out the window.
But, you know, when you're in Zoom but you really, when you are sitting there and you see the door, you, you are fully focused because let me show you what happens when you're not in a power position.
So if we show you these illustrations, where you're sitting with your back to the door, what happens is you are on high alert and there is You know, your lizard brain your amygdala and no matter how safe you feel in your space, you are going to feel that in your subconscious.
You're going to have these processes that are taking away your focus because they're going to be asking, hey, who's going to walk in?
What if somebody walks into the door and it has nothing to do with how safe you feel in the space.
It's truly something that is very Much instinctive and primitive and us.
So when you sit with the Dorn site, it's so much better for you and when if you're interested and you know, I do these Marco experiences.
When I do these Marco experiences, they're a little bit more intimate, right?
We have, I could see where you're sitting.
I could see your camera on.
If you choose to show me that and in these Marco experiences, not only do I tell you, you know, all of these things.
I also tell you what, your luckiest direction is for sitting and facing.
And in the past, I have done this to one of my clients, my one-on-one punctuated clients, and she just got a new her.
She worked for a real-estate company firm, and she was a realtor, and they just got a new office.
And she asked me, Marina, where do I?
Sit I can.
And nice eat and not only did I pick a good seat for her so that she's in a power position.
She was also facing one of her, lucky directions, and instantly, literally like the next day, somebody walked in off the street, and she made a huge million-dollar-plus sale in cash, instantly, right?
Because that is how this stuff works.
So if you're Interested to know what your true power position is.
It would be really good if you booked it Marco experience, because then I could look at your space and tell you specifically where to sit and how to face.
So, and I see, company says, window on wall closet, opposite wall, and the doors in a corner.
So, if you face the window, you are definitely with your back to the door.
Yes, there is a Way, no matter how small your space is, my kitchen area, was Tiny.
And I actually had maybe one want to say like two feet ahead of me because I insisted on sitting with my back to the wall and facing the entrance and seeing the entrance.
So if you remember that promo shot in the very beginning where I have my diploma, Has with me that was in my kitchen office and I thought you could never tell because it was so nicely set up.
It was like the previous promo shot.
But anyway, so, before we go on, I just want to say it's also really important for you to have a chair that gives you support.
So if you have a chair that has a higher back, the higher, the chair back the better, it is because A, if you are the royalty, you need a throne.
So somebody earlier said that they had they were victim into the living room or the dining room.
I can't remember because they had a screw loose on their chair.
Make sure that your furniture is not wobbly and not loose because that gives you really, really good support, okay?
And Kim is asking, are any tips on counteracting bad feng shui?
If For example, you can't change the location of your desk or get a new chair.
So yes and actually that's the third tips.
I am going to go to it but generally speaking when you work with a practitioner what they can do is they can sort of fix this situation for you by carefully.
Placing a mirror so that you do see the entrance from your desk, you just have to be very careful when you place this mirror.
Cause you don't want to bounce the money energy back out.
So that brings me to my next tip which is me replacement right here.
So this I thought was so important to share with you Sonia.
I love that.
You say that you have to hide all the wires and that's why you face the wall.
Here's the thing.
When you were sitting with your back to the wall, first of all, you can put the wires in a box or something like that.
When you're sitting with your back to the wall and you see your whole space in front of you, you will feel so much more powerful.
You will feel so much more open and more motivated to doing your work.
So give it a whirl.
So back to me replacement, I thought this was super important to share with you because I actually had someone who hired me.
They couldn't find a job for like a year and it was terrible in the moment that I walk into their space.
I see a long hallway and at the end of the hallway, there's a mirror.
And that mirror, what it was doing, it was reflecting all the energy back out the front door.
So mirrors, actually double the energy, and they double the, the they double and direct the energy.
So, here we have some illustrations of how you should Place mirror, so that they're not reflecting the door.
And so you see those two on top, it's really good to have a mirror in your dining room because it actually doubles the energy of food and people and abundance, right?
And in your workspace if you have a mirror that's adjacent to the door.
So, if the mirrors shares a wall with the door, right?
It's actually really good for you because it will double the energy that comes in and it also doubles the energy you have, right?
So why am is asking me here?
Can a mirror?
Reflect window?
Yes, it can.
You just want to make sure that it's not fully in front of the window?
It's a little bit off to the side so it's not fully lined up with the window but it's not the end of the world.
If it is most important thing is that it doesn't reflect the front door not opposite a doorway that it's not at the end of Long hallway and it's not reflecting a toilet.
Okay.
So a lot of us have a mirror.
Right outside, the bathroom.
You don't need that mirror.
There move it.
So it doesn't reflect the door.
So and I have so many good questions in the chat that I really want to answer.
Maybe we can open up a lounge after and I can get to it and use of the saying, how about facing?
Yes.
We will get.
Get to those questions later, they're so good.
So when I do a Marco experience because you can have your camera on, I can really guide you when it comes to the mirror placement.
So if you are really, really curious about how you're sitting or what your mirror placement as that is one way that I can help you really pinpoint this right now.
The final thing that I want to share with you today Is called a salt cure and before we bring it up on the screen, or okay, we will make it up on the screen.
I want to tell you what this is for.
So when I practice Fung shui, I practice classical Chinese Funk shui and you're actually going to see if you Google Fung shui, there's a very generalized layout of every space.
It's called a bagua and it's incorrect because it's too General, right?
So when you place a salt cure, it's something that classical Chinese feng shui practitioners often do because they take away the negative energy in a room.
How many of you walked into a room and felt like it was icky, right?
Just put a 1 in the chat if you felt into a room or space in your like oh okay.
So many people are missing one good.
So what you do is you put together this glass, Jar with Nolan with a wide neck and this would be a salt cure.
So, look at this illustration here, you're going to fill it up about 70% with salt right?
And has to be just salt, not, you know, Jane's, crazy salt mix, right with all the other stuff in it.
So fill it up with salt.
Put 6 coins in a circle around it, then put it on 90%.
Put fill it up, 90% with water so it doesn't touch the top against a little bit open and you want to put it on a platform that you can just toss out later because what this salt cure is going to do, it's going to crystallize.
How many of you remember the science project without the coins, right?
Like how many of you remember doing something like this and science class?
Yes, Amanda.
I knew somebody would because I sure did so You do this, you're going to leave this in a corner of the room.
You're going to let it breathe.
You can put it on top of the bookshelf, so it's out of you and you're going to let it crystallized and make sure it's like on a magazine or something.
So that it, you know, when the salt crusts up, you could just take the whole magazine and throw it out.
As a matter of fact, you have just put a plastic paper bag, over your hand, grab it and toss it out because it will have so much negative energy in it, then it will suck out from the room and it will actually make the room feel better.
I have done this in, you know, full disclosure, I have friends who were bickering and I said to my friend, I was like, you need to put a salt cure in your bedroom just right now.
And so she did this and her husband stop bickering, which was great.
So how often do you have to do this natyam I would say do this at the very minimum, right?
I mean, if you're going to be really intense about it, you could do it every month or whenever you feel weird.
I would say just do it once when you move into a place, right?
Or you could even do it once a year, but the energy and Funk shui, it, changes annually, monthly daily hourly, right?
The salt cure takes a really long time to cry.
Sometimes Crystallized it will crystallize into days.
Sometimes it will take two weeks, depends on how much energy is in there.
So make sure most important thing is that you keep the lid off and you do not touch it when you toss it out and ym is asking, do you need to do the salt cure?
Peru more?
Is it okay?
For the whole home, right?
It depends on the layout of your home.
If just to be fully safe, Do it for the rooms where you spend the most time and especially in the center of the home this year.
Especially if you have like an open floor plan in the center of your home is fully open because the energy those here in the center is not so good, it's actually more energy.
So it's kind of interesting that there's a war happening this year, like a big one.
But anyway, we don't need to get into that right now.
So, thank you all so much for joining me.
And remember, you can always book your Marco experience with me if you just click that link.
I would be so delighted to work with you guys more intimately and to see where you're working from.
So, thank you so much, Marina.
Thank you so much.
We are a little bit over time now, but there are still some folks hanging out, and we're planning on opening up a lounge with Marina.
So if you want to ask your Questions with her then that's your chance, stick around.
And we will get that room opened.
In the meantime, thank you again for joining our two-part event.
We hope you enjoyed it, the recording will be sent out to you.
So feel free to check that out and, you know, you're on welcome.
If you enjoyed this experience in any way you can click on the tab above, get a demo.
Check it out.
We have also got our next event.
Next Thursday with Torch and bonus, Lee.
And we're gonna be talking about the power of strong workplace relationships.
So lot more there, it's going to be a great panel, have a wonderful rest of your day and week and I will catch you next week.
See ya.