Hello.
Oh, is my camera glitching?
Hi, everyone.
Am I showing up?
Alright, I know I had some camera glitches there earlier, give me a Lindsay.
Thank you.
Hello.
I am Gina had a marketing and welcome.
We are so excited about today's event.
Thank you, Thomas.
I love the thumbs UPS, appreciate it.
And it looks like we have got folks tuning in from all over.
I am actually here in Honolulu Hawaii and it is 7 AM in the morning.
So It's nice to see.
We got folks in Toronto, Thomas you're at NYC Morgan, Seattle, Houston, Oregon all over.
Aloha everyone.
It's lovely to have you here.
And our topic today is a really special one.
It's about the power of purpose and how you can foster a greater sense of purpose with your employee.
So I am really excited about our guest today.
Her name is Olivia, He is the VP of partner, success, with d.
Before I bring her up, we wanted to do a quick little housekeeping check.
So note that we have a Q&A Tab and at any given moment, feel free to drop your questions in that Tab and towards the end of this event will probably pull in some of those questions and answer them for you with Olivia here.
There's also a help tab, so if you're trying to navigate the platform you're here on, welcome to Day.
And if you have questions, feel free to drop them in there.
Now, let us kick off with a quick poll.
Have you participated in any giving activities, virtual volunteering donations?
Both or not yet, feel free to start dropping in your votes there, and we will quickly be able to see oh, okay, both.
Alright, so some of you have participated in Virtual volunteering and donations, refining trend-wise, we're hearing that more folks in the last couple.
Years have actually been doing donations over virtual volunteering Olivia will give us more points on that to come.
So with that, you know, today's Workforce is looking for that common greater purpose and according to Deloitte 67 percent of employees, look for socially responsible companies and companies who meet that need are seeing at least a 40 percent Spike.
In retention.
So I am asking the question, we're all asking the questions, how can we build a community that helps our employees gain?
This greater sense of purpose.
Meaning belonging fulfillment at work.
So with that, I love to bring to the stage Olivia VP of partner success at deed.
Hello.
Hi Jenna.
Thank you so much for having me.
Absolutely.
It's great to see you.
And where are you tuning in from?
I am in Park City Utah.
So not quite as tropical as Hawaii.
But pretty dang good.
We got the mountains and some good Sunshine, so not complaining.
That's awesome.
You taught is beautiful.
So is it and it's good for you there?
I promised I would try to bring my coworker so hopefully that's Just a good kickoff wheat.
7 AM morning.
Thank you.
What's your co-workers name is?
Name is daily.
So daily you think he's gonna behave himself during our conversation but if not we will just see what he has to say.
Awesome, well, he's welcome to participate and if he's got a question, feel free to bring him on any given point, and we well yeah, I like xandria we id'd we have Frou-frou dog, and cat.
Really, any animal.
It's the role that if they're in the room, they have to be on the video.
So we love it to love that.
Alright, so Olivia, we saw this, the stats that came through a lot of folks participated in donations.
And there's some, a good amount of folks that also did both virtual volunteering and donations, just talking quickly about what you're seeing with the trends.
And, you know, you had mentioned to me that donations are a lot more.
Those are taking place more than virtual volunteering.
Can you speak to that a little bit?
Yeah, I mean obviously we have all lived it the past two years have been insane for so many reasons, but in the giving an impact Community, it's certainly been interesting to see.
I mean, obviously at the very beginning and even into the past couple months, folks really have moved away from volunteering.
Just certainly hard for nonprofits, like soup kitchens or like tutoring programs are doing a lot of things in person, but it has opened up the opportunity for more virtual volunteering and some more skills-based volunteering, which is super cool and exciting.
And then the other though, like really big push that we have seen is just through donations and so much generosity over the past couple of years.
I mean, starting with covid but you know, most recently we have seen a lot of help going towards Ukraine.
And like most recently, some things with gun violence and so people kind of putting their money where their mouth is over the past couple years because they weren't able to do it in person or hands on Gotcha, that's really interesting.
So I am going to take us back a few notches and elevation up here because we are talking about social impact Corporate social responsibility.
And, you know, there are some stats that we just read off that, obviously, make it important.
But I would love to hear from your perspective, considering the changes are taking place with work remote hybrid.
All of these things?
Why is social impact so important for companies to be considering Yeah, such a good question and I feel like we could just talk about that all day, but I think for me, there's kind of and for deed, there's like two different parts that we think about one is like really on the impact component.
And I have seen some folks and some folks that I know from the nonprofit.
So they know this even better is like when you have Collective impact, you can do so much more good and that goes for volunteering or donations, when you like getting more brains in the room, more ideas floating around.
Around.
If like you need to help a non-profit with a marketing campaign, like that's always going to be better.
And then obviously with donations, the more people that you have contributing, the more matching, you have four more companies.
The more you're able to do so it's just like better for your local community and our communities at large.
But then the other side that we have seen, which like companies like Deloitte have awesome stats around, it is really around retention recruitment.
Fulfillment at work.
Like being able to keep people in their jobs, I think especially with like the millennial generation and then gen Z is now entering the workforce, and we have seen those Generations caring about this even more especially when it comes to their job.
So they're like, you know, we don't want to work for a company that doesn't stand for the similar things that we stand for.
And, so, in that way, it's really important to like, HR teams.
People team to really, make sure that impact is built into what the He's doing mmm.
And as far as trends that you're seeing of do's and do Nots as companies start to get more intentional about pulling social impact into their business strategies.
What are some dues do?
Not yeah.
Good.
Good question.
So, well, first of all, maybe I can give to like a little bit of a little brief about deed because I think that will help you.
Yes.
Why we hear about this?
And because this is what we're doing on a day-to-day basis.
So deed is a social impact platform.
We connect nonprofits companies and employees and really help them do good.
And then, when once, and while all that goat is happening, we track all of it.
So on the admin side, you can see all the good that's happening.
And so we get to work with all the teams that are driving that to come up with really cool, creative ideas for how to launch that, how to push it out.
How to get people more engaged.
And so that's kind of why we see some of these Trends and where things are going and know a little bit more about like the best practices in this impact community.
And I would say, we talked about kind of like that shift to donations, but I think that in a broader sense is just about being agile, you know, three years ago.
You potentially could have had a program that was like, we're 40% in person volunteering.
Virtual and 40% donations.
And you know once the pandemic happened that would have totally gotten blown up, and so we always talk about like how can you be super proactive and say like these are the things that our company really cares about and stands for but then also build into your program like how can I be reactive?
Because you can never plan, you know, disaster relief or like I mentioned gun control.
Lots of folks are talking about that, you know, hurricanes Earthquakes like those you know, God forbid moment that have to happen and so being able to build kind of that agility into it.
I think is super important.
And then in terms of like where we kind of see things going, they talk like we talked a lot about employees having voice and choice but also companies being able to be super intentional with we're like they're matching dollars or going.
So something that I think has been super cool.
Is that?
Companies are kind of like narrowing down on the nonprofits and organizations that they want to support because it's something that like really aligns to their business.
So like banks, for example, I have seen them do a lot of cool stuff with financial literacy.
We work with Airbnb who such an incredible company, and they do so much with impact, but because they're in housing, they can do a lot with refugees.
And with like after disaster relief, they are always there to help another company sonder.
It does the same thing.
Like Adidas is another one of our wonderful companies, and they like work very specifically with sports-related nonprofit.
And so, in terms of like a trend, I feel like just getting a little bit deeper and more intentional with like what you as a company really cares about.
I think is what we're going to see things going, but also allowing your employees to feel like their voices heard to.
So, potentially you have like an open program for General matching, but you give to X2 sports-related nonprofits.
If your A sport.
Ah, gotcha.
Interesting.
So the strategy you basically want to provide opportunity, multiple opportunities of how an employee can participate and get involved.
Yeah, 100%.
I mean, I think if you're able the, the wonderful thing that I love about deed is that were able to work with all types of companies.
So super small and then also really, really big Fortune 50 companies.
And so it's going to look a little bit different, like the smaller companies just might not have as many resources but there's a lot of ways that you can still direct and support your employees and giving but 100% I think you said it better than I ever could like giving lots of opportunities for your employees to give back and then like particularly highlighting the stuff that you have as a company care about, I think is an awesome way to pair the two.
So let us pull that thread a little bit for Shins.
That may just be starting to figure out what is the right nonprofit to be a part of, you know, where do we donate to?
What is a good starting point?
How do they you have talked about super powers before helping, you know, organizations identify what that looks like?
Could you speak to a little bit about that?
Yes, 100%.
So that I would say is like one of our favorite things to help companies do is it so exciting when a program is just Starting it feels like the world is your oyster but it also I think can be pretty intimidating.
It's like we could literally do anything so what do we do?
And so yes, we talked a lot about this idea of the superpower and it's basically like what does your company do better than anybody else or really different from anybody else?
And how can you harness it to for good?
And so we usually talk about like three different steps for it.
One And this is generally for companies who are just starting out, but also could be if you're looking to Pivot a little bit more or even just to like realign your social impact mission and vision and how that's playing out.
So the first thing would just be like thinking about your company's social impact Mission, like, what are you trying to change?
What do you really care about as a company?
And we went about this before, but, like, obviously, extra bonus points if it's also what a lot of your employees care about.
That's why I think, Like the bank example is really cool, is obviously folks who are very entrenched in this like Financial world.
And so financial literacy, I have seen be a really cool cause because a lot of those folks really care about that and are super knowledgeable.
So like understanding what your social impact mission is obviously ensuring all the execs are bought in bonus, if all the employees are super Baden and this kind of like anchors, what your superpower is for?
Like what are you trying to?
Change what you try to do?
And then the next one would be identifying your company's actual superpower.
So I actually already gave some examples, you know, with companies that we have worked with, but Deeds, I think is more around our platform and, you know, our platform connects people.
So we connect nonprofits company's employees and so that platform allows people to do good.
And, so I would say our platform is our super power, but for different people, you know, A Consulting Group like their people would be their superpower and that, you know, they can help nonprofits, do all sorts of different things.
So it could be your people, your product, really anything, and so you want to identify that and so once you have it designs defied, your kind of like Mission and then your superpower.
Then it's really putting it into action, which is obviously the hard part, but it's really collaborating across the board employees Executives.
Pulling in employee resource groups, your local community.
So that they, you know, so that you can leverage your superpower in service of your mission.
So hopefully that helps a little bit in terms of like a 1-2-3.
If there's anybody who's just starting out or you're chatting with somebody who's just starting out, we like think a lot about your superpower and how you can use that for good.
That's good.
Yeah, so we got a note here from makinen.
We also love seeing the trend of new startups, and companies, building an impact from day, one really baking this into their model.
I think that's also key and, you know, talking about you and I were talking about this in the Green Room a little bit ago, right before the event.
But as far as looking at the employee journey in total, obviously we know the first 30, 60 90 days of really He for any new hire to fully get integrated with the culture and it would make sense to introduce the social impact causes and how to participate all that in those days.
But where would you advise to get employees?
Really involved of corporate responsibility.
Such a good question.
So I would say there're two places.
I mean one, I have seen people do it in the interview process like, you know, you can just add, depending on maybe It's like a man manager question or even like appear interview which I think folks usually do that.
It's something.
Just like what's your favorite cause like is there any nonprofits that you're working with?
Like we particularly focus on education like is that something that you care about?
Like you can truly bake it in and that way if nothing else just so that the folks know that's something that you really, really care about but that, in terms of like when they're actually hired on, we have seen a lot of our companies, they Have like a slide about deed a slide about the IMPACT program, a slide about the policies during the onboarding process.
So you know all companies do it a little bit differently but most companies do have an onboarding process, and they just have that as part of it and you introduce everything.
Some folks you know have like a seminar for all new hires that week or that month.
And so we have seen people like do those presentations then and then I really loved it too.
I did we call it new higher credit but It could look different and every client or company, but they give new hires $25 to spend on Deed from.
That's cool.
Yeah.
And so that's awesome because it also was like here's the platform we use.
Here's what we care about.
Here's our policies.
This is what it looks like and now go use it.
And so then it allows the personal log on to deed spend that credit they know.
The company is truly investing in that, and then they get to send some money to their favorite nonprofit.
So, It's definitely a win-win that's good.
So I am even as early as the interview process, you're introducing the company's involvement and then especially that onboarding process.
What about for employees that have been with the company for one year plus, how do you get them engaged?
Yeah, really, really good question but I think that is really one like the bottoms-up approach is super important.
I mean, and that's kind of buzzword.
I feel like it Point, but I have seen lots of folks.
Do like listening tours, where they go around and say, hey what have you really enjoyed that we have done with social impact, could be pre or post pandemic?
Like what do you feel like is missing?
Are there?
Some nonprofit say you'd love to nominate how our different things working.
So I think just like making people feel like their part of the process in the decision-making and then also just like identifying communities.
That would be really excited to participate.
So we often times see, ER, G's employee resources resource groups.
It's sometimes called A little bit different at different companies, but those groups often times really focus in on specific causes like speaking as a woman I can say like women at deed.
That's like a group that we would probably focus on supporting women-led nonprofits or nonprofits supporting women in different communities.
And so you can really lean into kind of those like cause specific organizations.
We have seen lots of different things, you know, depending on how dispersed your Is having like, Regional ambassadors, who were super pumped about giving back and, like, the culture of giving at your company and so having, you know, almost like satellite or like remote groups that are specified for giving or talk about giving her to help like lead, local activations is also, I think a great way for folks who might have been involved for a while and maybe like haven't done anything during the pandemic or like looking to get more involved.
But yeah, lots of like different.
Fun ideas.
I am sure some of those will come up more later too.
That's great.
And if anybody has questions, feel free to drop them in Q&A.
And we will I am we're looking at that as well.
So, one of the things, Olivia, you mentioned was leadership and you'd say the top down the bottom up approach, But ultimately, we all know that it needs to start from the top and so that executive buy-in, like how can you speak to a little bit about what?
You know what you have seen?
With leaders that are involved leadership, that's not involved.
What if there's a company out there right now where the leaders may not be fully involved in aware and there's an employee that wants to get the leadership more involved.
So there're different scenarios here.
But can you speak to that?
Significance of the leadership teams of all?
Yeah.
100%, it's such a, such a good point.
And so, so important like I mean, Jenna, you mentioned, like, it just is not going to stick fully if It's if the leadership is not bought in and so that's why you know, we talked before like voice and choice which is more Bottoms Up and grassroot but it is really important for the leadership to really be bought in on the call causes that.
The company is supporting and so yeah I can't like underscore that enough, that it's really important for the leaders to be bought in.
I think that more and more like it very many does seem to be the rhetoric and you know like ESG has become much more kind of like top of mine.
And, so I think that folks really are moving in that direction and it and hopefully, it won't be super difficult to convince any leaders who aren't yet bought in.
But I have just seen really effective uses of leadership bodden.
So, you know you have all hands maybe once a week once a month and to have the leaders talking about the programming and the causes and the nonprofits and the impact during those team meetings is really, really an Active and it certainly shows how much they care and are bada in.
I have also seen like really cool things where they will like, send an email and say I am going to this opportunity or like I will be attending this virtual opportunity and I would love for you to join of kind of this, like, Collective impact.
And it also gives you face time to spend with an executive which can never hurt and so stuff like that, you know, and even, it's not just like the top executive.
It's also like managers and So then with like your team meetings to have it is again baked in as like an agenda point to say you know these this is our policy reminder to use your vtl like stuff.
Like that is really important.
And then I think that last part of the question I am just like if they're not yet bought in like reach out to our team, we have so many business use cases of like why it's really important to invest here?
I think obviously like the big ones that a lot of people care about is Like the retention and the Recruitment, and the Fulfillment statistics, but there's even more than that.
So they're certainly like lots of stuff.
We can hopefully arm you with, to convince anybody who's not, but in yet, Laura just mentioned that they have done volunteer with me events with execs that have gone over pretty well.
That's an interesting idea to do events and have them have the executives, probably Express their passion, and belief around a certain cause I think that over communication is really key from the leadership perspective, totally.
And I think it like it reminds me some Early to PTO.
Like I think it's really means a lot when an executive says, Hey I am going on PTO and I here's my out of office.
I am not going to be reached and it really like sets the example of how important that is and that you want to feel refresh.
And it's the same thing for volunteering is like, hey, I am going to take two hours this afternoon, and I am going to be here and here's like a photo of me doing it.
And I am a proponent of all of our employees doing this so it's really just like leading, by example.
That's good.
I would think that storytelling is also a key vehicle to support engagement of employees.
This isn't something we talked about as a question, but I am curious Olivia from your perspective.
Any input on companies, you have seen that do storytelling really well around their social impact.
That's such a good question.
And yes, I mean I and I think Knowing like very specific stories.
And I think this Loops all the way back to the very beginning of what we're talking about with intentionality and potentially, like, Drilling in on one or two causes that you as a company like, it feels very authentic that you would support this particular cause or this particular nonprofit or group of nonprofits.
Then I think you become so much more familiar and you have like these actual stories of nonprofits and volunteers and donors that have been working together over weeks.
Sir years like that might have had a really incredible experience.
One afternoon with a team or with an executive like you can create more of those like deeper relationships.
So I think that's like another reason to kind of dig in a little bit on some of these causes.
But it also reminds me of something we have talked about, which is just how important it is for social impact teams to work, so closely with other teams.
So, like a comms team is a Perfect example is like you want to be super abreast of what comms is working on and what and you want them to know exactly what you're working on.
Because like you mentioned, like both internally and externally it's so important how you talk about this and how you really like make people feel included and excited and that impact is happening.
And so the more you can share like those individual Stories, the kind of like Collective impact stories.
We just had an amazing partner who they're like, Around sustainability and climate change.
And they had this really cool like walk challenge that we were a part of to and so that was just like it wasn't even like direct volunteering but definitely falls under the impact bucket.
And it was super cool.
Like how they kept all of us.
Abreast of like, how many steps did we have?
We met how many trees then have been planted?
Like how many steps do we have to go?
And so definitely, like working super close to with your comms and marketing team on.
How to message that and kind of like, spread the good that y'all are doing, That's great.
Thanks, thanks Olivia.
I know you got some questions that I am seeing pop up in the Q&A.
Before we transition to Q&A, I have one last question here, you know, companies even more.
So, today are being urged to share, not only what they stand for, but what they stand up for.
So that's in this case of diversity, equity, and inclusion.
A company social impact strategy.
Also, needs to be part of that core Strategy.
But how can companies do this respectfully and authentically with all the other things going on?
What do you advise?
Yeah, yeah it's really hard.
Let us just say that first and definitely something that like every single company is thinking about.
And I feel like even in the past year, there's been like many, many things that I am sure companies who is a kind of struggled with how to talk about and support or not support.
Another really good reason why you need to work.
Super closely with comms super closely with the people team, the HR team, and then obviously have execs interested in part of the conversation because those are likely the people that are kind of stakeholders there.
But I think, when we talk to our partners, about trying to figure out, like, where or how to come out on certain issues or questions, it's more like just what feels the most authentic to you as a company and that can sometimes be kind of hard to get at, but a lot of our clients that we have worked with that, like do it in the best.
Way it's a lot about communicating correctly, but then also like, leaving that space for folks who might not agree in the exact same way.
So either be heard or to feel supported.
So we have given this example a couple times but it's like you know the 1X matching to whatever nonprofits.
They choose within you know a certain we have a lot of folks who like won't do political or religious, obviously like hate groups are always blocked but that you do allow people to give somewhere that they would Like voice and choice, but then you're like doubling down on donations towards organizations that you really care about.
So that's one thing and then I think we mentioned this too, but like being really clear like what are the Evergreen causes that you care about and like those things likely won't really change.
But then building in the place to be more, reactive to disaster relief or different things that happen because then I think, We tend to communicate that like this is our policy like we designate 80% of our resources towards these certain things.
We know are going to happen and then the rest is like for things that might pop up.
And so we have seen that to be really effective because then employees just like understand what's going on.
Like they're like you know, they can't respond to everything because you only have 20% of resources allocated to disaster relief, or whatever it might be.
So just being like very upfront and then the companies know the best.
Like what is your company culture and community and like what's going to resonate the most with them?
So again just like a big plug to work.
So closely with the comms team, the marketing team, the people team to make sure that you're communicating it in the right way.
That's so good.
I love the clarity of the percentage breakdowns and being really clear with your employees.
This is, you know where we're, we're participating and how you can participate.
I think that Clarity is really helpful.
Yeah.
I totally agree.
And we see that we have an amazing support team and I feel like they really lean into that.
Like, you know, just simply saying like this is the That our platform is working on, like if you have questions or like working by, if you have questions on that like we're happy to talk you through it.
But like here's all the information.
And usually I mean, people usually are very reasonable, and they're like oh I understand because this is the policy that's been set up.
I think we're where they're sometimes confusion like is when there's ambiguity, but it's really, you know, I get it because these are really like difficult conversations and decisions to make, but I think like as clear as you.
Can be unlike your plan and your policies, and your process, the more that employees are like, oh yeah, I get that like that's reasonable, that's good and Ingrid just mention, it's easier to say no, as well, the clear you are.
So it gets me thinking, you know, it's really key to have an owner that's really driving this initiative and driving the cross-departmental alignment and communication all that With the customers that you work with, what, what are you seeing as that common stakeholder owner?
Like, what is their title, who generally owns it?
Where do they sit in organization?
Yes, that's such a good question and it does it vary for sure.
So, I would say, like, the most common title we see is like head of social impact director of social impact, depending on how big the company is and how much they have invested in social impact.
They will often times.
Like potentially a couple folks part of that team like somebody that might be focused more on volunteering, someone that might be focused on disaster relief, for example, or donations like somebody who's more on the policy side of things like, making sure the volunteer time off policy is set and write and like the donations policy.
So, like different people format in different ways.
Sometimes there's like an engagement specialist that job is so fun and like gets to come up with different ideas on.
Unlike how to engage folks, in that company's impact and then it also sits in different places.
I have seen it likes it, I think the most common and to me makes the most sense is under people team.
So like HR people just because it really is like such a benefit to the employee into the company.
So that's probably where I have seen it the most.
But I have also seen it fall like under like policy teams and comms teams just because like, depending again on the type The financial institutions is a good one.
Like they have to do so much reporting that it might make sense for that to be like under more of a policy or a comms umbrella.
That's helpful, great.
All right, let us transition into some of this Q&A.
We have got a question here.
Jessica is our producer in the green room.
Thank you so much for pressing, the keys here, because you bring the question to the stage.
How, and when do you introduce these communities and keep them relevant as employees settle in?
So, you touch this a little bit earlier Olivia, what are your thoughts?
Yes.
Really good question.
So when I think of this question and happy to go in a different direction but I think of like employee resource groups or potentially like Regional Ambassador groups, and so we can start talking about ER, G's and can take it in whatever direction is most helpful.
But again, this kind of seems like a theme so important to wear it with the people team in the HR team because they're often times the one's kind of standing up the ERG groups.
But as we also mentioned earlier like the earlier you can incorporate impact into ER GS the better because then it kind of becomes part of their ethos.
We have worked with some companies that the ERG is and actually on deed we have like special ERG pages.
And on that page, you put like your logo and a lot of companies have like super funny or do you logos and then also a description and so some people will have like mission statements for their ERG, and they will build impact into that.
Mission statement.
And, so I love that because it automatically creates a space where that is something that's like intended to be something that they think about and do and talk about that would be like, my biggest advice would be like early and often like try to bake it into the mission statement if you can.
And then second part I am just making sure I answered all the parts of it.
It might be in the answered part 02.
Keep them relevant.
So then I think the relevancy part is kind of again going back to like the listening tour in the surveys.
Like once that your G is going and has they're like impact part of the mission statement and is like rocking and rolling.
Usually they don't need to like too much driving behind them.
Because, like I said, it's like people who really identify with that, cause with those nonprofits, and they can kind of like, do it themselves.
Elves, but if it's not moving so much like kind of finding out why like, hey we have given you the resources, you have a budget of, you know, 25,000 dollars to go matching, how you want, you know, you have the time you have the VTO policies.
Like what, how, what's missing?
How can we support you to drive that impact within your ear G?
So hopefully that's a little bit helpful in terms of how args work I have .
Like seen people use them to do really cool.
Stuff.
And even do like full presentations again at all hands, that specifically about the impact that the ERG made in communities.
And so, that's like a way to kind of bring everything together that we have talked about of, like, highlighting the work that the ERG is doing, specifically focused on impact in there, cause area, which is just really cool and I think pretty inspiring for other people to be like, oh, I want to do that with my ear G with like the nonprofit's that we care about.
So good.
Are we have another question here?
What advice do you have for rapidly growing organizations trying to structure their current charitable giving programs and who are key stakeholders to get in the room?
Awesome, I think we're just pulling now from other conversations we have had but I, you can pull from kind of that super power structure of like, you know, feeling like a little bit intimidated of not knowing where to start.
But as I think MacKinnon mentioned like early and often like get it super built in.
To your company's ethos and the employees and as you're hiring, and then think about like what is the thing that we want to change or help solve, you know, what is our super power?
And then how are we going to actually tangibly?
Do it?
And then, in terms of stakeholders are moving, talked about this a lot too, but exacts leadership.
So, so important to have them on board, the like comms team marketing, team people in HR team and then I would say like those, ER, G's for sure.
Sure and usually ERG is had like a leader or some type of like boards that you could work with.
I mentioned these like Regional ambassadors, but we do have some companies who are super Global, and so they need to make sure that a lot of there they will have like a big employee population in India and so that's going to be like a very different kind of giving culture.
Then we might see in the US or the UK and so that Regional Ambassador is so helpful to be able to say to like help set up local opportunities.
But also communicate back and say like This is what we need as like, a team in India, that might be different from what the team is doing and Australia, or the UK or the US.
Wow, that's another layer to factor in is the regionality?
That's, that's huge.
And, and identifying the local communities to be part of per region across the globe.
That's good.
All right.
We have got our third question here.
What advice do you have on wedding organizations to partner with?
We want to make sure we align with their values and Mission as well, but this can be hard to find without conversation.
Good, classic and question and something we work on with our clients all the time.
I will personally give a little plug.
So at deed, we have a non-profit, success team, and so they work very closely.
We have a partner success team.
That works, that is like our clients point of contact.
Then our team is also working directly with the nonprofit success team.
And these are folks that have worked at nonprofits worked at wedding organizations and like really, really understand the landscape and what you're looking for there.
So with our clients, that is an easier question to answer because they get to work directly with our nonprofit success team.
And that team helps them like give recommendations.
They have already done a lot of the vetting.
They might be able to connect them if they can.
But if you're kind of doing it on your own, I think there's like a lot of different things that you can do especially now in the wonderful age of the internet.
I mean, obviously there's like the Baseline which is like checking on guidestar and network for good and places to make sure they're like in good standing with the IRS that's like Baseline and there's other equivalents in other places.
But then we do like a lot of research on social media.
Like a lot of times now, nonprofits have Facebook, they have Instagram.
Like are they active, are they doing things?
Like, are they being transparent?
Are they putting out different statements on things?
You can like glean, a decent amount of information there and then a lot of times, you know, nonprofits need and want our help especially companies just because they know that it is, the collective impact piece.
So I would definitely not hesitate in reaching out and just asking to have a conversation with them.
It would be like, good debt.
Probably have a couple questions that you asked all nonprofits.
Just so you have like an across the board questions that you ask for folks.
But yeah, those I think would be my recommendations is like, you know, check the, the validated sources that you already have access to like, look at their present you again.
He said, Network for good.
Now we're forgetting guidestar ones that we use a lot.
But yeah, those are just places that you can like type in there.
Ein, get some information, some financial information, so that's like a good place to start.
Look at their social media, look at their website, like some nonprofits haven't updated their website in a really, really long time, which could because of lack of resources, which is even more, so why you should help them.
But, you know, that could be something that you want to look into or ask about like maybe their defunct or not doing that much.
And then the last one would just be, you know try to get on the phone with them or at the very least like send some questions over email because they want our support, and so they should be super open and transparent about what they're up to and what the funds go to.
Our team just as like an incredible job and looking like, at what percentage of funds are going, we're like how much are they paying their stuff based on the donations that come in?
So, lots of different things that you can look at, but our nonprofit success seemed, like I said, I will give them a little plug, they are just incredible, and they do a lot of this for our clients and with our clients and partnership.
That's awesome.
Wow.
So many golden insights Olivia that you dropped for us during this time and it looks like we have wrapped all the questions if anyone has a last-minute question, feel free to drop that in, but other than that, Olivia, would you have any parting words of advice or anything for our guest today?
Yes, I think.
I think the biggest one which we already talked about is just making sure that you are building in that space to be reactive because, you know, it's a crazy world that we live in and so many different things are moving and changing.
And so, it's really important to have those core pillars of.
Like, this is what we care about in, this is what we stand for.
But then also, knowing that so many things are moving and changing that, you want to have that elasticity to be able to react to it because that's going to be really important to your employees.
So that's one thing.
And then the other thing I think Ink which hopefully we mention and gave some examples of but like engagement Employee Engagement, especially around giving should be fun.
Like there's so many fun things that you can do like, employee resource groups.
Have done the coolest things and it's stuff that like, they really, really, really care about.
I think my favorite thing and it doesn't have to be employee resource groups.
It could be like companies, and they got an insane percentage of Engagement.
Like I want to say higher than 80% of Engagement was like a I think Challenge and you could do it with exact switch.
I have seen done where like, you know, six execs record themselves singing to a different song and then that is paired with, like, they're nonprofit of choice.
And so, you play it during an all hands or like a happy hour.
And then to vote for that video, or for that, exact, and that nonprofit, you donate to them.
And so then you can see, you know, you have those six nonprofits and whoever whatever nonprofit raises, the most money, like that exact one.
And so, you could do that Also, by teams like I have seen that like, the marketing team versus the Eng team first, the Congo cetera, and so they will do like a group link saying core lip sync or like do it.
I have also seen the same thing done with a pet fashion show, so, you know, daily were part of that.
So you can make it really fun, and then they're like supporting a Humane Society or something like that, so you can make it really fun.
And I have seen that be really effective.
In terms of just employees, getting excited and feeling motivated and connected.
Their companies but also to their colleagues.
Those are awesome points.
Thank you so much.
I think each of us are going to take something away from this and be able to apply it very quickly.
So, thank you, Olivia.
Really appreciate your time today.
And we're going to have a follow-up email with the recording of this event along with a link for people to get more information about deed.
And so, if anyone's got questions, feel free to hit up Olivia, I am just putting it out there.
You hit us up at Then as well.
And so with that.
Thank you, Olivia.
And we have a couple of events coming up this month already.
It's like, you know, after Fourth of July week, we have got three weeks left in the month, and we have got a really awesome event coming up.
July 21st, it's called changing how we work, and it's with the CEO co-founder of oyster, Tony, and then Chris founder, CEO of First Base.
And our very own Co Roberto welcome.
And you know, we're going to be talking about just some of the insights on the power of working remote and how they're leading their District distributed teams while still empowering Employee Engagement and collaboration.
So feel free to check that out.
And you know, of course you're here on.
Welcome.
And this is an employee event platform.
That is uniquely designed for.
Port across the entire employee Journey from on boardings to doing those fun events that Olivia just mentioned where you can have the lip sync competitions and all that around social impact and so much more.
So feel free to check us out.
Get some more information by clicking on that tab above and with that, we're wrapping up.
So, thank you so much for being here.
It's always a pleasure to spend time with you all.
I wish I could see all of your faces but I do see your names.
I see your engagement chat and have a wonderful rest of your day and week until next time we will catch you later.