Hello, so great to see you all for some of you on the East Coast, it is way later than where I am at.
I am in Hawaii right now.
So it's 8:00 in the morning, but it's great to see some of you tuning in from Argentina.
Hello, Sophia Gwen from Toronto, Atlanta La Bay Area, San Diego, San Francisco.
Doug, why?
Wow, we have got Global representation here and it's Cool to be together all across the world all across different time zones.
So, thank you so much for tuning in.
We have got a power panel today and the topic is going to be fire.
It's all about developing strong relationships in the workplace, you know?
Actually before I jump in note that there is Q&A because people have submitted their this is a Hot Topic.
So we have had folks submit questions in advance, upvote your most burning questions and feel free to drop questions because we're going to answer them as we go.
So I want to start with this pole and I have got Katie.
Thank you.
She's in the Green Room, our event producer lead, can you pull up that pole for us?
And let us just take this quick.
Pull.
What's the workplace relationship that has had the most significant and positive impact on you?
Is it a mentor?
A coach, a manager appear a direct report or other feel free to drop in your votes.
Interesting.
Okay, so we're seeing manager as highest wow.
That is probably one of the most significant relationships.
We're going to unpack that email a bit more, and then we got peer and Mentor.
Very cool.
Okay.
Thank you for placing those votes recently Gallop had just released this study of the increasing importance of having the best friend at work.
And I don't know if that's necessarily your manager, or maybe it's more of a Here.
But take a look at that Nifty overlay there.
You can see the statistics and you know, the statistics are mentioning and you can see, you know, year over a year how much having the best friend at work?
Can truly tie back to retention and happiness at work and it's essential for social emotional support and ultimately supporting strong business outcomes.
And, so I want to unpack this a little bit more with our amazing.
Amazing panel.
If we can enter bring them up on to the stage here we have got a me who's the VP of people success that torch Elizabeth who's the head of Behavioral Science insights at torch and Vicki.
The VP of people Ops at bonus Lee, will you join me on stage?
Hello.
Anyway, Harry great, to be here to view.
Where are you tuning in from and what time is it?
Just curious.
We will start with you.
Vicki, I am in Colorado, and it is lunchtime.
Noon, noon o'clock.
Nice have a UAV.
Also, coming to you from Mountain Time Zone.
It's not very common that we have to, from Mountain Time Zone, but I am in Park City Utah.
Great.
And I am in the Bay area.
So I saw a lot of folks who are also in the Bay Area.
Hello, but I am on SO West Coast time so it's just a little after 11 year awesome and Elizabeth.
I am going to pause on you could you tell us a little bit about yourself and about torch, and then we will go backwards to go to a me then Vicki?
Yeah, absolutely.
So I am the head of behavioural science.
Insights that torch and torch is we really Torch?
We feel growth through the power of relationships and feel professional growth.
So we do mentoring coaching, and we have a Collaborative Learning platform.
And what I do in my role, my background is a little non-traditional.
I worked as a journalist for many years and then found the field of Behavioral Science and became an applied behavioral scientist.
But I think what really ties all of my interests together is this curiosity about why people do what they do and really want to understand human motivation and kind of how we learn how we grow and how we really kind of can reach our full potential as people.
So what I do at torch is I work with, lots of different teams are Behavioral Science team, our marketing team our sales team to really understand what are we learning from our platform about how people learn to grow and change over time and hopefully share things that really helped all of us do that better in our professional lives.
Love it.
Thank you.
Amy.
Maybe tell us a little about what you do with torch.
Yes.
Also hear from Team torch.
I lead our people success team at torch and people success is essentially another word for our people or human resources team, but it was really important to me as I came into this role to signal that we are here too.
Ali fuel, people's happiness, and success at work.
So, we actually use in part of why I work so closely with the amazing Elizabeth is, we use a lot of the science behind happiness and success at work, to organize our team and to really help people to bring their best selves to work so that they can do their best work.
So I am really excited about this topic because relationships and connection are such a huge part of our engagement and happiness at work.
Thanks, Amy Vicky.
So my name is Vicky young.
I am the VP of operations at bonus Lee.
Also, another word for HR and it's also interesting is my first time working in a company that sells a product primarily to HR people, to that talks about engagement and how recognition can enhance culture.
So definitely it's a bit meta.
I think, working at places probably like, torching bonus lie, where we do a lot of research, we share a lot of information.
We also have to make sure that we're living that inside our company so a lot of fun to be able to do that and to do work.
I think (differently) than how we fizz it happens.
That's great.
So I want to kick off with just a very real question right now, you know, we're in this time of a lot of change uncertainty.
Downturn is what it can feel like so.
So then why is building strong work relationships business critical during times like this, Yeah, I mean, I would say building strong workplace relationships is always really important but it is especially important now, and we can get into a little bit as far as what the research says on this.
Even though I think one of the reasons why this topic is so powerful is because we all kind of intuitively.
Also know, this is true.
We know that when we have strong relationships at work, right?
We're just happier people we do better but in terms of what some of the Nina sighs.
Let us start with kind of to Big Business outcomes.
That folks are looking at one is performance and the other is retention.
So, we know from, there's some great research from this research, Consortium called, connected Commons, and they have looked at the relationship skills of their.
They have looked at kind of what is critical to Performance.
And they found that relationship skills are really cored to individual performance team, performance and organizational performance.
And specifically what they have found is that somebody's ability to generate energy and enthusiasm within their network is the largest predictor of being a high performer at work.
And they found that leaders do this.
Basically, in three ways, one is by building a foundation of trust, the other is helping others, find a sense of purpose in their work and the third is really creating energy and daily interactions and I can go into any Those in a little bit more detail.
But I really thought that was super interesting that this is, you know, when we think about high performer and what a high performer, looks like that ability to generate energy enthusiasm within their network is so huge.
And you know what?
They have also found in other research and this was based on interviews, conducted with 160 liters across 20, different organizations kind of talked about the connection between Ation ships and retention and said that the willingness to stay in an organization is really impacted dramatically by the quality of relationships and somebody's Network.
So, according to these researchers, and I will quote them here because I think it's really powerful, and they found in their research.
Is that thriving at work is often as much or more about the relationships and quality of interactions with others as the type or Pace of work?
Eight.
So, and I think this gets at this kind of myth that a lot of us, hold around, hold around work which is that, you know, we have this idea of what a dream job looks like and like, oh, I really want to, you know, work on this particular topic and that's what's going to make me happy.
And sure that's important to your Wellness, you know, and kind of well-being and happiness at work.
But even more important is the relationships.
You have and so many of you responded, you know, to that opening question, how important a manager relation?
Essentia Paz, right?
Like you could be working on the topic that you think is so interesting and important to you.
But if your relationship with your manager isn't where you'd like it to be, you're probably not going to care very much about that.
Super interesting topic that you're working on the one final thing that I will say here before I turn it over to Amy who I know, has some other great information about this is they did a study, researchers did a study where they looked at connectivity across 40,000 people.
And they looked at voluntary turnover, and they found that when they looked at employees who had been there for less than one year when they looked at kind of what predicted them leaving, it wasn't the number of ties they had to other people but what did predict it was?
How many other people in the organization sought them out for help and advice?
So it's not necessarily oh I have this huge Network and that's the thing that It matters what matters even more was are other people saying or other people trying to bring this person in for help and advice, which is this really interesting indicator of trust, right?
And of kind of wanting to keep somebody around, pull them into your teams or groups.
So, I will let a me to take it from here and share a little bit more about what we know about why relationships are so business-critical.
Yeah.
Thanks, Elizabeth and such powerful data, and I am already seeing lots of people asking for links to the studies.
You know, I think one thing I would just add to that is how this need is kind of universal need.
That's probably always been there.
But we have seen it really spike in the last couple of years with you know a move to a lot of people moving to a hybrid work situation.
A lot of just challenging things happening in the world.
A lot of people soul-searching and Thinking about the purpose and the work that they do and in some, some research that LinkedIn and glint did at the end of 2020, that really struck me is looking at what drives whether or not people think that they have a great culture at their company.
And looking at the top drivers of a great culture, we actually saw that belonging increase to the number two, most important thing that drives They're not peopled love their culture and, you know, we have always known that belonging is important but that actually went up four spots in terms of impact, which is a pretty significant shift.
You don't often see that data shift as significantly usually stays pretty stable and you know it makes a lot of sense.
What people want to feel like I have so much going on in the world and in my life and where I am spending so much of my waking hours, I want to feel like I belong here and I will say to That the only thing that we ranked higher in terms of the impact on a great culture is opportunities to learn and grow.
And I think that's just both of those like number one and number two are so critical to relationships are so critical to people's ability to feel like they belong.
And we also know that relationships have an outsized impact on whether or not people feel like they can grow at an organization you more so than a training course or formal programs having someone that invests in you and that you trust And that can help you navigate and in many cases that might be a manager.
So, those are again things that have always been important, but that have really increased in importance that people are looking to more and more.
As you know, the world of work is changing dramatically and it gets really interesting when you try to think about how to create and facilitate belonging and what often is feels like a two-dimensional screen for many people.
So I am looking forward to talking about that, that more So rich.
I feel like I am processing all of those data points and thank you for Brian for sharing some of that research in the chat Vicki.
Yeah, I would plus one, everything.
Elizabeth and Amy are saying, I think, you know, just specially the last two years.
We were spending a lot more time.
Evaluating what we want to spend our time on?
And also I think going from a lot of office work to suddenly remote, for many people has been drastically different.
And how are we making those connections?
And I have noticed how when there is a lack of connection, you do see that attrition, you see the burnout?
You see the feeling of being alone.
Own when you're in the office you can kind of vent over the same type of thing.
They can talk to each other, and so we actually our company had our in two years.
Our first get to human get together in person at the end of July and the energy coming out of that was just so different.
And even before that, I think to the Elizabeth or eating might have mentioned this earlier, this is always been the case, right?
You have those connections with each other has always been important.
Anytime I see teams, especially cross-functionally, when they're not Working well together if you start putting them together to so that they get to know each other as human beings.
So it's not about work, right?
Like we literally took the team, bowling, put them on different teams, had them, you know, we put in by games and stuff.
So the team that scored the most points or do the most whatever's got kind of prizes, right?
And it changed the dynamic.
When they headed back into the office, to actually do the work stuff.
So there's a lot of, I think more empathy building, when you create those relationships, and a lot of more trust-building, when you create those relationships, That's huge.
So, you know, managers came up high in the pole and obviously, there's an opportunity and that relationship manager to employee even across department leaders to employee how if we're leader manager here, what can we do to help create?
And facilitate that environment that does build healthy team relationships Yeah, I think being a manager is really hard, especially right now and it's not often something that you're kind of taught.
Think most people are really thrown into it before they even get any training and there's a lot you could do.
So there's the building, I think of psychological safety and trust with the individual and then creating that on the team too.
So how are you creating space to actually make mistakes?
We talk about a lot of this all the time.
How you're supposed to do these things but How do you actually do?
It is a lot more difficult and sometimes not as clear.
And so being able to create Clarity for the team, helped create expectations, right?
A talking about the places where you have messed up or even how you react when someone messes up and especially under stress lately.
So, it's a lot about, you know, you show up as a leader you and your people manager showing up you talk and just I think talking about it often times, we're trying To almost spin things.
A little too much and I think if we just show a little bit more of our human side and be a little bit more vulnerable.
As people managers, it goes a long way saying, you know, I care.
I do have a question about psychological safety since you brought that up is there.
Things we can do is managers today to encourage and create an environment of psychological safety.
Yeah, I would say the biggest thing is consistency in how you and oftentimes how you react to things they need to.
Like, our brains are wired to go and look for everything that is wrong in our environment, right?
It's kind of natural, it's just in our brain.
So our amygdala goes off and were like, oh my God, is that rustling in the trees?
Going to be this giant thing that's going to eat me.
And now in the workplace is it is this going to hurt me somehow?
And it's not so much physical anymore, right?
But psychological, so, I think creating as much space for reducing that anxiety so like hey if something is you make a mistake I will bring it up in this way with you.
So that way they know what's coming or if it's you know this is what I expect like how much vacation time for you to take so that way they're not even worried about like oh it should I even ask for this or not, right?
I think it's just calling out those things and saying this is how I work.
Here's what I look like on.
Distress.
Here's what will happen.
If something goes wrong, this is how I am going to support you.
So, so just really kind of opening up that box of this is how I am going to support you.
This is how you can exploit, you can expect me to do, how you can expect me to react and just reduces that kind of magdala.
Feeling of like, oh, I don't know what's coming next, you do because I am going to help, hopefully clarify and tell you what's coming next.
I think that creates a lot of safety.
The other piece is really I hate giving you're trying not to be judgmental when someone's telling you something.
So that way, they can know that they can bring things to you, that you are going to partner with them, to talk through, whatever it is, that they're going through, whether that is personal or not.
And sometimes, you know, we're not therapists or most of us are not there because people managers.
So there's a line there for sure, but it goes a long way to even just listen and empathize with like, okay.
Yeah, your kid can't go to daycare right now because there's a covid outbreak and you probably We are so distracted.
So let us talk about what we can do to help you kind of threw that piece.
It's huge.
Amy Elizabeth, is you have anything to say, regarding psychological safety, or even the previous question about, how managers can create an environment of relationship building?
Yeah, it I think that so many good points.
Thanks so much for sharing video.
I think that the one thing I would add on the psychological safety front is also showing vulnerability yourself as a manager or a leader.
I think that can also go a long way and I think you know, so often we as managers and leaders think like we're supposed to sort of appear to have it all together, and we're supposed to have all of the answers, and we don't you know we don't want to bring up a topic and You know, exactly how to respond.
And it's just this sort of myth of management and Leadership that is what our people want from us.
When in fact, so much of relationships and human connection comes down to our shared Humanity, which is that we are fragile.
You know, people who have struggles and aspirations, and things that we're dealing with as well.
And so, you know, I think as much as possible creating space, you know, too.
To be able to, to not only hear from the employee but also to share, when it's been a hard time or I have got to take off early, to go be with my kids or, you know, some of that I think makes it safe because often what I hear and what I see is that we as, as managers and leaders can feel like we are open to people giving us all of the feedback and all of the information, and we might even ask the question, but if we never see leaders role, Modeling it in then the sort of subtext is.
It's not safe to share that here.
So that's one thing that has been a big learning for me, personally, is just the power of sharing.
You know, that two-way dialogue a couple other just quick things.
I will add that kind of just piggyback on what Vicky was sharing as well is that you know there's just one of my kind of Monitors this to try to, you know, create meaning in the things we're already doing.
So like one-on-ones are often just kind of firefighting to do's and it's so easy to get in that trap, but really making sure that you are once a month.
Creating space for that like deeper conversation and it's all like the power of great questions is always something.
You know, like having those teed up, I think is so important because you can always do the small talk.
You can always do the firefighting but it's the like really going deep.
Are one really powerful question that, especially after the pandemic, I found had a huge impact was asking, how are you doing?
And then stopping and saying, no, really how are you doing and pausing and being quiet and letting people share and that's where some of those other challenges that you know, just people can't shut off as soon as they turn on their computer can come up but then also asking meaningful questions that like get to our aspirations in the Workplace things.
One of my favorite questions is.
When do you think this is the best job for you?
And when do you think it's not?
That can just open up a world of like here is where I am so energized.
And here's this thing that just drains me and makes me feel like I am not doing my best work and that the, the data that gives you a lot as a manager allows you to then, you know, really start to, to cater to what is unique for this individual.
And by the way, very often, those answers could be very different for every person.
Not the team.
So you know I think so often what we want is to not just be one other person on the team.
One number, we want to be seen as humans and so as much as you can, facilitate questions that really get to that deeper connection than I think, you know, a lot of things start to naturally happen in your so much more empowered as a manager to really have a positive impact on your people.
Yeah, I love everything that you both have said.
I think just to add to this kind of question of, you know, how to create psychological safety.
I think building on Amy's point about powerful questions.
You know, one of the things that we also know really works is this process of active listening and part of that process is asking questions.
But part of it is repeating back.
What you think?
You have heard to someone just kind of pausing and saying okay.
This is this what you're saying, which is an incredibly powerful tool for to Amy's Point making people really feel heard and seen and creating that sense of safety.
Because you can really feel assured that somebody's listening to you, they understand where you're coming from.
And if you don't, if you don't get it right, then, there's that.
Powerful.
Question of, can you help me understand what I am missing?
Right, and I think that too, and we think about how do you, you know, kind of create those.
Conditions of psychological safety can be really powerful and also can help teach you as a manager, right?
Like what you might be missing or what you're what, you're not totally understanding about the person in front of you and reveal some of the assumptions that you might have in those interactions.
So I think it's kind of win-win in that sense.
So good.
I see an up voted question under Q&A Katie, if you can pull that first question up, I think it's related.
But now from the employees perspective, the question is, how do I develop a good relationship with a new manager remotely?
So now then remote brings on another layer and this is from the employee perspective manage, you know, trying to build the relationship with their manager.
What are your thoughts to this question?
Most of my team is actually remote, and I think This goes back to the I often find we ask these questions or will go to HR and ask these questions.
And like, we will have you asked your manager?
I have you ask the employee yet, and I am like, no.
Not yet.
Go talk.
Go talk about it.
There's no right or wrong answer here.
And I think it's like, hey manager.
I would love to develop a relationship with you.
This is typically how I have done it.
I am curious.
Like what can we do together to, to do better there and, and I think it's Lucky that in.
And this might say something about my hiring practices.
I have to look into that, but most of my team is very relationships, based on strengths finder.
So naturally we will, we have conversations, we know, kind of what generates connections on our team and so, we will do more of that.
I make my one-on-ones extra-long now because the conversations I would typically have maybe just randomly in the hallway or because our desks are next to each other, don't happen anymore.
So I am going to make sure that happens, and we even have just It's a monthly hangout that we keep on the calendar.
We can have lunch together and just talk about just, you know, sit around and talk but I think, you know if you have got a new manager, and they haven't done any of those things yet, it's bringing it up with them.
You know, saying, hey, if and if there's a problem already like, it's making me feel a little bit isolated.
I don't feel connected, is there stuff we could do that.
I think that can at least generate more conversation and then idea building from not just you, but then two to the two of you Iran, how to do that better?
Or if you have got colleagues that you can already trust, always great to run things by people.
I don't think we crowdsource enough information and that can be super useful.
So, first things first, I think to start the conversation and see where it goes.
Yeah, I love that.
I know it's funny.
I always really big on.
We need our managers to like start this conversation because it can be so intimidating.
As you know, you come into this organization and you're trying to do these things and like, and you don't know what's.
Okay, and what's not, okay.
And so I have like four questions.
I ask any time, I have a new employee start on my team and all of them have been remote for me, for the last probably six or seven years, because I work remotely for a while, and I was just reading through them and thinking whether I should share them or not.
And I actually think you could flip them is If your manager doesn't ask these that you could actually flip them, and they could still be productive.
So I will just share them really quickly.
So, first one on one, I have with a new employee, I first asked about their family and like, what's important to them and what I try to just you know, get a little bit of like they're their life like who are the people you're working for or most important relationship smoothie and your life and then you know also just kind of asked about like, what times were Work for you.
What's like the ideal?
You know, ideal Cadence because everybody, I seem to work with these days is pretty worried about work-life balance and like, trying to draw boundaries, especially if they're working remotely for the first time.
So we will kind of talk about some of that personal stuff, then I will say fast-forward to a year in the future.
You're thinking, I love this job.
I am so happy.
I feel so successful.
I am really happy.
I made this move like what are the conditions that made you make you feel that way?
So often when people join a company they have this like you know, really A sort of like true north and big picture of what they see, and they want to be with this company for a long time.
So I try to kind of get some of that out.
Then I asked, what are you most excited about?
And what are you most nervous about?
And the nervous one is really helpful to me, because then I can like nowhere, I need to lean in more and support them.
And then I will ask like, what are the qualities of the best manager for you and what doesn't work?
But yeah, I was just thinking I share that because I think there's some of those questions you could ask.
About, like, if I am the employee and the manager, you could say fast-forward a year in the future and you're so happy that you hired me, like, what has happened?
What does that look like?
Or you know, what are you manager?
Most excited about with me starting.
What are you nervous about?
What are the things that are top of mind for you?
So I can help you support them, but I always find that I need like 90 minutes for that first conversation because we get into a lot of (Rich) dialogue.
Could you drop those questions in chat?
Oh yeah.
It's a Polish them a little bit there.
Yep.
I would also say just to kind of build on this theme of question.
Asking one thing that's really interesting about this, is that there's actually quite a lot of evidence about why question asking works so well, to build relationships.
So, I don't know if folks are familiar with.
There was a New York Times article several years ago, 36 questions to fall in love, and it was based on This research by psychologist or there, Aaron who developed questions to help create Kind of intimacy and like relationship closeness in a lab, right?
And the idea being that questions, really helped create this environment of mutual vulnerability and that, that's what really makes people feel closer to each other.
So you know, it makes sense that across different context.
When we're asking people questions, I share a little bit about myself.
You share a little bit about yourself, and we kind of continue to get closer in that way as we reveal kind of more about each other.
So I think those questions that the Amy mentioned, you know, could also set the foundation for other questions.
You know, later on as you develop that relationship, that maybe get a little bit, even more into, kind of who you are, as people, what your values are what you're doing outside of work great.
But there's just one kind of bring that in as well.
And that's a really good.
It's a really good article to.
We can drop the link in there in case folks.
Haven't Just drop it.
Oh great.
Awesome in chat.
That's awesome.
Wow, there's like so much Rich information in the data behind this as well with some of these insights that my mind is processing a lot.
And in fact I would like to bring up one of the questions that came up about.
It's the second one Katie.
How do you communicate and interact well with difficult colleagues?
I am open to new ways to approach this challenge.
So I have seen some of that in chat as well, you know if there is a difficult period Where do you start?
I can, I can share some thoughts.
I mean, I think there's like some level of also just sort of knowing when someone's opened and with their dad and sometimes like there're some relationships where people just they're looking for something different in terms of what they come to work to get and there might be other things that are like, leading to that.
So, just trying to like, lead with curiosity, but also be aware when it might not be a relief.
Check that is going to go beyond, you know, the day-to-day one of my new favorite questions is what would need to be true for dot.
So, you know if you felt like there was a colleague where we're struggling to work together.
Well, like perhaps a question, like what would need to be true for you to feel like we're collaborating really well or, you know, you're getting what you need from me or you know, something along those lines.
To kind of get into some of the way that they're thinking about the relationship, and they might be like, things are great.
I don't have any challenges here or well, you know, I just feel like I need to like, really get down to business more quickly or you like there could be, there could be so many things and I think it's just really hard to guess.
And, so I think coming from a place of, I really want us to have a great working relationship and then you know, asking them what Yes, you can do could potentially give some insight that you just wouldn't be able to guess on your own.
First one is I love that Amy and it also reminds me of, and I am not sure the specific context that this person is asking about.
But I do think in times when you are maybe disagreeing on something or have two different perspectives kind of coming Head to Head.
Another interesting question is What would, what would you have to learn for you to change your mind?
And, you know, I think that's an interesting one, too, because it can help you get a sense of is this person open or not to that kind of first point that Amy was making.
Sometimes folks really might not be open to engaging in might be pretty, you know, stuck on what they think is true, or you know what they think is the way forward and that's fine.
But then that also gets to this question of what is going to be within your control and what's outside of your Troll.
And so, I think that there are certain aspects of a relationship where to save yourself kind of that emotional, you know, involvement recognizing kind of what the boundaries are.
What you're actually going to be able to change in that other person or in your inner relationship.
But I love that perspective of leading with curiosity and really trying to understand the actual kind of kinship that you have first and kind of dive into some of your assumptions.
And what they kind of think is true and what might be better than well as a starting place.
Yeah, and I Dad if you can, I have seen this work, a couple of times as find someone, you know, a coach or a mentor started to talk through this with is even better if you can kind of find someone who you think may be.
If the pain point is around, maybe the way you communicate or the way you think through things, finding someone that might think in that same way to get an idea of like it gave, this were you, what would, what would be some of that reaction because maybe there's something I am missing here and Why we keep butting heads or whatever, it is.
My husband's very different from me, and we act, I constantly use him for a lot of this stuff because he just thinks and processes kind of the same situation in a different way and it helps me catch stuff that I may not catch and then it's also a safe space to have that conversation.
So you can also process I think what you're feeling because I imagine as you go into the conversation, there's already probably emotions coming up to.
So it's hard to maybe step sometimes back and say okay I have Saying this between the two of us, like how can we fix this?
Because now we're just both frustrated in it and kind of maybe angry or something.
So, finding ways to step back a little bit, you know, look at kind of what you're reacting to and why.
So that way, you can figure out what their response kind of is or me.
What's going through their mind?
I would say huge plus, 1 to the coach or Mentor being able to help with this.
I personally have a coach who has helped me with A couple of conversations recently and one of the Frameworks that she shared as well is just kind of the ability to talk about if you are talking about a particular situation to really clearly articulate like the facts of the situation, and then the impact and the, the story you might be telling yourself as well about kind of why something why you think something happened and so detaching.
It If you can from your own assumptions or even just making those assumptions really clear, sure the person.
So, this is what I saw happen.
These are the facts.
This was the impact that I saw that have kind of objectively.
And this is why I may be, I think this happened or why you know that this is a story I am telling myself.
So and I think Amy you're probably familiar with that too.
I think it's it comes from some folks who Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, exactly.
But I think that can also be a great way to share and a way to kind of again, try to not necessarily let your assumptions or your emotions kind of completely drive the conversation.
Not easy.
No, not easy at all.
To your coach and mentorship point.
What if someone is looking for a good coach or Mentor, like, where do they start to find identify a strong relationship like that?
Yeah, so I think one great place to start is, you know, a torch.
We do facilitate those relationships with folks.
So we have a network of many hundreds of coaches and thousands of mentors.
And I think what can be really great about that.
Are you end up in some cases getting paired with somebody who maybe is not?
Ready at your organization and can kind of offer that different perspectives at the same time, I think there can be a lot of value in finding somebody in your organization and being able to kind of learn from that person.
That's maybe a level or two above you, and that person kind of helping you grow in that and that role.
But I think there are, you know, they're both kind of formal ways to go about finding a coach or Mentor, maybe through like a Platform or a program.
But then, you know, I think there's a lot to be said for identifying a person in your organization or maybe in your broader Network and, and suggesting to that person.
Hey, I really admire you, I really admire the work that you're doing.
Would you consider having a conversation with me every month or so or every couple weeks when I would be asking some questions and you don't necessarily if it makes you feel strange or awkward, you don't have done Really frame it in terms of like, will you be my mentor, right?
It can kind of evolved into that.
I know I have talked to some people who have told me like, well that sounds really weird.
I want to just ask somebody to be my mentor you know but you can take a lot of the strategies that we were talking about earlier about.
How do you start to build a relationship with someone, right?
So I think it's the same thing.
Here can kind of start slow and start by telling that person why they matter to you and why you are impressed with them and why you want to learn with them which I think can go.
A long way.
But really kind of starting to identify who are the people that I want to work with or who are the people that I kind of admire and why and what might I want to learn from them.
And how am I?
What I want to model those types of relationships but would love to hear from Amy and Vicki to how they think about that?
Vicky's anything else that you would share?
I don't think anything extra.
It's yeah.
Just kind of reinforcing everything y'all were saying too yeah.
And I mean, you know, we a lot more companies are offering coaching benefits, and so I think even if yours does not, you know, sharing asking your HR business partner or a leader like is there.
Some do we offer?
Like this is there anyone that you would recommend is good to?
I sometimes think for especially if you're new to an organization, you know, finding the hardest part, is finding the person.
And so, you know, that's the power of the network and part of white towards exist is because we want to make it easier for people to find those connections.
So, just would encourage sharing and looking into those types of benefits.
That's great to know.
So we have got believe or not, 15 minutes left.
So I want to start tackling some of these questions in queue.
A we have one that's upvoted, pretty high with the world shifting more and more digital, what more can should companies do for those who prefer an in-person work environment, especially for people, earlier on in their careers, that is such a good question.
And an Engineering Management.
Came to me, he's like, Vicki, I think we need two ships counselor.
He's a Star Trek fan, so he's saying we need a Deanna Troi, and I was like, all right, tell me more.
We started talking through all this stuff, and we realize what we're actually we brought in another manager Iranians of employees.
And we all had this discussion has been going on for months now of like, you know what we actually want is in person connection, and we are trying to mimic it as good as we can and is virtual environment.
But it is hard.
We are on when you're on resume call or meet call or teens, call all day long, you don't want to be on that screen anymore.
And so what we have been talking about is actually, all right, if we do this all company get together once a year.
What's the half-life of that?
Can it be kind of boosted in other ways we virtual events, and then, when do we need to get together again?
And then at what, what size is it?
Just our own team.
So manager and their direct team.
Is it, maybe the department coming together?
So we're still figuring a lot.
That out but one thing we're actually going to test.
So I can't tell you if it's going to work or not, but we have a hypothesis is we haven't really been doing kind of get togethers around like an affinity topic.
So we do these social hours right?
And it's like, okay everyone get together.
Most of our virtual events are in there cooking or trivia or some kind of show like one of those three things lately and so you get the same people kind of going to all those things.
So now we're like well, what if we did one where hey crocheters Knitters come?
Grab your stuff.
Come hang out for an hour.
We're just going to get on Zoom.
You're going to work on, whatever it is.
You're going to work on it.
We're going to talk because we realized because the four or five of us out cared so much about the ship's counselor topic.
We have begun closer because we have these conversations and there's a topic to be discussed.
So we're going to actually try this with kind of more things and maybe I will be like a video game night or something like that and see kind of how that goes.
So I don't think I have got an answer yet, but there's a whole lot of stuff that we're going to test to see if this works.
I love that.
I love that afraid.
He topic groups.
Yeah.
Yeah, it's you really well.
I have lots of opinions on this but I think it's important like contextually.
Every organization is definitely different and has different set of circumstances at torch.
We are remote first at this point.
Most of our growth has happened since the pandemic.
And so most of our teammates have basically joined Julie and stayed virtually.
We do have a few hubs and regions where we have a concentration of people, and we still have a little bit of office presents, but we're at the point now where that's kind of all we do.
But to the point of the question, I mean, you know, I think everyone a lot of people actually my head of recruiting always tells me one of the first questions people often ask is, are you really remote?
And that's like there are people that really want this and even those of us who really like working remotely Like and I really want to see human beings at some point.
So I think that largely what I am seeing is everyone's realizing is that it's not either/or.
It's really, how do you kind of facilitate both things, and so I will just share one thing that we're.
So we're given that we're remote.
First were thinking about how do we really put some systems around getting together and seeing other human beings in person, it naturally happens in the places where we had office space but It's everywhere else where it's not naturally happening.
And so outside of to Vicki's point the org-wide Retreat, and then we also do functional or like smaller team retreats in between we are working on.
We have not figured out exactly how to structure this yet, but we're working on trying to make it easy for people to get together with others in their area, grab lunch, or if they're traveling.
Be able to Ping people that are in the Chicago area and say I am in town.
Anyone want to go grab dinner?
And actually like having some funds associated with that, that were actively encouraging it because very often those like one-on-one I live in a place where, like, I have had several people have come in and out to visit go skiing or something.
And I mean, I remember the lunch that I had with this person or the coffee that I grabbed, this other person in a way that I sometimes, can't remember what meetings I was on, you know, all week, but I will remember and actually there's a lot of research around the way our brain works and that sort of spatial change can actually help things to stick in a way that being on the same, you know, computer screen, like it starts to just really run together.
So, we want to look for those like serendipitous put a little bit of structure behind it, but let people, you know, find each other and find those clusters again, we haven't figured out exactly to structure that because it gets really complicated and the funding of it and the policy and all of that.
But we know there's something there.
I love that.
It was serendipitous moments and changing the environment.
It's good.
Is there anything else?
Elizabeth would you add?
I don't think I would add anything else.
I think they covered it.
I would just say that this is a, it's a challenging thing.
And I think I don't know any organization that really feels like they have figured it out.
So I was just kind of validate.
The fact that everybody, if you're feeling confused going through this, I think you're not.
You're not alone.
Let us go on to this next question, here, how can you scale relationship building processes programs and events within a company from small departments across company-wide?
Yeah, so I think one of the first things that I would say here is relationship kind of relationship building program is one that can really help to scale those efforts.
So for instance, a mentorship program rate is one where you have some formality around.
How people are paired up, for instance, and then maybe there's some guiding questions you have a past that you're kind of being gay.
It through.
So it's not quite as much to you as either the mentor and the mentee to figure out.
What am I doing?
How does this thing even work?
But you're kind of really LED through that process and hopefully that's going to lead to better outcomes for you.
And that also means that if it is an organizational by program, you might get an opportunity to meet with and talk to people from different parts of the organization different functions.
So really kind of creating that type of relationship building that might not happen organically which can be really, really powerful.
So I think that's, that's one thing that I would share that can really be useful and kind of scaling up some of those processes and making it so that it's not just on the onus of or it's not the onus isn't just on individual managers to do all this work individual employees.
I can add a couple of quick thoughts, one, when I think about sort of larger team size, something that, that is a really simple intervention that I love is something that I call question of the day and it's just starting out every meeting every like team meeting or formal meeting.
So, not necessarily a huge group at sometimes.
Well, actually even do it in the chat and our company.
All Hands.
That's just a completely non-work-related.
Added question.
That is just fun.
I have like a spreadsheet of questions that will ask that, just kind of can get people talking and sharing and sometimes I have some crazy stories of how that's like turned into US learning about something that someone, you know, someone turns out that there are musicians, and they have this amazing talent, and then they share the video that they made and then suddenly like Elite one thing leads to another and you just know someone at a much deeper level.
And I think we just I always try to think with HR programs and interventions like, just enough to help people do the right thing and it doesn't need to be this huge program, but just like plant the question and then see what happens.
Another thing I will add is a technology that we just invested in, which is a, a start-up that's called whisk.
And it's w is q and it is essentially their mission is all around bringing more life to work and it is essentially kind of like this combination of Instagram and Pinterest but for The work environment where people can post pictures and share ideas or like a funny podcast that they listen to and people can comment on it.
There're groups and boards that you can join if you're interested in pets or woodworking or knitting or whatever that might be.
And you know, so we're trying to kind of to Vicki's point about around like getting together to work on a common interest.
We're trying to kind of create a place for those things to Bubble Up and populate, and They have a lot of cool things on their road map to where they're going to like create lounges and kind of version of donut dates that people can do through virtual interaction.
It's a there's just trying to we're trying to it doesn't solve the like need for in person but again if you can start to see people outside of their title and there, there's a new screen that can often lead to just these connection points that get people together more, and get them seeing each other as more.
Then just, you know, that, that product manager, that keeps telling me, no, or that HR person that keeps asking me to do this thing.
And so we're trying to just find a lot of different ways to do that.
Yeah.
I think a lot of this is also, you know, do you have someone who can own creating this or not?
And if so, then what is the remit for that?
Like what, you know, what are you trying to accomplish from a program wide level?
Because that does require budget, it does require someone to kind of drive it forward and I have noticed when we have tried to do some things that are like overly consistent, it almost Burns people out, and they don't want to do it anymore, which is you think about how we interact in life, it's very organic and kind of just comes and goes and Ebbs and flows.
And so how do we create more of that?
And I think a lot of it goes back to Leading by example to.
So we have donut installed in our slack to kind of create those conversations with each other.
To create those questions.
I set, slack reminders, in my own team, meetings of like, you know, what are you excited?
About for the weekend, it comes out on Friday.
What, you know what are you looking forward to getting done on Monday and just trying to Pepper things in like that?
We even do things were randomly someone might say in the plant Channel like, hey show us your favorite plant today or in the Dog Channel.
Alright.
It's Friday afternoon with the animals and it's just a spontaneous moment that we try to generate and encourage other people to do random things.
So to Generate some of that and I think it's it is a little bit difficult but just trying to find different ways and just creative ideas and just trying it and if it does is you do it once.
And that's it, I don't think there's anything wrong with that because again goes back to the ebbing and flowing of that's how we talk.
Speaking of Select channels, our team just started a social yell slack Channel where all you can do is type in all caps and it is probably one of the funnest slack channels that you have currently peopled are like, happy Monday and it's like shouting at you, right?
That's so fun.
I am speaking of slack, the one thing that I want to call out, this may be a less.
Exciting scaling opportunity but one that I think is really important, and we were kind of getting at the beginning to is just the consistency of communications, right?
Like I think just if you have a team, making sure that you're responding to people on slack or just kind of doing simple things every day that lead to more trust in relationships.
So I think there's this aspect of it that can be more formal and kind of more planned right around some of these amazing questions that I am beginning even bringing up but then there's also just if my manager responds to me in a timely way that's going to also impact how I feel about my relationship with them or if I am in a meeting with them, and they hear me, and they support an idea, or they kind of give me space to speak about an idea.
That's also going to really impact my relationship with them.
So I think it's important to take into account some of those other smaller, like kind of micro behaviors to that happened throughout the day.
Additional.
And in addition to these kind of special relationship, building things that we might think about doing, So good.
We're already at time.
This topic has been so rich.
Thank you so much.
Vicki, Elizabeth, Amy.
Each of your insights, your experience, your heart.
Your mind that you brought your presence just so grateful for each of you and how you're leading strong relationship building in your organization's.
Today, we're inspired Alright, well, thank you so much for all those who have attended the chat alone as I was going through this event or watching.
It is so rich, so thank you for the insights, the questions you have dropped.
Their, I want to go through the chat and maybe pull some of those insights.
Have a wonderful day, we have our next event coming up.
It will be a few weeks from now with a team.
And with HR transform We have got McGraw-Hill the CEO of a team, the co-founder of HR transform and Kim Roar, who we got that amazing social yell slack Channel idea from she's gonna be on this panel, and we're talking about the rise of cloud based companies, attracting and unleashing top talent in the new world of work.
So it's going to be a great event.
And until then, I hope each of you can invest into those solid relationships and Quality of life.
Have a wonderful rest of your week.
See you later.