Hey, hey, hey, welcome, welcome, welcome.
My name is Robert Ortiz.
And I am the co-founder and CEO of welcome.
The platform that you're on here today, looks like we have people joining from around the country and even around the world, I see doubling the building as he Paris, I see Canada.
If you have not already, please drop your location and where you're joining us from for real Brazil's in the building Boston is in the building.
Great to see this representation.
Here for this event.
I mean, we're talking about remote work and so it's only makes sense to have remote distributed representation here.
Love, love to see it.
You know, I think that the beauty about we're going to get into a lot of the beauty about remote work, but it's a lot of it is to represent it just by even what you're seeing here in chat.
Today, we're going to cover a lot of cool things and insights on what's happening in the remote work World, both personally for us.
Us in the market and into the future, you know?
Today I am actually joining you guys from Philadelphia that's my hometown.
However, I am living and I have moved since the pandemic to Puerto Rico so give me those to all you guys doing from there as well.
Quick housekeeping.
This is I know it's different platform for some of you folks, but we're going to have a strong emphasis on Q&A.
We have two amazing speakers there in the green room right now, they're going to join me on stage, and we want to have a conversation with all of you.
So ask questions come up.
As we get into these topics, please.
Please drop your question in the Q&A tab, on the right-hand side.
If you need any help with, like exploring the platform and such get the help tab on the right-hand side and somebody who love to show you around.
Now, let us go ahead and set the stage set, the table per se.
Why are we here today?
Well, outside of hearing from two phenomenal leaders in the remote work space.
We're here today because We're all being impacted whether professionally or personally by the shift that's happening and the shift that's automatically shifting how we work in changing, how we work.
You know, a couple weeks ago, I was in a gathering with other leaders in business and I joined this breakout session.
It was titled remote hybrid or in the office and the room was packed to the walls and I grabbed a see in the middle of the room because I needed it to listen to this conversation and you I felt the tension in the air, you know, this is like polarizing perspectives that some folks carry about where things should be at.
Is it in the office is a hybrid is a remote the pros and cons of it all and depending on where you stand, it can be very polarising today though, we're diving into the beauty of remote work.
Why it works?
How companies that get it, right?
Have an unfair advantage and what that means into the future.
Now before we kick that off about, why don't we kick off with a quick poll to just quickly pull the audience here.
Today, just would love to understand, where are you working?
Primarily today?
Is it primarily remote, primarily hybrid in office sometimes remote at home sometimes or just purely in the office?
We have a lot of remote only representation here today which is, which is great to see.
Which is pretty.
It makes sense.
Right?
The topics that were covering.
Good to see that.
Looks like a 60% remote only audience here.
So, good to see it.
Now, I am gonna go ahead and get a little bit of speakers.
Backgrounds, it covered.
So maybe let me get myself out the way.
So again, my name is Roberto and welcome is on a mission to help companies change the way they gather engage and Inspire their remote control.
He's, we are fully remote company, and we're doing the technology to empower the distributed Workforce.
Now, Tony Jamis who's joining us as well.
He is the co-founder and CEO of oyster.
If you have not learned about what you need to learn about oyster, they're changing the way you recruit and connect with employees around the world, he is an again, he is the founder and CEO of oyster and there are Global and Schmidt platforms that empowers companies higher pay and care for their teammates regardless of where they are, Tony is also a future of work activists.
Are we going to get into that in a minute?
Passionate about the global benefits of distributed work and how that's changing worldwide.
And how that's the impact that's having on both people and the economy and Chris heard?
He's the founder and CEO of First Base.
You probably seen both of these guys, flooding your Twitter, and/or your LinkedIn because I know I always tune in whenever these guys are posting and Chris leads first base, which is a hard word as a service platform that enables companies to set up manage and retrieve all physical equipment of remote workers and their needs.
Chris, founded first based on the belief that everyone should have more time with the people that care about most all while doing their best work.
So guys, Why don't you guys put it together and chat?
Give it up for both Chris and Tony who's joining us here on stage.
Anyone Tony Chris, good to see you guys?
Hey, thanks for joining us.
First of all, I think, you know, we were just talking about in The Green Room.
I have been looking forward to this conversation quite a bit.
I have gotten to know you guys and different levels as well.
But to have this representation on stage to talk about remote work, I can't think about two other people besides you two to drive the conversation.
So, thank you for being here.
Well, thank you for welcoming us on the welcome platform.
Yeah, absolutely.
So really quick.
Small fun fact as well.
You know doing some background on both of you guys.
We all live in different parts of the world, and we call home to different parts of the world, and we all live on an island in different parts of the world which is really fascinating you know, home for me is Puerto Rico Chris, you're in Scotland and Tony you in Cyprus in the middle of the Mediterranean which is In to see that, you know, I talk to people all the time.
I would never thought my wife and I always dreamed of going back to Puerto Rico and I will, we stop that.
I can't do that because I am building a tech company.
I am trying to progress my tech sort of career.
And here we are right doing that living where we want to live and building what we want to do build.
So in the core of our conversation you know we're going to be breaking up our conversation into three pillars.
Number one is the A personal impact of remote work and how to get that right for ourselves.
And what we're seeing is best practices because we know the shift to remote work.
It starts with us personally, I do, we have the right things in place for us to succeed personally, as we take on remote work, number two, the impact and the market, that remote work is having on the market.
And the, lastly, how is remote work shaping the future and those are the three key areas.
So don't, why don't we kick off with the first one?
Which is Around the personal impact of remote work.
So, with all that I already covered is pretty clear to say that we're all Champions over about work outside of building companies, for remote work, outside of building distributed teams.
We're also impacted personally by remote work.
So, just the first question.
How has remote work impacted both of you on a personal level?
And if you can unpack that for us here today, Tony when we Compass here.
Yeah, so it's really gives gave me freedom and flexibility to design the life that I want to live.
So, starting from where I want to live to how I want to work, how much time I want to spend with my children, how much I want time, I spend on myself, so, so just to give you some examples of how I do this.
So as you mentioned, I live on the island of Cyprus, I have always thought Cyprus Was the most beautiful country in the world 17 years ago, when I was there and, and, and, and that opportunity enabled me to pick where I want to live in the world in a place that I want to call home.
I spent the last 40 years of my life, pretty much all my life living in cities, chasing job opportunities and in London and Bay Area and Paris and so on and so forth.
And I just, I am done with living in cities.
I don't want to live in cities and for me, when I wanted to start this company, I It to work for me, first and foremost.
So it gave me a takes ability of location.
It gave me also the opportunity to design the life, I want to have.
So I don't work in the morning because most of my team is in Europe and in the u.s.
Time zone, so I work in the afternoon and in the evening.
So I spent the morning with my children, exercising doing whatever I want to do and in the afternoon I have a one-hour where I can spend with my children On the beach to connect with them and then Friday we don't do meetings.
We called it focused Friday where it enables me to, to get stuff done.
That.
I need to get before going to the weekend, and then we completely disconnect over the weekend.
So but that cannot be possible.
If the organization doesn't allow that.
So we can talk about this.
Maybe later in the conversation is that it's it has to be something that is shared this way of living as See, this Freedom across the organization.
Yeah, let us get into that on the second half of this topic because I think that it's important to, I mean, we you just switch on remote.
It doesn't take care of all the problems.
It has to be wrapped in intention and discipline has to be part of that.
But Chris fill us in on your remote sort of like how has it impacted you and by the way Tony and Chris are Super Active fathers, and they both have little babies right now as part of not just running a global company.
But also Raising kids and promote life, just changes that.
And so Chris, why don't you fill us in on that impact for you?
Yeah I think echoing well of for Tony said it was a quality life decision for me as well.
Miss. my first daughter walking laughing talking for the first time working in an office.
Had that question in my head which I remember having a conversation with my dad where I was like, this sucks.
Right?
Like, why am I missing the events to my kids lives?
He's like, that's how Oh, it's Gotta Be.
You gotta work to put a roof over your kids heads.
And I think for me it was like, well maybe it doesn't have to be like that.
And then founded my first business, we had a bunch of Discovery around all the challenges in operating that way.
And then eventually we came to build first base and I think what's became important for me over the time between having that realization and today, and all the things I have done since then it's probably the realization that no other time in history, could I be doing what I am doing today.
We were speaking about this beforehand where we have raised a bunch of money from some of the most prominent investors in the world without ever stepping foot in San Francisco.
And until it was recently as two or three years ago, that would have been impossible.
And I think like, yeah, Tony speaks about this a lot, the ability to democratize access to opportunity is a huge part of this.
There are incredibly talented people all around the world and being able to give them access to the best opportunities globally is such A huge enabler, whether it's single parents whether it's people with health conditions or impairments, but there's people that Just Can't Get Right visa to work in some of the more affluent parts of the world.
So that's being the real driver for me, trying to make that change.
And obviously personally having that impact with my kids, my family while still being able to do the best work I have done in my life.
Now that no doubt thanks to Sharon, and I like to jump in and add I was with what Chris said is that It also enabled me to reduce my carbon footprint and also great.
Gain more stability in my life.
So before starting this company, I was, I was a CEO of another company and used to spend half of my time every month in another continent.
I was in constant jet lag and when I took my transition to move this company, I run the numbers and see what's, what is my CO2 footprint?
And 90% of it was air travel.
And I want to be able to live and work and lead a successful company without the need to continuously be on a plane.
Now, in-person meetings are important, and we can touch base on why they are uncertain to make promote work.
But, but it has, it doesn't need to be the case to get stuff done.
So you can massively reduce your carbon footprint as a human, when you work from remotely.
Yeah, yeah, no doubt, no doubt.
You know, it's interesting.
Now, every time I travel, I first always start with the question of why like, is this, this is this trip.
Really, really necessary.
And typically it's not.
And now, when you go into running a company and let us say, way into that, because Tony you touched on this first.
Second here, around being set up for success in a remote.
You know, remote first remove oriented sort of culture, you know, just one thing just today.
I am in Philadelphia, I am visiting family.
I have been out here for a couple of weeks, and I was just like, mind-boggled, because I was sitting in traffic and I typically don't sit in traffic to go to work.
I am flipping anywhere, we walk into my office, and I am sitting there for an hour and it just Crazy.
Sort of like, I was taken aback by.
This was my normal for ten years.
I commute it two hours back and forth to work back in my early career, and I am glad that we don't have to do that but now as Leaders of companies and people managers and Chris you touch about this as well.
Like, you know, remote working remotely takes discipline, it takes attention, both discipline at the individual level, it takes attention.
In it takes trust leading with trust and assuming with trust.
What can companies do to help?
Like to help them succeed and to shift to remote?
Like if I am a people leader leading a team, and I am jumping into remote or my company just went remote friendly?
What are some of the things I could be doing to improve how we work remotely?
What are those things that come to mind for you guys?
Chris.
Yeah, this is a conversation.
I have had with everyone from exacts of global Banks to friends and family who live a globally.
And often the question I think becomes from an office first perspective, like how do you trust your people to do the work and the push back to?
That is really easy which is like you hire people without trusting them.
And like I think there's still a world in which that's true, right?
Like you spend all this time interviewing people, you check that they have these competencies and now you're not going to trust them to do the things that they want to do and I think to your point the commuting things I think Super interesting.
You look at that, the way we used to live as people spending 90% of their day getting ready for traveling to sitting in an office and by the time they get home, they have missed their kids, they leave before their kids.
Wake up, they got home after the kids have gone and bad their Partners exhausted.
They have got no time for friends.
Families and hobbies.
And we wondered like, why are people not enjoying work?
Well, it's because they're sat in an office chair night and 5, and they don't have any time to do the things that make them happiest, which enables them to do, the best work that they have ever done in their lives.
And I think the final thing which I hear a law, which is how do we do it right?
Like, how do we do this thing?
We don't understand that and what typically that happens is, we're going to wrap Replicate the office remotely rather than leveraging, the benefits of remote.
And I think companies that begin remote, they maximize that they have more written culture, they communicate asynchronously more.
Tony, I spoke about the focus Friday, so carving out that time to do deep focus work without distractions, companies are just going to replicate the 925, they're going to track people's clicks.
They're never actually going to get any of the true benefit of remote work.
And I think getting over that hump and recognizing the status quo Me different.
That's maybe the two biggest things I see.
Yeah, the data you know was interesting Chris about that is 12 company's responsibility on.
Putting these Frameworks in place you know, Freedom Fridays.
It was a focus Fridays.
It sounds like Freedom Fridays in my mind as well, freedom from meeting, but yes, but it's also like personally as an individual, I have to change as well, because if I, if I was already working 10 years and that was my Norm habitually.
I already, you know, running out the door.
This does this, do this.
Now I have control of my time.
What does that look like?
How do I put things in place?
That bring me life, that set me up.
Well, because for some people that commute and listening to Joe Rogan on the way to work, was there your transition from life to work and now us individually.
Working remotely, we have to build what works for us, and that takes some tension and it takes a lot of discipline to do that as well.
Tony, I know, Do you have a lot to say about this stuff as well?
We love to pull up to here.
Three things that I see a so company.
And we did as well as we adopted a successful remote work.
Model one is to intentionally build trust.
This is important because as you work remotely, you don't have these emotional signaling that come with body language and so it's harder to build trust in a remote environment.
So you need to be intentional and building trust it You part of our, one of the three values we have posters about.
What we do is we build trust and how we do it is by creating the maximum amount of safety, emotional safety for people not to be afraid to make mistakes, not to be afraid to say something wrong, is to be there for people when this happened and support them on that journey and it's a lot about storage from the top, right?
So the way you as a leader react to bad news, determine for instance, how the Company is coming to consider emotional safety and build trust.
We talk a lot about assuming best intent.
You have to have the default mode as you are in a remote work environment to assume that the other person has with the good intention.
Whatever these thoughts that you have in your brain, you have let them go and focus on best intention.
That's number one is building.
Trust number two, is you need to be very specific in how you measure and Define results.
Because you're not anymore.
Assessing people on their presence in the office when we moved from the Industrial Revolution, from the factory to the office, we kept some of these managerial techniques of measuring people on how many widgets they produce or how much time they spend in the office.
And then so, so that ship in how we measure performance has to change.
And, and it has to be a more intentional process to set goals, from the company, level to the individual level.
And thirdly is to be clear of how you work together, what are the tools and the rules about collaboration of the company.
You need to put train people on it.
You need to model the way you as a leader, and you need to evolve it over time.
So three things, building trust having result driven culture and, and be clear about the tools and the rules.
And, and by the way, like even if you're in office company and you do these three things, you get better.
Moving to the note, exposes your weaknesses as an organization and become a forcing function to address some of these high performance Behavior, building trust, having clear results, having clear way of collaboration.
That's why I believe that the distributed company on through tomorrow are going to be the best companies now da, da Tony thanks for breaking it, breaking it down that way.
You know I think the one thing that stands out from that is going remote exposes.
All the gaps because you have nothing else to stand on.
But good process, good tools, good ways of working without that, everything just falls apart.
You know, let us shift gears into the impact that remote is having in the market.
You know?
Like we were part of these conversations all the time, you know, 24/7, Chris Tony myself.
We're involved in these conversations because we're Using for this future, where I not only for ourselves individual, he's for our families, but also for our teammates, and the technology, we're building.
The services were building is powering that shift as well.
But when you look at the reports that are coming up, you know, every week, there's another report about the benefits of remote what employees want.
There's, the war of the office and not office City, Teas or empty Office business.
Buildings are empty.
Even after companies are trying to perk, put all the perks, put the Rhode show on and get people with come back to the office.
It's pretty clear that employees want flexibility, they want freedom if we bring up this Forbes overlay there was this report recently cited around just the simple fact that remote is here to stay and it will continue to increase.
But what I found interesting about the They was that ninety percent of people surveyed found, it promises more productive remote.
The impact on their mental health was better and even post pandemic.
They're saying, this is what I want.
I want remote to be a permanent fixture in how I work.
And, and the way that I work, the voice, the voices of the employees.
Come back really drastically on that.
However, there's been resistance As well from leaders and companies on this argument as well.
You know, I don't know which one of you may be that said, this, but it was something around the fact that this is the biggest shift that we're seeing in Tony, you touched on this recently, as well, kind of taking this back to the Industrial Age, this is the biggest shift we're seeing in 100 years in how we work.
Being able to hire people from around the world, being able to go to schedule, run your life versus around work, being able to get two hours back a day and commute being able to, for me, make pancakes for my little girl, every morning and to tuck her in every night.
That's, that's all that I know, I don't know, no other type of fatherhood, but that's my normal today and that's changing is going to have an impact on her life.
Is going to have an impact on my life and on our family's life.
How would you both?
With.
Summarize or articulate the actual shift that we're in because I every conversation I am in.
I have to bring people back to.
We're just in the beginning of the shift that when we look back 10 years from now, we're going to see, you know what, that to three year spans that five-year span that was the biggest shift, but we're just in the middle of it.
And sometimes we don't realize how big of a shift it is.
How would you articulate the shift that were undergoing right now?
You know, take off first or nay So far, it's Chris Cole.
Yeah this is a conversation.
I have with a lot of particularly investors, journalists friends family and I think there is a lot of Doubt, right?
There's a lot of media articles that are written by Rich real estate owners that will tell you the office is coming back.
And if you look at the date that they are doesn't really support that.
And when you dig in with people who the least offices, they don't support that either.
The more people I talk to Single day.
The more they tell me that they haven't the least new space in the last three years, and they won't the least new species space in the next 2.
So the belief that people can even go back to the office, even if they want to, is totally false companies.
Don't have enough space.
And I think, like, the second component is the best companies of today are leaning heavily into remote work.
You look at Airbnb doordash twilio You Yelp all of them have announced in the last couple of months that they're fully remote and that's a forcing function, right?
If the most desirable jobs are remote, the most talented people will go and work for those businesses, and they will Force the other companies to become more remote.
I spoke to Cal Newport about this as like a darwinian moment.
For remote work Evolution, eventually the most remote companies were in, and they kill companies aren't removed and people don't believe that and My approach to that has been well, what metaphor can we used to help them understand that and the one that I have kind of settled on is the rise of e-commerce on the internet, right?
Go back to the early, 2000's.
How much stuff did you buy on the internet then?
Like, even when eBay was first around, I am Amazon with burst around hardly anyone.
But hardly anything online by 2010, that changed the law, right?
I am as in matured ebayid, matured more people, some people bought some things online fast-forward too today.
Almost everyone buys, almost everything online, cars houses you order your food and it turns up at your door.
And I think like taking that piece where we started, which is like, this is the most important shift in 100 years.
Well, let us recognize how big a platform shift is.
It's the end of probably 30 years of innovation, right?
Mobile Computing, the internet communication software.
R like this, we have needed all this.
And I think the inevitable conclusion of that is you can work with anyone anywhere in the world irrespective of their geographic location.
And yeah, I think the consequence of that is that it's the biggest shift in 100 years It is pretty clear and pretty, pretty clear, Chris that you have been talking about this and thinking about this, for some time I get it.
That's, that's good stuff.
I will come on Tony.
Yeah, yeah, I mean it is a massive shift, and I am going to tell you what is driving that shift.
I mean, like, what is like, even this is a macro micro world we live in today.
Me give you some data point.
According to BCG even pre-pandemic, there were 90 million job remote knowledge, work job going unfulfilled in the west that's eight point.
Five trillion dollar of economic loss.
At the same time.
In the next 10 years were going to have 1.5 billion knowledge workers coming into the workforce, mostly in emerging economies.
That's the biggest demographic shift in workers demographic since the Industrial Revolution.
Combined, with what Chris said, at the maturity of Internet platform, collaboration software and the infrastructure that Chris is building for remote work.
It's going to enable these millions of people to participate in the global economy, Bryan Caplan Economist from George Mason University.
Argues in his book, open borders that if you remove the concept of borders from Talent Mobility we can triple the world GDP 3x and knowing how much growth this capitalistic system needed to sustain itself?
I don't see any scenario in the future That doesn't enable these companies in the west to tap into this massive talent pool that is coming online in the next 10 years.
No doubt, no doubt.
I have you know, you have been talking about the impact to the economy, not just a shift in like, how we work, but the shift and unlocking opportunity, I am not going economic power.
I think about even the work that you're doing right now Tony with making it easier to hire people from around the world.
The impact that has on that person on R household, their family on their generation without them having to leave their family in the first place.
You know, a lot of people leave from they leave their family behind to go earn some income and better enrich their families back home.
Now, with this shift, what we're saying is, you don't have to leave, you can stay where you are.
We're going to enrich that unit and change that life, and that, that household as well, which is even the undercurrent of all of this.
There's this other shift, that's On a global scale, not just on the headlines of what we see, not just what he line puts out on Twitter and not just what, you know.
Somebody else who says in office is the only way.
It's the global scale to the impact that this has on the economy, which is really, really great to see, you know, one thing I have this overlay, I am going to bring this up, you know, Tony your team has put out an employee expectations report recently, and it's pretty clear in the fine.
Things that parties just have changed, right?
44 percent of remote work says, it's the top three factors in their ideal companies.
They're looking for remote work as a thing there.
Expect 60% of them are expected to be able to work from anywhere, from their employers, and eighty, eighty percent of folks are saying that it's become so much, much more important since a pandemic for them to work remotely.
And, you know, numbers don't lie like when you have these conversations.
The folks us as Leaders, we're always hiring, folks.
I can't imagine saying I am not going to hire the best person best qualified person for the job regardless of where they're located because they're not willing to step foot into the office.
This is part of that big shift, the big shift I feel is like not just We have the technology to enable us to connect and work remotely.
Not just that there's been two years of us being forced to work remotely and productivity has gone up and the world continues to go around.
But also I think the sentiment for us as people to say, you know what, like work is always been super important to me, but in recent years, what I have realized is that my life is more important to me and giving all these hardships that we're going through in the world.
This reprioritization at the it was really pushing the investment of remote because of employees that want to show up at the office.
Then what, what options do employers have?
I posted an article recently?
I think was yesterday that showed from a survey, a poll server that you're giving out in the market employers, want these many days, these many days of work from home, only employees when these many days.
And what's happening is the chart is showing that companies are Moving towards what employees want?
Because employees control that story, which is, which is great to see, you know, Chris I when I see your pink background, show up in my Twitter or my LinkedIn and I typically just stop scrolling to see what's up.
You have clearly had taken a strong stance on remote and you get into these back-and-forth with folks that have these opposing views and it's a great to see.
And it's Great content.
What, what, what have been, some of your, you know, your learnings from that because you're in it every single day, you're having these conversations, it threads?
What has been your learnings from being vocal and taken the stance on both sides of the party?
Because I am sure you're getting opposing views that try to shoot down a post that you put up?
Yes, I think some people have extremely strong reactions to some of the things I say, and I think that's good, right?
Like this is a grand experiment at the end of two years of incredibly difficult times in people's lives and I think it's important to shine a light on that.
Not everybody doesn't want the same thing, right?
Like you look at the day to Leo's day, I was maybe the most interesting what they released.
99% of people never want to go back to an office again, full-time.
That's a fact, for a, 50% of people never want to go back to an office at all.
That's a fact, two or three percent of people do want to go back to the office.
And I think there's a real danger that 23 percent are Extremely Loud.
They're disproportionately and management position, so they're going to determine what other people do and that's a problem.
I think your point on The, the amount of work that people want is super interesting, right?
I think those numbers come out with something like two point.
Eight days a week is what?
Workers want, employees want to give them 1.2.
And I think that is very interesting and it's very interesting because I think we need to name the white elephant in the room, which is everyone for the most part, there were only three million remote workers in the u.s.
Prior covid.
There's going to be 30 million plus immediately after there is going to be someone something like 80 million by 2030.
They want to point eight days.
At the end of a pandemic in the worst possible remote working conditions.
They couldn't travel, couldn't see their friends, they couldn't see their families, their homeschooling their kids.
So, they have had pandemic remote work, and they still want to point eight days at home.
Wait, until they got the intangible benefits that we have experienced right being able to live where you want being able to travel, more being able to Your kids.
And I think that's the most important part, right?
We me and Tony are companies build the Bullring Dusty unsexy part of remote work, right?
We build the infrastructure that enables teams to choose it really easily.
We can stay here all day and talk about the future work until we go blue in the face.
Why I really care about is the future a living and that's the real conversation I like to have with people, which is like, let us not just talk about work, but like what's the impact?
What's the outcome?
We told our own stories.
Right, Rob, you're in Pittsburgh, Tony is Miss. Tilly.
Now I am going to lie down, we can't get in crisper, we can't get pissed, buried in Philly or be used as we got two NFL teams and then it's like, it gets messy, it gets messy.
But yeah, it like the real is everyone has a story and when you speak to someone you learn about them.
And yeah, that's what really matters here.
How can we enable that?
How can we build a bridge to a better future a living for billions of people globally?
Let us segue into that their topic here, because we're going to get into some audience Q&A.
And I want to make sure we respect for will be also times as well.
Just a reminder, if you have questions, I am sure you guys have a lot of questions.
Let us go ahead and drop those questions in the Q&A tab.
On the right-hand side of both the ones you want.
We will cover them here in a few minutes.
Let us segue into the third part of our conversation which is the impact in the future of work.
And I mean Chris you just said it you beat me to the punch here.
But you said this countless times when I think it's really intriguing that it's not the future of work is the future of living and will love to unpack that a little bit more because, you know, yes, we have shared it us three.
Yes, we have it benefits us as well, but we're legit and living, we're living the story, we're living the, the benefit of remote and the impact that has on our living and what that means to us, Chris.
I mean what was in it.
I mean you're talking about this stuff all the time what was that shift in your mind?
Because future workers been always a thing.
And I think organically, we have all just been having these conversations in our homes, with our partners, with our friends and say you know what like we have come to a Tipping Point that the last few years have been completely nuts on a Global Spectrum.
Mm, and you start to prioritize things, you know, I don't know if I want to give up all these other things in my life, to show up at this job or to work at this place and parties, have shifted data is proving that Chris, what can you do in fact that just a little bit more the future within Crossing that office, saying let us change the mindset to just the future of living and starting from that place and then figuring out Work in that world.
For sure, I think that started with a conversation which begins with like four of the first principles of why like, why do people want remote work and where we got to with that?
And we're often begins is all this work led to Broken ways of living and you start to unpack that and you say, okay, what does that mean?
Well, if you go back 50 years, people spent more time in their local communities that were affiliated with churches.
There was boot clubs, there was net in clubs and like whatever your feelings are about any of those things, like unquestionably people were more plugged into their Community, they were closer their friends, they were closer or their families and as the work they elongate people commute it for longer, they got less of those things.
And like the office today is this Adult kids club distraction Factory filled with ping pong tables and games consoles, where it's actually incredibly difficult to do your work.
And the reason for that is they want to keep you there for longer, right?
That's the way to maximize productivity.
Well, actually, like, perhaps there's a better way of working here, which is, if you start to trust people, you give them what they want.
The implication of that is they have a higher quality of life because they can travel more, and yeah, that lets not aim for a better future.
Work.
Who cares about that?
Let us aim for a better future a living.
So much easier and deeper way connect with people engaging with them on a real conversation.
No doubt, I love that.
I would love Crossing all the future work.
It just changes where you start from and you're starting from you first not the job, you're asking yourselves those deeper questions of why work?
What is the means to the end?
Is it, you know, it goes back to this one story or tail around.
Like, you know, like we have just been wired to work, work, work at all expenses and you're working, so that you can provide for your family.
So, You can spend time with your kids, so that you can do all these things.
And what I love about this shift is starting their first and asking how does work impact my life not the other way around, you know, Tony would love to get your thoughts on is segueing into the future a little bit broader than bike.
The now, let us go further out.
Let us go five years out and let us take, let us wrap up this conversation with.
Where are we going like Beyond?
And the impact on the shift that we're in right now.
How is this going to change cities?
How is it going to change real estate?
How is it going to change a ton of did?
I mean, there's a ton of things that would that's going to change over.
The next five years will love to Anchor.
Their what are some predictions?
What are some thoughts?
Some trends that you guys are seeing Tony would love to start with you.
And Chris, we can wrap up with you and we will go into Q&A here.
There are certain prediction that I would like to see happening in the next five to ten years and I will start with the more equal pay for equal work across the world.
It's a very charged topic, and we have seen some data that is encouraging a toaster because we employed people, we have all the employment data.
If your remote worker employed from an Emerging Market employed, for a company in the west, you at least can double your salary from local.
It's right.
So that's a huge impact on many developing economies, especially as you shift, the direct investment from north to south and add more investment into these economies than just remittance which is today, most of what economists get.
So number one is really about moving into a world.
Transfer economy, the 1.5 billion I mentioned earlier, secondly, is a like to see this to create an opportunity for increasing diversity and Workforce, think about just think about gender diversity now.
Now, half of my team are women with Children, what?
Why it's possible for technology company we to have over 60 percent of their Workforce.
Women in 70 countries is because we were able to provide its Civil way of working that makes people successful and no matter how they want to work.
And, and so, so I would like to see a world where there's, there's more diversity.
Presented representation, thirdly, is, is really around the decline of urban areas and, and the so.
So we today, we pour the equivalent of four times, New York City in concrete to build urban areas in the world.
That is not sustainable and a big majority of people that lives in the city, don't want to leave the city, they are forced to be in that place.
Now some people might decide to want to be in cities and that's great, but many of the population in urban areas don't want to be in urban areas.
So, so I do expect that we're going to see the Revival of secondary cities countries by the living was going to become More than norm, and what's going to happen that means that people are more connected with their communities.
People are more connected with nature and that has an impact on mental health and as well as the environment, right?
Because you if you're if you don't need to commute and if you're reducing your consumption footprint because you're not in a consumption world.
You know, I last time I was in New York like I was wondering what else?
But I am going to buy next like I had This feeling that suddenly that all these advertisement in my face, and all these shops, like, this didn't want to sell me stuff, but I don't want to buy.
And, and so, so it's really an opportunity to, to get out of this consumption trap that we have been fed by big Corporation.
And, so I do see that to be a very important move for Humanity.
No doubt, no doubt love it.
I mean, I think I The future, the future is bright.
According to those key things crisp top three on your side.
I know you put a long list post recently about the this as well, and then we will get into open Q&A for the last 10 minutes here.
Yeah, I think for me the biggest one which seems most obvious to me that maybe is still most contrarian.
Is that a majority of the desk jobs globally will be done remotely and majority of the time by 2030?
Like to me that seems inevitable.
So inevitable.
It's barely worth speaking.
About lot of people disagree with that.
Number to the best companies will spend over 75 percent of their time, working asynchronously.
Again something I see growing incredibly quickly in the fastest growing tech companies.
Go boy, typically, that's a trend that's extrapolated elsewhere, right?
Wherever the tech companies do most people fall and then the final one, which relates to, the is a rise in the, the need for Quality writing, I think it's a skill that gets and has been lost in offices.
Where the loudest person in the room often wins, and that shouldn't be the case.
It's the people who have The best ideas who change the world and I think that piece is incredibly important which again, is something I see playing out in a lot of businesses.
No doubt, no doubt love it.
You know, part of me is like, this, everything you guys are saying I am like over here, snapping my fingers, and I am pretty sure a lot of folks that are watching are as well.
Let us get into Q&A.
I see a lot of things happening in chat.
If we get it to the top questions here for free guys, to upvote your most you most potent question here will get the top ones about it onto the stage so kicking off with Jen.
How do you help create a hybrid environment or remote opportunities?
For jobs that are Hands-On and can't be completely.
Remote example in person education.
And if you guys want to take that one, I think the first I think we need to realize that there's a there's some on the quality in the world between the people that can remove the work and the people that cannot remote work, and we have to acknowledge that, right?
And I am hoping that the remote movement is going to create more human such an environment that everybody else in the work environment can benefit.
Now to answer this question directly is there?
There's Way to design your, your field work in a way that can be compatible with remote.
So anything that requires field presence, you are on the field, we're doing the work everything in, it does not require your field present can be done remotely, but again, this is cannot be your choice as an individual.
It has to be a choice of your team of your company to allow that to happen because you don't want to be in a case where you lose productivity or you lose opportunity to progress if you're not in the office.
So anything that can be done without being in this place, in a specific place can be done remotely, but the own field activities has to happen in Jama and person.
Yeah, no doubt uses an interesting one because you know if you're building a car and you need it like to go and service this car, that's a Hands-On type of job and there's always going to be times that I think would get really interesting is the knowledge worker side of that.
And I think 20 years I mean is there're parts to the job that could be very well be done promote week and there're parts that maybe right now can't and I think it will be interesting ten years from now.
I think it's gonna be a lot of change to even how we think about things today because there's we're going to keep evolving and keep changing how we work.
As we move forward.
Let us take the next question from Rebecca.
Looks like also interested in culture and how we build culture remotely culture, seems Then Fall to trust and feel.
Feel much more like Consultants.
I think just kind of also Rebecca just to add to this.
I saw a lot of chatter and chat about trust and how do we and Chris you talked about we hire for this?
We're hiring somebody, we trust that they can get the job done.
How does this play a part in building a remote culture that's built on?
Trust Chris what are you seeing on your side?
As you're building up first base?
I don't Love Culture, I often hear like it's always companies, talking about culture, that shouldn't be trying to protect the culture they have.
So I think that's like where I would start for I prefer and why speak about is I much prefer to talk about community and how can we hire people that are community and I think the extension of that which Tony mention touched on earlier, is just because we're remote, first doesn't mean that we never spend time.
Together, physically.
Like, there're often times that you do want to come together and that does enable you to build those relationships.
And I think often actually it's worth acknowledging that in person is better for some things, but when you acknowledge that, you almost have to say, well, how much better?
And it's not 50% better, right?
Maybe it's like somewhere between zero and 20% better depending on how much time you spend with someone.
But the more time you spend with someone the closer is zero, it gets and you then have this, I guess, matrix by which you can make determinations on, when you should do certain things together to build the community, to build communication to build collaboration skills, No doubt.
You know, it's interesting because this coach or thing is it is a term that's thrown around a lot, quite a bit, you know.
I think also just if we build the rules on the tools effectively for us to engage in work together, a lot of these things take care of themselves but a lot of times we're been thrown into this world of figure out remote without having that in place.
And we get into this like weird gray area of like, well, I don't see this person online.
What is that?
It.
Well our do you have the proper performance things in place and these are the conversations that lead to this tension oh Mark says I think is very similar to this.
How do you keep a remote only Workforce motivated and create trust and absence of physical team, building opportunities and I think?
So for us, we're remote team, and then we gather folks for a company on sites.
Periodically.
And that there is nothing.
You can replace us breaking bread and happen at meal or engaging in certain activities together that builds more connection.
And it's for us personally we are investing in remote first practices and tools and making time for us to connect face-to-face, periodically and the times, and we would connect face-to-face.
They're W, we're not talking about work, a lot of the times you were doing things that you don't typically can kick.
You can typically handle on video or a phone call, and we have done.
We have done that you know last year we do another one this year and that one day that we brought people together just injected this sense of community.
Chris back to your point is like the sense of belonging like these are my people and then I am going to climb back on my plane, and I am gonna go live where I live.
But now, I broke bread and strengthen that connection as well with my peers.
Chris Tony.
However, you guys looking at team building opportunities in this remote world, Yo, I will start, I think 1st grade question.
And you need to have a purpose in your business Beyond just printing money, right?
So that's going to create a lot of alignments and Clarity of purpose for the team.
So first is really you have to be clear about your mission and you have to live your mission.
Secondly is you have to listen too.
The employee.
So we do employment surveys to place a quarter.
The results are taken extremely seriously, they come to me as a CEO, and we talked about them and you should team meeting.
And then we plan ahead and communicate back what we're planning.
So that, and we have been having engagement in the company of top 2% of all these tobacco companies because you have implemented that constant feedback group of listening.
Yeah.
And I want to say, In-person meetings are important, but they're not important to get stuff done.
They're important to make you feel the trust.
And when we did our first executive in person, team meeting at oyster was November.
Last year, was 10 of my 10 people in my team.
One of them came to be, my VP product came to be saying before this meeting.
I knew, I could trust this team.
Now I can feel I can trust him to the difference between knowing and feeding.
They're both important.
But you don't need them necessary to.
You don't need to, to meet to get stuff done.
We need to meet to know certain things that you can build trust with other people.
It's good, it's good.
Well, look, this brings us to the end of this conversation and now ended their I think it is a good place to end the difference between knowing and feeling around trust with your team, your remote team look at the end of the day, this is an amazing conversation.
We're talking about remote work, how is changing the way that we work.
Chris Tony, thank you for being here.
Everyone tuning in, thank you for being part of the conversation, and we will see you were Living.
Now in the future of work, we're changing the story from the future of work to the future of living.
Prioritize yourself for start from there.
Figure out work around your life, not the other way around guys, thanks again, Chris Tony for joining us everyone for making this event happens.
Have a good week.
See ya, thank you.