Hello and welcome.
I am smarter Jaffe, co-founder and general manager of HR transform, which is the ecosystem bringing together.
People driven Executives investors and entrepreneurs.
All re-envisioning, the new world of work.
Thank you for joining us on this Monday.
As we kick off the week, I want to call out a special, thank you to our partners.
Welcome and a team for hosting this conversation with us today.
Really looking forward to learning from the great panel of speakers that we have and helping you all and thinking about your own cloud-based company, and teams, we have three amazing leaders.
Who each bring different perspectives to the conversation and have a wealth of knowledge to share with you?
I am going to be joined today by three speakers Justin sing Chief transformation and strategy, officer at McGraw-Hill Raphael who's on Founder and CEO of a team and Kim Roar head of employee experience at an oyster before I bring them on stage.
I wanted his dive in few housekeeping items.
The session will be recorded and will provide you a recap in the video following the event today.
Please use the chat window to introduce yourselves kind of talk with each other and engage in the conversation.
Please also feel free to submit questions in the Q&A section or vote up others.
Questions we will get to as many of those As we can and the time today.
And then, if you're having any technical issues, please use the help chat and the welcome team will jump in to support you.
Now, let me welcome Justin Rafael and Kim to the stage.
Hello.
Hello, welcome.
Welcome.
Well it's so excited to get this conversation going.
Before we do that instead of kind of the traditional bios, I am hoping each of you could share one of fun fact about you and let us begin with Justin.
Thank you for Marcus Lee thrilled to be talking to you all today and everyone online.
My fun fact is I grew up on University campuses Particularly from where I am from Australia, the University of Melbourne and so that really shaped who I am and my perspective and I guess it was no surprise that I ended up spending my career in education at McGraw-Hill.
I am Raphael and I grew up in the Champagne region in France, like very far away.
I think even philosophically and conceptually from where we are now.
And in a way I got a chance to get into programming kind of early on someone by chance which gave me a window into a much bigger world and started developing programming as a freelancer growing up in realize that there wasn't much of an ecosystem around me.
So I had to Leave moved to Israel.
Now the US and I realized that in a way, I have been waiting for the things that we're about to talk about my whole life, to be able to team up with amazing people to do, meaningful work, kind of wherever you are and collaborating to build great things.
Kim.
You might set up in your lighting setup.
You like, that's not my fun fact, but I just really am loving your setup here.
My fun fact is I have never had any formal HR training or education as a theater major.
So for any of you out there who are pursuing non-traditional career paths or your kind of wandering aimlessly around finding your way to people work, you are not alone out.
There are a lot of us out here who learn on the job.
Samara.
Yeah, over to me.
Let us see.
My son fact is that I may be not so surprising to those who know me but connecting a kind of I am a connector really like in My DNA and it was only during the pandemic that I had.
This kind of aha moment that really connected the thread throughout my life, which is I have always been a connector as early as I can remember.
I was bringing together individuals within different friend groups and of in high school and then it has been a thread that has really kind of driven me throughout.
And certainly.
Now, I have been in the business that I am at, which is building an ecosystem, it's all about bringing people together, bringing companies together Building Bridges.
So, connections, run, deep in my jeans.
So, thank you all for your amazing, fun facts.
Great to get to know you a little bit better.
Let us dive in today I am hoping that we can start by level setting on today's topic, and so I thought I would toss it over to Rafael if you wouldn't mind sharing?
What does it mean to be a cloud based company?
Yeah, you know, it's obvious in a secret that we have been through so much transformation of work over the past few years.
But if we try to Packet, even from starting from few decades back, we have seen more and more layers of the tools that we use, and the infrastructure were using to build companies.
Go to the cloud.
So much, so that I think is as Derek Thompson pointed out, you can be sitting in the same room with a colleague and yet, most of the time that you will be working, you will be working through tools in the cloud.
Even that you sit next to your colleague, and we have seen every piece of the stack Move online.
Obviously came with oyster is an example of that.
And there's many more we use slack with.
You seem we will all these things.
Now, it seems that, you know, the, the acceleration of the transformation of the past few years, is much bigger than just a question of remote and how many days in the office?
And I think we here today because we know that this is a bigger question than this.
And there is this transformation happening to the very models of how companies Being built the last leg sort of speak is actually the most important one and that's the people part moving.
Also, to the cloud kind of The Last Mile, that may change everything a good way to think about.
It would be to think about the focus point.
The focus point is no longer about geography, but it's about how to bring.
So you used to have hq's for example, where all the decisions are made a lot of companies are still working this way, and we find that to be less and less effective.
As we try to learn how to make decisions in a way that is much more distributed so that good people and Executives and leaders and teams all over the world, can collaborate an effective way.
And we have seen that there are new models emerging of teams that are forming essentially online.
We call this cloud-based teams that are enabling companies to form those hybrid Workforce going from full-time to Tourist people from different places that are assembling in a very Mission.
Focus way and are acting as drivers into the company's so excited to explore those new models and how they are changing the game for companies of pretty much all size.
Thanks for off.
Why don't we dive into talking more about each of your respective companies and teams and the cloud?
Maybe you could each talk a little bit about the models that you're deploying within your team's, you know what challenges and opportunities have you seen result from that?
And maybe let us get started with Justin.
I am sorry here at McGraw-Hill, we have a bit different to the number of companies either 130 year old foundation in the education industry and where we are a highly distributed company.
So we have been working in for many of you would know us as from the print publishing days.
Now to a point where we continue to transform and involved with our fantastic content through our digital platforms, Just like Disney place.
So, just like HBO.
And so, when we think about cloud based teams and cloud based companies, it's really about how we interact with our customer.
How do we react with our people and our processes?
So over the last 2, through 20 or so years, we have seen a rapid acceleration here at McGraw-Hill, and for us.
It all starts with our customer, and we will talk a little bit about a bit more, but how we're able to listen to them very A lot in a different way and much faster way.
But also internally Now teams we're able to deploy teams a lot faster, a lot quicker, a lot more dispersed around the countries and then also the tools as well that we put in place to make sure that collaboration is happening.
So you know whether that in my area where that's transformation, corporate planning em a new product development, we are deploying very fundamental same.
The rules as we go in and accelerate, the work that goes on in the cloud.
So, I will jump.
Yeah, I will jump in because I think oyster is almost the opposite of McGraw-Hill here in that.
We are a two-year-old company, and we are now about 650 employees across 70 countries.
So we are extremely distributed, but we are a company that was founded during the pandemic, and so we never had to make a transition from in person to hybrid to remote the company was founded.
On the premise that it would be a fully distributed fully remote company from the start and forever.
And so, when we think about the type of company, we want to build it is by default cloud-based, but it's also intentionally cloud-based.
I think, even if we stir wasn't founded during the pandemic, it would have been fully cloud-based as we say.
Because our Founders really believe in that and believe in the future of Distributed work as an equalizer in terms of employment around the world.
And so we built the company over the last two years, at lightning speed to, in service of this Mission and service of using cloud-based employment.
As a way to talk to open up opportunities for people, like Ralph, who had to leave home to find the right kinds of opportunities.
The hope is that we can make that change.
Very much relate to that as well because you know we ask ourselves the question at the beginning of a team of could we enable the most highly skilled Professionals in Tech to a to somewhat Escape rigid structures and team up with people?
They want to work with to solve problems, that matter, to them with full autonomy, and growing and learning while doing so.
And that was kind of the question that triggered this development of Information platform that enables the formation rapidly of highly motivated, High performing teams, that companies of different stages can use to bring on in supercharger initiatives or, or create new ones very quickly.
Now, we got started very much in the wake of the pandemic, like, we build that before that, with our, my cloud-based teams, sounded like something, that would be somewhat far away even though someone invisible just happen, much faster.
So, we don't have much of a choice than to build Fully remote.
I mean, I think it took a year until we could meet until I could meet my team effectively, but we grew as well to over 20 countries.
And now, the, the Network that has been built behind it to power.
That information engine is now seven thousand people strong.
Even though it's kind of by definition, by Design, hard to get into.
You have, like, product managers designers Engineers, data centers that are leaving Tech Giants, and other companies that have been asking themselves the question of Hey I want to be working on things that truly matter to me with great people and that's how I see my growth.
Kim mentioned something interesting about democratizing opportunity and access we very much see that happen.
I think it's great to have this group here of widely different companies in a way because we see that some of the most interesting opportunities for transformation.
For building, the things that will change the day-to-day and provide incredible drivers for growth.
Actually incredibly compelling for some of the best Minds on the planet and that's what we're seeing essentially every day.
And as companies basically rethink the models for company buildings for company building, they can tap into this opportunity to assemble phenomenal teams with it full-time, employees, part-time employees, whatever.
As long as they are formed around a mission and shared purpose, actually attracting people to solve a problem that they deeply care about.
Out.
Let us jump.
I guess, from higher level down to some more tactics.
So, I am interested to hear from each of you.
You know, what are you doing to Foster effective collaboration?
Within your team?
So how are you structuring those teams?
What processes are you putting in place to really help create that collaborative environment?
Just, and I know you have some good story.
To tell here.
So I don't over to you.
Of course, I think for us at McGraw-Hill, we a ticking, the team that I work with a very distinctly different whether it's a new product development, MMA, corporate strategy.
And what's important is the difference between what we found is the difference between the day-to-day work and the week two, I would say the week-to-week first worse, the goal setting.
And so for us, We found it, very important.
There is always there's a need for us to come together, and we typically do that every quarter, and we set our vision like the why, why are we working on whatever we're working on?
Why is it worth as Ralph said, why is this a problem worth solving?
I think we all go to work for a different reason other than just getting financials up.
And so when we meet it's almost entirely on the Y, and then we move into execution mode we have all agreed on the way, we all understand.
And we all bought in on the why.
It doesn't matter where the people are from.
There could be people from you know that we work with our partners and as long as we're sharing the exact same vision, we then move into a weekly cycle and what we found works really well is using tools to sit down every Monday over a zoom call or a Google call going through what are our goals of the week and then being very deliberate around deciding.
Well when do we need actually Foster Collaboration during that week and saying, okay, if we're going to hit this goal X or Y person, need to talk to each other, it would be good to have that kind of conversation with each other.
I think, what's also important as well, and what we do, which has been working its at the end of the week.
Coming together again, going through everything, we have achieved and celebrating it.
And so we have a nice clean end of the week, but there's a celebration of moving towards that Vision that the collective team has been working.
Words.
And so, of course, my will keep iterating.
I am sure like we're everyone on the call will be, but it's certainly been a learning journey, and we keep getting better and better, and keeps working better.
Government relate to this as well because I find that, you know, there's some fundamental shift that's happening with the way particularly highly skilled, but I think workers in general was I thinking as shown by the great resignation.
Now the latest version of it which is more quiet.
Apparently is said, look, ultimately, this is something that was bound to happen for.
For while we're, you know, in, in the days of the past, you would say to a company Okay, I will join you for and I will give you the right to tell me where to be what to do, who to work with.
And you will give me stability and early into the pandemic.
We saw that the stability could expire very quickly, but to go at the time, where a company's thought that the world was ending, and they were like, okay, you, you're laid off right overload.
And then a month later it was like, oh, actually the world is not ending.
If you could, please come back to be great.
Now, there's a, there's a market checkup.
And in some potential bad news coming up.
And again, you know, second time in two years people are getting laid off again, including from profitable companies that have to increase margin.
And you also find alongside that companies are getting bigger and bigger faster than ever.
So that the overall appeal of the mission of a company becomes diluted, the bigger it gets.
So people saw that plus at a time when there was a remember that life can be short like you know during the pandemic I think that's the realization does a big religion of people have, they really care about working on things that matter to them.
And so the core thing to bring a team together is to is and of course shift.
I think that's happening with companies is they're starting to forward-thinking leaders, a rethinking, how the think of the workforce from the old ways of thinking and headcount and departments basically trying to fill up you know spreadsheets that you do at the beginning of the year.
And you basically say okay I need that many Engineers have any product people Market ourselves people to think in terms of what are the initiatives?
What are the Real problems?
I am trying to solve what are the real solution that I want to put forward and what are the teams that I need to drive those outcomes?
And when you start thinking that way you basically start, not just having the overall company Mission but you have the missions within the mission and those missions enable them to think in terms of teams and for those mission-driven team's Mission based work teams, essentially you can attract and retain.
Really good people that are motivated to share common adversity and common experience.
And that's where all of our human elements kind of kick in of, you know, teaming up with people.
Really driving to an outcome and that requires for the teams to be more, autonomous to be cross-functional right to have essentially as much of the skills of the diverse skills needed perspectives and backgrounds in order to accomplish that goal.
And that empowerment of teams toward mission is enabling companies to move.
Much faster to tackle a much wider surface area and to enable company that hasn't haven't been able to transform for a while.
To certainly be able to do that and people are happy through that because they get to choose.
I think what rastetter that cross-functional teams was spot on the challenge with tech and cloud.
Based, organizations is Convergence and when anything in ref, we talk about it when everything converges and it converges a lot faster and more frequently with tech whether its product.
You know, back in the day used to be about the supply chain, you have different teams doing very Rolls and then there was Pastor down the supply chain.
These days, the hardest part is managing convergence and being proactive, around convergence, and you need a cross-functional team even if you're doing HR transformation and HR initiative to a product initiative, the need for a cross-functional team that's focused on one.
Common goal has never been more Paramount to be successful if I could jump in and get attacked.
Uncle for a second here.
I am not sure what the breakdown is of our audience in terms of Founders and leaders versus operators, but I will speak to the operator perspective for a second.
When you're bringing people together, I noticed in our poll that 75% of our audience here or respondents are in a hybrid environment and eighty percent of our respondents here are a mix of full-time and Freelancers.
So in either of those cases, you have a serious risk of Creating an equity in your organization, whether you're treating full-time employees and Freelancers in a different way, in terms of inclusion, in terms of perspective, sharing or your hybrid and, and or your rest are your remote.
And in office, employees are having different experiences to think, really tactically about what you're trying to achieve as an organization and what you're trying to achieve in terms of input, in terms of involvement from People around the organization being hyper aware that when you have people who have different types of employment, or different locations of employment, you have to be all that more intentional about how you include their perspectives in the conversation.
So, whether that's something you see, a lot is in meetings, where you have some folks in the office and some folks dialing in, it can be really common for the people who are sitting around the table to be talking to each other around the table and ignoring the folks, who are on the call to the extent that someone mentioned On a panel, I was on recently that they were watching they feel like they were watching a meeting happen, and they were kind of off to the side and the meeting ended.
And before the zoom ended they saw.
People going off to have side conversations.
They're like wait, I am over here on the screen and now they have missed out on that potential to collaborate and there's all this research about how this type of environment, more directly benefits.
Men, specifically benefits, white middle-aged men but to really be more inclusive in how You're thinking about who makes decisions, who's, in the room when those conversations happen, who has access to the people of influence, within the company and your role, as an HR practitioner, and an employee experienced practitioner, as any sort of operator who touches this field is to be looking for those unheard voices and to be looking for, not just who makes the decisions, but who's a stakeholder who needs to be involved, whose voices, haven't we heard?
Is everyone on the decision-making?
Team kind of homogeneously.
Acted or do we have a real diversity and thinking about, thinking about things, like, how you include folks, who aren't in the, in the physical space with you, you have to, you don't have to do that as much when you're fully remote because it's more about whose invited to the column, who's who can make it to the call.
And the only thing I will add there before I shut up about this is when you are really distributed.
Everywhere in the world, you have to think about times and inclusivity in a way that you don't, when you're all physically in one space, I spent most of my career with companies who were primarily in the San Francisco Bay Area occasionally with one or two folks around the world occasionally with like a New York office and San Francisco office.
But when you're operating in time zones, all over the place, coordinating offices, hubs people working from home, you have to really think about what does it mean to have a standard operating schedule?
Is it mean to have core working hours?
What needs to happen, synchronously versus what can we change to happen, asynchronously?
And it really takes a nun learning of how you work together and what you need to be successful at work to make sure that you're being inclusive of all of the people who, you know, are in your same physical location, okay?
Cam before we move off of that, I know.
Sure and always stir, I think have a philosophy around You know, creating some of that inclusivity.
I believe you call it like follow the sun.
Maybe I believe we do.
Yes.
Can you explain?
Absolutely.
I will.
I can try to find or if someone from the Welcome admin, team wants to find him pop it into the chat.
We're open sourcing.
All of this, we have it all in public facing the ocean pages but our internal philosophy of following the sun is that the sun is always going to be rising on someone a toaster but that doesn't mean You work 24/7.
We are enabled to have our work happened in a good 24 hours anchors, you know, cycle around the world but you have to get really good at knowing when to shut off and knowing how to hand your work over to someone else so that you can shove off.
And also that means sometimes taking advantage of really weird nonlinear work schedules.
I was working late last night because my colleague in Australia and I really Just like needed to unblock something with each other.
And it was his morning.
It was his Monday morning and it was my Sunday evening, and we just kind of jammed on it for a little bit and knowing that like that sometimes is necessary to get what you need out of work.
That's traveling all around the world but I also knew that I needed to get things in a good enough place before I went to bed that my colleagues waking up on Monday morning who needed to take the Baton and carry that work forward, would have everything they needed to be successful.
And I knew that, like, Do you have being very candid Friday?
Was a little bit wacky for me and this weekend.
It was wacky with the kids and I didn't have any time to catch up so it was Sunday night Sunday, night, prep work that I had intended to do in more reasonable working hours.
But having that idea, that I am going to do my work during the day and do a handoff either to My Future Self or to my co-worker, who's going to wake up 812 hours from now, I need to pick this back up.
It allows the work to continue and allows it to keep moving forward.
In a really kind of respectful and responsible way.
And we have hilarious videos on our website about this, but also tons of great content and templates that we can find in share with attendees, because we really believe that if you're going to build companies that are in the cloud, you have to allow your work to be in the cloud and you have to allow your connections.
You can't just try to replicate that experience that we talked about in the beginning.
It was like we're working in the cloud, but we're sitting next to each other slacking and Google docking next to each other.
So we can just turn to the person next to us and like, talk live and then get back into our Google Docs.
I don't know if that's the healthiest way to work anyway.
So this is okay for work, is truly going to be distributed in the cloud, we are going to also be distributed in the cloud.
How do we still connect the dots so that we can still collaborate together and that's thank you, Katie for sharing that this is That we're at we worked on?
And I will say, very candidly that we released this.
About a year ago, we were about 300, 250, 300 employees.
When we released it, we are now a year later thinking about how does that scale for 650 people?
How does it feel to 800 people?
How it will this continue to scale with us over the years?
I am not much is changing about the structure of how we work.
It's more about how we bring people on board and how we, how we get adopted.
Option, that's that to me is the piece that we don't talk about a lot with this, as you can have, all the great room at work philosophies that you want.
But if people are still stuck in their old ways of working, then it's going to, it's not going to work.
It's so interesting.
I think hybrid is its red.
The hybrid is, in a way like particularly challenging but, you know, I am interested to see like we have in the polls as I see 60% of people of mix of ft and Freelancers.
We just run a just ask like 600 founders of companies, but of question to understand the transformation happening.
And I think it was around that as well as, but 70% that used kind of Highly skilled contractors as part of their teams.
And, you know, something happened to me early this year That was a big surprise.
I so, as I mentioned before, it took over a year to even just meet the team that we have assembled in person because we were deep in the pandemic when we got started.
But at some point we're about 60 people back.
Then we were like, okay, let us gather everybody full week in Portugal, and we did.
And when we got together there and look around, like, wow, that's crazy.
I have had a chance to start a few companies before and be involved in a bunch of companies.
I have actually never seen in that level of diversity.
And I mean diversity from the sense of people coming from all kinds of countries.
Speaking with all kinds of different English accent and coming from a very different background.
And the really amazing thing about it is that it was obvious, that they share the same values, despite their vastly different backgrounds, and the, and the came to this, to the respective mission-based teams, because they care about the On the care about the mission, the value, we're trying to accomplish.
That was a big surprise for me because early stage, typically, as you mentioned Kim, like, if you build team in San Francisco, you can try to push for diversity, but at the end that you have people in San Francisco versus in a bunch of countries.
And I see that also, with the type of teams that Justin is building.
I think there's diversity in all kind of dimensions of his fascinating when you see people from not just on different locations but also that come from small company, background startups, large companies, Etc, and seeing those people come together, Heather learn from each other share.
Different perspective is really powerful, so yes, it's brings a ton of challenges rethinking and of that get that new muscle memory as someone mentioned in the chat, but it has the advantage of actually finding the world.
Bring the best of the best from a much wider aperture in perspective.
It's exciting to see how that makeup is maybe a way to deliver on the diversity.
That is needed to solve.
Complex problems came.
I could not, I could not be loved your intentionality around equity in the workplace and it's certainly something that, you know, leaders need to be proactive on fostering in the workplace, it doesn't just happen if you don't proactively think about it, you know, I just maybe add to two different two separate rules.
We have put in place for that in that, in light of that, Kim as well.
Well one, we have a rule that if everyone you know this equality server, all hot online, we're all going to be online.
No one's going to be in the office.
Happy barking, me office.
People are going to be on Zoom.
We felt when we work with contractors and Freelancers is really talented people.
Everyone's the same.
Everyone's equal when they're on, we're on a call like this.
And so, that's been really important to bring people together and have a voice.
Secondly, one thing.
We observed as well, was particularly at the executive level we weren't.
It's hard to see the people that are moving up the organization and then a shining in the doing the work every day and when we come together and do steering committees, right?
Very formal steering committees.
We realized that this was a great opportunity to ask people.
Ask is we are getting the same Business Leaders every week presenting.
And we said well, how do we bring different?
Different people to life.
And so we now make it a rule that someone in the actual working team needs to present a known the work, and that has really changed that the culture, and we can see it going.
Instead of just hitting the top, it goes up and down a lot faster now and that's made a big change for us.
I really like that Justin.
I think something that we when you look at leadership teams, and we look at communication, a lot of times I think leadership teams feel like they have to represent the work that their team has done because that shows connection and that should just buy in.
And yeah, even if they're even if you're a movie, go from the equation which is not always easy to do there.
Is Often this element of like I have to show that I believe in this work by Speaking on behalf of the people who did it and sometimes you do need that, sometimes you do need that executive level or leadership level by and especially when you're delivering a message, across a wide range of people and locations and you're doing it on virtually.
It's nice to have that kind of executive presence.
However, I think you can accomplish that by having the executive presence as the like introduction or a be like this is something that's super important.
And now I am going to shine a spotlight on the people who actually did the work.
Work.
And then that provides really nice growth opportunities for those people who might not get that exposure.
Otherwise, and especially, I mean, we talked about as a hybrid work environment and folks who having access or not and who's in the office, and who's not in the office, who does that disproportionately benefit Giving the people who do the work, the opportunity to speak up, whether they are in an office or dialing in provides that platform.
And that access, I think anyone out here, who is a manager.
Like, like, I encourage you to take really take that to heart.
And think about, why do I feel like I need to be the one presenting this?
Why does, what does it say about my ego?
What does that say about my insecurities?
That I feel like I need to present on behalf of the work that my team has done and instead using it off And opportunity to elevate your team and Elevate the talent that you have.
Well, so sure I am strong Martinez.
Also, showed a strong and cohesive your team is, that's comes across really strongly for the great teams.
Great pie routines that were together.
So, let us actually take an audience question that was submitted during registration, which was beyond the it organization, what culture shifts are needed.
Within the rest of the organization to maximize the benefits of a cloud-based company.
Oh my heart.
There's it might I say my heart because it's something the whole we're always, were always wrestling with it.
We stir with in terms of like hiring and onboarding and education.
And so, when you think about the culture shift, you need the culture ships, you need, are you need everyone to be bought into the way you're working first and foremost.
And it sounds really simple but it's actually Quite interesting, the more you hire.
The more people you have to bring on board with the way that you're working, and I like it to like when event if we could all walk back in time to our in office days and remembering how like no one ever does our dishes in the kitchen, right?
And everyone's feeling the sink with their dishes and your poor office manager is like watching everyone's discussing dishes, but if you start teaching people, that part of your company culture is to do the dishes and it's part of your ritual as part of individual.
Ship and accountability.
And you start teaching people that when they come onto the team as new hires during onboarding.
I promise I am going somewhere with this as the, as your ratio changes and the more people you have, who have learned that as part of their new hire experienced, the that drives the culture shift because you suddenly, you have more people who know that it's their own personal responsibility to do their own dishes, then you do people who are used to somebody coming in and doing it for them and it's the same with any culture.
That you need to be a successful cloud based company.
The more people you have who are bought in to the idea of the ritual, the Norms that are part of your culture, the less work you individually, have to do.
And there's a lot of work that ours like dish doing work, the like the documentation the handoffs, the pre reads before the meetings the remembering to make At the meeting is happening at a rotating inclusive.
Time the taking note of whose in the room and who's not in the room, the virtual room, all of those things are things that it's really, really easy to get lazy about and it's really, really easy to revert back to the way you have been working for 10 years, 15 years.
However, many years before you transition into working hybrid or working fully remote, and the truth is that the in-office behaviors and Norms are not directly preferable one-to-one with working.
That sort of individual administrative burden that you take on like needing to show up in a different.
Like that's very different from like the culture shift of like we all say hi at the beginning of the day like yes that's nice but that's not what makes up the experience of being a part of your team sculpture and all of that other stuff is about individual responsibility and buy in to the way of working that you're trying to work.
Boy stur, folks.
It's everyone's job.
I know my coworkers are listening.
Justin, do you want to add?
I am curious mean at an organization that has so much Legacy right in his has certainly been in office historically how I guess what advice do you have in terms of driving that culture shift?
So who questioned culture is so important?
I think one when you're a larger more established culture, there's a reason why you have been sohrab us for so long and it's taking the tenants.
You know, I think about when I am back in the day, when I used to play basketball, you know, you have your pivot fit, you got one pivot foot of what made you, what makes you so strong.
In our case, it's out, purpose around improving education.
It's our commitment to high quality.
Be content and Trust in the education industry.
But then pivoting accordingly and that pivoting requires that's the part that requires a culture shift at times.
And so for us, it's allowing our teams to experiment allowing and whether that is like different models, working with different types of vendors, different types of employment, type of ways, whether it's contractors Freelancers, which you hadn't traditionally done.
Whether that is different types of people with different types of background and allowing the team's only to work faster.
But also it's okay to fail as long as there's a reason and there's a vision of why we're trying to get to a certain location.
So that has been as we improve the culture just being okay with saying okay things aren't going to work.
Tools aren't going to work, but we're going to keep trying.
Going to get better and better whilst we keep our pivot foot.
I want, what makes us successful company over the last 130 years.
So let us take one more audience question and then I will get to some of our others that we had too many questions for the time allotted today.
But maybe from Joe what do L most often get wrong when it comes to managing remote teams, and we're off.
Do you want to take that one first?
Yeah absolutely.
I think you have also break down leaders.
I think this is of transformation just makes the people leaders.
The HR leaders such kind of the Agent of Change.
Julie that have to get into the business if more than ever because those culture shift that we talk about and kind of moving away from the supply chain type of thinking, that, that Justin mentioned before is really important.
But when you think about it, it's been great in us forever like essentially, like ever since the factories, right?
We are used to, like, coming in the morning, doing work synchronously, living at night.
And that's, that's our starting point still today.
So what Leaders with leaders?
I think that the shift that's happening is power to the edges.
I can you truly Empower a team to drive results and to own that result And that is a significant change from the way decisions have been made and organization have been designed.
But it's also the way to be not as to be much less commoditizing as we used to write like people, leave commoditized position communities jobs leaders, that argument sizing them, effectively.
And want to join the places that give them the power of choosing.
The problems that they care about to actually driving the an actual impact that matters to them.
So being able in the hard part about this with leaders that it's actually hard to remember, what are the outcomes that you care about?
When you ask yourself today, like, can I depict the vision very clearly to my team of what success looks like?
So in six months from now by the end of the year, It's actually hard to do.
It's hard to do in simple words like I found, I find that you got to push.
You got to push on that and really think about it.
But once you have it, and it's Crystal Clear people find within themselves, unbelievable power to actually achieve it and drive towards it.
So I would say, l, capturing their vision and powering their teams toward an outcome that they can depict.
Clearly is a big transformation.
Way that we manage.
I suddenly saw a friend of mine and I certainly think wrap your.
I, the role of the manager is much higher and what I see, sometimes leaders getting wrong, it's coming because you have to get this balance, right?
One of being, not taking for granted as a manager.
What the goals of the team said.
As you said, rat flag into one sentence, what is that?
Your goal?
Your team for the next six months and how are you?
Breaking it down and making sure all People just join your team and going in and out aligning to it.
So that's really important.
But it also what's really important is to give them autonomy, right?
And I think you mentioned it, right?
Like people have what's so amazing about hybrid and remote is, you know, now I have teams where my team can pick up their kids, they can work other times they want, but you have to have trust that we have agreed to that mission and now just you can work out when that work is going to be done, and we have all agreed and you just Were it and so not you have seen some managers getting a little bit to control it controls controlling, so they want to control all the way from the start, all the end and the challenge really is course, sending the vision setting, the execution path, but then also empowering your team to fit in their schedule in their lives and getting the work done.
And if you have the right people that will always deliver well If I could add just one very quick thing to, this also is, it's very easy to overlook the emotional relationship, building component of management.
When you are remote, when you're in the office and you see each other physically, or you're sitting down the same conference room, you can, you can feel the energy and know maybe this is like very briefly.
If Me by like you can feel the energy that the other person is bringing into the room a lot more naturally easier when you're in person.
And, so I think it's something that I struggle with personally, as a manager is remembering to take that time to connect human to human with the person that you're managing, whether that's a social check-in your meeting, or pinging them on slack to see how they're doing or using a mental wellbeing, check in tool, or whatever way it is, remembering to keep those human connections going.
As you, it's very easy for me as a manager.
I will just only take accountability for myself.
It's very easy for me to get focused on the work and execution and saying, okay, we're aligned go off and do your thing.
I am going to go off and do my thing.
Let us come back.
We have shared goals.
This is all great, but then you miss that human connection element.
And if that doesn't come naturally to you, or it's something that you may be leaned heavily on, you know, running into each other in the company kitchen about Out.
You have to, again, be like very intentional about how and where, and when you Foster those connections such a great reminder.
I think that's a good segue, you know, hybrid work cloud-based teams, right?
They take different shape and different people based on where they are in their own life, experience, experience them differently.
So I know one of the concerns about this new model of work has been for Gen Z and weather early kind of Skill employees are getting the mentorship and training and upskilling that they need.
How do you think we solve for that?
Could I talk about intentionality again?
All right  functionality again, I know Justin is passionate about this topic so maybe over to adjustable I really I worried we worry about it.
A lot, you know, I think about personally, my experiences when I was younger as a graduate you learn a lot on the job and mostly mimicking.
Right?
You don't know what you're doing.
You're mimicking people.
You're mimicking.
How they prepare.
You see the other side and The Human Side of them, right?
You see them nervous before a meeting you just observe and watch and the work that other people put through put in.
And you can ask questions very freely bit more freely at those times.
And so we it is very fun of mine for us because Typically we have worked with highly skilled team staying.
Yes, you have.
We must have a common goal.
We must have a shared understanding, but typically they know how to problem.
Solve they know what they're doing when you're at least, when I started at work, I had no idea what I was doing and so for many years and for you know, when we go into this remote world it's and to When he came and ran from show, you would say the same thing.
It's 10:00 in tashjian, intentionality about putting a frame of the picture or these being addressed.
So, a practical example for that, you know, we're putting more mentorship programs, particularly for new starters and really I wouldn't call forcing it but making sure that we're checking in and seeing the feedback we're getting from my interns or a fresh grad.
Adds.
Secondly, we're bringing fresh Senna and turns much closer together, more often than we normally would have done, and we know we want them to share their experiences and much more cross collaborative way more often as well.
And I think thoroughly, it's just empathy, right?
Many of us have been in, you know where leaders we have been organizations as well.
We feel confident, our work Trails, we feel confident.
Coughing about switching between jobs and having that empathy around.
That's how I felt like when I was a fresh bread Jew, a tour when I was a fresh into and that's the off that Azul and I have given all this task.
Do you remember when you were 18 and you got given tasks and how you felt?
And now imagine you're at home by yourself and how that would have felt and making a follow-up Zoom call and saying, hey, how are you feeling?
Did you understand every thing?
It's okay, let us go.
Do it again and just being very empathetic to gen Z's because they're not going too necessarily.
It's not cool to talk about these things or say that loud, especially when you're just starting, just starting an organization.
We're off to do you want to jump in?
I mean, you.
You see right what's happening across so many different organizations ride from large organizations to small organizations.
And, so I would love to hear, you know what lessons you're learning from all of those different organizations in terms of what they're doing and how they're deploying cloud-based teams.
Yeah, we have had the benefit of seeing hundreds of teams and deploying and it's absolutely right.
What Kim and Justin was what we're saying before.
There's this Mission focus and there's trust that are really key drivers and when and there's the surprising thing is like You can actually today like assemble some of the world's best product Builders to help team up with you on the most important outcome.
So there's literally we live in a world that is becoming more and more democratized that has provides much more access turns out really how skilled people are looking for the type of challenges that actually matters.
If you think you're doing something that can matter that's it.
Here you go.
You can actually do it because now the boundaries Of the four kind of logical.
Walls of the company are dissolving for the better and that's what the cloud has brought us with cloud computing and is now bringing us with teams and the whole stack of the company as a whole, becoming wider can move faster.
Power goes to the edges, creates a ton Ami and creates intention ality.
And I agree that's such a key word because If in the past, you know, culture kind of happened in the office, we thought we had it down but really we don't know.
We have to think it through and it presents this kind of New Foundation that helps address some of the problems that we have always struggled with their gen Z kind of upscaling.
And the asking problem, General has always been an issue.
Except when you have strong teams that are cross-functional, that bring diversity of skill, set of backgrounds where Talked about how that's how you can solve really big problems.
What A diversity, can also come at different levels of experience because sometimes if you have a team of really strong people, you can also have someone that ask the more basic questions and turns out the most basic questions may be very helpful so that you are getting stuck and don't take things for granted.
You may have taken for granted for a very long time.
So thinking deeply about our team's by identifying the core missions and outcomes within the organization and looking at the teams that Can drive those outcomes, helps structure the cloud-based companies and the fourth thing in companies to go into a new level of pace, a new level of potential of outcomes and driving products, and revenue streams and access to customers that were just impractical before that.
Well, and we didn't talk about this much today, but it's still a downturn going on.
And a lot of uncertainty in the, in the economic Times that we're in and iCloud is done.
Computers, you don't actually have to commit.
The way you had to commit with buyings bunch of servers and putting them in your office.
You can benefit from the flexibility that cloud-based everything bring you including cloud-based teams so that you can reduce overhead, increase your ability to be agile and Nimble and build with the capabilities that enable you to not just survive in those very crazy times, but actually find ways to is to move like and thrive in the way that no one could before.
So sadly we only have a few minutes left.
So maybe in closing, let us get back to some tactics to leave people with, so hoping each of you can share two things leaders can do today to accelerate their success with cloud-based teams.
Who wants to start?
I will start us off.
So two things leaders can do one is get very clear on what your culture means because knowing what your culture looks like in practice will help you identify how you need to communicate how you need to work together.
How you what behaviors, you reward, but behaviors, you correct.
And that only becomes more important when you are fully.
Did hybrid just hybrid in the cloud?
And the second piece of advice is communicated early often in multiple locations multiple times a day.
You can you, you know, you're communicating too much.
When people tell you to stop telling you something and that will very rarely ever happen.
Cool.
Justin.
Sorry, not much time.
Left to things rapid fire.
OK, my two things that, you know, it's up to lead us to model the way and I will put the keyword of this session intentionality.
If I think, what ref mentioned a lot around diversity, there's no excuse not to work with different types of vendors, like, 18 stuff to bring diversity opulent and really realistic, you watch need done quickly and you as a leader have, Tim all the way and slowly build trust.
New methods work.
I think we had a little technical challenge there, but intentionality model the way Ralph over to you to close us out.
Yeah, I think intentionality definitely key word.
I would say experimentation empowering teams like today.
Think about the missions and describe the outcomes.
You're trying to drive for your end of the queue for, for H1 next year.
And try to ask you the question, what is the right team for the job?
And now you have all kinds of ways to assemble this team, you can bring diversity of skill.
Set of abilities, of seniority of backgrounds, obviously, and many more and you can build in and you can keep exploring.
Ring new models for company building, that may change the game for you and your organization.
Very cool.
Well, thank you so much.
This has been amazing.
I wish we had more time to continue the conversation but please connect with the speakers.
I think all of their LinkedIn are in the chat and I know they'd all be happy to continue the conversation with you have a wonderful day.
Thank you again to our partners.
Welcome and a team and oyster for joining us today.
I hope you have a great week.
Have a good one.
Thank you.
Thanks for having me.