Aloha, everyone, great to see you here.
My name is Gina.
I am head of marketing with welcome, and I am tuning in from Ewa Beach, Hawaii.
It is on Oahu.
For those of you who may not know, and I am just looking in chat here, and we have got a great representation of folks, all over the world, including our panelists.
And so we're excited that you're here joining a Samantha.
Yes.
Where are you tuning in from?
If you'd like to trade, please join.
Join me here in Hawaii.
Awesome! Well, we have got a great panel today.
I am so excited about the rich conversation that we're going to have around the productive power of work relationships.
It's so critical especially in this post been pandemic era that were in before we jump in though, note that we have some tabs right over there to your right column and as you can see, there is a Q&A tab.
So at any given moment, feel free to drop in your questions.
Throughout this time, we're going to keep it a very organic dialogue and so as you submit the questions, we will pull them in where we think it could fit in the conversation.
Thank you to those who submitted some questions in advance as well.
Some of those are actually dropped in there.
Okay, so let us kick off with a pole.
Katie who is in The Green Room?
I see you some of you don't see, see you're there, but Thank you, Katie.
Could you pull up our poll?
So we get a quick pulse on.
What's the workplace relationship that has had the most significant and positive impact on you?
So go ahead and just click on the screen right there.
Is it your Mentor, your manager appear a direct report or other feel free to drop in your votes, okay.
All right, so we're seeing that appear is coming up.
And then your manager and Mentor.
Okay, Amanda is mentioning your manager.
Yes.
Okay.
All right.
Well with that, I would love to invite the panelists if you don't mind joining me here on stage.
All right, so we have got Laura, Nadia Rodrigo.
Let us see here.
Okay, can you all hear me?
We can hear you, okay great.
Yeah, it's so wonderful to see each of you if you don't mind introducing yourselves.
And let me know where you're tuning in from as well and I will start with you Nadia.
Great to be a Gina.
Hey everyone.
I love looking at all your locations extremely distributed audience so that's a lot of fun.
I am here in Johannesburg.
We finally have rains celebrating that Latakia.
And I am VP of people at remote, we have gone through significant scaling in the last two years, and I am celebrating my two year anniversary at remote in December.
Hand it over T Rodrigo.
Hey Rodrigo, I am tuning in from Southern California where it's nice and sunny outside.
I work for a company at coat called torch.
People success manager over here were a remote first company where we really served to fuel professional growth through the power of trusted relationships and really on the for employees democratize access to coaching.
And then for companies really provide some powerful analytics on the back end to help produce like Roi.
So excited to be here today.
Awesome, thanks Rodrigo.
Laura amazing, thank you so much.
I am Laura the VP of marketing here at Loom I am joining from Colorado about 20 minutes, west of Denver's right?
At the foothills of the mountains, and Loom is a video communication platform for work.
So we help our connectedness among teams while also feeling a reduction in meeting by allowing teams to communicate via video messaging.
Love it.
All right, well before we jump into this discussion, I would like to pull up this Gallup stat that I had found.
So Katie, if you don't mind pulling that, you know, having the best friend at work is increased employees.
Workplace, net promoter scores during this post pandemic.
And so as you can see in 2021 2022 having that best friend at work a lot of folks, strongly agree that it can make a big difference.
This is in retention in having a thriving employee experience and communication, commitment, and ultimately outcomes.
And so, what I love about this discussion, Katie you can pull that down right now, we will Jump Right In what I love about this is we're not just talking about having a bestie at work, but there's actually productivity.
We're seeing that there're results from these surveys that Gallup has conducted in business outcomes.
It's in having these type of productive relationships.
So, I would love to unpack this conversation a little bit more with each of you.
How are you seeing the importance of building and maintaining strong workplace, relationships through the employee life cycle?
I will start Gina if that's if it helps the panel yet, I would love to hear from Laura and Rodrigo on this topic as well.
I think, for me, social connection is so much more, especially in a remote in hybrid environment, right?
And we also, remote first, I didn't mention that earlier, but like our name, we are absolutely remote first in more than 75 countries with more than 900 employees.
And I think that social connection leads to the ultimate as Of belonging.
And if you cannot be friends with people at work, or if you don't have that type of connection, it's really difficult to trust someone, if you don't really know them.
And if you don't actually have any interest and connection with them, so to me, it really starts on that.
It starts about the impact can really impact your culture, how you work day to day, how teams connect with each other?
I think behind that comes a lot of intentionality and will Speak a lot more about that in today's store but Katie a little bit from Laura's.
Well, yeah.
And I think that friends really hold you accountable and unintentionally kind of hold up a mirror of the value and the caliber of work that you're driving and producing.
So when you see your friends or at the very least, people that you empathize with or trust doing really great work, it inspires you and it also kind of gives you a template in a framework to do, your best work as well and at the end of the day, we have probably an easier time letting a business.
We have a harder time letting our friends down or the people that are relying in depending upon us.
And I think that's one of the Crux is for why it drives value from a business perspective.
But also friendships, just make us happier because we spend so much of our time at work on these little Zoom boxes and screens.
It's so important to also have fun and not just always kind of be grind in through it.
So right on, I guess the only thing I would add to that is I think that one of the most important things about friendships is that they had meaning to work.
I think working sometimes be a grind in regards to the tasks that you have but doing them alongside of people that you respect the you trust and then you build a sense of purpose with really adds meaning to the things that you do.
It allows you to once you build trust with people, you're able to come alongside each other because you know each other because you can see where your spread thin You need help where and specifically like, where one person might have a specific skill set, that needs to be highlighted and in turn things, that they're not good at taking off their plate, so that you can actually have the right, players on the team, on the field, doing the right things.
Yeah, that's how much of that scheana.
Now that Rodrigo mentioned that if you think about the world of remote work, hybrid companies in person companies, communication is usually at the core of everything.
If you have great relationships with people at a social level and at a friendship level, the how, and the way you will communicate is just so different from you would with someone you don't know, right?
And so, it does actually unblock the communication gap, a little bit as well.
This is someone gets to know me, they will know.
How I talk.
Why you certain slang?
Living out here in Johannesburg?
And so it does actually, I think it does take a few barriers away when it comes to communication cultural differences because you take the time to get to know each other and so that can have a huge impact on asynchronous, communication and positive intent.
Because with friends, you're going to have that positive intent on a way higher scale than which you would with someone you absolutely just don't know.
So those Things come into play.
I think as well.
I think that positive intent thread is interesting and you know, at some point I would like to pull that a little bit more because I think there's so much misunderstanding that can happen while we're just seeing each other on slack as emojis or oh that person didn't respond to me within 5 minutes of my chat.
Like, are they upset with me?
You know, there's a lot of miscommunication that I feel can happen very easily as we're working in this remote circumstance.
So I guess across in thing about that life cycle, employee life, Cycle again, and each of you are our leading teams and hiring folks onboarding off-boarding folks right across that entire life cycle.
What are the key opportunities across and employees lifecycle Journey?
Do you see where you can help to as a manager?
Build those moments of trust and encouraging building?
The right kind of relationships To me and Haley starts on the day you make an offer.
The moment you say yes to someone onboarding actually spots, it doesn't start in the day you start because there's such a nearly like a runner-up towards day one.
And so taking of a little bit of pressure Away by scheduling a, welcome call having an onboarding buddy, or if you have a cohort or something that intentionality is needs to be there for someone to feel, welcome and excited, and they cannot Pressure on them to schedule on day one.
If you say to someone, you need to schedule 5 coffee Chats on your first day.
Chances are they not going to schedule any because they weren't no way to start but if you take that pressure away and set them up for that first day before they join it, kind of sets them up for success, and they feel very comfortable you know to enter that first day I never start with a question about like so how's your first day been?
So tell me about leading up to day one like what's been happening?
In your life.
How is your, you know, how is your family, taking your friends, taking the news, and immediately start to get to know things outside of work, there might drop a pet name, you know, Etc.
And so I think it starts date.
It's also the hardest time because right?
It's like first day of school, first day of University College, whatever the case may be, is the hottest time but also the best time to start introducing that.
I completely agree and I think we talked about this too when we were catching up before even coming on here live but an onboarding buddy I think is so important as well.
Just it can be somebody that like isn't maybe going to work with them every single day to like you really want a pair like these cultural ads so you can bring life into people's work immediately.
So it's not just somebody that's going to be like telling them how to fill out a Google doc or create a template but somebody that can also answer those like where's the bathroom?
Jen's that they're not going to feel comfortable asking their manager, especially in a remote workplace because that would be super weird.
But like, you need people that can kind of feed off of each other build on each other and can teach them the language.
Because any new company that you start at, you really are relearning, how to work relearning, how to communicate, everybody uses slack slightly differently, you might be in Threads or you might be in a lot of channels or everybody might just respond 121 and having somebody that can kind of show them the ropes and that way is how you really start to build an ingrained cultural.
Culture.
It's thinking about all the little things not just how work gets done, specifically from a project perspective.
I also think to your point Gina talking about off-boarding is also really important especially when you think about wanting to retain more people.
So if you have somebody that's leaving and you really didn't want them to you don't want to just like shun them or like ignore it.
This is like a really important time to build connections, Foster, ongoing relationships, and ideally, make sure that person is Champion and a cheerleader for you and your org from the sidelines.
Because friendships don't stop.
When you disconnect from your company.
Zoom, you want to build connections that are going to be Everlasting and Tech, or your industry is probably a pretty small town so to speak.
And those friendships and connections can only help our you and your future career.
Wherever you, may go next, as well as continuing to drive insights, and valuable institutional knowledge for your company after that person has departed.
That's so good and huge.
On the off-boarding side I think is managers it's so easy to kind of fall under you, like, you don't know what to do.
And so it just kind of like an after it becomes an afterthought, a lot of times but really securing that off-boarding and celebrating even the transition.
And the decision of the person transitioning, I think is a huge win.
Do you know, the only thing that I would vote add is I think that the other major point that relationship, screw, Credibly important is transition points.
You think about when someone gets promoted when someone moves into a different apartment we put all this emphasis on onboarding but it's almost like the way I have seen a frame sometimes like in boarding to a we put as much intentionality into helps helping someone transition into something bigger, something new like the first time someone manages people like those are big scary things which they're jumping into something new.
And so really being intentional about those times to really, really I think sometimes are one of the most I overlooked points in the life cycle of an employee.
So good.
I am actually going to pull in a question here.
I am seeing thank you everyone for dropping in some of these questions in queue.
A, let us actually pull in that first question from Riya.
Are there specific initiatives and programs?
You'd suggest organizations Implement to enable more work.
Friendships both in person and virtually.
So, I know we're getting a little bit in the, in, maybe a tactical idea here of initiatives.
But as we're talking about that employee life, All, what are some ideas recommendations that you have in these initiatives and programs?
I think a very simple one in the world of people is just leaving space in a budget for meetups.
So whether that is local International like whatever budget you have.
I mean we are in a year of sustainability and efficiency a lot of tech companies are, and so I know that people budgets aren't very stretchy but living space like whether that's 60, 100, 200 dollars for meeting up and having a meal together doing something fun together.
I have seen folks go on Hikes together, go, I had an experience with a remote We used our own budget to do hot air ballooning when they visited South Africa.
And it was such a cool experience, and it made me realize that budget.
I am not 100% sure.
I would have been able to commit to that amount in that sort of stage of my career when it happened.
And, so I just think it's so important to make Financial space in your budget for it, like tactically and it up, it doesn't have to be a lot of money, so that's a nice in person initiative, but also gets very Tribute teams together in smaller locations especially if you're not doing a company-wide Meetup but there's so many other beautiful tools like take a child, take, you know, tools to get together virtually as well.
I sometimes laugh, when we get this question because it's like easy for all of us to say like we're VP is, were people leaders like making space intentionally for social interaction, we can do without the fear of any backlash.
I think that a lot of the times ice needs or first-time managers or people that are just more Junior in the org, don't feel like they have the space or the, okay, or the go-ahead to be able to just have a team virtual happy hour or, like, have a competition of who had the best Halloween costume and so being able to Set those examples and encourage the teams to set up those two.
That time is really, really important.
You can't just assume the team leads know that they can do that or that I seized conspiracy had that from the ground up like you do have to lead, by example, and you should remember to like clearly articulate that to your team's to give them the space.
Oh that's yeah.
I think the only thing I would add to that is I think sometimes there's always the issue of like what we do, but I think sometimes the most important thing is to recognize why we do it and that's why I like one of the things that we have really found important is giving people opportunity to serve together and what comes about from that.
Like, for example, I got to brag on one of my co-workers.
Renee she launched kind of welcome like a culture team at our company, they call them culture Champs and, you know, they talk about Ways that they can celebrate, you know, hello is goodbyes, you know, big a big event, you know, but the bigger part of it, yes, those do things that produces things in the company.
But the biggest thing that happens is what happens among the team itself.
Once they are serving together, once they are doing things together, that is where the bond really is happening.
Is the way that they bond with each other?
So, the more that you can facilitate initiatives like that, that usually ends up being kind of just such a fertile ground for people to build friendships and really build development and develop.
You know, trust among each other.
That's powerful.
So there's a lot of lead by example that I am hearing there's some over communicating as managers as leaders that we need to do to make sure that our individual contributors are managers are all knowing that they have permission to be able to gather and come up with activities of gathering is there like a sweet spot number of in-person impromptu.
Gatherings that you have seen work, you know.
Like what's the right?
Cadence because you know some folks they're going to do a company Gathering maybe once a year.
Maybe there's some leadership, only Gatherings that happen throughout the quarters.
But is there a Cadence that you're seeing employees really responding?
Well to, you know, is there like an excess amount in a given quarter?
We should have at least these amounts of asynchronous opportunities to meet along with maybe some virtual You know, I don't know if happy hours are still in but having social Gatherings virtually, like, what are you seeing as working and not working?
Nadia, I am so interested in here if you have a magic number on this one, but I feel like for me it's like a programmatic thing.
So anytime if I can feel the team is really stressed, or we have just done or in the middle of a really big project or work is starting to feel like all work, no, play kind of thing, even though that's the hardest time too.
Stop work for a social interaction.
I often think that's the most important time to remind people to come together to build friendships that have fun to talk about how hard it is.
Like it.
All these things don't have to just be like manifested positivity, like sometimes it is just being able to be like this is tough right now.
Like now let us have a virtual beer and getting to gather town or something like that just breaks it up and acknowledges what's really happening from a programmatic perspective?
I think it's like identifying those moments.
Pants as they happen is just as important as having things pre-planned.
I think, for me, social connection is also sometimes and especially if you want to build that deep connection, you really need to look at that team size.
Because if you're doing it, company-wide really hard, how people show up in front of people, they don't know, at 900 employees is, much harder than looking in team like five to 10 people.
And, so I really like doing something socially with the people team.
If I And twice a month.
If I can't once a month of yeast, that Cadence just works really well for us.
Interesting fact, is our people meetings that Weekly at a stage was social first, and meet and work second, and that was our weekly.
People meeting everything else was soft, async we became better and better at solving hard problems.
Asynchronously, wherever (else) than doing it on a zoo call or virtually together that together.
Time became this fun card weight over the top, you know, opportunity and it never sat with me.
I realized that if I become a single source of failure to create social connection, I need to make sure the whole team is responsible for it.
So we have to rotate the ownership of it, everyone in the team.
And if there's someone that truly doesn't want to do it, absolutely, they can reach out and go.
I need to skip.
This is way too much for me.
This is not something I am comfortable with and that works as well but I think we have created is Through the creative things people come up with a my brain space.
In terms of creativity has a limit, I have a lot of things to think about in one day, but the things my, you know, the people team came up with was so incredible and so fun, we lost week, we did a picture to play who's in our people, enablement team, and she asked for a picture of your fridge.
And you know, we did this like live meet.
I have been guess, like, who's very just that there was a name for it.
I can't remember the game, but it was like a nap.
It was so good and you know looking at people's fridges working at a remote company, our team is distributed in more than 10 countries just the people team.
It's really hard to get together but it created this like super weird connection about oh my gosh we use the same butter or, and I am on the other side of the world and so that devil of connection was really fun.
Also, how we crossed guest people that are similar and just realizing, oh my goodness, this person.
And this person did have some of the fridges We focus that.
So I think it's really about that lightness and doing it regularly, but the size of the group matters, meetups at a company.
This size in 75 countries is really difficult.
It takes a year to organize it.
There's always inequity experiences, right?
Someone's going to have to fly for more than twenty-four, five hours.
And usually it's the crowd from Africa, the crowd from Asia, and a pack in Australia, New Zealand and that stuff.
And, so I think the pandemic halted a lot of in-person M, I would certainly like to see more of them.
I think the only thing that I would add to that is that aside from kind of the in-person Gatherings and stuff like that is the importance of just finding small ways to incorporate it into the rhythms of our everyday life.
Like I mean one of the things that we do for a lot of our teams is basically whoever's birthday it is they rotate like someone figures out like what's the favorite color?
Like what some favorite things, and then we just all come that day dress in a favorite color or like you know having a virtual background just little things like that are kind of Moving into the fabric of everything that we do usually ends up being really meaningful as well.
These are great ideas, Samantha and chats drop an idea.
We did something similar where on our Global employees screen, share Google Street View.
Yes.
And walk through neighborhoods.
Love that really good one.
Yeah, that's great.
Yeah.
If any of you have any other ideas that's working, please drop it in chat.
Thank you all for sharing these.
Yeah, these are ideas that I am like taking notes on, and we're going to figure out how to implement them with our team like today.
You know, going back to the point, Laura, you were talking about intentionality communication, like we need as Leaders to be examples to do this.
How are each of you intentionally championing friendships at work today?
Like, what is this?
Look like in your day-to-day in your month to month and your quarter?
You know I do think it is a lot of what we have talked about already like it is setting up and making space for it so it is making sure that all of your team meetings aren't just business down to business.
Like, you have to set aside space to have fun.
It is onboarding buddies.
It is celebrating Transitions and promotions and whatever it might be.
And making sure that everybody feels comfortable with that, it's all of the ideas we have had in the chat and then also it's allowing your team, the space to like, decide what they want to do themselves.
So, one of the things that we actually do is a quarterly quarter day here at Loom, so each of the sub departments to keep the team's a little bit smaller to Nadia's Point.
Get Pick a Friday that they come in for a quarter of the day, just to spend time together, socially, purely social, and then they sign off for the rest of the day and get to go live their lives and do whatever they want with their own friends or people in their lives, or whatever it might be.
And I think that's been a really great way to make space, not just for friendships at work, but friendships outside of work.
So you're consistently connecting with people around you in your life, without always having to be plugged in and on and responding to the millions of questions.
And I think that things like that are really important.
Similarly, there are people that I try to Champion when I see them doing really well for building up culture.
So if somebody drops like, hey, this is what I am listening to on Spotify.
In our marketing team chat, I will always send them a DM.
That's like thank you so much for like being such an advocate for building a culture here at Loom.
That's incredibly important.
I would love to see you continue doing that and almost always those people start building on one another.
And when one person is doing in that in the chat and it's not coming from a leadership perspective, because that always is, Like forced sometimes fun but it when it's like the ICS and the people that are creating this from the ground up, that's really.
When you start to see to Nadia's Point, like all of the creative ideas that you never would have thought of before coming to life.
So it is like making sure that you're praising people for being cultural Advocates, the same way you praise people for doing a really good job on a project hoof.
That's huge, you're talking about what you celebrate, what you encourage, what you don't as leader.
I think that's huge in indicating and just guiding the direction of the culture.
Any other thoughts Nadia Rodrigo.
I love doing exactly that they're in a public, thanks Channel because not only are you like celebrating the person but all of a sudden, everyone else sees it and it's interesting how those things do manifest, because someone else use it.
And they like, yes, I needed that today.
I needed to see your French Bulldogs, like, do something really weird in a single call or, you know, I needed to see your kids like cycling or whatever the whatever you're into and I think it's like is a great space for it.
Formal communication.
I think the pandemic blood alliance you know so much.
We became formal communication.
And so if you don't make space for that thank you.
Like thank you so much for posting that amazing, you know, update or Spotify playlist or video or whatever.
And what I also like is we have an IRL channel.
So in real life looking at that is also manifesting something the amount of people that are clicking an emoji and saying, Like wow, I wish I was there is manifesting ideas of who should I meet up with?
How can I use my budget?
Like I need to connect with people, and so I am seeing interesting requests about, can I use my meter budget to do something virtually because I am not near anyone.
And so that's what other ideas for people in my seat to go.
Oh my goodness, there's some unfair Equity yet.
We need to figure out how to meet that person's needs.
And, so I think yeah is about Public thanking but I love that idea.
Laura, the only this one thing I will add about this connection ID.
So one-on-ones, this is not just about manages any.
I see you can do this as well.
Anyone and one that you start, if you start that with a question about.
So, Gina, let us say, your dog is, like, Luna and I go Gina.
How's Luna doing you mentioned, you know, Luna refused to go out for a walk last week, all of a sudden you're going to remember Amber that I remembered your pet's name and that they refused to go out for a walk.
And it was so significant to you when you shared it with me, that, that, that builds, that one-on-one connection with leaders, and Isis, and peers.
And so at all levels, you start really manifesting connection.
And I think that's often missing in the world of Zoom not that product, the environment infrastructure just because everyone hates an agenda or like, you know, starts a DM with.
So what have your priorities In this week?
And we can all stare care of that and David until later in the course.
So to me, that's really important.
It's also that one-on-one time.
I love that video.
Paul told me, I will see you will see me around a message about something he purchased, or something.
He's kid did like a random photo of his kid to doing something.
You know, very random, very extreme, very cute.
And to me, I think that relationship at all levels is necessary.
It's just, it's not supposed to be just a joke.
It is supposed to be everyone that has that social connection with each other so good.
Yeah.
I think one of the things especially for companies that have gone from an in office setting to having to be remote or hybrid, I think we can easily fall into the Trap of feeling like we have to recreate the in office environment, and we kind of just have to come to terms with the fact that's not possible.
I mean there's a reason why I like you know Mark Zuckerberg is spending billions of dollars.
Drinking the metaverse was like we got to leave that to him, but we I think that there are ways in which we can look at the outcomes that come from in-person interactions and reverse engineer it from there and kind of building.
This s*** is around that, you know, like I think about like what happens oftentimes.
It's like if you're an in-person setting, what really happens is self-disclosure you end up being vulnerable.
You end up sharing your story and from that comes connection from that comes belonging from, that comes building a sense of trust.
And so, we have really leaned into creating avenues for people to Are their narratives because that doesn't always happen very naturally in setting.
So like one fun thing that we did is we launched this thing called me to Torchy.
Oh, we're basically we just do an interview, like it's really funny like basically it's like a 10-minute interview.
We asked him questions, you know, ranging from kind of like what kind of coffee they have in the morning to like who their best friend was in junior high to my personal favorite is I ask them.
You know if you were given a year-long sabbatical what would you do with that time?
And then we do a bunch of different settings.
We found ways to do it live during our Person retrieve.
We just did one that we just recorded, and we just dropped it in the, in the general Channel and it's interesting.
Basically, it's once you create that content where people are able to put out their story out there.
People build connections based on that, you know, like one of the people that we did a me to torture with was a gal cat.
And in doing that, I found out that she is a child of an immigrant and you and she was raised by immigrants and then that's my story too.
So we end up having a whole hour long conversation.
Just on that.
And that wouldn't have been something that we would have like, naturally.
Like that doesn't.
Exactly come up in conversation, naturally, you know, and so providing Avenues to where people can intentionally share their stories really, really proves powerful and just making that stuff happen naturally.
That's so good.
The storytelling aspect are there any just tactical ideas in how you can facilitate you know, within your team Gathering of the stories and then sharing of them?
We have done like a trivia session.
We're starting Nadia.
Oh, we have done like a trivia session where I will DM the people on my team in the background and ask them random things.
Like, what is one weird thing that you have about food or opinion?
You have about food or tell me one embarrassing story from your childhood or tell me the moment that you're the most proud of and then I will put them all on a screen and everyone will try to like match who they think it is in the chat and then the person will reveal themselves afterwards and Give us more context about the story or the moment or whatever it might be.
And that's been a really fun and funny way to like, learn more about people's lives, without having them feel like they're a talking head, would just, like, spewing a story at somebody for five minutes kind of thing.
It adds, like some freshness to how they're sharing.
Love that.
Nadia did you have a?
Yeah I think it will hand is even a really nice time for storytelling and specifically stories that are meaningful to that person it can be about anything.
And, so I am actually considering implementing storytelling it remote in Q4 where instead of having like all hands and another update, we so good with a sink updates at remote.
I would love to leave a bit of space with someone can just share something that's happened this year.
And the outcome or the impact on them and again, we can bring different trains, we can bring different subjects, we can bring the fun side of it in but you know has remote work had a meaningful impact on your life has remote.
The company had a meaning for you impact on your life and so you start building a connection with someone else.
Who's going to listen to that story and go my goodness?
I can relate.
I have to set up a coffee chat.
This person exactly like Rodrigo said he found that connection with someone that I didn't know existed and that was accidental.
All right, and so in a remote company you need to find a way to set up accidental connection and that's a great way to do so, you know, two things I would throw in on that.
I think one of the things that becomes really, really important in.
This is to make room for different temperaments because like we have had a very intentionally look for ways for introverts to be able to, you know, engage with this you know, because obviously we're going to do an in-person interview.
Like I remember when I was talking to folks to do them at all Retreat, you know, one Was a great candidate for.
It's like, there's no way I am going to be standing in front of 160 people.
That I have never met telling my story and that really.
So that's why we end up also doing ones that are written out and put them out in the newsletter.
So like really making, you know, avenues for different folks on that.
One thing that our company did that was incredibly powerful.
We just had our in-person Retreat and Utah in our CEO.
I am sorry one of our co-founders LED this really it was kind of like life story Workshop.
To where people were able to sit with their, with their story, reflect and kind of create chapters to their story.
And then there was three different sessions that they did ten minutes.
Each the first one was going over a high point.
Second one was going over a turning point that it was going over a low point, and they were just able to share with each other on that.
But I think the most important thing about that one is that it was modeled by the top.
Are you know, a co-founder was able to share his story first?
So he was able to say hey here's what it looks like and secondly Like you was a really able to model like guardrails.
If you will like you went through this whole thing about kind of like the scale of vulnerability, you know like one to ten, you know, here's under, sharing here's oversharing, here's kind of where you want to be in the middle.
So creating those buffers.
And really that modeling really, really went a long way to people feeling comfortable, sharing their story and really engaging and it was incredible.
The kind of connections that were built by people.
The level of self-reflection that happen and kind of just, it was really exciting and, you know, and we're looking at ways to do that.
We as well because you know in person thing is a little difficult.
So yeah, that was one thing that came up for us.
What I am hearing is the theme of just humanizing one another that's like yeah, it's the bottom line.
Like, I think we have missed that when we were in person and just always in the office you know, 23 years ago.
And now as we're trying to adjust to figure out how to work asynchronously, a lot of those human, just basic components, get lost in the interactions.
And so being intentional and I think articulating and In those things out is so important.
And I am hearing a lot of that lead, by example that over communication.
It almost feels like you have to over communicate, even ten times more than you did when we worked in person.
You know.
So yes, thank you for sharing those ideas.
I want to jump right into some of these Q&A questions.
We have one, that's been upvoted from Dan mohel.
Katie, if you don't mind, putting that on stage, I have read push back to calling workmates family, it can get toxic, we're all family.
We work late while making business decisions like replacing people, how do we balance the idea of friends?
While remaining professional great question.
Anyone.
Yeah, I don't think work is.
I don't think your family work with you.
You're not going to off-board a family member, you're not going to have a very Frank or difficult discussion with them, or maybe you would, but I think it's harder to do it with someone family.
And with, I think when you call someone family, it does blur the lines of the relationship boundaries were really important at work.
I have met people and work that I am absolutely best friends with To the state, whether we work at the same company anymore, not and I think those relationships to time and how much I shared in the beginning, versus how much I would share with them in my life stage now is very, very different, right?
But I think it's about the our boundaries and I think what you're sharing and that vulnerability, I love that God real story that Rodriguez s*** about storytelling with God, rails, and reflecting and showing up for that.
You can write a guideline of, you know how friendships at work.
Work.
You can open source it for amazing other companies like all of us.
And then we can, you know, all share that experience.
But I think it's important to have guardrails and place.
And I don't think you work with your family, unless you really do unless you're a small start-up and have a bunch of having rivers, but I think it is.
These are your colleagues and your friends and there's a difference, I love looking at the comments and Sandra.
I think you hit the nail on the head to where the imagery of Team.
Oftentimes, it's so much better than family because yeah, like Lee like you're, you know, for lack of better term.
You're stuck with them like it's a, it's a permanent relationship.
When you think about the imagery of team, it's all about.
Do you have the right people on the field and there're times to where someone is the right person on the field for a season but things change and now and then someone else actually becomes a better fit for that and having that framework to where everyone has the Viewpoint of what's best for the team.
What's going to produce us winning?
Then it doesn't become as personal, you know, like maybe I am for a season.
I was right person for this position, but then things changed and I had to move to another position.
So having the image of Team feels a lot more healthy than the imagery of family.
I completely agree with that and was going to use like a really similar metaphor to talking through it.
But I think that it is so important to understand that, like, when you are part of a business, ultimately the businesses survival and the, what's best for the business is the only thing that matters and that like, sucks to hear, especially in a community like a Station where we are talking about humanizing things and it is important to bring human elements to work.
But at the end of the day you are all there so that this business can survive and so it can hopefully Thrive.
And unfortunately when we look at the macroeconomics today, when we look at what's happening in the world, the perspective of what businesses needed, three months ago, one year ago are all incredibly different, and we're seeing a lot of really hard change happen to companies right now and that's not personal.
That's not you excommunicate somebody from I am your family, it really is just you have to take people out of it.
When you are making really, really difficult business decisions.
And when you're making decisions about your family, you can't take people out of it because people are at the Crux of it, and that's the core difference.
Now, what I will say is like that gets harder and harder As you move up in your career when you are.
And I see I actually think it's okay to have like your fam of people that Empower you, that are your peers at work because you're not making decisions about their well-being.
How long?
They're Be staying at the company how well they're going to do or delivering performance reviews.
Having hard conversations or having to have the ultimate hardest conversations about exiting a business.
I think it's okay to like rely on your peers and I do think a lot of those friendships transcend, the business, a lot of the times and you're making decisions that impact those friendships and that work group.
Now, that's should stay at like a peer level, sometimes those things change, people get promoted and then, unfortunately, that will rupture change the friendship.
And Some kind of meaningful way, but that's kind of the game that you're playing.
When you are building friendships at work.
It does just look quite different from building, friendships from somebody.
You met at your yoga class or whatever?
It might be, there are different.
There're different steaks.
Very good.
Clarifications yeah.
Wow, I am like taking all these mental notes here.
I will be able to re watching the recording and definitely jotting down the notes.
We have got another question here from Hamza.
How do we mitigate or prevent biases unconscious implicit bias when they are healthy friendships at work?
That's such a meaningful question and it's so hard.
I think it's really hard in the role of managers and any one of the people team because if you have that framed in another team, how you need to make decisions about that has to remain unbiased.
You have got to keep that intact and I it's never ever easy but very often when I need to make really difficult decisions.
I put everything aside and have a good fact.
Because that is going to tell me what's really going on.
So if someone is underperforming, and we have provided feedback and there are a friends of mine, we are going to have a hard conversation.
Because factually there's a problem, and so I think that's also leads back to the family comment.
It's much harder to do that with family.
It's way easier to do that in a team setting.
And so, it is really about the dynamic of again, in Oro, City saying, you know, it's about the business.
I see it in three ways.
Actually, it's about the business, it's about the customers but the people do't work for the business and it doesn't work for the customer and it doesn't work for the rest of the people.
There's a problem and so that often helps remove the bias Factor just because you need to look at it from those three angles and not from any other ankle.
But yeah, it can be really difficult if you really close to someone, especially during the stage of the economy and for what companies are going through right now.
It's also super important always to like trust yourself.
Trust your instincts, look at the facts, but sometimes when you do know, there is a bias involved, you cannot just trust yourself.
Even if you think your objectively looking at the facts, I often think that there are times when it's really important to bring in a trusted Confidant or trusted Confidant who maybe are closer or have other contacts or other perspectives that are not skewed by your own personal biases, whatever that might be, that could be friendship.
That could be recency bias.
How recently, You started working with this person, whatever that might be you might need to get other qualitative opinions that are equally as important as the quantitative before making some kind of decision or whether that be positive or negative for somebody that you have a perceived friendship at work.
Now, the only thing that I would add to that too, is the importance of feedback loops, you know, be they Anonymous be, they, you know, providing a really safe place where people can come tell you directly.
Well I think that with that too is to everyone's Point making sure that we understand that.
That doesn't, that information doesn't may not necessarily control where we go, but it does provide context for it.
It's a data point.
It's something that we need to take in and self-reflect about and let that be, you know, add to the conversation that we're having in situations.
This is great.
All right, I am going to keep going through these questions.
We have one from Sarah and this is touching a question that we may have sort of answered earlier, but what are some of the top ways to facilitate bonding?
So if you were to identify, here's the top one, two, three things that are working right now, with my team, what are those things?
I will start, I think one to me is accessibility rodrigue or touched on it when it comes to introverts.
We have a whole world of difference at this stage, right?
No matter where you work.
There's a complete world of difference.
And so was that difference comes nearer, diversity.
Introverts and extroverts.
It comes so many cultural differences that some folks might be comfortable with, and completely uncomfortable with, or not even normal in their cultural country.
And so on, I think it's really important that you have a fiery nicely documented process or I would lean into documentation have a guideline on how to do social connection.
One to create accessibility for all these amazing people, we have got V RF remote.
Not a lot of people enjoy it, but we do engineers really do enjoy it.
But they also have folks in our growth marketing team that really enjoys it and in the people team and another team's.
So I do see that as a completely different.
Bonding opportunity, they live in their Avatar and that's how they connect and bond, and they know each other's avatars.
And so making space for accessibility for those different groups and different individuals in your organization and different cultures.
I think is incredibly important and my third one, I am going to lean in to say go lead by example, you have got a shot for that sharing being vulnerable at executive leadership level manager level.
And then with your peers, Yeah, I love that.
The only thing you didn't say they're Nadia that you have said before that I think is also equally important is remembering the personal details.
Like I really do think it is so important that if someone tells you something personal about your life like actually make an effort too intentionally.
Remember the pet's name, the partner's name, how many siblings?
They have whatever it is that they felt like sharing.
That's often an extreme moment of vulnerability at work.
So like don't take that for granted.
Absolutely.
I would also say like really setting the precedent of encouraging people to take it off of slack.
I think like we had a previous place.
I worked, we talked about like level one and level two conversations to we're level one.
It's just what happens every day like, you know, just back and forth.
And really it's anytime you have a communication that's not necessarily up for interpretation.
But anytime that goes above that hop on a call, you know, do a quick like, you know, Zoom meeting, you know, do use those funny little like chat features that Have in slack, you know, just because if you look at the statistics, I mean only 7% of communication actually happens.
Be of the words that are said, the rest of it is all tone and body language.
And so in the absence information we fill in the blanks and so really encouraging people to hop on those calls is really, really helpful.
And then, the other thing is really weaving it into the day-to-day.
Those finding those small ways for it to happen, and not relying on the big ways solely.
You know whether it's like, we're Going about, you know, in everyone saying remembering those details for when it comes to birthdays, you know, doing those virtual backgrounds, like those small ways, add up quite a bit and especially if they're kind of happened again and again, and again in the fabric of the day.
So good, thank you, Dan mohel.
Has another question here, work-life balance question.
How do L Foster friendships, while not cutting into personal time?
This is what the idea I said, earlier, about forced fun.
I feel like and naughty.
I think I always knew this to you, I am so sorry.
Lord, I want you to always do not talk.
We always want to talk at the same time.
No, I prefer.
It is.
You go with this and I agree, so I am going to give yes, I think.
All right, and then we will hand it back to you because I am sure you're going to add on to it too, but I think the idea of forced fun is really difficult.
Like if you're forcing your team to join a happy hour during the time that they're usually putting their kids to better bed or trying to make dinner or something like that.
That's when you start showing that you're not making fun accessible and you're not making friendships accessible to these people.
We have to be thoughtful about cultivating relationships at work.
During work hours and understanding that it's just as important to build space for culture and cultural and connection to be happening as it is for them to get projects done during work hours.
So you're making time for social behaviors, should not happen on the weekends or when these people have already set their, like, I am I don't take meetings during these hours types of things like you have to think about prioritizing these hours, while these folks are at work, how do I do natya?
Really, really well.
And like time zone inclusivity is a thing, right?
So exactly what you said, if, if you distribute a teams are hard and the one day I tend to stay away from for social activities, especially considering I have a lot of folks in a pack at remote is Friday's?
Just because if you're doing something on a Friday, you are eating into someone's weekend.
And that someone could be 10% of your organization.
It could be one.
It doesn't matter.
So I agree.
I think what it comes to time zones and this, like, not cutting into personal time, it is about sharing the load.
If you join a company that is this distributed where I am at, you have got to understand.
There will be times when you have got to lean in, but there has to be times when the other person is going to lean into.
And that I share that feeling about social connection as well.
So maybe this week, we have a social time for very earlier mayor, Ed back overlap but next this week we're going to have a man.
Erica saw the lab.
So I think it is a little bit about sharing the experience and knowing that it is going to be different part of the future of work, but time zone inclusivity is so important.
Scheduling something at someone's 6 AM is going to be awful.
They are not going to show up excited and ready for a beard happy hour.
So they'd much rather have a coffee.
So yeah, I agree.
Yeah.
You know, I have actually always struggled with that term work-life balance.
I have always found it.
Much healthier to view it as a work-life rhythm, because balance.
Always, you know, it communicates.
Everything is always the same.
Everything is always static and that isn't true.
You know, it's like you think about, like, what makes a song?
Good.
Sometimes it goes fast, sometimes they go-slow.
But that's actually what makes it that rhythm is, what makes it, you know, a good song and understanding those rhythms of our life, like we have had again like As everyone's, you know, alluded to like my on my team were across like a bunch of different time zones, and we have to understand everyone's rhythms.
I remember when I was joining the team, it was right as I was about to become a new father for the first time.
And I was talking to one of my co-workers and I remember when she was asking me how I felt about it and, you know, said a bunch of stuff in somewhere in there.
I said, I just want to make sure it doesn't disrupt my work, and she said, hey, stop right there because that's the wrong way to view it.
It's like, because we really have come to see that It's just all continuous like it's all part of the same thing.
There's going to be times when your kiddo is going to cry and you need to get up and you know go be with your kid over there, going to just jump in the middle of a meeting.
And having that Grace in awareness of each other's Rhythm, has proved Monumental and how we engage with each other.
Wow.
So rich.
I feel like we could continue talking for another hour, but believe it or not.
We have 5 minutes left with our time together.
And the questions have come through All the insights have that have been shared are so amazing, you know, one question that I still have that.
I just quickly wanted to go around with is are there any tools?
Are there any processes?
We have touched a lot of different ideas here, but are there any tactical tools that you see teams can start using today to be able to build productive, strong relationships?
I think we have said a lot of them and I do think a lot of them are like the obvious ones, like it's like Zoom.
Like, do take things off slack to Rodrigo's Point earlier, like bring your body language and your face and how you're trying to communicate things, especially if it could be easily.
Misinterpreted, if you're delivering hard news, if it's something that requires like decision-making, like, don't have that.
Be an asynchronous communication like think about other ways that you can personalize it shames.
Self promotion of loom once again, but I do think that bringing like your face and your body language and your tone to what you're saying is super, super important, and we tend to get really lost in slack.
A lot of the time.
I also think there are fantastic tools to Nadia's point about creating these channels where you're giving shoutouts.
There are tools like bonus lie that exists, where every person at your company gets, you know, ten to twenty dollars a month, and they're able to give those dollars out as think use or congratulations or celebrating people.
Apple, it's a fantastic way to build and drive culture and its way that your tangibly making more money or like getting bonuses for doing good deeds or for connecting with people or for helping out a pier.
And I think that not only helps Inspire like connection like these moments of recognition for folks but it also just creates a more collaborative and inclusive work environment.
We love bonus lie, we use it as well and Loom.
Yeah, I think to Laura's point we have mentioned a ton.
I know when that we use a lot is whisk.
It's like a social network that specifically tailored around work, but one of the things I keep coming back to is like I am reminded of like, you know, when the space race was first happening to the Moon, you know, like they had to solve the problem of, how do you write in you know, zero gravity, you know, in the u.s.
Spent like millions of dollars and thousands of man-hours building a pen that can write a 0?
In the Russians, just use the pencil and sometimes like the simplest approach is the easiest, you know, and it's right in front of our face.
Be, they emojis be, they virtual backgrounds be they everything that we have talked about today don't feel the need to always have to rely on that Silver, Bullet of Technology when you know because that oftentimes the Vols money and involves time and it's okay to, you know, to use the products that you have.
And yes, Laura, that's actually how I fell in love with loom.
Is that same thing?
Sad.
Say I will add one thing that's going to nearly take this on a different straight but just like a thought the more integration and automation you do no matter what team you have.
People team like any team that's doing tactical, operational administrative work.
If you can use the right Tech tools to integrate and automate those stuff so that no one is sitting and doing data.
Capturing, there is so much more time for engagement.
I find that especially in the people team.
So what I find is, if I do that and get rid of like uman data, capturing very heavy, administrative tasks, my team can have space to be more creative and show up for Theory engaging conversations.
But this is not just the people team, it's across the whole book.
So I love HR, Tech and integrating an automating stuff, and leaning on my Engineers for help.
Love it and I think Laura you summed it and chat, you can't automate human connection, it's got to be manual, it's got to be intentional.
So with that, we're going to wrap up our time.
Thank you so much.
Nadia Laura Rodrigo, for sharing your time, your insights, your presence with us today.
Thank you everybody who attended in chat, your engagement, you have been present with us as well.
And though, we're all virtual I can feel the connection with each one of you and it's very special so have a wonderful rest of your day.
You know check out we have got a couple of other Spotlight interviews that we're going to be doing over the next few weeks.
And we have got Alex from first base Brooke from Loom and Mattea from tight form.
And we're going to dive deep actually into their stories and journeys of how they got to doing what they do in B2B marketing.
And also here, there Their expertise and wisdom in what they're learning is working with not working in their practices.
So with that thank you all so much and I look forward to seeing you at our next event.
Alright, have a wonderful rest of your week.
Bye.