Kanikapila in the old Hawaiian way.
We do it from the mountain, to the ocean, from my Windward, to the leeward from now, I will do lives.
From now on, we will do the leaves.
Go Grandma's house on that.
We can clean your.
If we don't know where my God, oh my God, from the mountain, to the ocean from my window.
We do it from the mountain to the ocean from the windward.
My mom's in the kitchen cooking dinner, real nice, beef stew.
Almost all of them are sending with us.
We drink and we sing all the time from now.
We do it from the mountain to the ocean from now, and we will do the leave.
Into the ocean from Maui.
Hi everyone.
Aloha, I hope you enjoyed the tunes.
We are so excited today to see you all here.
We have Alex VP of marketing from first base who be joining us.
I am Gina head of marketing with welcome, and we're starting these Spotlight series, and we're just kicking these off for the first time.
So today is our first interview.
We're going to try to keep it within 30 minutes if we can, and we welcome your questions.
As we're diving into Alex's Journey, his story and ultimately what?
All of us are curious about is the LinkedIn phenomena that first space had where they were able to get their first 100 customers just through Linkedin as their sole marketing channel alone within 18 months.
So all of us are really curious to hear more about that and Alex is going to share.
But yes, please drop your questions and Q&A.
And in the meantime, Alex would you join me on stage?
Hello.
It's great to be here.
Thanks for having me.
Absolutely.
So we had to have the Aloha Island Vibes because, you know, I am actually out here in Hawaii right now, and I am in Ewa Beach because my husband's from here, but I am from La.
So I am still learning about the Aloha Spirit and the pigeon accent, and even how I pronounce Hawaii.
Like it's with a like a V pronunciation.
Write the W?
Yeah.
If you're strictly speaking.
Yeah, be Hawaii.
Actually have a lot Hawaii.
Like, if you see it spelled out there's like a little accent kind of apostrophe after the first.
I so but you know, people argue, no say it, the normal way.
Awesome.
Well, test is when you're driving down the highway in your life, What's kalanianaole you like the all the, all the syllable vowels, right?
Totally.
I butcher all the names.
So still learning over here but you're from Hawaii, and we have a quick little poll that Katie in The Green Room.
Our producer.
Thank you for pulling that up.
How many of you have visited, Hope Hawaii, feel free to drop in about they're not yet or yes you have Gone ahead and drop your votes.
All right.
Oh, here we go.
Awesome.
So we have got a good chunk of folks who have Vince of Hawaii and also a good number who haven't yet.
So we're kind of even here.
I mean with that Alex, you actually grew up in Hawaii what part?
So I grew up in a hunter Lulu which is, so I am a city boy in Hawaii terms.
Yeah, for sure we got the tunes.
I was looking all the landscape shots as I was kind of putting me in my feels because it's yeah, it's a beautiful place.
It is and you actually went to Punahou which is a private high school here on Oahu and I had to throw Obama's face on it because Obama went to Punahou, right?
Yeah, right.
He was in the class before my older brother who also want to go home.
So I mean, I never crossed paths with my brother did, but he was not obviously was not famous.
Then he was known as Barry at school.
So you know, he's just like another kid, totally it's.
But when you were going through school you know I guess it had he been known, yet I guess not yet, right?
Totally, not totally not yeah, we're looking at now is the love as an Alum though.
Is it a big deal to be a Punahou Alum and like Obama went there as well?
You know, it's funny for sure that I think the school super proud of that as you would be, you know, it's funny because our class, my graduating class.
But now has another celebrity that they're kind of attached to from the clouds, which is carry out.
Another was one of the judges on Dad's.
So it was like, wow, these little sort of celebrity connection that I take precedence in a particular class.
Super fun.
All right.
Well, I would love to dive into three parts for this time together.
And, you know, first diving into thank you for sharing the little bit of the Aloha.
But diving into your background, your story, your journey about all of this, you know, you're a Serial startup marketing leader and so you know, just walking through a little bit of that journey and then going into the big question that we have around how first base was To get its first 100 paying customers will go into that through Linkedin as an engine.
And then finally, we'd love to wrap it up with just some sort of point of encouragement for the group that we have here.
So let us start with your story and if you could just track back and walk us through first of all, like you got to be a little crazy To Be A Serial startup leader.
I mean you have been through multiple vc-backed startups building the marketing Ian, can you walk us through a little bit of your Tech background?
Yeah, sure.
I mean, I think, you know, I stumbled into startups relatively early in my career, you know, you know.
And as a marketer one of the things you know, I think about it as I didn't start a, I didn't start out intending to go into marketing per se was a little bit journey to get into that.
I was actually in the field, you know, Solutions engineer and then kind of morphed into and then I kind of Not that I wanted to be kind of in the morning, the center of things and there was doing like tactical marketing and then, but I will end in a start-up where I ended up owning a product line that I had to kind of do everything for, you know.
And, you know, went through an acquisition.
It was my first sort of, like, eye-opener of like, oh my gosh, you know, this happens in startups, right?
And, you know, and from there, I think, you know, journeying through a product management, a little bit of segments of product management, and then I Think I got a taste of the marketing side because I started owning product marketing, you know, and then it just sort of dawned on me that I really, really liked that aspect of the work I was doing.
I mean, not putting on product management enjoyed this, my stent in it but it's a very, very, very process-oriented thing and you know it has its own world.
I love the fact that you know, you know.
And I was already at that point doing startups, right?
And experience all the ups and downs.
That you have in startups like a start-up start an emotional rollercoaster, basically, right at the marketing, part of that, what was fascinating for me is saying, like, Okay, well, how do you actually boot up the connection to, to the market, right?
And in, and I start off in B, to B and B to B is itself.
A very to be startups, are a particular, kind of marketing as anyone who does it know.
It's As much there's as much intuition as data because your sample set of what you're dealing with and customers like your daily with maybe dozens and then hundreds and that, you know, you're not dealing with like okay.
We have a, you know, a million people interacting with the brand, right?
So it's I think that sort of intuition and content and how to create that connection to the market was really fascinating for me, especially because in a start-up environment, usually start Founders or Like you know, how do we do this?
It's the it's often times at least known discipline for Founders because they tend to come from a technical background and that's one of the joys and challenges of being a B2B marketer and start out, right?
That's right on.
Can you walk us through some of the journey?
Like, well, we're different tech companies that you have had the opportunity to work with and, you know, just even to describe a little bit of, like the engines that you have had.
You build over time?
Yeah, I mean, I first kind of marketing leadership get came in a company called package design.
It was started by a Serial entrepreneur and, you know, it was is one of those situations where there's probably like, you know, like 20 people I have started at multiple companies that pretty small, right?
First marketer kind of walking in the door.
Maybe there's a few things written by an enterprising salesperson or someone else that sort of thing or you know someone else who owns And marketing, but it was like, we need someone to go do this and yeah.
So this was a while ago.
So marketing Tech was very nascent, you know, Mark has exploded as we know and there's like a bazillion tools to choose from now and everything, you know.
But, you know, in the sort of the naissance of that flick, how do we actually just got to be a be effective online with web, with SEO, you know, just the, the foundation's is where I started with that.
They first automation stack, I went to an Israeli startup called quali actually.
We rebranded I came there to go from that first start up, and we grew up and then basically went to an Israeli startup called quali and had a really fun time there, but it was a kind of company that was reaped.
It was pivoting, you know, so it wasn't, there was a little bit of marketing at that, but they need to completely redo the positioning, The Branding, the message, They were shifting into a different market.
So that was an interesting, one against River, you know, my job was like to get them from that, you know, from The Old Company to a new identity, a new brand, new growth market.
So that was a journey there.
I did.
It start up called kentico, which was in the kind of monitoring space of quality was sort of in the devops space can take was sort of in the monitoring.
I did a couple of monitoring things, cantik was one where there was this huge analytics engine, Again, you know, new technology, sort of new approach to an old problem, kind of thing and again, very, very little existed there.
I was the first marketer in the door, you know, building.
You know, it's like one of those things where you have got like five or seven arms, mostly basically contractors as agencies and doing all this stuff for you, you know, trying to build out a tech stack and then growing a staff from there.
From there.
I actually took a little bit of a sideways John into a later stage.
Build out as a head of product marketing company called thousand eyes, where they were kind of trying to get from that.
Let us say 30 40 to 100 journeys, and they needed to redo their go-to market around, you know what's the cross?
The chasm message, and the content of the thought leadership and building that all out.
So we built a big research, go to market research arm that really, you know, to engage market with the data we have and stuff like that.
So what through an acquisition there?
To a little small tiny Australian startup called sineva that wanted to wear the founders were, you know, had built a really cool product and you know, focus on remote work actually, which is sort of the dotted line to how I got to first base because I started get interested in the space.
And that, you know, they had an outcome in mind which was they want to plug into larger tech companies.
So, the job there was a go to market and really grab some share, get some mind share your proof of the product, you know, build a pipeline and at join another company, which happens so Palo Alto.
They were acquired by, we required by Palo Alto networks and then from there, you know, I did a stint at a company called pack of fabric which is like a newfangled Telco likes is totally automated Telco because I knew one of the co-founders there.
So again full stack, build them almost all these things.
It was a complete from the ground stack, build out, you know, and demand, gen nothing, no programs, no stack.
No nothing, right?
Very little content and then kind of try to grow that.
And first base is sort of is an interesting case where you know as you know hinted by the title of this, the company had actually grown a lot through an incredible organic sort of social presence of the founder which I think is really fascinating to look at and learn from as I look at it and have an I came in again to kind of build the Systemic stuff of marketing, right?
From the ground up.
So that's, I mean that those are kind of like my journey points, you know, in as fast as a nutshells, I could put him Incredible Journey and like, wow, major props and respect because there's probably a lot of Battle Scars and stories that you have for being able to Journey with so many companies.
So many different.
Founders, what are some of the like if Looking back at that Journey, you know if you were to pull out one or two nuggets of the things that really worked, when it when you're talking about like your stack, like this is the one, two, three Tech stacks that I always build.
And these are the layers of foundation that I always start with like, what works and then what didn't work maybe if you'd give us you know, a nugget of each of those, that would be great.
Sure.
I think the foundational Foundation to The stack is, is the message, you know, the message is the thing that drives, you know where you want to take your brand identity, its understanding, you know, getting to a really clear sense of what's our distinctive.
And what is it that?
We because I think it's sort of like marketing is about connecting, right?
And a B2B buyers, not just a Persona, they're a person and their that I think the foundation is empathic connection to the audience and to the problems, a B2B startup has a problem to solve and you have to often times.
If you're innovating, you have to unpack that problem for people.
Because if there hasn't been a solution probably, they have just suppress awareness of the problem.
It's there.
It might be very painful, but they haven't really impacted.
So if you can unpack that then that's the Foundational thing that allows your message and your mechanics to create a connection.
You know, people we want to be felt seen, you know, as a buyer I want to feel seen like you get what I am going through and you're speaking to my needs, right?
So that's the real foundation.
And then, you know, on top of that is then is I am just a huge believer that, you know.
Okay?
So text acts and stuff like that are all about your data, you know, Know your data is Destiny and marketing, right?
So like building a really clean hygienic sort of data set knowing what the value and relative like cost of that data is important, right?
Knowing whether or not you can find your audience, Sofia with, sufficiently targeted way because ultimately marketing is, you know, enables commercial things to happen, like in this, you know, opportunities and Pipeline and stuff like that.
Right is, is sort of like is always taking an Ouch what works for me is always making sure that the way I think about the data and how we identify our potential buyers is a strong fit sometimes that you can just get that out of off the shelf.
You know, whatever.
And sometimes you can't and some which case you have to be willing to go there and enrich and think about the metadata that will help you Target and connect to the right people.
You know.
So the because the rest of the stack is really, you know whether whatever choose your automation sweet.
You know, I have kind of been on a Marketo sort of Journey for a little while so that's kind of the way I tend to build but it's like that's your journey in terms of the stack Stacks can work for whatever your purpose is, right?
But it's really about making sure the data is a good fit so you can deliver that empathic connection and open people's minds to the possibility.
That their problem is something that can be solved.
And if you're the one who's communicating about it, effectively and connecting with them, then they're going to say, well I think I am going to give mentally speaking this brand, a chance to tell me how to solve it right the rest of the mechanics.
I mean, let us face it.
How many ways can you communicate?
With people, they haven't changed.
All right, you know, you have email, you have various platform, kind of things, you know, experiences like this.
Right in person things phone calls, right?
Let us just, you know, I mean, in B2B you're not sending a lot of text messages, you know, typically, right?
So like your mechanics are very similar that automation Stacks are commercial choices your data and how you curate that.
Data at the right cost and volume and, and targeted.
Sort of is the key anyway, that was a long dissertation, but that's I think those are some of the key things I think for success in B2B marketing.
That's great.
And so, when you say data, if you could get a little tactical, are you talking about?
Just the key, insights and attributes on the buyer and their behavior.
Like what kind of data points are you immediately setting up your Tech stack to Capture?
So I want to know the ICP from a sales point of view, right?
Whoo-hoo constitutes the best Prospect, you know, the partnership with sales is super important because the pipeline of service to sales is like you're doing marketing engagement, other engagement, you set meetings through SD or bdr teams Etc.
What's the ICP really mean?
What are the points of insight or qualification or Discovery, right?
That really matter those The thing is, I am going to draw drawn, and so I want to do a really good brainstorm there might be.
For example, if you have technical qualifiers, right?
They have to have these conditions in their environment.
Technically speaking to sell your product, they have to have theirs from a graphic size of company, all those sorts of thing.
What's the zone, right?
You want to be in.
There are, you know what title classes and B2B, oftentimes, you're dealing with title classes, and then there are sorts of like propensity to buy indicators their keywords.
You can find there are other things like that, right?
So, and some of those things, again, are collected commercially by, you know, big databases companies, like, Zoom info or others, or whatever, and some of them are just not, and you just have to go and get it right.
There're different ways to do that, but part of it is also the calculation of targeting and going finding data to go after an audience that you have profiled as it were based on, you know, data that would indicate they could benefit from your solution and would be open to it.
Says the venue based right?
Like hey, if you go to conference, you have you are sort of targeting but you're also having a certain amount of Randomness right to like, people come with interest in all sorts of reasons to various venues.
So the balance of how much but you're going to pay a lot for certain kinds of datasets engaged more or less engaged datasets versus you might pay a lot less to discover although you have to go and engage it.
So that balance because marketing is economics to as like you have a finite amount of money to spend to reach the market, right?
I don't know.
That's at least some of how I think about it.
Any do not dues like, is there something clearly that you have learned through failure?
I don't really believe in content syndication.
Hmm.
And here's why because a lot of (Kit) because content in syndication, it's in of itself.
But I think now they're all sorts of places where people consuming things that you subscribe to this.
Whatever thing you know you go to the site over and over to consume stuff.
How much brand awareness do you really have when you can when you consume a piece of interesting content from that site that you have been visiting over and over again very low right clutch often times the price you pay for that can be pretty high you know I mean because like the brand awareness and that the link to a solution, you know, is Important because often times when you're trying to communicate, it's just those little small degrees of awareness that makes someone more like this segment.
I am going to actually read this email or mmm.
I am gonna actually, you know, right?
You know, like consider a conversation.
It's we're dealing with in because so much of the buyer journey is hidden right today?
Much of the buyer journey is become more digital and more invisible for a variety of reasons.
Privacy reasons.
Also, Two things.
So, your brand awareness points and how much you are paying to get those, that mental awareness, and thought leadership awareness, that degree advances over time.
Many cases ways you don't see It's good.
Okay.
All right.
Due to time and this is this has been rich.
I hope folks can still stay beyond our 30 minute Mark here.
This is our first one, give us Grace on.
They're just such Rich content to be able to discuss here.
Let us jump into the LinkedIn.
Yeah, I beg, you know, I think this is like the burning question that we all have.
How did you guys get 100 paying customers Within In months of literally only Chris, herds LinkedIn profile.
I mean, he's got, is it up to 60,000 followers?
Now?
So as long as 50 feet between 55 and 60, I think now and just to give some do, like he's also very active on Twitter and is about the same number of followers there.
So I think there's a combo effect, you know, there're different objects, audiences, that lurk different places.
And I think the, you know, the lessons I take away is that You know, he took what I was.
What I am going to say is a cultural thought leadership angle, he was not, flogging the service, right?
He was speaking to a big felt need and I think that the thing that's the important lesson there is that your you have a corporate brand and a corporate brand, has a communicate at a business level of value, right?
Corporate Brands need to take business value, thought leadership.
But in Social, you're really dealing often times with a different level felt need, which is about the things that are driving those the needs and the felt sort of problems or the challenges in the environment, you know.
So I think one of the lessons from what I saw see you know that Chris has done is he really aimed at that higher level?
What I would say?
Cultural thought leadership.
Hmm.
Now in the remote work space, you know, pandemic the Of work, all that kind of stuff was a big ferment, right?
But there maybe you know it's but whatever the field you're in.
I think that social impact really comes from taking that Higher Culture, maybe it's a tech culture angle, maybe it's in this case is about future of work and things like that is very broad, but I think the big lesson is that it can't be about you.
It has to be about what's having a big impact of what.
What is a point of view, you know, that adds value to people's lives or ORS, helps direct of way of thinking.
So, Chris has taken a very, very assertive.
Very assertive stance.
On.
A lot of things he's been willing to put his kind of ego online and say this is what's going to happen, you know, you won't be if you don't Embrace remote work, as a company, you're just going to be less competitive remote work.
Oriented companies are going to be the more successful.
This is akin to e-commerce.
He's taking he's making these sort of level of claims and that is a so that's a stance that Doesn't really have anything to persuade doing with first base.
And I think that's really important lesson, you know, that's really interesting, and he's very like he's willing to push the bar of his perspective and even get angry, you know.
And I think that's, you know, it's a, it's one of those things where, you know, that does get attention.
But it's because it's pushing a, it's pushing the bounds of comfort without being, you know, may be disrespectful but it's saying there're some places where you To push the bounds of comfortable thinking, right about things.
And that's something that I think is very effective.
You know in Social especially if you're not coming from the angle and you know like would you like to buy one of these kind of a no angle?
That's huge.
I mean, it seemed like Chris.
He also was able to just own his profile like you didn't have to.
There wasn't a marketing leader that came along his side and was Like hey you need to build your profile.
Like he took his own initiative right?
As a Founder.
Yeah, I mean I think that's conviction, you know, I think as a founder or someone who's going to lead out on that, you know, you have to have a certain amount of ego strength, you have to have, you know, willingness to go out and not be perfect.
And you have to have a leave with a lot of conviction.
What do you really have?
You know, super strong conviction about that.
That is speaks to the zone of the world or fly fulfill traffic America.
Sorry I got my little one that just entered into the room.
This is what happens, remote work, folks is you know, that level of conviction comes through, right?
And I think that speaks to where people are at and that see, that's connection, right?
That's, that's a real connection, you know, your brand corporate brand cannot do that at the same level, you know?
No, it's good.
So okay so just speaking tactically here, you know, strip strategy and tactics of like okay if I have a B2B SAS brand where I want to elevate my LinkedIn.
What if I don't have a Founder?
Like Chris heard that, you know, has that sort of even the energy the strategy to put into LinkedIn.
Yeah.
Could it be another figure Within The organization that takes that sort of cultural Transcendent stance where they're not getting into buy, buy, buy my product, but like they're really taking a stance culture like can it be or does it need a come from a founder of a company?
I think what recent what needs to be happened?
Is the founder.
You know?
And yes I mean I haven't previously worked for a company where the founders has had this much sort of social presence.
But I have worked in a space where You know, and I have worked with more techie products and sometimes those just aren't as favorable to the level of like culture thought leadership.
But I think the thing is that someone has to have some conviction and courage to go push at things and say, we're going to take some stance on something that's relevant to what we do.
And in service of what people need in our environment.
And maybe you have data, you know, for example, maybe you have data that, that if you actually like positioned in it, Shushes others in the industry.
You have to be willing to do have some controversy.
I mean, a very nerdy sense.
I will give an example for when I was a thousand eyes.
One of the things I saw, when I got there was here, we have got this amazing.
We have got this data about what's happening in these various Cloud applications and stuff, and one of the things realize there's a lot of Business Leaders.
It leaders are like, when something goes wrong with slack or whatever, it's like, nobody knows really why it's happening.
Because of course, if your slack, you're trying to fix that, but you're not going to say like are out all that like It's not your focus to go.
Analyze, what's happening like from an outside in perspective, so it's sort of like we had this data.
So like, let us go put it out there, you know, and that probably was and I fact I know that was uncomfortable for some applications and Cloud providers and such and, you know, we put our reports and stuff like that.
But are found when our co-founders had the conviction, this was the right thing to do because there was so much lack of understanding, you know.
So we went And I just built a program to kind of push that out there in a responsive way and that got a lot of coverage and attention and all that sort of thing and became some that we could stand on to say we're all about providing intelligence and visibility even though in some ways it might be uncomfortable to call out like hey yeah you know this part was the internet but this part might have been the provider sorry but it's just what we see, you know, it's very helpful.
It was very helpful.
People Express a lot of appreciation for but Others expressed that it was uncomfortable for them.
Our co-founder had the conviction that this was worth doing, and we're pushing hard at that you know.
So there's you know is there something like that you can contribute to the dialogue to the value of people's lives that will push the boundaries of the push of comfort a little bit to get at what's real.
So good about let that simmer with all of us because there's something really powerful about that.
Thought, right there.
All right, we have got some questions coming in.
Let us pull up and questioned on to stage and if you don't mind answering this, what is the most effective LinkedIn marketing tactic you have used at first base?
From know, I tend to believe that especially as a, if you're a startup, that's not very well-known yet.
And, and let us remember that every startup is not very well-known as much as you think like, well, you know, people already know as they don't write, even when you think they really know you, most people don't.
So, I think awareness you know it's like it's the you know the truism awareness that comes in before demand.
That one thing I really like from S cost point of view is doing per company.
Targeted awareness ads you know because creating and going Beyond just your narrow buyer.
You know going a little broader.
I really like that because I think that, you know, it creates brand awareness and it creates if you're proposing sort of problem.
That's You solved it creates an again awareness like oh this is something that we could solve again much of the time.
When doing something new, you have to sell the problem right before you ever get to sell the solution.
So I really like that as, you know, as a way and I have seen in other cases that it works from Prospect point of view.
It also really works in a pipeline point of view, you know, there's a lot of people when someone is considering a purchase that need to start becoming wearing of a brand to, you know.
So I really like that.
That's incredibly helpful.
We have got another question here from Justin.
How do you bridge the gap?
Between cultural messaging and corporate messaging.
Such a good question.
So I think you have to let them have breathing room between them, right?
Let your cultural message be it and then the then you're just doing breadcrumbs, basically, right?
You know, because your corporate messaging should also be value, added thought leadership.
In much, you know, you know, like how to, you know, in a sense you're trying to answer, how to solve a problem that you have that you might not be fully aware of, but we're going to help you understand, right?
That's the cultural thought leadership, the corporate thought leadership is business value thought leadership.
In both cases, there will be a lighter breadcrumb Trail to Brand hey you know, like from a cultural point of view, by the way.
This is what, you know, this is why we, you know, we do.
I start first base or this is my first base exists.
That's really you want to go.
I, in my opinion you want to A little more, just brand awareness kind of thing, corporate value, sort of business value, thought, leadership your bread crumbing from the solution topic 2.
Here's you know, and here's what, you know, this is what we solve, right?
Your cell, your kind of explaining the world of the problem and all that kind of stuff.
And then, you know, this is what we solve.
So they're your bread Crumb from both of them because people don't want to be like assaulted with a pitch.
They want to be, they want to gain knowledge and insight.
And all thought leadership, you have to do that primarily and then you breadcrumb down to if you want to know more, how to solve this, you know, dot here, you know.
So that's my thought about that.
I almost see like an Illustrated buyers Journey, kind of map that likes as you were like saying dotted line to Brand, everything has dotted line to brand, but these are like the levels of messaging that really good thought leadership piece, Alex.
Yeah, hopeful thought leadership dots to brand and Corporate value thought leadership dots to Solution.
That's my mother's whines.
That's good.
All right.
And we have got a question from Sal here.
What are the most effective SEO practices optimizing a marketing campaigns online?
Content?
SEO is all about content now, period, right?
I mean it's that's just the way it's going.
It's less and less about technical games.
There are things you can do to Ruin yourself, technically, just by being bad at constructing websites and stuff like that, but mostly that part's pretty straightforward.
Now, the most effective SEO practice is to is fundamentally to invest in Awareness targeting, their simple tools to do this, right?
You know, the SEO sort of analysis tools, there's a number of those.
And then, and really to do sound, SEO content analysis, fundamentally.
There is a way to write and this is It is a tricky way of it's not easy.
You have to make enough domain knowledge and writing flexibility to do this, but you have to Target things to rank and that is a competitive environment keyword environment, but you also have to have it has value.
That's, you know, say you target then you get a Content analysis and then you have to be really good at writing in between that's How you will you know, that's how you win in my opinion and SEO is, is content optimization in a way, that doesn't lose value to the reader from a, you know, kind of like readability and, you know, I mean, consume ability point of view, I can't just be a pile of weird keywords, you know.
But you do have to pay attention to that.
There's a technical angle to SEO writing.
That's something I have learned through a lot of, experimentation over a number of companies, and investment in tools and agencies and all that kind of stuff.
So that's what, what are your key Tech stack tools that you go to, for SEO and even across the board across other channels, like what CRM?
You know, I mean, social tool, if you have anything like what's your go-to?
Well usually I mean You know, I like I said, sort of, I have been kind of building Marketo Salesforce tax for a while.
I mean, that's what's happened.
I like to have in the flexibility in terms of the programmability, from automation, but without getting into true programming there and I, there are a few, there are a few tools that when one of them got deprecated, that, I mean, II think you should invest in a tool.
I think now.
If I am not mistaken, there might be what for drift that is a routing tool routing is really important intelligent routing and response to email.
Because like, I mean, these are like the fine details of like you send out an email, someone responds to it, who does it get routed to write an owner and sgr?
Someone else.
Whatever.
If there's an auto response, where does that come from?
Right.
If you're sending from an alias, like you don't, you don't want all those things get messed up.
So like there's some nice routing tools.
I think that you that are really smart to invest in, you know.
I think there's gosh, you know, the thing too is like tools.
Keep on like getting Consolidated.
There was a tool that I really love that detected out of offices and, you know, noted other potential contacts, but I think that you two got bottles or something like that.
I think it called lead, no more Spike that, but I am not sure if they're independent anymore.
They're like the little oftentimes, like there's the big tools, and then there's a little, you know, sort of that nuanced things that you if that just prevents you from having to do a lots and lots of manual labor from SEO point of view.
I mean you can choose your semrush or other or sort of analytics tools.
I mean there's a number of those and in fact if you want Fidelity, get two of them.
You know and compare because they will have slightly different angles and you know and Gosh.
There's a really nice content optimization tool that I am blanking out on right now.
It's I am having a brain fade moment.
I know there's Jasper.
AI is something.
We have been looking into as far as content generation with AI.
Yeah, that's been interesting and then I am curious about like, like headlines to like is there a tool we use that co-head code, analyzer headline tool.
Do you guys use anything like that?
I mean, for topic subject lines, you know, at this stage not yet, I mean I like some of those tools I think the Part you know part of a lot of what I also get focused on.
It's just the technical enablement tools to check the biggest one of the biggest dangers is just like managing your Center reputation and like you know, your ability to get through today.
So you know, a combination of your MX toolbox and you know, some other things like that, that will analyze for like how will, you know, how will system see it?
You know, I think that's those are you know, kind of your sender reputation and your ability to actually get messages through deliverability and all that is one of the biggest obstacles that we have to overcome now as marketers, right?
So I think those, there's the class of tools that deal with that is something to just make sure that you have in your toolbox like don't neglect that, you know.
That's great.
Wow, there's so much like Rich information here and it looks like we have answered the questions in queue an Alex.
Is there any last word of encouragement or advice that you would give to the broader B2B marketing community?
I mean in a start-up scenario I think just remember that.
It's not uncommon that technical Founders for technical Founders in particular Market is the least understood discipline and always be an educator, you know keep hold onto your conviction, you know and you know you're going to have to devote a certain The energy to just be explaining and educating as to the why, why want to do things this way?
Why, why don't do things that way right?
You know things you know will work because that knowledge isn't necessarily something you can assume and most Founders want to learn but you just can't leave that Gap.
So I think but in an environment like and especially these days, you know, with all the turn, all the things happening, it could be easy to be discouraged, and two questions.
Some of your convictions especially this B2B as I said, you don't have massive amounts of data.
You, you're doing some things based on best practice and unobserved best practice and things like that, right, you know.
So just hold on to that and be encouraged like that.
That's has a lot of value and to lean into being, an educator and Communicator internally as much as externally is super important.
And then, you know, and I think that level of conviction and willingness To say like this is, this is the way to go and here's why and here's you know why we want to stick with this is its just super helpful, I think just for you know, kind of like almost like emotional health as a start-up and B2B marketer, right?
Like to not get so buffeted by all the, you know, things that demands and all that in the pressures.
But also just knowing that you have to You know, educate a lot so that you don't become misunderstood and what you're trying to deliver in the challenges of it.
Right?
Expectations and all that.
That's my big encouragement of one big, big lesson over time.
Is that?
Yeah, Market is just not well understood in B2B often times.
And so, part of our job is to be that, you know, educator internally.
And as we do it reinforces our convictions, right?
Helps us believe in what we're doing and like to follow that path.
We You know, obviously follow the data and all that kind of stuff too.
But I don't know.
That's that would be my encouragement is don't lean away from that like lean towards that and it's super helpful.
It's encouraging for yourself, right?
To believe in yourself in that way.
And it's helpful for others.
So you know, that would be my encouragement.
I would give love that.
Thank you so much.
Alex, it has been a pleasure To be able to spend this time with you and glean your wisdom and insights of your experience, thank you for sharing your Aloha with us today.
And with that, we will be sharing this recording with all of you who are here today.
Thank you to everybody who's here joining us, and feel free to LinkedIn.
Connect with either one of us and DMS.
If you have any questions, we'd love to stay in touch with you because we are here for one another.
We're all in this crazy B2B game together.
So, just a point of encouragement from Alex and I even to the rest of those here attending, you know, we're all here for each other, so, feel free to message us, and we'd love to connect.
And if you got any questions about what you're solving for and marketing, feel free to hit us up.
All right.
Thank you, Alex.
And in the meantime, Katie is gonna pull up another.
Yes thanks Katie.
So we're going to continue this interview series week over week next week.
We're going to be meeting with Madison who's the head of demand gen at Loom, and she's going to be talking about Revenue marketing across the entire customer lifecycle.
So, please join us for that.
It's going to be great.
And until then Aloha and have, it's actually a greeting.
Both goodbye and hello.
So aloha to all of you.
And I hope you can enjoy this.
These Tunes, it's John Crews.
It's called Island style and it's a classic Hawaiian song that Katie's going to flip on right now.
Have a wonderful rest of your day.
We do it anyway.
From the mountain to the ocean from Mountain, to the leeward.
Side.
Only are we do it again?