I am confused on some chiffon and stuff.
She fought off that come to use.
It will cause Only one is John Kohler Company may want for the police.
Can't do.
I find the real life and set them pain killer, you must think, also some emotion has a lesson, some wind flipping to be bleak.
F***** up.
Yes, I saw him connect song last 15 years.
Having my lunch before can walk.
It comes name gonna be Hi everyone.
Oh, it's so great to see folks trickling in right now.
For me, it's early morning, I am tuning in from Hawaii and so it's 8 AM and I know we got folks NYC your six hours ahead of me.
Jordan and we got Quan from Chile.
Hello, Kylie.
And we have got Janet.
Okay, we have got some fun folks.
Today, it's going to be great.
I am so excited to have our guest.
Addison.
She is the head of demand gen at Loom, and she's gonna walk us through some of just her thinking behind Revenue marketing.
I mean, I think all of us have questions and how she's defining Revenue marketing.
So, before we jump into that note that we have a Q&A tab, so at any given time, feel free to drop in your questions, upvote questions that you see that you really want answered and throughout our conversation.
Verse ations will pull those in and get those answered.
All right, so Madison jump up here and join me on stage.
Hello.
Hello how are you?
I am good.
It's a beautiful Wednesday here in New York, you got mid-60s, gorgeous fall weather, so I can't complain.
Oh, I love it.
So your six hours ahead.
I think what time is it for you to PM at night?
8:00 AM over?
Annoy.
Well, I am still drinking coffee even at this hour, so I don't matter.
Yeah, here's to that awesome.
Mmm.
All right.
Well, you know before we jump in, I don't know if you know Madison you noticed, but we had in our intro video a runner, he was a French Runner who is chasing that van really fun video there.
And your Runner is As well.
In fact, I heard you.
Do you have a half-marathon that you're running?
I do this Sunday will be my first half-marathon.
So I want to know, say I am a full Runner but I have gotten into running and it's been fun.
So half-marathon this weekend.
I am going on PTO soon.
So I have no complaints right now.
Excited for some first across off The Bucket List.
Nice.
And how long is a half-marathon 13.1 miles?
Wow, that's still Seems poof like quite a journey.
Yes, when I actually put it into perspective of like walking a mile versus running a mile and how many 13 is I regretted it.
But I had already signed up so couldn't turn back at that point.
Good for you, I look forward to hearing how that goes.
The other thing that I know about you is you're a movie buff and you know, trivia like no other.
So we actually have a fun poll that we're going to get on stage right?
Now all about movie trivia, okay?
So for any other movie Buffs that we have our there, feel free to drop your answer to this which nominated musical won the Oscar for Best Picture.
Go ahead and drop your votes.
I don't even know if I it I don't know if I know this one.
I mean, it's their all pretty up there Madison in the Jeopardy music.
Just really takes it to a whole nother level like the intensity is there, it's there.
All right, looks like votes are still coming in alright it's head-to-head with Wizard of Oz, in la-la land but majority votes are in West Side Story.
Oh, there we go.
Okay.
Madison, you are our trivia buff.
What is the answer?
It is as the majority voted West Side Story.
The 1961 version, not the most recent.
Who?
Yes, Jordan.
I see in the chat, you mentioned.
LOL.
And one for about 5 seconds.
And at the 2017 Oscars was announced as the winner.
Hold back.
And it was actually moonlight.
So that's honorable mention will give it as Jordan called out.
Nice.
Wow.
Okay.
Well that is some good stuff.
I know who to go to next time, you know if I am up there and money's on the line for a movie trivia Madison, I am giving you a call, I will be your phone a friend.
Thank you.
All right, well, we'd love to hear more about your journey and your story getting into demand generation.
Loom, can you walk me through you and I had a little dialogue?
Our to this and walk me through.
Like, when you just, you started your journey just getting into B2B marketing.
How do you re?
So I actually started in the fintech world as an account manager.
So really customer success focused and I started at Bloomberg and it was a great experience.
It was so amazing to be able to work at a big company that had clients all around the world, not only the us, and what I learned from that, Experience was I love to speaking with the customers was a B2B side of it.
So you know, how are people using your product?
What is it solving for?
How do you think of it?
Internally verse how your customers are using?
It can be so different or it can have unique use cases that you never had thought of.
So I really loved working with customers and I had the opportunity to travel across the u.s.
And meet with them in their offices.
So back in the day, when people were traveling like crazy, I was always on the plane, I am racking up.
As Delta SkyMiles to meet with people and just like, how are you using Bloomberg?
What problems are you facing?
Not only that Bloomberg is solving for but like that's top of mind.
Like what are you worried about?
What's, what are you thinking through?
And then trying to figure out how as a complete partner, not just a vendor or a software, can we work to solve those?
So that's kind of where I started was more on the account management side and then I realized fintech Financial Services was great, but maybe not.
But kept me up at night and Was riveting to me.
So I moved into the more Tech space and I have tried to keep more marketing roles since then and more like marketing B2B SAS still, as kind of like through and through.
But started in a very different world compared to where I am today, I would say, wow, okay, so roots are really with the customer in stripping them, as an account manager, and getting the ins and outs there.
So then from Bloomberg, where did you go next and face?
So from Bloomberg, I knew I wanted to get into a more marketing rule but also a little bit more, like the more Tech space I wanted to try out.
So I moved still to a SAS B2B company but called Bounce X, which then up branded to wunderkind and I moved into a sales role.
So kind of instead of the post sale what about the pre-sale motion?
And I worked in both like a bdr and account executive fashion.
So very top of the funnel.
How are you understanding the market landscape?
And you're proud of your solution and how do you, how do you solve for the problem at hand and actually trying to gain that interest from people and start at the top of the funnel from a sales perspective.
So did that for about a year when I got to try to break through the noise of like, hey, this is how Wonder can help your company.
Worked with some great e-commerce Brands learned so much about the pre-sale cycle and what that looks like from initial conversations up until signing a contract and formalizing a partnership.
But Realized once again I loved the customer and the prospect conversations but the selling aspect and that AE role wasn't necessarily what I found a lot of passion, so I made a pivot internally at one Dirk into their customer marketing team.
So really looking at customer advocacy and how do you do that through referral programs customer advisory boards events partner with our events, team case study is.
So how are you taking that customer voice and bring it to all the different channels which I just Fell in love with marketing from there?
So that's kind of the transition from Bloomberg to wunderkind and then from sales to my first quote, unquote, marketing title.
Wow.
And then from one organ.
Did you go to loo right after that?
Yeah, so from one Jerkins, one of my really good friends.
And also co-workers Kate, we work together at wunderkind.
She leads our Event Channel and it's just an absolute rock star.
And she was joining Loom, and she was like, hey, they are starting a strategic marketing.
And you would be a great fit.
You should apply and Kate and I have worked together and I adore her.
So I was like, sure.
I will take the call, we will see what it is.
And I fell in love with looms Mission.
I fell in love with the team from both the marketing and sales team at Loom, I was leadership was great.
That it was kind of great opportunity.
To not only further my career with a new industry and a new product, but also start strategic marketing from the ground up at a hyper growth startup, which I just Couldn't pass up the opportunity from every aspect, that's awesome.
And your collective experience working pretty much across the entire Prospect to customer Journey.
Gave you the experience and tools needed to really be successful.
So like coming in Tulum.
What were some of the key problems that you were solving for?
And, you know, then we can go into some of the revenue marketing questions that we have, and how you guys are solving for Revenue marketing.
But yeah, what were some of The initial problems.
And how did you go about tackling them?
Yeah, I think when I was looking at joining Loom and when this role was created, it was leading the Strategic marketing team was, which was going to be a net new function within Loom.
So it was also building it from the ground up and not necessarily a lot of problems, but a lot of opportunities that Loom was looking into finally like breaking into and growing out.
So, when you're looking at the Strategic marketing World from looms lens, we kind of break it up into new busy.
Account-based marketing.
So how do you do, like, one too few and one-to-one campaigns to generate Pipeline?
And then from the customer marketing perspective, how can you have close alignment with your customer success team for renewals upsells expansion opportunities?
How do you create that customer advocacy?
So it was a really big, like, Boulder project of what does strategic marketing look like at Loom and getting to work with marketing, folks and colleagues and also sales and customer success to understand.
What does the moon look like today?
From a customer's perspective in the Enterprise world and how do we want to up level that and take it to a Next Level compared to necessarily like these are the gaps we're like hey these are the opportunities they're endless.
Where do we want to start?
And what's most impactful to start?
Oh, that's so good and interesting.
So then I have a question just going into your initial like even targeting.
You know, you said that you guys focused more on like an ABM type of strategy versus a one Many strategies or let us ?
Do you do both?
Like, is it more so a spear fishing game versus a Netflix?
So I think it depends on the channel of marketing you're looking at.
So when I was joining, I joined in the Strategic marketing role I and now head up, our demand generation team, so it kind of oversees both you have your one too many tactics but you also have your one, too, few in your one-to-one and it kind of depends on what is your goal outcome.
Um, so Loom is a product LED Growth Company, which means anyone who's listening right now, can go on lulu.com, sign up for free, try out the product, learn to use it, and then we also have an Enterprise offering.
So, if your org is looking at bringing on loom as a partner for asynchronous work in collaboration, that's the kind of side that the demand gen team focuses on.
So we do one too many campaigns like content, launches and webinars and conferences to get the loom name and brand out there and educate people on the shift to a sink.
Is work, but we also do some really high level one too few and 121 channels like executive dinners or an account-based marketing like campaign from a gifting perspective, so we get I think demand generation and my current role.
I love it because it's a really good balance of both.
Just depending on like who the audience is at hand.
Mmm, that's good.
And you know, one of the things I think is constantly keeping that pulse on the data that you're getting, you know, Across.
What are some of the key metrics that you're constantly?
Just keeping top of mine.
And you know, how are you measuring that and having those conversations with sales and customer success?
Yeah, I think we're looking at like the who were targeting, there's a couple of things but like, keeping the customers, keeping the customer Centric, which of course, is the topic of this.
But like who, what is the end goal of like, their current knowledge?
So we're in a great spot where we have a free and a business product, and we still want to continue to get people just using loom and on the mission of transforming, the way people work.
So when you're looking at that group of people, you really want to make sure you're nurturing them from like a thought, leadership, activation and usage, adoption perspective.
But then, when you look at what you'd consider, like your ideal customer profile for the Enterprise skew, which is where our demand generation is really focused on driving that.
Ripa sales from our sales lad and our prize offering perspective, you're looking at who is the right fit for us?
Do are these topics like distributed work, hybrid work, top of mind for them and like making sure that your value prop is aligning with their business needs.
And that's kind of like what you're keeping a pulse.
I was like who's talking about async work, who's talking about looking on collaborating through different time zones and like that's the data you want to make sure you're staying on.
Above because it makes you a partner compared to just a line item, vendor or solution.
That's great.
There's actually a question that just popped in and I actually think it aligns very well to what her talking about here.
So I am going to pull it on stage, oops, sorry, Katie.
Katie is my producer.
They're all right.
So how do you prioritize your budget and resources between campaigns for your free product versus your Enterprise offering?
Great question.
Yeah and I will say if anyone has a full correct answer to this like let me know because this is how we're approaching it but there are so many different ways from Marketing perspective.
I am really fortunate to have great marketing Partners within looms marketing, departments such as like products marketing, growth marketing, our brand Team and then our comms team.
So, when you're looking across the different marketing channels, we all have different like key Focus areas while we're all leading up to the same goal.
So something like our product marketing team.
There's a few people on that team who are really focused on like creating products for a marketing products, like the free offering and our growth marketing.
Team is really focused on just sign up.
So across our free business, they're really focused on that, like, self-serve side.
When we're looking at like demand gen, so my team specifically, our number one, focus is going to be that Enterprise offering.
So majority of our budget and our time and our resources will go for our Enterprise offering with in helping our counterparts, that growth marketing who's focused on signups.
Because I always feel like you hear this flywheel of, like, you start.
Someone as a sign up.
They begin to use Loom.
They might switch companies.
Then they.
Common Enterprise client possibly, then you can in front of them.
So you're having that whole life cycle.
So our team focuses on our budgets and resources for the Enterprise offering and then different marketing functions and teams within Loom, like our product and growth team will focus more on like a sign ups for our freedom business.
So that's kind of how we break it up based off of teams and priorities.
Gotcha.
And, and okay, so here's another question because you mentioned a growth team and you guys are working on, demand, generation mainly, Jean Enterprises you mentioned, but I see sometimes growth getting intermixed with demand gen.
Yeah, how do you define, you know, even just from Madison's perspective, like, how are you defining the differentiation between demand generation and growth and how they work with the right teams to?
Yeah.
Comes so our head of growth marketing, Nick Lafferty is a phenomenal human being that.
I am so blessed to work with as well.
And when Looking at kind of like his world in my world.
Nick works with our product and growth team as well.
So they're focused on signups.
So how do we get more free and work signups and then my world is then when they're ready to graduate to our Enterprise offering, how do we engage those people?
So I couldn't necessarily do my job without their team focusing on signups and where you have that intersect is something like ads.
So if you're trying to run some ads on LinkedIn, that growth team would typically maybe take a lead on but there's a really specific Target list that we want to get in front of from an Enterprise offering how can Nick and I work together to launch at ad campaign both for a wider audience but also for a specific account list to get in front of them or when it's looking at launching new ads, and he really wants to integrate the customer voice.
How does he work with customer marketing?
Which is under my team to like, get those customer voices in those case studies to launch from an SEO or an ad perspective.
The way we Define it as they're really focus on those like free and business offerings.
And we're focused on graduating those to an Enterprise offering.
But there's so many cross-sectional areas in campaigns.
We both get to work on together which I think just makes the entire Loom message and voice.
One holistic company, compared to siloed, teams working for different goals.
That's good.
Wow.
Okay, so going back to holistic.
This is where I think the term Revenue.
Getting comes into play.
And how do you define revenue marketing?
They're seeing different things out there.
I have to, I have always seen different definitions and I think it's really interesting the way I have historically, like viewed.
It is like, how are you using marketing tactics or campaigns events or programs to drive pipeline opportunity for whether that's however your business is set up?
How are you driving like marketing campaigns and efforts to drive pipeline or realized Revenue as a company?
And I think that looks different depending on every company structure.
But from looms perspective, we're looking at the revenue from demand General Revenue marketing, like really close alignment with your marketing and sales team to generate that.
So, I think Revenue marketing to me has a closer alignment with sales, then some other types of marketing at different companies.
Gotcha and describe that relationship with sales.
I know this is also another big topic that often, but how is it for you?
What's your philosophy on that partnership?
And you know what does that interaction look like for you on a daily on a weekly monthly basis?
Yeah, I historically and even now say I think the thing I love about demand generation, strategic marketing is you get to work, so cross-functional across different companies.
I think I have always gravitated towards a customer marketing, strategic, marketing, or demand generation Rule.
And I think, when you're looking at the partnership between sales and marketing, the biggest thing for me is making sure that you have one unified goal across both teams.
So, like, how can you create a goal?
If it's pipeline, if it's close one Revenue, if it's signups that both teams are incentivized to work together or there's at least a flow of, if marketing hits their goals, it clearly translates.
Stu, how sales can then achieve their goals and I think that has been huge for me.
And at Loom, one of the reasons I came to loom, is the sales leaders and the sales team I was working with were just phenomenal, Advocates of marketing, and vice versa.
So I work with our sales team, they're probably some of my biggest stakeholders is making sure that we're helping them hit their closed, one Target.
And when we're launching campaigns from a one-to-many went too few one-to-one, we have their support, and we're Speaking, that's a message of we're going after the same targets, we're having a unified message.
My success is directly linked to your success and like, making sure that is like, in lockstep has been great.
But I think I talked to sometimes our sales and say yes to more than my actual like marketing counterparts at times.
Wow.
So that the frequency is quite often.
And is it like a daily interaction on check-in?
You know each other's metrics and holding each other accountable?
We do.
So at Loom we have like a revenue leadership.
So from the go-to-market side of our business, we do weekly check-ins from a sales leadership and Market leadership.
I try to also meet with the leaders one-on-one every week, every other week, just to make sure we're in alignment.
And then on top of that, I think, like, throughout the day, there's plenty of things or ideas or hey, can you jump in this team meeting to explain this new campaign that's going live.
Our hey, we're thinking about investing into this conference or this ABM campaign.
Do you have some time to chat?
Through it.
So we're all in the same shared slack channel.
So we see what each other are posting.
We have sync time, check-ins, and then selfish plug is like, I use Luma lot to be like, hey this, these are my thoughts of the team's planner.
Hey, this is a campaign, I am going to run.
Can I get your eyes on and I send it over, and they send thoughts back?
So I would be shocked if there's a day I go without talking to anyone from sales, but we do have formal check-ins as much as just informal check-ins as well.
That's great.
And I love how you all are using your product asynchronously we use Loom.
Similarly, so we're making it.
Yeah, it just helps when you, I think the thing with sales and marketing is you're just running a million miles a minute like very other teams and departments and personas as well, but, you know if someone's on a live call and that's the only time I am between a call, it's just hard to always, like, a line schedules with, like, calendar Tetris so looms.
When a great way to be like, hey, here's a campaign idea.
Let me, We have a second or like the salesman cake, here are some feedback of what's worked in our sales process.
Like feel free to take a look when you have some time, and then we can mold that into each other's work as well.
That's great.
So, as far as the key stakeholders across the company that you're in touch with regularly, are you in touch with the head of sales, the head of growth marketing, the head of customer success.
Like are those the key folks that you're working with Anna?
Yeah.
Even a weekly basis.
I would break it up kind of into like the Different departments.
So from the marketing perspective, Laura hard our VP of marketing very closely with her and the other marketing leaders which span across a growth marketing, our brand, our products, marketing, and our columns because we want to make sure that the message we're saying is Unified across all of our marketing channels.
So meeting with them frequently weekly as well, and then from a sales perspective, looking at our head of customer success, our head of sales, but also the managers for our AES, the managers for our Those Dev teams as well.
And then, I think another benefit that I get to work closely with is our products team.
So when you're looking at something like your site and web forms, how can you experiment with our product?
How do we build Enterprise features and offering?
So then you also have the product team that I work closely with.
And then very fortunate that we have great exec team here at Loom.
So getting to work with them.
I like what's resonating with people different areas we want to test into marketing how they view.
Our Relations.
And then also using them to get it from the customer.
So how can we create more executive relationships and like, full Partnerships from a thought, leadership, a Solutions, a networking opportunities as well?
So looking at like a full partnership with people and bringing our execs into that as well, so good.
Okay, cool.
That's really helpful.
If anyone has questions, feel free to drop them in QA Madison, I would love to move into the conversation that you and I had Before this time when we were talking about just the inundation of crowded in boxes and how, you know, we're in a funky time right now, with the recession with tech layoffs, taking place, you know, you see a lot of folks, missing forecasts especially this quarter, yet Revenue numbers are still higher than last year.
So it's kind of like this like a really funky time and so you know from a B2B marketing standpoint Fires and Prospects are inundated with emails, in particular, seems to be like that's like one of the go twos.
But I mean, I hundreds of emails a day and it's like, ah, you know, noise there.
You're now LinkedIn, massive Channel.
Like there're other channels, Facebook Tip, Top stuff.
You know what's working for you?
What, what, what's like some tea?
I don't know if you figured out your Bullet to get in front of, get through the noise, what's working?
What's not working?
You know, I think that's, I mean, I definitely feel it from both sides from like the consumer of getting lots of emails, then from the marketer trying to break through the noise.
And I think the thing we try to keep in mind, is every person consumes information differently, and I think you go back like elementary school and then you get learn to you get taught to learn different ways like Hands-On verse reading.
Denver's video.
And I think what we try to keep in mind is like, how can we continue to diversify our channels or hit multiple channels?
So you know, some people might still prefer email, but then we have to do that channel incredibly well because it is so crowded.
And then there might be another person whose like, hey you know what, something that's kind of hard to do.
Because we're distributed now, but like Direct Mail.
I am a huge fan of gifting and direct mail.
I think you break through the noise that way.
And I know personally, like, I check our Box every day I do, I am not expecting anything, but I love a letter, I love a package.
Like I will always look that way.
So how do you take what's under your marketing or sales per view?
And like, make sure you're hitting people through different channels at a respectable Cadence.
So how can you partner in email touch point?
And then maybe three to five days later.
Try a LinkedIn touch point and then see who's engaging from there.
Okay, both of those were myths.
Okay, let us try to introduce a direct mail piece or hey, email the Age, but they didn't click through?
How can we take email a step further?
You know, maybe we add a layer of personalization with like a specific landing page or an image, like really just evaluating everything on an ongoing basis.
So, you're partnering LinkedIn with in-person events with direct mail with gifting and then still doing email.
So I think for us it's just like how many channels can we use and continue to like keep a pulse on the learning.
So that if something is working, we can catch it.
If something's not working, we can pivot.
I think that's the name of the game is, like pivoting quickly, while still realizing like some things will work.
Let us test them.
Some things will test, and they won't work, and that's okay.
You learned.
Mmm, that's good.
And you mentioned the pulse not going back to your customer experience passion.
You know, you got to be tight with your customer.
You gotta know.
So how do you all do that?
Like, how do you keep that pulse?
Because it could get very, you know, how it is.
There's so many channels so many things to manage in marketing.
How do you keep your pulse?
Really close with your customer?
Yeah, I think that's whereas much as you can.
You create a holistic relationship with a customer compared to a transactional relationship.
Now, not everyone wants that at Time Square.
Like, hey, I need a solution and that's fine in.
Those can still be your strongest Advocates but are there ways?
As you can row, a relationship with the customer.
Are they hiring for their team?
Can you share that job posting with someone?
You might think it's good fit, your personal Network are they having issues with like figuring out how to onboard in a remote World?
Okay, can we share how we do that at Loom and how we have approached it is they looking to you know maybe they want to get into content more, do we have a case study, we could feature them in or do we have a blog post?
We could have them post and I think we have a phenomenal customer success team.
Here that is able to build those personal relationships and then when you take it, that next level is like, okay, how do we up level that to be a more thoughtful, istic partner than just that transactional like, hey here's our service.
You use our service, I will talk to you at renewals, which RCS?
Tune does not do their phenomenal but sometimes you have to go that white glove service, a little bit above and beyond compared to other times, which takes more work, takes a little bit more creativity, but your point in turn.
Having your pulse on your customers and getting to use their voices tenfold every single time.
Mmm.
Okay.
That's interesting.
So, do you find yourself, aligning prioritizing, even a lot of strategy towards that custom Mark marketing angle.
Like, like when you have the prioritize across that Journey, where do you see is like really strategically important to focus on?
I think it depends on your company goals, as well.
Like We're how mature are you from a sales outside of the business, and I am.
Sorry.
There are some construction going on, if anyone can hear that but well at my previous role at wunderkind where I was specifically full-time in customer marketing.
That was we were more mature company in terms of like our customer base.
We had so many Brands we had to show them love to.
So our primary focus was we had one clear buyer.
So how do we work with that fire to be like they're complete partner?
Through all things that they might worry about when you're looking at Loom, and we're still growing, our sales inside the business and our Enterprise offering you have to balance it with.
How do you get new customers versus how do you continue to love and nurture your existing customers?
But we will throw is like the same love.
You'd give to your existing customers.
You have to apply to your prospects because they could be that customer.
And the moment you start interacting with them from that first touch point with loom, that's going to set the stage for the Our customer lifecycle.
So how do you make sure from that first patch Point?
You're still giving them that white glove service or that flower that solution, that then will nurture them and continue to grow, through the sales cycle, through closing through becoming a customer and then the lifetime of renewals and expansions and partnership opportunities.
That's key it.
And would you say like that's something I know you're passionate about is being able to align that thread line experience across Ross, all those touch points.
I mean, how challenging is that, though?
You know what I am saying?
Like, why?
I mean, you're looking at bandwidth to like in a world that's distributed at you can't get in person anymore.
You can always travel.
So I think it's like an ongoing question of, like, what is the right way to do it?
What's the most effective way to do it?
I think from My Lens it's just like being very thoughtful in your brand and how you want that to come across?
And that's where we work really closely with like Brand Team, visually our content team from the content we're putting out.
And like, how do you from the beginning?
Make sure that like, your brand voice is consistent through a webinar or piece of content or a one-pager follow-up, and that you become more of just, instead of just like a name, you're like, oh Loom.
I understand like they're, they have that logo.
They have like this, you at work messaging.
They have those reduced meetings, the meetings canceled candle, like how do you become more of a moment?
No movement, then just Unnecessary, like, oh, I think I heard of loom weights, and that, then we will have that credibility, that will bring you throughout the entire life cycle, whether it's high level or 121 touch points.
That's great.
I am going to ask a more tactical question when it comes to Journey mapping and you know, just beginning to ideate shape and strategically identify the areas that you want to focus on.
Is there like a team?
Like do you guys work as a team to build out journey maps of your existing prospects?
And is that how you get alignment?
So that everybody is pretty streamlined or what's an Activity or thing that you guys do to be able to map that out.
I think when it comes to our Enterprise offering and working closely with our sales teams like our sales Dev leader and r8u leaders and just the head of sales as we do talk to you through.
Like okay, who are we targeting?
What's that account?
What does that Persona?
What is that customer profile, that's a right fit and then what is the message?
Messaging that lands with them and then who's going to own that?
So what is that formal process of like, hey marketing will own these efforts.
This is where we will need support from the sales Dev team sales devil on these efforts.
Okay, we have alignment there now, what's the handoff process look?
Like, how involved is marketing from an open Ops perspective?
What's that Cadence?
Like, it's really mapping out.
How do we need this journey to look, internally from what we think and then who's going to own what?
And how does that all speak together?
And then when you're looking from a Smurf success perspective.
It's kind of similar.
It's okay.
What are the biggest?
What are the biggest issues?
Our customers are facing.
Do we not have, you know, executive relationships that are strong enough?
Do we have questions regarding use, cases and adoption?
Okay.
So what does that Journey look like with our head of onboarding Brittany and then our head of Cs like, what does that Journey look like from signing a contract to Renewal?
And what points do we need?
Touch points?
And that, how did marketing support that how will onboarding on that?
How will see s on that?
So it's really just like when you're looking at the life cycle, understanding who's going to own what and with what channels and then keeping those touch points on.
So be like, hey guys, this is where we're at with this.
Where are you at with that and keeping those lines of communication open?
That's really good.
Thank you for breaking that down.
I think that's helpful to hear.
I often think time like everyone does it a little bit differently, you know, hearing how you all aligned to it.
Far as creating objectives and like accountability.
That way, is it also done in a similar fashion where you're aligning with each team head and determining where the priorities are for the business need and then coming up with objectives together.
Yeah, I would say it's a little bit of both.
So it's looking if you're looking at the revenue side of it.
So the go-to-market side, it's like, you know what?
Our goals for closed, one Revenue This quarter and, you know, how do we want to Pace towards a company?
Okay, so this is how much we need to close.
How much pipeline do you need to generate?
Because an ideal world, every deal you open closes to pipeline, but we obviously know things.
Come up.
Timing isn't perfect.
So you know what is our goal for closed?
One Revenue as a company, then how do we need pipeline generated and what does that pipeline ownership look like?
So, you know, looking at your typical like pipeline generating functions like a sales development team or a marketing team.
And this case Duration breaking those out into ownerships.
So then what we do is when we have our pipeline Target or our opportunity Target, you know, I bring that back to my team, and we say, OK, this is our goals.
How do we think we can hit this?
What campaigned, what events, what content can we create?
Launch and run that will help us get to those goals and then you bring that back to your cross-functional partners and say this is our cue for plan.
This is the calendar we're proposing.
Does this work in alignment with your guys's goals as well?
You know, can we get the brand support?
We For this the product marketing support the cam support.
And, you know if sales comes back with a very different calendar, okay, now, we know ahead of time, we have to both reset and like, figure out what that makes up was, but really just coming together.
Collectively then going to the experts in each area and saying, how do we hit this?
Then coming back together and be like, is everyone aligned on this calendar, to start great.
Let us run with it.
And then you those weekly check-ins really helped be like, hey, we're under pacing.
We're over pacing.
We need to Pivot But as much as is much pre understanding of like, this is what our goal is as an entire sales on motion.
Here's a the demand gen team thinks we can do in terms of achieving it.
And how does that align with it?
You guys are thinking or are there any red flags that either team needs to call out or get support on for this to work?
So that's a whole like pre-planning process and Alignment before you go into execution.
Exactly.
Because I think the worst thing you can do is silo that off to, okay, I have this pipeline goal.
I think this is what we will hit it, and I am just going to run in my race and do what I am doing without other input because, you know, you could be missing something huge, the alignment could be a little bit off, or if you don't have that cross functional support or understanding.
Like, you could be running all of these efforts which are great but then the follow-up falls through.
So I really make sure before Or anything is executed, you guys that you have buy-in and you have an understanding of the impact in why I think translates into a program success in smooth execution before you're even like Off to the Races.
That's good.
Wow.
Okay.
Rich.
Insights that.
If it is anybody has any questions feel free to drop them otherwise we can move into you know, we here.
We're trying to create an environment where we can encourage one another as well, because B2B marketing is tough right now, you know, I mean, you called out like the market trends the cluttered in boxes, like now more than ever to you have so many other obstacles and new barriers of prejudice, but we used to have.
So, I mean, it's yeah, it's a tough world.
It is.
So with that Madison, do you have any words of encouragement?
It or advice to us.
It could be a tactical point of encouragement or general.
Feel free to share that.
Yeah, I think my professor and one of my mentors once said, it's when you're looking at like an obstacle or climbing a mountain, you know, you take it one step at a time and you can't do it alone.
And I have been incredibly fortunate to have so many great mentors and even just co-workers and friends who have I am willing to share insights and advice and thoughts exactly.
Like we're doing right now.
But like thing, my biggest piece of advice is just give that back if someone asks a question, if someone raises their hand, if someone wants to network, take that coffee chat.
Promote thought leadership, as much as like, each company has their own goal will make it a better community and will become smarter more efficient marketers if we're all willing to like work together.
So I think for myself it's like you take it step by step, so you Each challenge by each Challenge and take it for face value.
Do the best.
You can learn how to Pivot quickly but also be grateful for what you have learned in those moments.
And then you can't do it alone.
So, you know, reach out a helping hand because there will be a time when you will need help too.
So, just continue to give back and network and be willing to promote thought leadership, whether you think it's thought leadership or not, I guarantee you someone will find it useful or helpful.
So I am always wanted to be like a try to give it back as much as you can, because it means that much, and then they do it tenfold as well hoof.
Powerful, those are powerful words.
Madison, thank you so much for taking the time to share your wisdom.
I know I am going to re-watch this recording and definitely take some notes and share them with Wendy for having me to it was a great way to spend my Wednesday afternoon, you are Wednesday morning.
Well it's a pleasure.
In fact what I love to do, I know this is a little impromptu, let us open up breakouts because we have an intimate enough group here.
Anybody wants to join a man.
If you have some time, we'd love to have you in there, as folks may have some questions they want to ask you directly and maybe just meet you.
So if we can open up breakouts or our lounge, and then we can click on the tab above and feel free to jump in just to say hello.
Other than that Madison, we're going to be connecting with you on LinkedIn and like what?
I like what I like to say is rdms are open.
So like why thoughts questions.
Russians.
We're going to be pinging you and vice versa.
Anybody has thoughts questions.
My DMs are open to.
So thanks Madison.
All the message for you.
Yeah, okay, great.
Well that wraps up our time here if you can join us in Lounge please do so say hello.
Otherwise, our next interview will be same time, same place with Mattea who is leading Partnerships at Form, and so she's going to talk about the key Magical elements that make remote Partnerships successful.
Alright?
Everyone have a wonderful rest of your day, your evening, whatever, time zone, you're tuning in from join us in lounge.
If you can catch you next week, Choose the book.