Hello everyone, I am Gina, and I am so stoked to be here with you all tuning in from Ewa Beach.
White, which is on Oahu about 30 minutes from Honolulu.
If you all know and are familiar today, we have a really special guest.
Her name is Mateo, and she is the partner manager at tight form.
So we're going to dive into her story.
But before we go into that, let you see.
Is tuning in.
We have got Laura from Texas, Janet Mendocino.
Hello.
Ivan from Jersey City.
So glad that you're here, feel free to drop.
What city you're tuning in from and chat?
There's also a Q&A tab, so as you're going through and listening to Mathias story, and if you got questions for her, feel free to drop them in the Q&A, and we will be sure to pull those on stage as we're getting to know, Mattea.
So with that, I would love to introduce Matea to the stage for free to join me up here.
Hello.
Hey Tina, how are you?
I am doing great.
Thanks for having me.
Good, good.
And you're tuning in from where today?
I am from Seattle awesome.
And what's the weather like It's sunny, but deceivingly cold, and it's about 40 degrees, so Seattle will get you that way.
Yeah, absolutely.
But we will take it over the rain.
Okay, nice.
Nice, great.
Well, before we kick off into this really great breakdown of your story that we have got here outlined.
We wanted to play a quick little game to get to know you a little bit.
It's called two truths and a lie.
And basically, there are going to be three facts.
So let us go ahead and get that on stage.
It's a quick poll, okay?
So of these two of them are the truth and one will be a lie.
So Mattea could you break down these troops and what of one of these?
It's a lie and folks, feel free to vote wherever you think the LIE is.
So what are these fun facts about?
My brothers, are the fifth generation of twins in my family.
I was a D1 athlete and my favorite food is hamburgers.
All right, go ahead and drop your votes.
Like D1 athlete?
Hmm.
And twit fifth generation of twins.
That's like, I don't know.
Hamburgers.
I love hamburgers.
Hmm.
All right.
Okay, so votes are in All right, Mattea, reveal of these?
Which one is the LIE?
My favorite food is not hamburgers.
I have been a vegetarian my entire life, so definitely out of the question.
But someone put in the chat and no cheese, I love cheese, so I am not vegan, but yeah, I was a D1 athlete.
I played tennis University of Dayton and my brothers are the fifth generation of twins in my family.
It actually didn't skip a generation either, so pretty crazy.
Wow, that is crazy.
And how long do you were a D1 athlete?
We're at again.
University of Dayton in Ohio.
Wow.
Very cool.
Tennis head-to-head.
I don't think got, I think, you'd totally slam me in that and I would not want to make very cool.
Well Mattea, tell us a little bit about your journey getting into partner management.
And, you know, I would love to hear a little bit of your story getting into Tech as well.
Well.
Yeah, definitely.
So I majored in entrepreneurship and Supply Chain management when I was at Dayton and then I went directly into a sales role.
After college, my dad has been in sales pretty much his entire career.
So, followed in his footsteps and I worked at AWS started in their sales internship program and then into a full-time role.
So, had a couple years there where I was helping on the inbound sales team and then on the outbound sales team and then I transitioned into an account manager role, Amazon's on the other side, not on the cloud services anymore, where I was working with our vendors in Latin America for Amazon Explorer, which is a virtual travel experience, and it happened to launch kind of right around covid, even though it wasn't really a covid play.
Say, and so I was in that role for a bit working with folks in Latin America that were providing those travel experiences which is wow.
Okay, so describe that a little bit.
Because we're yeah, we're in the events world as well.
So you all were providing virtual experiences like what kind of experiences Yeah, so, in Buried.
So you can have a shopping experience if you wanted to go to local shops in Argentina, and they would send you a pair of earrings.
You could have that or you could have one of my vendors in.
My favorite experience was visiting a rescue ranch in Costa Rica where you got to see like toucans loss of all these animals up close.
So I was yeah, it was pretty cool.
Well, unfortunately, they're they have shut down.
I think a couple weeks ago but yeah, the time being it was yeah various thought.
They tried something out.
Yeah.
And you said yeah, an experience to we did after.
So after you mention that Katie and I were just like, so curious about this, we went on AWS, we're like whoa, they actually do offer these virtual experiences there was like a tour in Israel and a Sorry and all these things.
So we signed up for one just to try it out and it was an amazing, just whole rundown with this with the Safari.
Dude, that walked us through different animals that he brought up to the camera.
There were like these exotic animals, it was really fun.
So very cool experiment by AWS and you know, unfortunate that it had to get shut down.
But so you were reading that and were you managing and identifying and getting all of the different vendors and partners that would be part of this program.
Yeah, so it was an interesting time because it happened all around covid.
A lot of travel companies were starting to go out of business or looking for ways to make up that Revenue that they weren't getting within person travel.
And so it was a very, I would say easy way for us to get involved with them in the beginning, because they wanted to diversify how they were making revenue and oh, well, we can off, we can solve our tour guides, you can pay them, they can offer these experiences like they would Good in person and have them on Amazon.
So, Gotcha.
Wow.
So interesting was that hard to identify them or like, how would you go about demon find?
Yeah, somebody that gives you a tour and Israel, or how do you find?
Yeah.
Most of them were major tour companies and then a lot of them have individual hosts, that do the experience.
And so we started with a bigger ones, and then scaled down to smaller tour companies as well.
Because some were just not built for the virtual experience environment.
Like getting them, they had to get a phone, download our app and go through training with our team and everything and it was somewhere just not built for that.
So It was a Rancher.
All right.
Okay.
So then fast-forward you're working with AWS managing these incredible epic experiences and then.
And then what Yeah, and then I joined type Forum, which is where I am now as a partner manager.
And I kind of wanted to switch out of a sales role and go more into business development Partnerships because I think that's kind of the way of the future of selling.
And luckily I have had a really good team of mentors to coach me through the process of Partnerships and kind of get me up to speed because I was coming from a sales back.
Round, but a lot of (Mike) my skills were really transferable, I think.
How long have you been with typeform?
In this.
Just over a year now.
Yeah, yes.
Okay, so break it down a little bit because Partnerships, you know, there're Partnerships and marketing, there're Partnerships and product.
There's so many different types of Partnerships.
How do you define it with the role that you're in at tight form?
Yeah, that's a good question.
I think Partnerships could sit under sales.
They can send or Business Development.
They can sit under product depending on the type of partnership.
We're under business development, but we work with all of those cross-functional teams.
So we have, I would say two major types of Partnerships out type form.
We have our Tech integration Partners.
So, for example, HubSpot you can build a type form and then push your responses in top spot.
Or we have our referral Partners.
So marketing agencies that we work with that refer typeform to their clients.
Those are our two main partner types.
We have you know affiliate style like a few others.
But those are our main focus.
Gotcha.
Okay.
And then, where is your main focus?
It's a great, it's a great question.
I would say, mainly on our marketing agency referral Partners, it's who I work most closely with gotcha.
Okay, so can you walk us through what, what's a day in the life?
Like are you identifying agencies talking to them?
And then ultimately what does a win-win look like?
Yeah, definitely, so most of our partners right now come in organically, they love type warm, and they want to be a partner.
So they apply on our landing page, we get them review the application, put them into our partner relationship management tool which is partner stack, and then we will work with them and have like an onboarding call work.
With them to get up to speed and different enablement material certified.
And then from there, that's when they're referring clients.
It's to type form, and then we're sharing leads to them because they will go up on our directory.
And so for example, if someone needs help with their typeform, they can go on our directory and find a certified partner to work with and get that started on their own.
Gotcha.
So, when, when you're trying to get a win-win going, what does, what does that look like for you?
And also for the partner?
Yeah, definitely I think the most important thing about Partnerships and if you don't take anything else away from this entire conversation is that it has to be mutually beneficial and it has to be a win-win for both us and for the partner, otherwise, it's not going to be successful.
And so, you know, kind of what we look for in a good partner is having a shared ideal customer profile or ICP.
If we don't have that it's not going to be successful and then also an overlap in our Text, a core ecosystem is also really helpful.
So if we have an agency, that is also certified in HubSpot, for example, and type form, then were continually growing that customer base, and it's kind of win-win for all types of Partners and that's the ideal situation.
Gotcha.
Okay, that, that's interesting.
And at a given time, are you meeting to manage like X number of relationships, you know, and how do you do that well, especially remotely and, or do you go in person and meet with some of these Partners sometimes?
Or, I mean, how, how do you all keep the relationship?
Good.
Yeah, I think it's a tricky question and something that everyone's figuring out in the remote environment.
I have actually been I think over 90% of my time.
Working has been remote and building relationships.
Pretty much through a little square on the screen.
So I think the biggest thing for us is Obviously developing a personal relationship and figuring out little things that you can take away from a call with someone really listening.
You know maybe it's something personal to not related to the deal or what you're working on but you can pull that into the next conversation and just show that you're a human being and you care about them.
But also automating our program where possible and so obviously, for getting a lot of inbound interest into our program, we still want our partners to feel You know, like they have this personal connection, but we can use tools like type form where it feels like a more genuine connection and video, ask is our other tool and so, it's a synchronous video.
And we have right now.
We have a welcome video to all of our partners and it's basically me on the screen, so they don't just get an email.
Hey, what's up?
They get me on the screen and it's talking them through the program, what to expect and it's just definitely a more personal way to do it.
And so, if you can find But always to do that for Automation and it helps you scale the program because obviously, we can't have a one-to-one relationship with every single partner that we have.
There're certain ones that will get that, and then certain ones, that it will be more automated that makes sense.
Wow, that's interesting.
So you have got this process dialed in, and we touched that a little bit about your process in starting the Bishop all the way through to nurturing it and then continuing to maintain the win-wins and the checkpoints along the way to know.
Okay, this is a good partner to keep, or this is probably a partner that we should probably part ways with.
So, could you just walk through that process?
Like, you know, once the request comes through, then you started to touch like the video intro do, does everybody get that?
Like, just walk us through that, that experience.
Yeah, so first is figuring out.
Is this going to be a beneficial relationship for both parties because you can have a pretty simple process there?
If it's not just walk away, no hard feelings.
But if it is then we would kind of go through.
They would join our program, they get the video, Welcome, everyone does get that.
And then we have time set with me and my colleagues so that they can put a face to the name of who's messaging them when I have questions.
And stuff like that.
But I would say as far as the process goes for ass off identifying if it's a win-win second is building off of our current ecosystem, kind of smarter not harder approach.
So you know, we have our Tech partners, and we want to make sure that we're utilizing them and creating a better relationship and that's how we get a lot of our agencies and then Third.
It would be building the personal relationship where we can identify which partner is really fit under our ideal partner profile.
Because there are some that we get that apply that might not be exactly what we think is going to be the best, but they will still get in our program, they will get all the resources and information that they need.
And then the ones that we think will be really successful will develop that personal relationship with kind of that give to get mentality.
And then really creating an open line of communication, so making sure that they get product updates, and they are in the know of what's going on.
And they feel like they're really an extension of our team, pretty much as how we want them to feel.
And then I would say the last piece of that is continuously asking for feedback.
So we can improve the program and implementing changes where Hospital.
Gotcha, thank you so much for breaking that down, A-Z, that could be your white paper.
You just turn on Partner management.
This from Matea Matias, key Magical elements that make partnership successful remotely.
Yeah, so that's interesting.
Now, as far as the agencies that come through, are they already customers a type form or are they folks are just interested in Snoring?
It's a mixed bag.
I would say, probably 60% of them actually, probably 80% of them, at least have a free plan with us.
So they were familiar with type form.
And that's how they found us.
They love the product, and they really want to be a partner, which is awesome for us.
And it's a really easy way to start that relationship when you don't have to explain you know the solution that your product solves But then the ones that don't, they're usually from us reaching out, so they might have hurt.
Usually they have heard of type form, but they might not use the tool yet.
Gotcha.
Okay.
So do you guys take both?
Like almost like an AVM approach in identifying, certain accounts that you want to partner with along with, you have got sort of that product lead, growth motion of folks, just coming.
To you asking to be partners.
So is it a mix of both?
Yeah, I would say for a long time, it's just been in Bound which has been a great way to grow the program.
Just because we have that organic interest, and we have a pretty small and mighty team over here.
So it's nice to have, you know, that organic growth coming in.
But now we're starting to be a little bit more strategic on the types of partners that we want to add as well as what's organically coming in.
And for typeform, like what would that?
What's your ideal partner?
Yeah, so for our referral partner, it's pretty much a digital marketing agency or digital experience agency and a lot of times they already use our ecosystem Partners.
So HubSpot slack MailChimp, they are very well versed in that Tech stack.
And yeah, I would say mostly that inbound marketing.
They do branding design.
Web design.
That's pretty much our ideal partner profile.
And they're mostly agencies.
They're not necessarily.
Yeah, they're always okay, gotcha, very interesting.
Wow.
Okay so quick question here on like key outcomes of success so when you're looking your in a journey with the partner and you're like oh this is like exactly what we want to see happen.
What does that look like for you all?
Yeah, I think the key the major key outcome is sustainable growth for us and for them like if they're growing their client base because now they offer type form or refer type form to their clients and their certified in it, and they know how to use it, and they know the ins and outs, and they can be a champion for us and that grows their client base while also growing our client base, because we're getting more lie.
Needs more clients that are interested in type form because they work with that agency.
And also they are getting more leads from us to by being honored being on our directory being a certified partner.
I think it's comes back to the win-win, and we look for just that sustainable growth instead of just oh, they referred one big client, which is great.
But we want to see like, repeatable, motions, and beautiful clients.
That's good.
And you mentioned earlier an ecosystem.
Partners.
And you were saying, like, MailChimp and HubSpot.
All these others is that a different type of partnership, relationship versus the agency relationships that you have like, went what is it?
How do you define your ecosystem partners?
Yeah, I think ecosystem is kind of buzz word thrown around in insides for now.
But basically, our ecosystem, I think it includes are all of our partner type.
So if you think of it like a circle type forms in the middle, for our Circle, not for everyone else's.
But we have, you know, HubSpot MailChimp on there, and then we have our marketing agencies on there.
We have our Affiliates on there, so that's that kind of encompasses the entire ecosystem.
And then when I think of our Tech stack or figure Partners like that, HubSpot MailChimp, etc.
Those are our integration Partners.
So the partnership is much different because they're not exact, it's more about because we integrate with HubSpot.
A lot of their clients want to use type form or vice versa because they're using type form, and they see, oh, I can actually add this into my CRM.
That's awesome.
And so it kind of goes both ways like that.
Instead of a direct referral model, it's more of like an influence model that makes sense.
Gotcha.
Yeah, that makes sense.
Wow, that's interesting.
So your team needs to strategically be aligned on all the different types of partners that you all are managing.
What is that even look like for your team's alignment?
You know you got different folks that are managing different types of Partnerships.
Do you guys all aligned on goals together and meet on a weekly stand up?
Like how does that work remotely?
Yeah definitely.
I would say We're really lucky because we're all on the same team even though we manage different types of Partnerships.
So we work really closely together and there's, we're a pretty lean team.
So we're in touch at least obviously once a week when we go over when or what everyone's working on and what people should know about.
But we're also trying to go forward work a lot more closely together because for example, if we have a new product features, Launch with one of those Tech Partners.
How do we get an agency involved as maybe as a spotlight story, for example?
And so there's a lot more that can be done with using the different partner types and making a bigger Splash per se on that.
Very nice.
Alright, if anybody has questions for Mattea, feel free to drop them in Q&A.
Otherwise, you know, I think for those that are interested in getting into partnership like how where do you start I think that you can come from a lot of different backgrounds because the skill set is transferable.
Obviously sales is a pretty natural fit, but say if you worked in product before you'd be a great fit for our product level Partnerships because a lot more of that is more technical base or if you're like a customer success manager, for example, you could switch into Partnerships because you're working with a customer To deliver on an outcome together.
And that's really similar to partnership.
So I don't think it's, I think it's similar, but different.
And if you can apply your skills, I mean, we're all of us are learning every day.
And, so I have been lucky to learn from my co-workers a lot that have had more experience in Partnerships.
But if you can just bring your transferable skills and interpersonal skills, I think a lot of different people could go into Partnerships.
That's great.
Yeah, so basically like if you're if you have got a background in, go to market or even in product management, it could be a really good get path.
If you're interested in getting into Partnerships, all right, we have a question that is popped on what was your best partnership and why?
That's a good question.
I would say.
I don't want to say exactly who are what it is, because I don't want other ones of our partners to be sad or offended.
But I would say, the reason why it's great, and one of our best is because there's an open line of communication and the relationship, I mean Partnerships take time and so developing that if you have an open line of communication and you're sharing, when's, you're sharing things that are working things that aren't working.
Being and you're constantly changing and developing off of that.
There's a lot of partners that aren't as open with the communication.
I think that's the biggest thing.
Hmm.
Gotcha.
Yeah.
Maintaining.
That Communications both ways.
It's not just yeah, on your side.
It's also on their side as well.
Yeah, it looks like we have another question from Brielle.
What are the main types of Partnerships?
If you had to categorize at a high level, and do you take a different strategy for each inbound versus outbound?
That's a good question.
I think the main types of Partnerships depend on the company and where you're at and your stage of growth.
But overall, I would say Tech partners are or product Partnerships or integration Partners.
That's all pretty much synonymous for the same thing and then referral Partnerships and affiliate Partnerships or kind of the main three and four.
Taking a different strategy for each.
I would say that again, depends on where you are in your stage of growth.
So for us in the beginning of starting our program, we realize that a lot of our customers using type form where agencies and so that was a perfect way to get started and bringing them in as partners.
Whereas now that we have grown a lot more we can identify what is our, you know, best partner type look like and how do we get more of those and it becomes more of an outbound?
Sound strategy but in the beginning, it was more inbound.
So I think it depends on where you're at in the journey and it's hard to know what your ideal partner type is until you get started.
You can say, you know, do research and say, I think it's going to be this type of company and get really specific and then you start working with those types of companies.
You don't you realize it's not ideal.
So then you have to Pivot and go to a different partner time.
So I think casting a wide net.
When you're first starting out is probably the best way to do it and then over time realizing what is the best partner type and focusing in on that?
And going more of an outbound strategy.
That's great.
All right.
Angela's got a question.
How do you manage Outreach to new potential partners and then how do you prioritize who to approach?
Yeah.
So I think that being methodical with your Outreach is the most important, instead of, you know, kind of doing a mass blast on LinkedIn.
Like, I think we have all received those messages and you realize it wasn't just meant for you.
So I think focusing in, on obviously understanding who their target audiences and making sure that's the same as yours.
Because then, you can say, I really do think this is going to be a positive.
Relationship.
And we're going to grow, because we have the same types of customer.
And so, you will get more of your time working with us, and we will get more working with you and prioritizing who to approach is kind of, if you are able to see customer overlap, like in tools like crossbeam and reveal, those are ways to prioritize, kind of whom to work with.
You can see how much overlap you have, but if you don't have that, You kind of just have to do trial and error and see what works best and who's the most responsive?
And what types of partners are providing the best relationship?
That's great.
So you mentioned crossbeam as a tool that you used to identify strategically partners that are using type form a 10, our customers.
Yep.
Yeah, so you can share your overlap with a potential partner and you can see what your overlap is and Prospects.
You can see what it is and paying customers.
You can kind of see that full picture which definitely helps prioritize.
I know it's a way that we have prioritized our Integrations and kind of what product level work goes into it as well, because we can see, you know, once the we want To get the biggest bang for our efforts.
Oh, because it takes a lot of work.
Yeah, to have to get these Partnerships.
I mean, the process you walked us through, you know, that takes some work to get done.
So it makes sense that you guys want to be very strategic with where you place your resources time and efforts.
Awesome.
Okay, here's another question from Angela.
Do you manage referral reward programs?
If so, do you use any tools to manage those programs and awarding perks to your Partnerships?
Yeah.
So it's a great question.
We do have a referral reward programs, it's a rev-share model with those agencies that I spoke about, and we managed that all through partner stack which is a partner or CRM tool.
And so they will see their rewards referrals, they will see click signups, and they will also get our we have a certification program that also lives in partner stack so it's a way for us to kind of how's everything?
And if we wanted to email a bunch of our partners all at once, we can do that.
Also, through Partner stock That's great.
So then go piggybacking off of Angela's question.
As far as your Tech stack of what helps you get, your day-to-day work done, how would you map that out?
Yeah, I would say I use partner sock, the most for sure, and then type form.
We use a lot for our or like, for applications for working with cross-functional teams for, you know, our sales, team needs, a partner to get involved to close a deal.
They submitted type form to us and that, and then we connect that with slack.
So I think there's a lot of productivity hacks and you could almost have an entire session on that.
I love learning more productivity hacks and all about automation that you can use.
And, so I would say, partner stack, typeform, slack, those are the most that I personally use.
I know on the other side of our Partnerships team, they use crossbeam a lot and seeing overlap more for their Partnerships make sense, okay?
Great.
And then as far as slack, do you create slack groups for each of your partners?
Or how do you manage communication with Partners in Slack?
That's a great question.
We have I think it depends on we try and stay away from it unless that's exactly how the partner wants to communicate.
The reason being is you don't want to have a million slack messages from your partner is just Vic.
A lot of times they will ask a question where it will build, you know resolve it on their own as well.
So we encourage them to reach out to us on Partner stack.
Messaging because it's just easier.
And that's where all their referrals and information is.
So it's one platform, but we do, you know, make exceptions for a certain Partners if that's kind of the only way to communicate with them.
Then we will make it work but That's great.
It's always, you know, these details of how you work together, how we work to the community that can either like make or break these experiences and ultimately the productivity.
So that's why I ask those kind of questions.
Yeah, and I think, I mean, I think traditional ways of communicating are kind of being thrown out the window now and it's all what works best for a partner or for yourself and your own productivity.
So I think it's just Being flexible on what people like to do, some people don't like to get on Zoom or like, some people are video shy, and they prefer to go over email, you know?
You just have to be flexible.
So with that, we would love to wrap up with a point of advice or any encouragement that you have for the overall B2B Tech Community.
This morning, we heard the news about meta Letting Go almost 11,000 employees.
Salesforce, there's a lot of these lip layoffs, taking place left and right and it's just a hard time to see your friends and fellow colleagues go through all of this.
So you know, just being mindful of what's happening today.
And then also just, you know, with the best practices that we're all learning they today, is there anything that you would offer out there as advice or encouragement?
Yeah, I would say, as far as the layoffs and everything going on in the tech world, that can be kind of nerve-racking to see everything that's going on.
But you are not defined by your job, you know, you bring a lot of skills to the table.
So even if you are laid off, you know, there's a lot of opportunities out there.
There are areas of tech that are still growing a ton.
And, so I would say just kind of keep your head up and it's not you.
It's your fault and yeah, keep pushing forward.
And see, where can you go from here?
That's awesome.
Alright well thank you so much Mattea, really appreciate your time.
Sharing your story with us and giving us some really awesome strategic and tactical points of insights that we can now hit the ground running with if we're interested in getting into Partnerships.
So, thank you so much.
We will be sending out this recording to all of those who registered and attended.
So, thank you for joining.
We have our next event coming up as soon as next week, and it is going to be about creating human marketing experiences across the pipeline.
So, we will cut off there at the top, but we have got a great lineup of speakers from sin do.
So and roll works, and Marco were also going to have a magic show that we're going to wrap up this event with.
So it's going to be a great event.
Check it out and I will see you next week, have a wonderful rest of your week.
Take care.