Roses and whiskers on kittens bright, copper kettles and warm water.
Toni's and crisp, apple strudels doorbells and sleigh bells and schnitzel with noodles.
These are.
Roses and whiskers on kittens.
Aloha.
Hi everybody.
How are you doing?
It's so wonderful to have you here.
Hope you enjoyed those Tunes looks like Lani.
This was your favorite movie growing.
So, I am glad that we were able to make a good selection there.
Hi, everyone.
I am Gina.
And I am so excited about today's event.
We have got some B2B Tech Titans that are going to be helping us understand what the predictions what is going on for 2023 and B2B marketing.
A lot of great questions have also been pre submitted in advance, so if you have got questions today, there is a Q&A tab.
Feel free to drop it in Q&A and any given point, we will pull that up on stage.
So in the meantime I am really excited about today's discussion.
You know, we're in this really uncertain funky time when budgets are getting tighter resources are Tighter, and we as B2B marketers need to completely innovate the way that we think and do and work.
And so we got to become better stewards of the business while still building.
Trust with our buyers across the Our buyer Journey.
So today we're going to dive into some strategies from tactics.
Some real talk from Latin and Amanda CMO of g 2 and 6 cents, they're going to be talking about recession proofing, our marketing strategies.
So I would love to bring them on stage before I do, I would like to give a little intro on our Tech, Titans here, Latin e.
So she is the CMO of six cents and author of know.
Forms, no spam, no cold calls.
In fact, the first 100 to have registered for this event will receive a free copy of her book, delivered to you.
So look out for that.
She is passionate about empowering, marketing Leaders with effective technology predictive insights, and thought leadership.
She's built an exclusive community of 2000 plus CMOS and marketing leaders, its heart.
It's called a CMO coffee talk, and she's keenly focused on leveraging data.
To ensure marketing programs result in deals and not just leads prior to six cents.
She was the CMO and sales leader of a pierrot.
And then let me get into Amanda.
I love shouting out these call-outs of our guests because it's pretty incredible.
Manda is the CMO G2 the wealth of experience in both Fortune, 500 and fast growing Tech Brands.
She's often found at the intersection of marketing creativity and Tech prior to G2, she led mailchimp's partner program.
And Marketplace business.
She then served in executive leadership, roles across several, high-growth SAS companies and help build the digital agency 360.
I which is named the most influential marketing firm of the 21st century by add age and Forbes.
So with that please bring up Amanda and lat me and let us give them a warm welcome.
Join me on stage here.
Hi guys, I love your energy.
It's amazing.
Thank you.
Thanks for bringing the energy, Jenna.
Absolutely, it's actually Gina.
Oh, Gina.
There we go.
No, worries.
It's all good.
Thank you.
I am just inspired by yours Lanny.
Great.
Well, we have got a fun little map that I want to put up here, and I am tuning in.
From Ewa Beach, Hawaii?
I wish.
Could be doing this in person, Hawaii.
And it looks like both of you are tuning in from Chicago.
Yep.
We had dinner last night.
Ria and we're about to.
This is a map of the flight were about to take to Hawaii to come.
Join you in Hawaii.
That's the whether I want to be having right now.
Please do our next event.
We should do it on the beach over out here with my ties.
Awesome.
Well I am really excited about the discussion that we're going to jump into before we do that.
I have got a few fun facts, and we love our fun facts.
Here.
So each of you also have fun facts are, so I will start with mine, I used to do a lot of Television, movies in my early 20s and I actually did a lot of work with Ugly Betty.
And so she was the lead actress, and I was in the back.
There's the shot right there, love that, and so I will hand it over to you Latin me.
What's a fun fact about you?
Well, I think I have about 200 pairs of shoes, maybe more.
So actually, my husband had to like, redo the attic crawl space to house them all.
So yeah, just you know, it's always a confidence booster when you're rocking a cool pair of shoes.
So there you go, upset, awesome.
I am handing it over to you Amanda.
I wish that was my fun fact.
I want 200 pairs of shoes.
That's what I want my friend back to be mine is I am related to two of the three people who have ever broken out of Alcatraz which you know I guess as a marketer I am very crafty is the way that I will put that but really there.
I never knew them.
But a couple years ago we did the family tree through ancestry and discovered that.
Yeah.
Yeah, I am related to two of the three people like shared a shared.
A maiden name on my mother's side.
So wow.
That's an incredible fun fact.
I do love the rock Bethany and so it really was a full circle moment for me when I discovered this.
Yeah, crafty, that's how I am choosing.
Did you do that?
Awesome.
Well, thank you for sharing some of your fun facts jumping right into this conversation.
So, you know, as we know to set in the landscape here, Tech has been uncertain tumultuous to say the least.
Layoffs, marketing resources, budgets getting tighter.
Marketers needing to rethink the way we do marketing.
And we look at forecasting and budgeting, Amanda your team just Put together this amazing report on software, buyer behaviors.
And I think if there's any G2 team members, if y'all can drop that in chat, that's a really great report that we can take a look at and Latin me.
I have seen your LinkedIn post where you're tracking close with the Forester.
B2B Trends, drop in your predictions.
I mean, I just want to get the poles from each of you.
What are the key trends and insights that you're seeing, what do you agree with what do you disagree with?
With could you share with us your thoughts?
Well, I will share some of the insights from the G2 report, and then we maybe can take some of the themes I know Latin.
He's been focused on and tracking as well.
I think one of the key themes that we have seen for a couple of years now but was most acute in this research report?
Thank you.
Jenny just shared it here in the chat.
Was that more than ever buyers are looking to?
If you ask them what's your top source of influence when you're deciding, what you're going to use particularly for software those responses.
Has been overwhelmingly.
I am turning to my peers and influencers that I know and trust.
And so what that means for anyone, in who's looking for software marketing software is you really need to be thinking about whom, how am I leaning into Community?
Soul at knee, and sixth sense?
Has this amazing group of 2,000 plus CMOS and how am I allowing my customers to talk to other customers and potential prospects?
And certainly you know, peer reviews and G2 is a great way to do that but there's a whole host of other Are ways that you can lean into, you know, really peer influence to help potential buyers, make more informed decisions so that's one Trend we're seeing I think the other Trend we're seeing is that there's a lot more consolidation in software and text acts as people look to next year.
And so it just means the bar is higher.
It doesn't mean there's not opportunity.
There actually is a lot of opportunity in that statement, but it does mean the bar is higher.
So, for those who know me, I am a control freak, I try to let go but it's very challenging for me.
And, so I guess, first of all, you know, our number one job in marketing is the market.
And you know it makes us even more relevant when markets are changing, right?
We saw that with covid too.
And so, our job is to adjust to changing market conditions.
And help kind of steer the ship so to speak.
And I think that when the market is changing frequently there you got to control what you can control and to me, you know what I am advising and what we're working on is doing that and there's three big buckets for me.
One, is your ideal customer profile and it's so interesting to me how, you know, when times are good, you might not need to be as refined and diligent around this.
But when ties, maybe aren't as good, you have got to really understand your ideal customer profile and eliminate waste, right?
Because if you're spending a lot of sales and marketing energy, and even product energy, just company, energy trying to be everything to everybody, you know.
I think you're going to quickly a struggle and so and you might need to rethink it.
So every time there's a shift in the market you need to reconsider you know, is that Deal customer profile.
Maybe there are more affected by this economy.
So, maybe we need to start to warm up, other, slivers of art, am that are less affected.
So, that's number one for stand.
First, and foremost ideal customer profile.
And then the in Market ideal customer profile, know those.
And then the second thing for me, is your message and your value prop.
So, you know, again, in times of abundance, You know, it's could be a different message, and value prop.
We're not in a time of abundance and so yeah.
If you have a consolidation Story, Probably a good time to dust that one off right, you know, and I don't want to go out with an in these uncertain times.
Message.
That's pretty tired, but rethinking, you know, how what is your, what is your Mary thinking and feeling and needing right now?
Now, and how do you connect with them?
So we just rolled out our new kind of the highest level message, which is proceeded with confidence and, and that's been really effective for us, but we had to quickly pivot come up with that, get it out.
And so, you know, I would challenge folks to do the same and then last, the third pillar is execution.
We can control how well we execute, and we can control how efficiently we execute.
So I would say, you know, teams everywhere ours included are thinking about, you know where how do we eliminate waste?
You know, what are the things that we did last year?
That maybe weren't that great.
Let us cut them and so and I have a lot more under that pillar but you know, those are three things.
I see p message and execution, that's what we can control, hmm.
That's good.
That's that those are right on.
When it comes to buying behavior and patterns going into 2023, what are some observations that you have about those patterns?
How will they shift as companies?
Decrease, their budgets and Workforce.
I can take this one and then I will throw it to you.
So a couple things one we are seeing its harder so just know it's harder, right?
Let us not expect it to be the same, right?
And, and so, when I say it's harder, and I am sure Amanda has probably more broad data on this, but this is just my own data.
So we look at every single deal that we won in the previous quarter.
And then we just look at all the patterns.
How many contacts do we need engaged?
And how many activities did we need to get from one stage to the next just raw math?
And we when we look at our raw math and I bet everyone is feeling this, it's more people engaged and it's more steps per stage.
So, just like when you go to the grocery store, your salary, doesn't go as far we're experiencing inflation.
And that, you know, it's, it takes more work to get a deal done.
And so, I think we need to understand that and how we collaborate across Teams to scale up our efforts and address that kind of call.
I would call it by, you know, deal inflation.
The other thing I would say is there are going to be probably fewer deals and so if you aren't Savvy about capturing signal like Now's the Time because you can't afford to miss out on deals right now and you can't afford to not be relevant, you're going to have to be all over the deals that are in.
It and make sure that you're highly relevant.
And so, and there're all kinds, there's always new forms of intent data.
You know, we're talking a lot about pre intent data.
So understanding tangential, buying patterns, understanding hiring patterns, understanding job, posting patterns, you know, all of these things help you understand, you know, is a company growing, are they investing where they invest?
Does it look like they have a problem?
And then, of course, the classic kind of, you know, first party and third T and then you know some of the things that like Amanda and G2 does like someone's researching you and your competition and you don't know about it.
That's kind of bad that's irresponsible.
I think right now given there are going to be less potential opportunities to go after.
I think I am just going to Echo a lot of what Latin he's that?
I mean, in the research report, that's linked here we did.
Ask buyers, you know, how many stages are there?
How long is it taking you to do deals?
How many people are involved?
The thing that stood out to me the most in that part of the study was that eighty percent of buyers said we make consensus-based decisions, which is terrifying, right?
Because your Having a conversation, you think you know who the decision maker is and the reality?
Yes.
As a seller that's incredibly hard and so you know, ICP matters more than ever be really focused, but it's not just who do you think is the decision maker?
It's who's going to be part of that decision because the reality is to see if I was probably part of that decision, you know there's going to be people from maybe depending on if you're Marty Goetz sales and marketing sitting at the table making that decision.
And so your job as a marketer is to also think about Who is our kind of core ICP and then the decision-making set around that and what is the message we need to bring to those parties?
So that when they're at the table making that decision, they're all aligned on why they should choose you.
And so, that does make the deals harder.
Because it's more complex for buyers to make decisions and more complex for us to Market and sell to those decision-makers.
And then the other thing that we're seeing is there is going to be, there are going to be fewer deals and your and there are going to be fewer deals that result in any sort of lot.
People are research mode.
Yeah, so it doesn't want to be able to look for mazing.
Yes, and I am conversion, rates are low and so, to lambie's point, really understanding within your own data set, what is within our control here?
Can we incentivize deals to close faster this year?
Can we keep really be clear about when a deal is probably just in research mode?
How do you keep them warm?
But then not overtax your sales and marketing resources on deals that aren't going to maybe Because they're not ready to make the deal.
So I think just getting really Savvy on who is the buying committee and then within deals being savvier about how do we get more of them to close and be smarter about knowing which ones maybe aren't going close knowing that again fewer deals to be had top of funnel.
May look great, but we all know it's not converting as well.
Yeah, I want to double down on one of your points and actually introduced a term that I find marketers aren't as familiar with.
But There's a term in sales called multi-threading and if you're in marketing, it's a it's an important concept to understand.
So right now, there's a forecast call happening somewhere in the world.
Probably many.
And some poor AE is getting in big-time trouble because his deal is not multi-threaded.
He's only talking to one person, or she there, and they're only talking to one person.
And the sales manager is saying, there's no way that's going close and you can say, that's not my problem, but it is our problem as marketers, and we and actually the longer a deal progresses the harder, it is to multi-thread.
So what does that mean for you?
And me as marketers we can start multi-threading much earlier than typically we do.
And that's one of my challenges with passing a quote-unquote lead because a lead is a single contact.
And that's a single-threaded deal.
That's not good for sales.
So think start to think about your SLA is like, when an account comes inbound, why do you just follow up with the person who were requested a demo?
If you're buying teams, 810 people, you probably should try to get at least three or four meetings right then and there, right?
And so three think you're SLA s with both your intent-based leads and your just classic inbound funnel.
If you are B2B and you're seeing this contact thing and like you can be a force multiplier to the selling cycle, by having multi-thread plays early, and then even as the deal advances, Is there any advice you have on like the number of contacts that marketing could be warming up for sales?
You know, how is there a good number that strategically?
You know when we die Lander?
ICP, here're the companies.
How what do you recommend there?
I mean we have landed on three or four because if you look at you know what used to be six for us is now 13.
So you know and you want to be clear about whom those key personas are and then that could mean changes to comp plans for you know some of your Frontline roles like mdrs like SDR.
So you do want to be clear about these are the personas that qualify for LT thread but, but, you know, me, we put out a CFO ebook recently and are promoting that just as, you know, are cover because guess what, a CFO or a finance business partner is going to be involved.
So we want them to understand what we do and the value prop we provide.
So things like that.
Yeah, I think there's the in multi-threading and marketing, you can do the proactive, you know, a Cover is Latin, he said, like be very clear on who is within that decision committee and where are you going to actually create messaging and plays targeted to them and the accounts you care about or a counselor showing intent and then one that is really enabling conversations within the organization.
So are there things that you can do one of the most successful plays I ever ran a multi-threading was actually creating conversations around topics that could bring those personas together sometimes across multiple accounts, not a selling conversation, just a relationship building Isolation that in this environment, maybe it is a great conversation to have, you know, the CFO, the head of marketing and the head of sales joining around table.
For example, with other peers, you can facilitate that in a way that helps, you understand and build those relationships.
And so there's that are cover within the broader ecosystem of accounts and then really doubling down on how do you create more relationship building experiences within the accounts that matter?
Most, especially if your you have longer deal Cycles, you have time to Do that.
But you have to be really proactive in which accounts need that kind of attention, hmmm.
So there's an interesting question.
That actually Spencer, Tucci is asking right now, I think is relevant to this how much time effort.
Do you spend your on the?
We put on stage, there you go.
How much time effort?
Do you spend marketing to secondary personas to enable, multi threading, compared to primary?
Is it more or less, or even split or something more, like, 70/30 percent?
Like how do you approach this when resources are thinner?
You know, we have got to be better.
Words of where we focus our time and our dollars.
So, it's interesting because I don't think that we have thought about it.
This way currently, but as I am looking at my future budget, I am going to start, I would say soft allocating program spend based on our key personas because what it's just like with anything you find that the ones that you know, and understand and have done before you, you continue to do more and more of and you know doing something new is always a new muscle.
So you know, we're going to be doing that and kind of have RV to Mom and some of our kpis, more tied to again, looking at our ICP and then within that IC PR, you know, are the best Persona fit, you know, we're finding that maybe we need to kind of force rotate to some other personas.
So I would say, look at your deal like, like, do the look back.
Look at One deals and look at the patterns and then that's how you determine the percentage for you, you know what's a winning pattern and how do you tap into winning patterns over and over again.
Yeah, I think that's right.
And I don't think it's going to look the same for every business because the weight of different personas in a deal cycle.
May be different.
If it's, you know, for example if you're a CV is 10 grand to, you're probably not going to over index on the CFO as much as if your deals six-figure +, right.
So, you know, I think the it's multi-threading is going to be pretty important, no matter what you're selling and to whom, but I think how important the various personas are Depends greatly on your product, your personas and Then, of course you're a CD.
Makes sense.
We got another multi-threading question here from Eric.
We have opened think I do?
Can I know it's a good topic is with multi-threading increasing more and more?
Do you believe it would be beneficial to try and reach advisors to that company as well, to create more relationships and take it a step deeper on pain and priorities?
Well, you learn in Seattle's gravity, only goes one way.
So yeah.
I mean, if and I think when you say advisors you probably mean like board and that level.
So yeah, if you gravity goes one way, so I would say the higher, you can get and the higher you can get introduced, obviously the better.
Yeah, I agree with that.
That I would depend on your interpretation of advisors but assuming you're talking about board then.
Yes, awesome.
So going back to I know you kind of went into a little bit of squid squirrel here with multi-threading but it's such a solid strategy.
So, thank you for bringing that up.
We do have a question here from Alina and you know, it's going back up to sort of the metrics and how it what we're presenting.
Ink on a quarterly basis from your perspective, we're going into 2023.
How should we look at metrics and what do you advise in?
How?
We present a not just to the board?
I would ask.
But also to your leadership and to your team and to your organization, there're multiple tiers, there of communicating this Well, I know a lot knee has a great answer for this one.
I would say, I we do a couple of things.
So we also use the framework lightning reference, which is the V2 mom framework to set our goals.
If you do is you're familiar with okrs it's similar it's just a different acronym and approach but similar end result.
And so we have primary kpis that I actually put into sort of scoreboard for marketing.
And the first thing I do is you want to be Abel.
So they're not seeing different things from are getting every quarter because then it's like, well, what are you really focused on?
So at the beginning of the year, we set our scoreboard, we're repeating that every quarter, and we're reporting out on our metrics.
And I always make sure, of course, everyone cares about pipeline, but I always make sure it also includes other metrics, even if the board's, maybe not keep it up in mind.
So we always have a brand metrics.
So what are we really trying to achieve for our brand and for positioning so that we're balancing short and long-term even in this climate that Really important especially in this climate because a lot of people won't do that and if you invest in your brand now you will come out better later and then I actually include an efficiency metric because even if they don't ask, they're thinking about it.
And I am so glad that we do that because now in this climate, if someone says, how are you looking at the efficiency of what marketing is spending will?
We have had an answer for a while, and we have that as part of our scoreboard.
And, so I think just thinking about what are the things that you need to do to solve the businesses goals.
Goals, and what can you achieve as a team, and then putting that into something that, you know, makes it clear the value you deliver across the business and then making sure you're showing yourselves as good stewards of the business as part of that.
So, we actually have, you know what?
We call an efficiency metric and there's a whole methodology behind it, we reported a recorder.
So I would say so similar.
So yes.
And, and the way I think about V2, mom versus my dashboard is because we use V2.
Mom to those are the kpi.
Those are the things we're doing to change and evolve the business.
And so those have an Associated group of kpis and then there's what we're doing to like run the business and sort of report on the health of our Pipeline, and I am You know, pretty opinionated about how we do that.
Here, we create essentially pipeline quotas and so, it's marketing's responsibility to not necessarily owned all of pipeline creation, but be the stewards of measuring all of pipeline creation and be the stewards of indicating how we're doing against the plan and so, you know, it's pretty simple.
I look at you know for top of fun.
Do I look at ICP website traffic?
So are we getting the right contacts and accounts to our website at an increasing basis?
You know, pretty simple.
We have the concept of tier one account, so I look at penetration of Tier 1 accounts.
That's another good kind of top of funnel Focus metric and then you know deals don't happen without meetings.
So we track meetings and how those meetings.
Grass and then stage two for us, which is Pipeline.
And the interesting thing about it is we're looking at like raw created Pipeline, and we look by segment by Channel, and then we're always tracking win rates conversions and asps because that's what you used to come up with how much pipeline you need to create.
And so, what I love about the dashboard is it has pipelined, created count and dollar but then right next to it has the ASP cycle times and win rates that we assumed and it goes, right?
And if we assumed a 40% win rate and oh by the way, we're at a 35% win rate.
That's a problem.
So those red.
So we know, okay, we need to do something about this or if the cycle time show slows down, right?
So it keeps that check and balance of us, not just creating a ton of Pipeline and feeling super happy.
That Create a pipeline in it and it's not progressing or something like that or and it and also allows us to drill down by go to market segment, because sometimes, you can look good holistically.
But then you can start to drill in, and you see, oh, well, actually, the commercial segment is, is not hitting their pipeline numbers and Strat had a great month.
And they had all these big lumpy things come in and that masked like this other.
So you have to like really drill in and be looking at it on kind of That basis to keep the pace healthy.
And that's a big priority for us.
It's the best way to future-proof.
Your bookings are future proof your pipeline, so that's kind of how we think about it.
And then I would say yes and on efficiency, we have kind of version of almost a CAC, and it's sort of like, what we spent a couple quarters ago versus the pipeline we created this quarter and you know, there's no perfect metric but the faster you get to something that is Trackable and everyone understands and trendabl the better, and then we do like basic Roi for any big program or big chunk of spend.
We're going to be looking for at least a 10 times Roi on that.
So and we stack rank every quarter with a qvr how we progress against those?
So some of the ways we kind of measure so good, thank you for breaking that all down.
I feel like I need to re-watch these segments and captured some detailed notes here, you know.
It gets me thinking about then, okay, in order to be successful, obviously we need to work as a team across all go to market.
And I know both of you talk a lot about sales and marketing alignment and even customer success alignment going into 2023.
And actually, Spencer asked another question that sort of aligned to this, you know, he's an Asking here what does sales and marketing really need to get aligned on in 2023 in order to be successful in all these strategies and different things that you're bringing up?
Like what does that look like?
And I would also include customer success into that and I know customer marketing is another topic that we're going to tackle a little bit.
But what's what are your thoughts to that alignment?
So we talked about functional metrics which is great.
You have to have a bead on your functional metrics, but I think also just good financial literacy and alignment on the highest level metrics and in assurance that the whole team understands that.
So we talked about efficiency sales and marketing share of wallet, and ultimately a board is going to be looking at kak.
So we can be the most efficient little beans but if you know were doing crazy stuff on sale sales it's just not going to work and vice versa and so you know things like gross retention, net retention, you know, are per employee like there's just a lot of kind of like overarching things that like indicate the health of us a specific, your SAS company, which we are indicated that and I think just making sure that It everybody on the team has Financial like literacy around those and how every single, you know, we're all like cells in the big organism, right?
And we all can contribute to those.
And so, I think keeping those top of mind, so you don't get to myopic in your own functional metrics.
Yeah, I think that's right.
We were actually I was just having a conversation with my team about this about sort of like, let us talk holistically about next year and not marketing or sales but just like holistically across the business.
What do we need to achieve?
And I think taking that down to like what is sales and marketing have to get aligned on the first one is that?
Where is growth going to come from next year?
And then if your plan looks the same, your Revenue plan, your sales plan, your marketing plan.
Next year, you're probably not making enough big changes.
Not that you have to make totally radical swings by like next year's probably gonna look different.
Your plans should probably look different.
So what we have done is we have said, okay, what do we need to achieve next year?
How is that going to be different?
And then what is the role of sales and marketing to do that?
So what is the role of sales versus Marketing in driving nrr?
And we want to have a really collaborative relationship in a world of abundance.
Where we came from, we could all just go.
Go against all the metrics that the Game time together really fast in a world where the board is looking at Blended sales and marketing efficiency.
Well, what can I do to have a more collaborative relationship, and so we're not duplicating efforts?
How can we best support each other in the most efficient way possible and you might make different choices?
So I think that's a really important one is what do you need to achieve for the business?
And then what is the handshake role and relationship for sales or CS forces marketing to achieve those kpis?
Is going into next year, and we actually do that by segment and by metrics so that we understand like on Enterprise.
For example, what's the role of marketing versus sales?
And then when there is you know what's the role of this?
Yes team as well.
So that's really clear.
Here's the top line of what we need to do in the segment and then here's what each team and function what we need to do and deliver.
Is there a recommended Cadence like howdy just practically speaking like on a week-to-week monthly?
Like what's the Cadence of that alignment that takes place in communication and meetings because we don't want more meetings.
We want to work asynchronously as well.
But like how does that look in each of your organization's?
I mean, I think for us, we plan we do annual plans, we revisit every half, and then we have got a pretty tight alignment on a monthly basis with our sales leadership, including at the segment level to see how is what we are.
Delivering performing so that we can iterate along the way I would say you probably can't you can over plan in this climate but you can't communicate enough.
Like I don't think there's such a thing as too much.
Munication in this climate because things are changing, its really unpredictable.
So the more conversations you can have to make sure that everybody has the same shared information on how we're performing and what's trending in the market the better.
So if you're not doing that at least monthly you know you probably need to think about increasing that frequency across sales and marketing line am curious what you all do from up from a planning and Alignment.
Cadence.
Yeah, well, our exec team, we meet for two hours.
Every Week.
So that's sort of standing, you know, huddle, and we cover all kinds of topics.
Obviously, you know, it's funny.
I wish I could give a better answer because there's a lot of things that we do.
There're meetings, that we have, there're dashboards, there's this, there's, there's Monday reports that go out.
I mean, we have all of those things, but I call it getting in the flow.
And Anna and it's a little more organic but I just think that there's like knowing when you're in the flow with someone and when you're not and to me like being in the flow is like the I have got 10 minutes before a flight.
I am just going to call you and see what's going on, you know?
And, and I know that sounds but I think sometimes we almost over engineer and then almost I don't have his real conversations, whereas, Sometimes just a little text here there or a quick, you know, 15 minute, I am waiting in carpool.
What's shakin bacon?
Helps with that.
I don't know.
Flow.
Anyway again, I don't think that's the answer people want but that's what, but I think you're hitting something Latin, especially moving into next year.
You know, I think what you're hitting is trust.
I think in flow can happen when you have this the trust amongst your key colleagues that you're running in the trenches with and it's like how do you get there?
You know if rather than falling default to our Templates.
And okay.
We have got this meeting, Cadence sometimes there's core things that we need to address, but it requires that level of trust and communication to get there.
So what have both of you done to get to flow?
Because I think that is a very powerful note.
I think sometimes like putting down the agendas in the slides like to build off that.
Like so we have pipeline meetings every month and there's the slot, you know, the dashboards and the slides and the whatever and all the Rev world leaders are there and marketing's there.
And one of our last meetings I was like, let us just I read the pre-raid, can we just like put that aside?
Can we just talk about what's happening in the business?
And like what's it?
And we had the conversation on what's within our control.
And so we started looking at The metrics, you're like, okay, what's within our control and it was a very helpful conversation, but we just sort of like it was sort of like just we're doing all the things.
Can we just pause for a minute and just have some real talk about?
What do you think's happening?
Just intuitively, we have informed ourselves.
What do we think is within our control?
So I think it's a really important thing about building trust but also trusting yourself.
There is going to be very little certainty including in all of your data in the first table.
Future things.
Are going to be wonky and you're gonna be like, I don't know why top of funnel looks great, but bottom of the funnel conversions are lower and I think just trusting your own intuition and form yourself and then trust your intuition.
And have real talk with your team's is it is pretty powerful and so that's resonating what Latin he said and what you said, you know, with me as well.
Love that.
Okay, I am gonna pull us back up into some other questions that are popping up here and I would love to tackle customer marketing as well looking at time.
Alina's got a question here on okrs and structure.
So as we're talking, still about teams and how you all do things within each of your orgs, how do you structure Okie ours, specifically for your marketing team?
So I am a V2, mom Enthusiast for the record, but we also do, okay, ours and so.
Okay, ours to me or more bottom up.
V2, mom is more top-down and you need both, but they calf they can't connect.
And so what we do is we have the company V2, mom, that comes out at the beginning of the year and then gets a refresh, you know, in the middle of the year and then I develop off vibing off of the company, won the marketing lie to Mom.
For our artwork and then individuals, do okay, ours.
But I ask that the okay are has one objective, no more than 31 objective.
That's tied to the overall, the overall kind of V2, mom, marketing, and or company.
But the whatever the top priorities are from the company, s is a functional thing, something they're going to, you know, tied to their overall functional goals.
Then third is personal but no more than that.
And then we do a check in on those every quarter.
But I think you can kind of over do it.
If you get to I mean, so much of being a good manager, is just consistently having a one-on-one with people.
So we do, we do almost the exact same thing.
So we have the company V2, mom's published at the end of the year.
We do a mid-year kind of refresh of that.
Based on what's changed the market, we have a marketing one that fives off the company, one, and then for ours, we have key.
I have key leaders who own what's called a method.
So I see Spencer here sharing it.
So each of my L will own at least one method.
And then they're accountable for the cross-functional work required to make that method, come to life and to happen and to hit the metric associated with it.
And then we do individual V2 moms as well that we pair with what's called a performance development plan which is here's what I am going to achieve for the company.
And here's what I want to achieve in my career and sometimes those are very much correlated and sometimes the career ones are longer term, and we check it.
We do those quarterly as well, but they're two different documents.
One, sort of the Personally to Mom and one is the personal development plan, it's called a PDP, not to be confused with a pip which is where acronyms can go really South.
That's good clarification, awesome and thanks caver, eccentric, a break for dropping in the V2.
Mom framework, right there.
That's great.
Here's another question coming up about the structure of your teams and within each of your orgs is coming up from a Lena, how do you structure your team or so moving into 2023?
How are you looking at structuring?
Your team to support the goals that you have all identified?
Amanda.
You want to take this one for sure.
Well.
So G to my org looks a little different, and she too because of the nature of our business, but I have kind of traditional ask structure and then I have a Brandon Communications function which is really responsible for our story but also includes things like events that really Naturally Fit within the skill.
Set of that team.
They have a creative function, which supports a lot of our organization.
I have product partner and Summer marketing actually together.
And that's really nice because it helps us I think tell a better narrative around our products but more importantly, even the value that we're delivering to our customers and that they're getting from the products.
And then I have a, I have an interesting organ, it's our user lifecycle and Community organization, which is really focused on the buyer, side of g 2.
So how do we get more people coming to G2 to search for software and to leave reviews for software?
Providers.
And so that's a function and actually, it includes support as well, which is a bit unusual for a marketing team, and they're all focused.
We have got 80 million buyers who come to G to it and growing, and so they're a big part of that.
And then we have a revenue marketing function which is in a very important function that also includes our marketing operations and Tech stack, which is near and dear to my heart are a great team and the mar Tech stack is pretty core to everything we do at G2.
So, That's kind of the core functions.
We have it in marketing.
I would say similar, we have competitive intelligence under pmm, but customer is also under pmm and partner.
We have a separate ABX team which for us, is just a, it's all of our experiential marketing which we do a lot of and a lot of like high-touch campaigns and things like that.
At, and they're their own team.
But other than that, yeah, I was a pretty standard.
That's great.
Well, I do want to pull the thread into customer marketing because this is a topic that has been coming up a lot.
And, you know, moving into next year investing into existing customers focusing on retention and expansion is a no-brainer and a big priority, you know, there're many ways.
Ways to go about to do this, aside from getting G2 reviews from customers, holding an advisory boards.
What does customer marketing look like?
What does that look like for each of you and where does the budget headcount come from?
Because it's not quite a fully fleshed-out, you know, maybe it is for you all, but I think I know right now.
There's a lot of folks still trying to figure out what does that look like?
What is the ROI?
And attribution look like with customer marketing.
Yeah.
Well, I think it starts with how do you define customer marketing and I can get on a soapbox about this but I think it's one of the most critical functions and also one of the most multi-faceted if you define it in a really strategic way which is not often defined in a very strategic way.
To me, it's incredibly strategic.
What you think about customer marketing is the function that both it's sort of Yin and Yang helps you grow with your existing customers and also leverages your existing customers to grow with new ones to me.
That becomes a really strategic function within the organization.
Like, it's not references and reviews.
It's actually, how do we grow our existing customer base and turn them into Advocates that can help us attract new customers?
That's a strategic customer marketing function.
And so for us, that's how we have defined it, and we have a couple of pillars under that are really important but one of the most important ones for us right now is customer education but for Us customer education, starts presale.
So we don't gate our customer education for like when you become a customer because we know that buyers want to understand how they're going to be successful and using the product while before the sale.
And so we spend a lot of time thinking about what's the right training and education for our customers, including presale and how do we carry that through?
And then certainly advocacy is the second pillar.
How do we actually build customer Advocates and have them?
Share the stories of how G2 is impacting their own?
And growth.
And then expansion is sort of the third pillar.
And how do we actually make sure we're growing our customer relationships and really strategic ways, especially for our larger accounts?
So those kind of how we have defined it, it's a really big and important function, but it can often be like, well, we have someone who does references reviews, which isn't a bad thing, you want that, but I think there's so much more to it than that.
So we I would say one of the things that we do is customer and Community is one group, and they really go hand-in-hand, and so we very early on at six cents.
Realized we don't really sell software, we sell change.
And a change in approach that is, is more efficient and has all these great benefits, but requires a change.
And so we decided, we need to support.
We probably need to provide support other than just how to set it up in the software, right?
Like it's a mentality, the measurement around it, the process around it, the organizational structure.
So very early on, we decided we were going to invest be And communities.
And so, that's a huge part of our customer marketing.
It's about, you know, how do we make sure that they are engaged, right?
You think about Employee Engagement, we think about customer engagement and, you know, we measure things like, we want to make sure that ninety percent of our customers show up every quarter.
Like if no one is coming to learn about our new roadmap from an account there.
Probably read.
They don't.
Care you, right?
And so it's like, people vote with their feet, and so we do a lot around keeping customers engaged.
Keeping them, you know, we're innovating fast.
And so we want to, we want to also address them in their whole role.
Not just what they do with six Ed's, right?
So I want people to say six cents, made me successful in my role and my kpis, but also my overall career.
So we take, I would say a very broad approach for customers.
Getting, you know, the funding of it is, is interesting.
It's sort of like you for me, you sort of, don't ask and you just do and then it's amazing.
And of course people want to fund it but not everyone has that luxury, especially right now.
So I get that.
But I would say going back to some of those important metrics like nrr and gross retention and you know, No, we think a lot about adopted use cases and so, you know, how are we helping get more adopted use cases?
So that's that is like a score that we look at.
So yeah, it's a much more I think holistic.
It can have a lot more value than people, I think perceived in the past.
But it does require the right level of investment, right?
I mean, we said oh, it's It just reviews and it's not just references in case studies, but that's a lot of work.
Justin just that's still a lot of work.
It really is and I know and you know, requires investment of a different kind.
So yeah.
But I think again you know, when you think about the cost of losing a customer and you think about LTV and like again great SAS metrics, they come down to retention and growth.
So just making sure you're tying that function back to those.
Yeah.
And I do want to say like, The reference is a reviews, it's really the foundation.
Like if you don't have customers that are willing to Advocate, right?
And there's no real Community, it's going to be a community of complainers.
You're going to be screwed.
Yeah.
And it gives you those hand-raisers who you can see like are we ready to build and kind of create our own connection and who should we invite?
But yeah, you want to make sure you have got people who are willing to come to the dance before you put on.
Don't put on the party, they don't it's going to come to.
So those are pretty critical at the foundation of God.
Marketing.
I love that.
You said budget to.
I feel like, if you ask a CMO, what do you have?
Budgeted for Pipeline and acquisition, they will be like, I know exactly my number next year and I fought with my CFO about it and if you ask them like, what did you budget for customer marketing?
That's a much harder question but I think a really good one to ask heading into next year and just try honestly just tracking upsell pipeline.
Again, if you take this holistic pipeline model, I can flip back and forth and a second between net new and upsell pipeline.
And if we now and then going back to the financial plan, if we know that this year, we have agreed of higher percentage of our Pipeline and bookings is going to come from expansion or cross-sell.
Then, you know, there you go, then you sort of have your metric.
But anyway, so that's also another way to look at it.
So good I can't believe it.
We only have five minutes left time just flew, and we have some questions here.
You know, looking at all these, I would love to ask this last question.
I know there's some technical questions, Leo.
Chris you guys are asking some technical questions will reply back to you after this event.
But in this event right now as we're wrapping up, I want to bring up Christine colosimo's, question.
Oops, sorry Sal could actually hit the button.
He's our producer.
Maybe you can pull it back up, but she was asking basically how do we keep our team's motivated in times like this when budgets are smaller efficiency?
Super important headcount is harder to come by.
How are you inspiring the teams?
It's probably the thing I worry the most about And Amanda and I were at dinner last night talking about this.
Like you know a no-brainer is getting people together but that's also expensive, right, looks like, right?
So it's like, It's hard.
We're going to have to it's like covid part 2, right of being creative, especially with us.
You know, embracing hybrid, you know, work environments and I think that I have decided I wrote in prep for this like You know, this whole does more with less is just b*******.
Like that's not inspiring to anybody.
So I think what we have to do is really commit to We have to fundamentally change the way we work and that either comes from better focus.
It comes from tapping into things like, Automation and AI for scale and then I think it comes from eliminating complexity because complexity comes at a cost.
And, you know, when you're in a high growth environment, you can just add a dad and sometimes you just need to peel it back and be like, wait why are we doing that?
Like, you know, and so But it, I don't know.
I would love suggestions for what, what people think work, I mean, I can't do another virtual wine tasting.
I know that, you know, it's okay.
We had to, I mean, I don't know.
I think so.
A couple things I have three.
I don't.
First of all, this is a journey.
I think for everybody, our team included, but I think the first is people can't feel motivated.
When they don't understand and know, and trust the people they work with and you don't have to do that in person.
It helps But we just do a chat every month, and it's just, there's no agenda.
There is no, we did the wine tasting.
It's just like just show up, and we're going to talk, and we often have themes that are like real, and we find ways to kind of connect as people because it's hard to just be work people all the time through resumes green.
So that's the first thing is get to know each other as people, because it's, you're going to be more motivated when you're working.
And supporting people, you really know.
And trust the second thing we do is find the creativity in it, which is easier said than done, but there's always peopled on this like, I am one of those people that's like, who doing more or less have fun.
Like, I know, I am a rarity right.
Like, I am like, oh, that sounds really exciting, but there are ways to find the fun and creativity on it.
And so, I think just saying like what can be what if this was fun?
Like what would have to be the conditions in which this would be enjoyable for us and it might mean, I mean, what we need to do less stuff because otherwise, it's just overwhelming and can we prioritize better?
And it may also look like efficiency and optimization and finding new levers to pull this fun because we can test and experiment and that's fun.
And I think the third thing is just like being transparent.
It gets really hard to stay motivated if you think there's something behind the curtain.
And, so I think it's m like the more you can be just transparent on what you know and what you don't know.
Because there's a lot, we don't know and won't be I think super important.
Wow, thank you your time so much Latin e Amanda.
It's been a pleasure to have you here, and drop your wisdom and insights for all of us.
Thank you so much for taking the time.
We actually, I just want to communicate as a B2B marketer were so inspired and grateful for both of you as we know that you have invested so much into us.
So this is just an appreciation back to you.
So, thank you so much for being here.
Here for everyone else.
Thank you for sitting in and joining the conversation.
We will be sending this recording out to you all.
Oh it looks like hey the first 102 registered will receive Latin.
He's book we have another event tomorrow with Nick Bennett who is the director of evangelism and customer marketing with Alice, and we're going to go deeper into evangelism and Customer marketing and pull that thread.
All right, so for that with all that have a wonderful rest of your day, we hope to see you tomorrow.
If we don't have a wonderful rest of your week, stay positive.
Keep the joy.
You got this, we can do this.
All right, take care.
Bye.
So you are honor him.
I played my drum.
Put him back.
I played my best for him by a bumper, to bumper.