Wait and Oahu to be specific.
Ewa Beach and it's 10:47.
A.m.
What time is it for you?
It is 347 right now and I got to say it's pretty amazing that we're on opposite ends of the Earth basically, right?
And we're having a conversation here on welcome, it's kind of crazy when you think about it.
Just like sometimes when you think about technology, we tend to take it for granted but I think, I don't know.
Some comedian.
I heard on Late Show one time, and he was like, you know, isn't it kind of crazy?
Like you're in an airplane you're in a like a metal cylinder, just flying through the air.
It's a crazy concept.
Don't think about stuff like that.
We don't think in depth about that, you know, you kind of just like, oh yeah, it's just a bullet train.
That's going 200 miles 42 mph when your machine gun send in Japan or in an airplane.
Yeah, totally.
So, yeah.
Being on, welcome and being able to connect in completely different time zones across the globe.
It's pretty awesome.
Yeah.
For sure, it blows my mind sometimes.
Talking about mind-blowing topics.
I am really excited Jerry to be able to pick your Noggin.
You know, your big Noggins is like part of your friend, which I love, but really pick your brain on how you're observing the trends that are taking place in the economy, you know, feds recently, increase interest rates and all that kind of stuff.
Elon Musk, Twitter getting layoffs, layoffs, left, and right and Tech.
We're going to talk about those things.
But before we jump into some of those topics would love to learn a little bit more about just you and your background as a serial founding entrepreneur.
So can you like let us rewind, I think it's way back.
Like, like back the sure Blackstreet how far?
How far back do you want me to go?
When did you where were you born?
And then when did you migrate to the states?
Yes, I was born in fishing Village in China called Ningbo.
And when I say Village, it's a city of about 5 million people, right?
But that's basically what a village in China is these days.
So I was born there in the 80s and then I moved to the United States when I was 5 years old from there, I lived in Columbus, Ohio.
And then, I guess the first formative event in my life as it relates to, my career happened in the late 90s.
When my dad actually got a job in Silicon Valley, as part of the first.com, boom, and subsequent bust.
So, that's when I started to get interested in technology went to school in California.
In the Bay Area, went to college at Cal, graduated had my first job at Lockheed Martin, which is a defense contractor.
And that's where I also met Roberto.
My current co-founder here at welcome.
And I think ever since I was young Was interested in entrepreneurship.
I was interested in technology, and so I always wanted to start a company.
I always wanted to be at the Forefront of innovation and I made the leap.
When I saw Steve Jobs unveiled the iPhone for the first time I was like, wow this is a pretty revolutionary piece of technology.
I was actually very amazed when he first unveiled in 2008, and my first company was an app company.
I made a fantasy Sports.
App for mobile phones later, I sold that to Yahoo and that's where Roberto and I work for a little while, so stay there for a couple of years and then Roberto and I decided to work together after that, as well.
He what?
That's where he met, you, I believe in Colorado, and I moved to Colorado at that point.
And we started welcome about two years ago so that's brings us too today.
Wow.
And, you know, you just mentioned a See at, but that's actually like the fantasy football app that was sold to Yahoo right.
Huge.
That's right, there's fantasy football, but I also supported a bunch of other sports as well.
Like my personal favorite sport is basketball.
So I didn't play too much football played a lot of fantasy basketball though.
Very cool.
Wow.
What a journey.
So, here you are today with welcome, you're one of three founders.
So it's you.
Roberto and tiger.
Who's your brother?
In fact, you have two other brothers and all of you are in Tech as well, right?
Yeah, I guess, you know, you know what they say the Apple doesn't fall far?
Fall far from the tree.
My dad was in technology and all three of his sons are also in technology.
So maybe there's something to that, that's pretty awesome.
Wow, cool.
Okay so then now fast-forward to where we're at today and you know you're seeing how things are trending across the economy, across the globe From, as mentioned earlier, the feds raising interest rates to hopefully decrease the inflation that's taking place.
But I would love to hear your perspective and thoughts of what you see from Jerry's lens with how the feds increase is going to effect?
You know, it's affecting all the economy and even affecting what we're seeing taking place across attack.
Yeah, you know it's interesting.
I started my first company after the last crash the last time.
The economy crashed was in 2008 and I started a company and 2009, right?
So, you know, I don't claim to be an economics expert at all but just for my own life experience, the Federal Reserve and the greater economy has a much larger impact on companies.
He success than we like to thank, right?
We often sort of get this idea in our heads and it's propagated by the media where if you just have a great idea and you execute well you're going to become rich, you know, your company is going to do well but really if you look throughout history, especially in technology and technology is not really that young being at the right place at the right time and understanding how the economy works and understanding how money works.
You know, really has a big impact I think on this.
Success of companies.
So yeah, you mentioned the federal the FED rates raising interest rates.
Now, we could go in a couple of directions here, right?
We could talk about, you know what that even means.
Let us start with that.
What?
Interest rates.
Let us start there.
Yeah, yeah.
So Now, what do we started?
I think it's one of those things where, if you think about what money is at the end of the day, You come to the conclusion that money isn't really real, right?
A lot of this things like oh it's, you know, I want to make money, there're tons of money out there if somebody has money and I don't have money like, how do I get money, but what exactly is money, right?
Like its kind of interesting question to think about and that's where the FED comes in, right?
The FED while they can't print money that, that road belongs to the United States Treasury.
They can certainly influence the amount of Money that's out there in circulation.
Right?
So, the, the interest rate that set by the FED is the interest rate at which the Federal Reserve Bank lends out money to other Banks and that has a huge impact on the economy.
Because economic activity is composed of two things, is composed of the total amount of money that's in the market, but it's also composed of credit and there's a lot more credit out there than there is money.
Probably, by an order of magnitude, right?
So I mean I don't know the exact numbers but I think there's probably less say around three trillion dollars of just like cash like US dollars out there in the market and there's probably something on the order of 50 or 60 trillion dollars worth of credit out there on the market, right?
So for example, let us just think about your bank account, right?
You what do you use for your bank account to use like, Wells, Fargo or Bank of America?
Thanks.
Okay, okay so let us say you put ten dollars into Chase right now?
Chase can take that ten dollars, and then they can lend it out to other people.
And they have, what is called a reserve requirement.
Which means they only need to keep 10% of the amount on their balance sheet in cash at any one time.
So if you put ten dollars into Chase Bank, they actually have a hundred dollars that they can use to lend out to other businesses.
Right engine.
So the majority of our economy is actually composed of this credit that Banks can lend out.
And the Federal Reserve is what's considered the lender of Last Resort, which means the banks, where do they go to get money?
They actually go to the Federal Reserve.
So when the Federal Reserve sets low interest rates, that means Banks can borrow money very easily, which in turn means you as a consumer can borrow money very easily.
So, let us say you want to buy a house, right?
You can get a low mortgage so you can afford that dream house and Oahu that you always wanted, right?
And the economy booms.
But then when the Federal Reserve raises interest rates, then, you know, it's more expensive for banks to get money.
So it's more expensive for them to lend money to you.
So then economic activity tends to grind to a halt or slow down when the FED raises interest rates, which is what's happening today in the market.
Gotcha.
Okay, so let us even rewind, a few steps back.
Why are the feds even raising interest rates?
And I know I have heard about yeah like there's inflation taking place it's supposed to help decrease inflation.
But how do we even get to this point?
Yeah, very good question.
So interest rates have been very, very low for a long time.
In fact, from 2008, all the way, till the beginning of covid, interest rates were close to zero.
And that's because of the previous financial crisis.
So, back in 2008, the entire global economy basically melted down.
And so, in order to stimulate the economy, because remember, when the FED lowers interest rates is stimulates economic activity because there's more A borrowing, there's more lending.
There's more credit available for businesses and individuals.
And so from 2008 to 2020, it was good times, right?
Home prices went up, stocks went up, technology went up, because people were making more money.
They wanted to invest that money and often that money went into technology companies and even riskier assets, like, like crypto which we can talk about, right?
And so covid-19, David hit, Really, the Federal Reserve went into overdrive, and they lowered rates all the way to zero the United States Treasury printed a lot of money.
In fact, I think the statistic is around forty percent of all US dollars, that have ever existed in history were printed during 2020 and 2021.
Wow.
Right.
So what happens when you print a lot of money?
Well, the money that's in your wallet becomes worth less because now there're more dollars out there and that's what triggers inflation?
So, to answer your question, simply the FED has to raise interest rates because inflation is going crazy.
I think the latest official numbers are nine to ten percent, but a lot of people think, due to the way that inflation is measured.
It's actually a lot higher than that.
So, the FED really has no choice.
But to raise interest rates to combat inflation, got it.
What's what are?
You know, economists saying about how long interest rates will be kept this high?
Nobody really knows, right?
So I have some friends on Wall Street, I have some friends that are in finance, they seem to think it will be about two years, but it's kind of like reading tea leaves right?
The Federal Reserve is not very up front about exactly what they're going to do it.
And often times they don't know right?
They make moves the market reacts you know there's the Federal Reserve Has two main jobs, right?
One is to control inflation and the other is to control unemployment.
So those are the two things that they look at when inflation is too high.
They have to raise rates but if rates are too high again that slows down the economy which creates unemployment, right?
So there are always trying to balance these two things and it's not easy.
I mean If you look at governments in the past, even, you know, before the United States, right?
You had the British Empire, you had the dungeon power, all these different Empires.
A lot of them went broke because they couldn't figure out the right balance.
Right?
Says wow, not easy to figure out and you know, I really don't know how long it's going to last but it is one of those things where covid-19 as unprecedented economic event, I mean the entire economy basically shut out.
Across the globe.
So, real economic activity was very low but at the same time because You know, the US Treasury was spending, so much money stocks were going through the roof, right?
Crypto is going through the roof.
Real estate was going through the roof.
So you kind of have this weird dynamic where, I mean, everybody knew the economy was down, but at the same time, all the traditional economic indicators were, right?
So yeah, it just created this, this is where weird scenario that the FED has to try to fix them.
So now understanding a little bit of the last couple of years and the macro of what's taking place with the feds interest rates, how does that affect all other parts of our Lives?
I mean, if you think about like we're in Tech so, you know, address that but what else are you seeing?
Across the globe across other Industries and you know you anything that you see trend-wise like how is the ripple effect of this Affecting all other parts of ultimately, you know, economy in our lives.
Yeah.
So it's interesting.
What effect is that the u.s?
Dollar is going crazy right now, right?
So I am here in Colombia and the Colombian peso to dollar exchange rate recently broke five thousand to one which means it's 5,000 pesos for every US dollar.
That's a historic Height.
Been Never, it's never been this High and the same is happening with currencies all over the world, right?
And the reason is, because as the FED raises interest rates, that means that things like treasury bills, all of a sudden become better Investments.
So everybody is buying us treasury bills and things like that are denominated in u.s.
Dollars.
So the strength of the US currency is actually shooting through the roof, which is not that great for other economies around the world, right?
Because every economy did the same thing during covid, they all printed money, But the United States because we have the world Reserve currency, which means that everybody wants to hold US dollars, right?
Even though we printed money, we can, I mean, we can get away with it more than other countries.
So I mean, I am here in Columbia and everybody is worried about the exchange rate, because the services has become way more expensive in Colombia, especially things that are imported from the United States because they're denominated in dollars.
But everybody here is Hayden pesos right?
Wow.
So it's really having a drastic effect in people's livelihoods outside of the United States.
So that's one thing I have noticed this but being outside the United States currently and you talk about technology how it impacts technology is.
If you look at where all the Investments went over, the last decade and a half and especially over the last two years when you know, forty percent of the dollars were being printed.
A lot of that went to riskier Investments like technology stocks, like cryptocurrency and all of this came from all this money printing, right?
So, essentially in Tech, Money's been sort of free because the government prints, all this money, and most of that capital.
Ends up going into the hands of Technology startups, technology companies and cryptocurrency.
And now all of a sudden that's gone, right?
So it's very challenging environment for technology companies in particular because in a lot of ways, the last 15 years of tech has been a giant bubble and now that bubble is popping.
So describe the bubble.
What do you mean by that?
So, remember when I said I first moved to California, because my dad got a job during the first.com.
Boom.
So that was another example of a tech bubble, right?
There was actually the first tech bubble that we had.
And so what happened was everybody was putting their money into Tech, right?
And then, so there was this, a lot of money sloshing around in the tech ecosystem.
So one example I can give you is Yahoo which was the big internet giant back in those days.
As they sold at who bought those ads.
Well, they were startups that were funded by Venture capitalists right?
Those Stars didn't really make any money but the only way to get new users was to go to Yahoo and buy ads.
So then Yahoo's business went up, but and the entire Tech ecosystem was booming, but it wasn't really based on anything real, right?
It was just a bunch of money being funneled into the ecosystem to drive that Innovation.
But ultimately these companies weren't really making that much.
Real money, right?
It was just this all circulating around the same ecosystem, and so I think in a similar way that's sort of happened in the last 15 years as well during their most recent Tech.
Boom, and Tech bubble.
Although obviously there's a lot more people on the internet.
Now they're certainly more money to be made on the internet now.
But are these companies are these startups really that valuable?
And from what we have seen, the answer is no right.
Like Once, you turn off the spigot of free money from the Federal Reserve, you see companies lose 80% of their valuation, sometimes, 90% of their valuation, right?
And so that the markets really correcting itself right now and it's happening in the riskiest assets first, right?
So, so crypto corrected itself first and then, you know, private tech companies.
And now you're seeing the same thing with public tech companies, there's a big correction there that's happening to the value.
Ation because people were trying to figure out.
All right.
How much are these companies actually worth?
What's does it ever actually have any clothes, right?
Or is it just funny money that, that they're playing with here?
How and this might be a whole nother conversation, but how are those valuations even determined?
That's a really good question.
So there's their standard measurements, right?
You can take your revenue and assign it a certain multiple.
There's you can take profits and assign a certain multiple although revenues a little bit more.
Common because most tech companies are not profitable.
Right?
At least in the beginning.
So you can say, you know, say your company makes a million dollars a year and you want to sign a 10x multiples of that.
Then, the valuation is, is 10 million dollars.
Right?
But you also have to remember that, it's a free market.
So the ultimate answer is the valuation is whatever investors are willing to pay for it.
So if there's a lot of money available for investors to pay for Tech startups and there's a limited amount of tech startups which is always the case.
There's always more money looking to find a home.
Then there are good hopes, right?
Interesting.
So it's going to artificially inflate, the value of text are because at the end of the day, your valuation is whatever.
Somebody is willing to pay for it.
So, so you're saying that, there's, I want to pull that through that statement, you just made, there's more money out there to invest to land somewhere, but there's not enough maybe startups.
Fill tool and the money in?
Is that what?
I heard?
Absolutely.
For the same reasons that we talked about, right?
It's really easy to make money in a sense, right?
Federal Reserve can just print money out of thin air or more specifically, the US Treasury could just print money out of thin air.
And because the best investments are typically technology because technology is what drives human productivity forward.
Most of that money goes into technology but the scarce resources always innovation Right.
People that can truly innovate companies that can truly innovate are actually quite rare.
So what tends to happen is you have the big Winners or the people that, you know, like Facebook or Google or Tesla, right?
They receive a Lion's Share of that investment because it proven that they can edit innovate and then startups receive a big share of that investment as well, right?
But not every startup is It is going to succeed.
And so, what ends up happening, is the valuation of a lot of startups gets over inflated as well during those times.
Gotcha.
So, you know if you just look at this last year, I have heard there's been over 42,000 layoffs to date and probably more counting what's your take.
I mean, I obviously you have shared all the reasons why we have gotten to this place but Are we going to continue to see more layoffs across tech companies?
And is it going to stop or is this just a norm and what's going to happen with all those employees?
Now who don't have jobs in Tech?
Is this where employees in Tech?
If they want to stay in Tech, need to start their own startup.
Or, you know, how do you stay in Tech and continue to survive?
Yeah, I mean that number honestly, sounds low 42,000.
I don't know the exact number of layoffs, often, you know, those numbers are not made public, right?
Certainly, if you're a large public company, you have to, you have to file those things.
But if you're a small start-up, you might not necessarily in might not even necessarily be on everybody's radar.
Yeah, I don't lie.
Don't know, I don't know.
If there will be more layoffs, I think it really depends on each company's individual situation.
And by the way, not every company is, is doing that poorly right there.
There are certainly technology companies that have very resilient business models, or for some reason, not as impacted by the economy, the current state of the economy or as impacted as other companies.
So there's certainly companies hiring I You know, we're part of the Kleiner Perkins portfolio and whenever one company in our portfolio has layoffs often those profiles are circulated to other portfolio companies that are hiring, right?
So I don't want to pay this picture that it's like, just doing Gloom across the board.
There, there are, certainly companies that are hiring.
There are jobs to be had.
Yeah, it's, it's tougher out there, right?
And, you know, salaries that have gone up.
Over the past few years really for every role.
And I think a natural thing that's going to happen is jobs might be available but I think salaries are going to have to correct as well, right?
Because if companies are making less profit they have you know they want to get to profitability really.
The only lever you have aside from layoffs is your compensation And, so I think we will start to see correction in compensation at tech companies.
Honestly, it's, it's been pretty crazy.
Like how, how many salaries and compensation has gone up over the last few years, right compared to before.
And now that companies don't have the prophet and the valuation to be able to pay for the salaries.
I think you're going to start to see those those celery start to come down.
That's interesting.
What are your thoughts on?
So I want to pull the thread of what you mentioned earlier of like there are certain tech companies that are resilient and thriving.
What type of companies are those?
So that's one question and then the other question I had been for those who want to stay in Tech, maybe they were affected by a layoff.
What should they be doing?
You know, so there're two questions there, but we can answer the first ones first.
One is the companies that are resilient.
What do they look like?
Why are they able to do?
Well during a time like this, Yeah, I think there's a few interesting data points here.
The effects in the economy are not really spread out that evenly, right?
So for example if you look at Airbnb is actually doing quite well because even though you know overall people's paychecks might be getting Slimmer one area where people are still spending money is travel, maybe that's intuitive.
Maybe that's not right, but people are still spending a lot on travel.
So travel companies are still doing quite well.
Like Airbnb, I think one area where Companies are really struggling as if your company is advertising dependent because one of the first things that gets cut, if a company seeking that become more profitable is advertising spend, right?
So that's why you see layoffs at maida, you see reports that you know, at Google and other companies that depend solely on Advertising as their business model, at least in the short term, right?
Like those companies are really going to struggle.
And you know, one other thing is, you know, SAS sped, right SAS spent at least from what we have seen has been pretty strong even in this economy and I think that's because at the end of the day, you know, SAS is just such a big part of how companies run today that it's tough to completely rip out some of these systems, right?
And so companies like Salesforce for example, or companies that have a really strong lock in for as a SAS platform.
Two other companies.
They're doing, I mean not great, right?
But they're, it's all relative.
They're doing better than some of these other companies.
Gotcha, an AI.
That's another boom.
That I am seeing Jasper AI, for example, their content generation company.
They just got 125 million series a like a 1.5 billion valuation or something crazy like that.
So we're seeing the AI technology really, boom?
What are your thoughts to that?
Yeah.
I mean it certainly seems to be you know the new hotness, right?
Like I think every year you sort of had this new technology or there's new promise that a lot of investors flock to and that currently seems to be AI A lot of these companies, I mean, I don't know how they're doing financially, right?
But they're receiving a lot of investment because There's been, there's been a few advancements that have been pretty revolutionary recently, and they're all around this idea of generative AI.
So what exactly does that mean, right?
So one example of AI is you say, for example, Google Search, right?
Google uses a lot of AI.
So you search for something in Google, can kind of point you into the right direction or Facebook.
Is another example, right?
I mean, it's kind of creepy, but they sort of know what you look like.
And so it will suggest you images, where you're in the picture, maybe you didn't know, and you can tag yourself, things like that.
So, that's really where a, I was at for.
I would say the last decade was, it was just really good at finding these patterns and a lot of data and more recently, there's been advancements in what they called generative AI, which is using AI to actually produce unique things.
Whether it's a blog post, right?
Or whether it's an image or You know, meta and Google recently, it has show that it's possible to use AI to even produce videos, right?
And if you look at, if you actually play around with these tools, you will realize, I mean it's got a lot of bugs, right?
It doesn't often produce exactly what you want, but the rate of innovation is increasing in these areas and venture capitalist want to pour money into an area, where a lot of smart people are working on it, and the rate of innovation is high.
Nobody knows if there's actually a good business case for a lot of these Technologies.
But right now it's, you know, sort of the, the hot, the hot technology at the moment.
So interesting.
Okay, I wanted to go back and answer the question that I had earlier which is around those affected by the tech layoffs right now.
And, you know, for those that want to remain in Tech, how do they need to innovate?
Like, do they need to be learning more about Ai and, you know, studying some of the trends of the most Innovative Tech that's out there and jump.
On board with those type of companies, or what do you advise, for those who have been affected?
By layoff.
Yeah, so I mean that's a tough question to answer because I think it depends on the individual, right?
What they're interested in what their skill set is how they want to apply that to the technology space.
For me, when I thought about at least when I was an employee, right?
One of the things I thought about was how do I, how do I put myself in a position to succeed in the long term?
Right.
And so, when the iPhone first came out, for example, I knew that technology wave like, I didn't know how big mobile would be.
But I was like, you know what if I put my bet in this mobile wave, I want to learn everything that I can about it because I just see a lot more growth opportunities there than I do in defense for example, right?
Like but defense, is it just wasn't innovating at the same rate and so, I think you know, layoffs are always tough right?
But I think sort of aligning yourself and hitching Your Wagon to technologies that you feel like have a lot of promise that a lot of investors are putting Capital into I think is always a good idea.
Again nobody knows how long this recession will be but there's still companies hiring right there are still companies hiring.
Even during this time, it's again, it's sort of uneven wear which companies are most impacted.
So what are as an entrepreneur as a Founder?
What are the qualities that you think employees people need to have in a bear market like now you know in order to be resilient and to be successful?
That's best.
However, they Define.
That I know there's some just mindset attributes that can help folks.
As they are waking up every morning and whether it's working on their resume and getting things out, or tackling a product that they're trying to drive pipeline for, you know, Across the board.
People are feeling the recession and the effects of the uncertainty it creates.
So what do you advise for how we show up?
What's the mindset we carry?
What do you do?
Yeah, I mean stay resilient.
This is one of those things where if you think about the economy, right?
It's very psychological.
When people's, I am sure you have noticed this, right?
Like when everybody thinks the economy is doing bad, the economy is of doing that.
Because at the other day, the economy's is composed of people, right?
And yes, of course, the Federal Reserve and all these macroeconomic factors played a part in to it.
But I think our Collective psychology, also plays a big part in to it as well.
That's why certain companies do better than others, right?
Because their Collective psychology is, is more positive.
They're like, well, yeah, you know, I am just going to control what I can control these other macroeconomic factors.
I can't really control, but I mean, it sounds sort of tried to say, but keeping a positive mindset actually does help because then you start to think about ways, we're okay.
Well, you know I can't really Troll these things.
So I am not going to worry about those.
But this is one thing I can't control, right?
So for me right now, one of the things that I can't control is our own product and our own company, right?
Like how do we innovate in this time?
What are some opportunities that are emerging now that didn't really emerge before, right?
Like you look at a lot of our competitors, and they're struggling to write.
So in a way it's harder to catch competitors.
When the economy's doing good, Because they receive more funding and more funding leads to be able to hire more people and there's this positive Loop but when the economy isn't doing so great, right?
The if you're a larger, you actually have more of a disadvantage, because it's harder for you to Pivot, that's hardest for you to adapt.
And I think the same is sort of true of individuals, as well, right?
Like you have 100% control over what you can control and being able.
Able to Pivot and adapt quicker is always going to be an advantage versus, you know, feeling helpless, which we all I think tend to feel helpless during these times.
But I do think the ones that can keep a more positive mindset and think about what they can control, both companies and individuals are going to end up being more successful and coming out the other side of the recession in a better spot.
That's great.
Love that.
All right, I am going to ask a completely different question.
We're going to move into cryptocurrency, you're touching it a little bit.
Walk me through just a little bit of your experience in crypto and, you know, as an investor.
Like all those things yourself like, give us a little bit of a history lesson of crypto and how we have gotten to where we're at today and like help.
Help Define that landscape if you will?
Yeah, so I am not super involved in crypto.
I played around with Bitcoin and a few others, but I am not the most knowledgeable person about crypto.
There's certainly other people at welcome that have a lot more knowledge and experience than I do.
But the way I look at crypto is its the first real fundamental innovation in money itself, right?
So if you think about what money actually is throughout human history since the invention of money, Any money has required basically like a centralized authority to say.
This piece of gold is valuable or you know, this dollar bill is valuable, right?
If you think about it, if I give you a dollar like how do you know that dollars any good?
It's because the government of the United States says it's valuable, right?
So throughout human history, it's been government's typically that have had control over money and crypto starting with Bitcoin and the fundamental Innovation by Satoshi Nakamoto that the you know, pseudonymous Creator Vic.
Coin was that now we can use math and I won't go into the specifics about that math.
But essentially we can use math and place of governments to create a currency that people can use and Trust, right?
So this is, I mean, to me, I think this is probably one of the most breakthrough ideas and breakthrough, Innovations in all of human history.
I think, I think it's bigger than the internet.
I think bigger than computers.
I think it's bigger than cars.
It could fundamentally change human civilization.
So that's why a lot of people are excited about it.
That's why there's been so much investment into it.
It's been, I think it's been about 14 or 15 years.
I can't remember the date.
Exactly.
But it's been about 14 or 15 years since the invention of Bitcoin since then, there's been applications of the same decentralized technology into other areas, right?
So instead of just Money.
That's that centralized people are working on ways to decentralize the entire Financial system decentralize laws decentralize.
You know, a lot of people make fun of MIT and if T is right, but even decentralize art and collectibles and things like that.
So there's a lot of really smart people working in crypto, but it's also a very risky investment asset.
So just as it went up.
Really sharply during the last couple of years.
It's plummeted quite a bit now, as well.
Hmm.
And you know you were talking about earlier just something very interesting that's happened, even today about the purchasing of the ft x.
And you mentioned, you know, even today in history there's some pretty unique things taking place in crypto Yeah, I mean cryptos kind of like the Wild West, right?
Like if you remember, all the western movies, The Wild West is an untamed place.
It's a place of, there's a lot of lawlessness, there's a lot of scams, there's a lot of shady characters, and I would characterize a Cristo space, the same way, right?
It's a, it's not for the faint of heart.
I will say that I live in Puerto Rico and there's a lot of crypto folks in Puerto Rico, some people are generally trying to advance Humanity.
Some people are trying to You off and the governments around the world, have really been slow to react in terms of like, how do we regulate this thing, right?
How do we regulate something that's fundamentally decentralised and is designed to take government out of the equation.
Very difficult problem to solve, right?
And, so I think the, the same reason why a lot of people are attracted to crypto, is also what makes it makes Dangerous.
And also what makes, you know, what makes it risky for a lot of people as well.
So, the event that you mentioned today.
I mean, I have to jump in about a minute, so I can't get into a whole lot of details, but essentially, the number one, crypto, Exchange Finance.
Excuse me, in the period of about bless you in the period of about two or three days, triggered a series of events which led to Their number two, competitor, FTX essentially needing a bailout and a now, they're working out a deal.
Where the basically, the number one, crypto exchange is buying the number to crypto exchange.
And people are still trying to sort out what happened but there's not a lot of regulation in the space, right?
It's sort of shoot first, ask questions later type of environment and it's pretty crazy.
It's straight out of a Hollywood movie I think and maybe in a later episode we can get into the details but it really highlights, you know what makes crypto so interesting but also makes it an extremely risky proposition as well.
So fascinating, the Wild West indeed.
All right, Jerry will thank you so much for your time.
I look forward to our next conversation.
Yeah, thank you, Gina.
All right, I am stopping their Gordy.