Still, enough time to figure out how to chase away.
Who loves me?
Hello.
Hello or I should say aloha as I am tuning in here from Honolulu Hawaii, and it's so great to see you.
This is our first event actually of the Year and a happy New Year were Midway into the first month of a fantastic year.
I have a lot of hopes for this year.
It's going to be great.
And today's topic is on webinars, at every step of the buying cycle, I am really excited.
Cited to introduce and I would love to bring up to the stage actually Megan Sullivan.
She is the demand gen lead at tulip interfaces.
Meghan, feel free to jump on up here.
Hey, how's it going?
Thank you for letting me talk today.
I am really excited to talk about my experience here at tulip and you know, past experiences focusing on how to engage folks using Ours.
Yes, I mean this is, this is.
But before we jump in to, to the topic, how are you doing?
Where are you tuning in from?
And how are you thinking about 20-23?
How are you doing?
Well, based in Boston, Massachusetts, which is nice company HQ as well.
So it's a little chilly kicking off this year, but hitting the ground running.
I already have a lot of the webinar calendar planned, which is great to see and have a great team behind me to support in that promotion and production.
That's awesome.
All right.
Well, we can jump right into.
So, what I hear is that 70% of your pipeline, that's generated.
That's marketing generated right now of that webinars.
Is a huge influence of your pipeline?
What percentage would you say or?
I don't know if you can quantify that.
Yeah, I would say right now with first touch.
So we identify a lot of our marketing Performance Based on that first touch.
I would say it's about, you know, 15 to 20 percent of that overall, 70%, give or take on the seasonality, right?
We all see that there's A lot of (webinar) for Teague in various parts of the Year, especially the summertime is a lot of (webinar) fatigue, but we're starting to see that ramp up a little bit more, but there's a lot of influence with webinars and our existing database continues to attend multiple webinars.
Which is why it's really important for us to think about our topics that are timely and at what buying stage, that they're apart of, and I have been in the marketing field for over seven years now, working in marketing agency, working at a consulting firm and something, always ties back to those Live Events, but if you're smart about it, and I think we're seeing that Lay out here at tulip a lot as I kind of ramped up our webinar program and made it a sustainable program that creates you know, high quality content for our sales reps.
But also thinking about our personas right?
We want to make sure that they're attending an event that's going to create insights or leave insights with them to be able to use those insights tomorrow and their day-to-day I love that, and I am excited because in our conversation today, we're going to unpack a little bit more of everything that you just touched.
But before we jump into that we do have a quick poll.
So let us pull that up real fast and just get a feel for how many of you actually two different Bolt.
The other one Sal.
So we have got our amazing producer.
Hey Sal.
He's a dark green room.
If you can pull the other one, there we go.
All right.
Do you use webinars as a key channel?
In your marketing mix today?
So feel free to drop your votes in there and give us a sense of how many of you are using this channel to actually drive your pipeline.
Wow, okay.
All the time.
Got a couple of votes and let us see if there's any other ones.
But okay cool.
Well, we have got folks that are very familiar with Averaging webinars.
I actually don't see a ton of folks who have, you know, maybe leveraged it as frequently, as, as you have Megan, or even as we have here.
So, okay, here and there, we have got another boat that cave in.
So okay, great.
Well, that gives us a pulse and understanding of, you know, we got a lot of folks here that are pretty Savvy.
Probably with the power of what webinars can drive.
Before we jump into our conversation on that though.
Meghan, I would love to hear about your story and how you got into B2B marketing, can you take us back into your memory lane?
Yeah, yeah, absolutely.
So actually got dual degree in public relations and marketing and, you know, I kind of jumped right into the agency.
Working at a full funnel demand, generation agency, based in Burlington Vermont, HubSpot agencies.
So I grew to, you know, own client base of, you know, around 13 clients at a time.
And we focus on any kind of demand generation strategy from the top of the funnel, all the way to, you know, sales enablement.
At the bottom of the funnel, even the systems integration in between you know Revenue operations ensuring that there's marketing and sales alignment from a systems perspective.
But also from a, you know, go to market and campaign strategy perspective and took some time as well working at IT consulting firm as a, you know, marketing lead identifying Membership program for certain members in the organization at that consulting firm, but then really love the agency life.
So I kind of went back to the agency locally, managed accounts again for a little bit, with a little bit of time and it's, I loved it.
I think especially as a marketing professional, if you can dip your toes into agency, See life, you learn so much and that was going to be, you know what of, what of my advice notes is, you know, the B2B marketing Community is so close-knit and the connections, are you gain or pretty much career long?
And I did see that at the agency that I worked with, you know, with my clients, with my peers, I am Facebook friends with the, a few of them.
So it's, it's been a really great experience so far.
Um, and then, you know, I decided to take, I wanted to just have one client of my own and that's where I found an opportunity at tulip interfaces where I was the first demand generation manager and then grew to, you know, lead a team of demand gen folks and one of our core tactics and our overall integrated campaign strategies webinars there webinars, and we went from running around for webinars a year to I believe we ended the year at 20 webinars, all from large-scale webinars to you know smaller scale more intimate settings.
Wow.
Okay.
Well, first thanks for walking us through your, your path, your journey that's noted on the agency advice tip that you're putting out there, I actually come from an agency background as well, but more so B to C.
So it looks like an inch at she mentioned that she also came from a HubSpot agency.
So there's a ton that you can learn in agency life so that's great to hear.
So jumping into what your career you that the number you just mentioned, you said, you know, you started with doing for webinars at tulip and then last year you ended at doing 20, what was it?
21 webinar.
Yeah, I think we ended officially at 20, a big increase in webinar production.
And it was kind of testing period, right?
We saw some success and 2021 with just a few webinars and wanted to ramp it up and see, you know what?
Topics are resonating and relevant with our Target.
Personas, we do what our Target.
Personas want to learn more about, and what are their kind of watering holes?
And our, our platform is targeted for manufacturers Global manufacturers, whether its life sciences General Manufacturing.
Almost any company that, you know, manufacturers, our product will benefit from our platform and that industry is kind of Delayed in terms of they're progressing and you know where they look for Content.
So some of it is still in person events and trade shows and, you know, now we're seeing that increase in and attending online events, mainly webinars.
Gotcha.
So give us a little snapshot of who your ICP is.
And you know what?
What are their interests in your webinars?
Yeah.
Absolutely.
So like I mentioned were global company.
So we our customer database as you know, ranging from, you know, manufacturers based in the United Kingdom to India United States.
And we generally look for larger manufacturers that have multiple manufacturing plants so it is something to consider when we're targeting.
Certain people on LinkedIn is we do you know consider their company size and then you know the who is really important for us.
So we're targeting, and we usually have successful sales conversations with those operations leaders.
So manufacturing operations director that manages a few manufacturing sites that's experiencing certain pains like production efficiency.
You know they're not creating enough of a specific product in a certain period of time.
Time to be able to meet demands.
Additionally, you know, they might be experiencing some product defects and not know why or where in the entire assembly line that they're experiencing that's causing that effect.
So our Solutions help improve, you know, production efficiency you know decrease the number of defects and identify those root causes of you know issues.
And the assembly line.
So where we want to create content especially at the top of the funnel.
When people don't know much about tulip is, we want to focus on those pains and how people can solve those pains today.
So we might not get directly into, you know, tulip as a solution, but we identify blueprints with, you know, their current Manufacturing tech stack or their Current.
If they only use paper to you know track production, we provide insights that they can Implement tomorrow or start thinking about change management or start evaluating what their Manufacturing tech stack should look like.
You know, it's important to be really relevant.
I mean what you're seeing today is a lot of issues and supply chain.
There's a lot of issues in Workforce transformation, you know people are You know, back when you know covid-19 an all-time high, you know people were retiring older more, you know seasoned workers on the assembly line that had tribal knowledge about, you know, how to assemble certain products and rolls behind it.
They were retiring and a younger more digital first.
You know, Workforce is coming in.
You know, how do you navigate that in?
And today's era.
So you know, it's really important to really understand where our personas are coming from what their daily challenges are.
And, you know, for just about all of our webinars, we, you know, talk about tulip as a potential solution towards the end of the webinar, once they, you know, see the why, you know, we're relating to them, you know, we have a lot of people at tulip that work.
In the manufacturing industry, which is why they wanted to work for a solution like tulip.
And I think it's really important to understand the Persona and maintain that Persona driven architecture, through throughout any content.
You create not just webinars.
Persona driven architecture that sounds like a real II love that articulation of, you know, the Each and optimization of the buyers journey is kind of like, also, like, how I see it too but can you walk us through?
Even just the process of how you were able to architect that for your personas and really identify?
Okay, these are the type of webinars that we're going to do top of funnel middle of funnel, bottom of the funnel, and why could you just walk us through your process?
Yeah, yeah, definitely.
So I went in a little bit into that top A funnel.
So thinking about what trends are happening right now, what's going on in the news that's affecting, you know, an operations leader today and really discussing those Trends and ways that you can adjust your operations, today really gets the attention of our personas because we're not, we're not pushing our product, you know, we're really just talking about the Core issues happening today.
Well for those that you know about tulip and know that they need a solution like tulip or there's a gap right now, and they're Manufacturing tech stack where we like to focus our middle of the funnel pieces.
Of content are more tailored.
We call use cases.
So a big challenge with manufacturers today is efficient traceability.
So being All to identify the and Trace.
Everything from the raw materials to the form the suppliers, all the way through to those finish completed products.
People are having issues, you know, there are identifying those defects or there's a, you know, there's something missing that leaded that led to, you know, something being recalled, which is a huge, huge issue for big Brands because you show up on the FDA website for five years.
I think saying that, you know, you had a product that went out that was recalled and being able to efficiently Trace those Raw materials, the Assembly of products to, you know, ultimately you know, out to the wholesaler is really important for certain individuals and even those plant managers, so getting taking deeper dives into those specific use cases is has been, you know, really beneficial for us for people to know, you know, how we solve for those specific use cases, but also it gives it a more.
To its setting.
So we get a lot of Engagement in our, our chat throughout the webinars, and we especially for some of those topics, you know, it hits home for some folks.
So they talk a lot about in the chat and you sometimes know our subject matter experts to go off script which is something that, you know, I even encourage.
You know, I think it's everyone's human and it's nice to you know, have that You know, sometimes like emotional communication through chat, you know, similar to this platform, we have the Emojis.
So you see, if, you know, people get angry at a certain, you know, controversial topic within manufacturing.
You kind of see those emotions right there.
But, you know, that's what we want to encourage.
We want to correct encourage that discussion.
Mmm, I gotta ask.
What platform are you using today?
So where are you?
We're using live storm.
Okay, gotcha.
So that does encourage then the Emoji engagement, all that stuff.
Okay.
God I gotta know.
And then what do you find as far as the average number of registrants to attendees?
Does that vary from top of funnel middle of the final bottom of the funnel?
Yes I would say for registration number you know for those mo-more top of funnel webinars and you know Live Events we do see a higher registration count but with that, you know, we do see a lower attendance rate which is okay.
You know, I think it's important to you know edit it down a little bit and have a nice on-demand webinar for people to access.
You know, I Can, you know, I even register for a lot of webinars and I either forget or, you know, a tense and watch kind of while I am well, I am working or watch On Demand or catch myself, you know, watching halfway through or, you know, everyone's super busy.
So, sometimes I have to hop off early because I have meetings, but usually we see for those top funnel webinars around a thirty percent attendance rate.
Were you know, continuing to engage those registrants to get them to attend the live event?
But we're also really tracking heavily those watches after.
So those that are watching on demand, and we even have that as our its own source when reporting.
Because a lot of people watch webinars On Demand, they're just, they just rather watch videos and maybe ask questions later.
So, and then for the middle of the funnel webinars, we do see like A lower registration rate because it's a little bit more tailored and more Niche, but a higher attendance rate, so closer to, you know, 50% attendance rate, and a lot of chats, a lot of chats during the so encouraging, that continued discussion even through the chat, especially for those middle of the funnel webinars.
Gotcha.
And then do you have any bottom of funnel webinars?
Like I guess I will be more like demos Riot.
So we actually we just towards the end of this calendar year.
We had a it was actually a just a live event on YouTube, so we encourage registrations just to get those so you can get those reminders, right?
But it was actually an open event and it was called the Tulip showcase and it featured a lot of our product releases.
And then towards the end of the day of the event, we featured a few customers and what we call the groundbreaker award.
So, those true champions of our platform where nominated by either customer success managers or their own peers within a customer company, and we presented Awards to them so, that's awesome.
Yeah, it's um, Thing that we do it you know the first time we tested it and I think as we continue to evolve our webinar program and you know live event program it's we test you know what might work and this is something that was really successful.
So hoping to do that, you know.
Probably two times a year because a lot goes into, you know, recording those demos.
And, you know, hearing from those customers dominating those customers, but it's good to really great to see that success.
I love that.
That's great to hear.
And in fact could you walk us through just the event types that you have from top of funnel middle and then bottom?
Because that's a great example.
Of what somebody could do for a bottom of the funnel type of event.
And I know you have mentioned at the top of funnel, it's more awareness Trends, things like that.
But even with your industry, could you just give us some like topical Hands-On examples, what types of events you do, and we can start with top of funnel and then work on, yeah, yeah for sure.
So some of the examples of our top of funnel webinars, So the beginning of last year we kicked off the year with kind of you know con little bit of edginess in the title in our in the manufacturing industry there are larger systems compared to, you know, start up, you know, platform like tulip.
There's these manufacturing execution systems that have been around for so many years, and we, you know, challenged Relevancy of those types of systems and it generated a lot of interest.
So talking about the challenges today of people that have a legacy or traditional manufacturing execution system and, you know, predictions for this, you know, for 2022 because we did in the beginning of last year.
So that was one of our big top of funnel webinars and to kind of Pull It fulls circle where we're actually in a couple weeks.
We are running a related top of funnel webinar.
That's, you know, still kind of challenging manufacturing execution systems today.
Revisiting those predictions that we made last year we write.
And, you know, noting some of the either the continued trends that we're seeing as well as, you know, new trends for manufacturers to Consider when you know, optimizing their operation strategy.
So those are two top of funnel vents that, you know, one is happening in a couple weeks that we're really excited about and another type of funnel event.
It's, you know, more geared to those that are you know evaluating either their current Tech stack or you know really He will experience those pains and potentially identifying budget for, you know, a solution that might fit their needs.
So it was almost kind of buyer's guide, you know, key considerations, when evaluating your Manufacturing tech stack or a manufacturing execution system.
So, and I think for some of those type of funnel events where it's like it's focused around evaluating a system, the time Is super important.
So either, you know, towards the beginning of the year, when maybe budget has been approved, baby budget has been cut.
So you have to really think smarter not harder with your budget.
So it's something also to consider when identifying topics and your webinar calendar is.
What's timely right now?
What are your target personas considering right now?
It's top of mind and that's why we usually do.
Everyone does kind of Trends, peace.
But a little spin on.
You know what?
What's in your Tech stack right now and should you be re-evaluating it?
That's good.
So, that's top of funnel.
That's a funnel.
Yep, middle.
What kind of event types, you have?
Yeah.
Yeah, absolutely.
So we did have the, the traceability webinar.
So that was how to make traceability your competitive Advantage.
Not your burden.
You know, people especially with compliance audits people just consider our manufacturers.
Sometimes, you know, they think about traceability as just a compliance check box when in reality, It can be a competitive Advantage.
It can base on what your tracking, you can automate it and it can be.
It can provide you insights and how you plan ahead not look back.
So that proactive and almost like predictive insights that you can gather from, you know what you're tracking and tracing on the manufacturing floor.
Or is its kind of we, what we wanted to do is really have a spin on, you know.
This doesn't have to be something that pains you every day, you know, it's actually something that can help you be more proactive and scale your manufacturing operations.
Yeah, so that's one example.
We also have been, we're actually planning an event with some of our integration partners and focused on.
So that's going to be more, you know, middle of the funnel.
So, you know, we integrate with AWS Microsoft, which is something that like manufacturers really use and their Stack.
So doing more silver round table with some of our integration Partners like Microsoft like AWS.
That's something that we are planning and really excited about to.
So not only thinking about we what we did in the past but new ways to lead a conversation.
That's awesome.
Okay.
And then the bottom of the funnel event ideas that you mentioned were like the award nomination ceremonies are there any other ideas for bottom of the funnel events?
Yeah, so we are kind of going along with the use case Niche topics.
We do want to, you know, do more live, demo experiences.
It's not something that we have tested yet.
Yet, you know, a live demo, where someone can, you know, it's in a webinar platform.
We usually, you know, maintain our webinars as videos or when people are ready to have a conversation with us.
Because our tool our platform is, is a really large platform.
So, we want to tailor a trial or a demo to fit their exact needs.
That is something that we do want to test, and I really want to plan for that is based on one use case.
Here's how you can utilize tool.
Appears the different ways that you can create an application in the platform.
That's great.
Yeah, all right.
Well, we have got a question here in Q&A.
You can pull that up do you find yourself using several different platforms for different kinds of events?
Getting Clips out after and getting data and results?
Yeah, so right now for webinars, we have actually, we used to use it for our virtual events that have multiple sessions, we would test out a platform and it wouldn't work out.
So we for our webinars, you know, we do like live.
ERM it, our marketing operations person on our team.
He built out and infrastructure to be able to, you know, it's not a direct integration.
But it does connect through zapier into Marketo, which is our marketing automation platform.
But I think with a lot of our systems that we have today, it does lead to exporting data and importing data.
And some spreadsheets which is you know something that we don't have to navigate daily.
So I do find myself and some different platforms and exporting.
Hoping to improve that soon but sometimes it's good to get into spreadsheets every now and then but yeah.
And then what about your on-demand content?
How are you guys handling On Demand right now?
Yeah so we have a multimedia producer that we sent our webinar you know files to, and he cleans it up slightly, and we have all of our on demand.
Webinars on our website so people can fill out a form and be able to access it.
We what we're starting to do now is Put our webinars into more bite-sized pieces of content as well as chapters so people can click right to you know a section that they wanted to focus on almost like when they're downloading an e-book.
You know the table of contents should have a shortcut that leaves you.
No right to that section especially if it's a big white paper.
So we want to make that experience the same as we do, you know, with our ebooks is being able to, you know, get to the, you know.
One just watch 10 minutes of you know when we talk about a specific customer case study, then they can do that.
That's awesome.
So this would be on the landing page of where you house the on-demand video.
You actually also have other offers you include.
Yes.
Yeah.
It's, and they're all single in that specific on demand video, you know, they can jump to the section that they want to listen to In Depth because you know, who has time today and I feel like everyone's attention span is, you know, just getting smaller and smaller.
So, so give them the tools to, you know, absorb content quickly and easily, so they can, you know, learn from it and get back to their day or hopefully continue to navigate through our content, but it's good.
So big question.
I have next is around promotions and driving registration and attendance to all of your events.
What are some of the key strategies?
Jeez, that you are finding effective to drive registration across the funnel.
Absolutely.
So we have a set of standard promotional tactics that we run.
We're always going to navigate to our database especially for those middle of the funnel webinars or for the top of funnel webinars.
If people are unengaged, how can we re-engage them?
Almost consider them a top of funnel lead, even if they have had a conversation with sales and it's been, you know, for months.
So our database This is really important to, you know, send those promotions to and engaging way.
We also utilize LinkedIn, LinkedIn ads with the LinkedIn lead gen form, especially for those top of funnel webinars.
It's kind of lower barrier to entry especially like with the LinkedIn Legion form and you can be extremely targeted.
So we can Target certain industries, certain job functions within those Industries.
You know, make sure we're excluding you Competitors.
Or those that might not be a good fit for tulip today.
So that is a key, promotional tactic for us.
Additionally, we utilize tools for web content personalization.
It's actually something that we kicked off just in the most recent webinar.
So based on certain intent, that we see if they're looking on our website for you know, specific topic.
Then we can tailor.
A website experience where we're promoting engaging or tailored content to them.
So we're just testing that out actually today.
So always continuously improving and testing more things.
Additionally, because the manufacturing industry tends to navigate to specific watering holes like industry Publications.
We work with industry Publications.
A lot for some of our top.
The funnel webinars because that's where they go to be our Target.
Personas, go to access insights to get reporting, you know, ways that they can report on their manufacturing operations, or they would search for or subscribe for various topics.
So we want to be right there as a contender.
And we also have a tailored pop-up experience on our website.
So, based on relevant Pages, we also link right to a call to action.
And if there's a relevant webinar coming up for, you know, those that are looking at our manufacturing execution system guide, you know, we want that next call to action for them.
So we have those on our website on relevant pages.
Of course, and we also want to make sure that we're engaging LinkedIn organically.
So, we're ensuring that, you know, our speakers are reaching out to their connections, you know, promoting the webinar to their own audiences, so it's really organic there.
And then, lastly, and most importantly, I would say, is engaging and enabling our sales So we want to make sure not only when we're promoting webinars that you know the our sales team isn't able to promote those webinars in a timely manner to prospects those that are just trying to get, you know that booked meeting.
Maybe you know watching a webinar or attending a webinar that's relevant to their you know email conversation is going to help get that booked meeting or lead to a phone call or even you know lead to that close one.
Done deal.
We see a lot of prospects that are in the later stages of the buyers Journey even attending top of funnel webinars because if it's, you know, beginning of the year, they're just trying to evaluate everything.
So sometimes that gets, you know, us to, you know, show tulip as a contender and, you know, an RFP evaluation, but we're really trying to test all different angles and engage people.
In the most relevant way.
That's those are a lot of great tactics strategies you guys do biology across multiple random rant in a lot of different actors that we're testing.
But yeah, it's I think it's important to test different Avenues and learn from them.
That's great.
What website platform are you leveraging right now to be able to iterate quickly?
Yeah.
So we're using craft Hazard or CMS, and we also have other tools in our Tech stack like six cents.
So we're able to identify those accounts that are showing intent for various topics that are showing more intent for tulip, and we can t up some of those relevant webinars to them.
That's amazing.
Great.
And then about you mentioned also your connection with the sales team and how you leverage these webinars to enable them.
Can you describe like what is that interaction and regular communication like around webinar because?
Yeah, absolutely.
So I think it is so important to have that two-way communication between marketing and sales.
So that Marv up sales sees that what we're doing is really to help them and to help them progress deals, and get new leads, and that marketing is listening to their recommendation.
So for that webinar traceability, you know what we did was I created a survey for the sales team to understand, you know, what do our prospects want to hear from us?
What is leading to the most Well engagements is it you know focusing on a use case like traceability and that was one of the recommendations that they shared.
So it's not only enabling them but also hearing from them too.
And when I first started here at tulip sales didn't really see webinars as a true demand gen tool and now they're kind of waiting for the next one to come out.
You know when's the next email coming out of you know, Adding the sales enablement content for our resources, for our next webinar.
So it's, you know, I think there's always a loop of continuous improvement with, you know, marketing and sales alignment.
But that's a, it was a good Milestone to hit their, you know, they're excited for that next webinar to be able to promote to their prospects or really excited to see.
You know, the high quality leads that come through that top of funnel event.
That's amazing.
Okay, I am going to get really tactical here on communication because you know, I asked these things because most of us have remote teams and so is there like a shared slack Channel where you're able to share out the upcoming webinars and the sales team can ask questions?
Are you updating them on daily weekly?
Like how does that interaction work?
And look like.
Yeah.
So I used to update the sales team weekly and their group email, I think what and kind of learn from their feedback that what's really important is to get all of the resources upfront and kind of monthly update but with weekly reminders and check in.
So again you know hearing feedback from sales, you know, how do you want to receive the sales enablement content?
When do you want to provide feedback right now?
That email communication is most beneficial Initial.
But you know, for some of those weekly check-ins we have that shared slack Channel where they can also reach out to me.
Also, you know, my doors always open to hear feedback and I think that's what's in route.
What's really important to you that myself and my team is always willing to hear feedback that comes from sales and new ideas and recommendations because we do move forward with them.
And we hear what you're saying.
Huge that communication alignment is huge and that's awesome.
Yeah.
I mean you're always learning to it's a yeah.
I think it's like kind of I don't know if you work folks on the call or feel that too but there's always a gap that you identify and marketing between marketing and sales and how to you know fill that Gap is and understand why you're filling that Gap.
Across both functions and teams is what's most important.
So it's an uphill battle, but climbing up, awesome.
Well, I think you have shared so many amazing golden nuggets about webinars and how we can attract folks to webinars what they look like across the funnel.
Is there anything else that you would add specifically about what And ours that you'd share to us?
Yeah.
I would say, I shared a couple tidbits, I think if you're able to live experiences compared to you know pre-recorded experiences are what drive that quality engagement throughout the event.
And you know, I think technical difficulties are okay, we're all human.
One of our top performing webinar that generated the most Revenue compared to all the other webinars.
There was a total dekhna technical difficulty in the beginning of the webinar.
But people, you know, stuck through and the quality of content was what's most important.
So I think those live experiences also show a company or as you know people that are, you know, Wanting to hear more from our Target buyers and engage that discussion.
So you mentioned a few things about you know, the beauty marketing Community, really maintain those connections that you gather even, you know, early on in your career because they are kind of career-long connections but also from a webinar perspective hearing from sales and when you can really, you know, have that live experience.
For, for prospects, to be able to engage in real time.
That's awesome.
Is there any?
Final advice that you would give to the B2B marketing community, yeah, those connections are important and I think continuously learning from what you have produced and what you have launched, I think that's, that's another huge tidbit, especially if you're producing a lot like we did in the last year, learning from what worked and what didn't and being able to, you know, have that retro and clear, open conversation with those important stakeholders in a project this is really important for the sustainability of your team but also for you know your marketing program Amazing.
Well Meghan, thank you so much for taking the time to impart your wisdom across webinars.
I am sure we're going to take re-watch this and take some notes and apply them even to our own.
So I hope all the best for you and tulip in this coming year and for all those who are here watching, be sure to check out tomorrow.
We have got an event with Julia.
And we're going to be talking about the top three, metrics and attribution myths.
So it's going to be really good, and she is metrics attribution Guru?
So feel free to join us, then have a wonderful rest of your day, and we will catch you next time.
Just hoping for the best but expecting the worst, are you gonna drop the bomb or not?
Let us Die Young or lettuce leaf forever.
We do not have power pony, never seen it sitting in a sandpit.
Life is a short trip the musics for the sad man.
Can you imagine when the phrase one not gonna faces into the sun prison?
Our leaders we get in and turn the music played by them.
The mud, man.
So more like what is someone like to hear some of the men in some other be sooner or later?
They all will be gone but don't He stay?
It's so hard to get on without it, cause I don't want to perish.
Like a fading us cues like diamonds in the Sun and diamonds are forever.