Hello and welcome to today's Spotlight interview with Nick Bennett, who is the director of evangelism and customer marketing at Alice.
We are so excited to dive deep into what he's up to.
And so we're going to talk about evangelism in general.
What is customer marketing, dive, deep into why that's really important, especially, as we move into.
23, where it could be a down.
It's a down market.
So we need to be innovating and being good stewards of the business in general.
So I am really excited.
Nick, will you join me here on stage?
Hey, hello, how are you?
I am doing great.
How are you doing?
I can't complain.
It's a beautiful day outside.
Okay, so where are you tuning in?
From II?
Think I have got a map here that shows us sell our producer.
There we go.
Okay, so you're in Boston, I am all the way out here in Hawaii.
That's its like it's look how far away we are that.
But look, we're still here together.
Pretty amazing.
What time is it for you?
It is 220, 2 PM nice.
Okay, 9:02 PM or am sorry here.
So we have definitely got that distance between us.
However, what's amazing is, we could still be in our the same virtual room and hanging out together today.
Absolutely cool.
Well, Nick, tell us a little bit about what you're up to these days.
Yeah, so, you know, my in my nine-to-five we at Alice would like to do things.
So like everyone knows what you are and your 9 to 5 and so for me I run evangelism and customer marketing analysis.
I am a traditional field Market or an ABM Better for tech companies and for the last 10 or 11 years.
And then what we like to really talk about is the 529.
So what are you passionate about outside of work?
And so for me I play baseball still competitively, you know, I like to do a lot of fun things.
I love New England Sports, absolutely devastated me that Bogaerts signed with the Padres this morning, I was cursing the front office most of the day.
So, you know, hey die-hard Boston, sports fan and I have a four-year-old daughter.
Who honestly means everything to me and everything I do is for her.
That's amazing.
Well, we definitely were tracking with that baseball.
Fun fact, so Sal I went ahead and put that up there but yeah, jumping into some of these fun facts.
You know you got baseball so just so you know for me I used to do The movies television back in the day and I actually did a lot of background work for Ugly Betty, and she was awesome and it was fun playing these like we did these like Japanese Entourage Fashion Group type of, type of roles.
So that's one of my fun facts.
But there's another fun fact about eunuch that we would love to share and you were a rapper.
It was, right?
I went through a phase in high school.
Yeah.
It was something I went out and bought all the expensive stuff.
I had someone that mixed and produced all my music for me and it still floats around the internet.
All these years later.
Well, in fact, we have got this track right here and I have got to play this a friend of mine.
You got to get together to buy.
I have got my hat here.
Get out.
All right.
Can I put this on the chosen son?
And it's just your luck.
You about to Bear witness.
I got acid ronschuster CD as yeah any day, but they will be stepping on the see white Shades Boston fitted in a disc.
Three.
I think my track is my campus in the pain to my heart.
So for this, I still Blood, Sweat tears, and love, just so you can feel the inspiration from above Thanks for letting me play around, be little goofy with you there, but that's pretty dope.
You're very talented, Nick.
I like to do a lot of different things.
You do a lot of different things and you're handling it as a girl, dad, so lots of Kudos and props to you.
Thank you.
Hopefully that wasn't embarrassing.
Are you all right?
That we played that?
Yeah, absolutely.
Yeah, it's funny cuz I will share like that song randomly as I like, you know, we could be at Like trivia or something, like I will just drop in.
Then people like I had no idea, and I was like yeah I went through like it was like a two or three-year thing and it's just it's crazy that it just still flow.
I mean that's the internet for you just floats around there forever.
Hopefully in like 30 years it will still be there.
For sure, it's a great track.
I am impressed with your lyrical Rhymes there.
Cool.
Well, you know, customer marketing as we dive into this topic, there was this one fact that I got from Bain & Company and the research shows that a 5% increase in customer retention can increase profits by 25% to 95%.
I mean that is insane and it's like, okay, why aren't we?
Holding down more here.
Can you just Define for us?
How do you define customer marketing and yeah, I didn't see it today.
Yeah, it's you.
So I want to kind of guess put it out there, so I have actually never done customer marketing before.
So this is all new to me, like I said, I am a traditional failed marketer, ABM marketer.
That's what I have done.
I was actually in sales before I moved over to marketing, so I have walked in sales is shoes which I feel like made me such a good feeling.
Field marketer and ABM marketer because I understood how it all worked.
I understood the stresses of not being paid, your quarterly commission, and things like that.
So it was probably earlier this year before the market started to get really crazy and in my boss at the time was like, hey what do you think about moving over to customer marketing?
And there's going to be a strong focus on retention from the board and I said, cool, I am all for new Challenges.
I like to be a better well-rounded marketer.
I said, I am up for doing it, but I want evangelism as a part of it, and we can get to that later, how I broke that down, but my goal was to help with the nir.
So like their net revenue, retention side of it.
And I think that marketers today, you know, the customer marketers, get it, absolutely.
That NR is in is so important.
However, so many other marketers don't really focus on that, as a metric.
And I think that you should actually be focusing more on Nar today, then a lot of the other metrics that marketers are focusing on because we all know it costs less to retain a current customer than, to acquire a new one.
So why wouldn't you double down your efforts on that and that was really the whole thing?
And for me my goal is and it's, you know, again, I want to preface this.
It's a little bit easier when you Market to marketers and you are the ICP and you know, exactly the pain points.
They're looking to solve because you were looking to solve it for all these years and I have just been able to really jump on with customers strategize with them.
Focus on the social proof aspect the customer stories and not just fluffy customer stories because some let us be honest like who writes a bad case.
Study no one puts bad case studies out there.
Why would you talk bad about your company?
But when you can get tactical with a customer story and turn that into a Playbook, now that not only does that help with retention, Tension.
But it also helps Drive acquisition as well.
So those are some of the things and honestly, it's even more alarming a little bit that leaders within companies, specifically in Tech right now are actually laying off customer marketers and keeping acquisition marketers.
I don't agree with that.
And I have seen layoffs affect a lot of customer marketers.
Unfortunately, within the last couple of months, you would think that is the one piece in the marketing.
Or that you want to double down on and I don't see why more companies don't put more resources and money behind it.
Do you think that could just be because customer marketing?
I mean, how long has it realistically been known and the practices the disciplines, the ROI, the attribution, calculated around it like, is that really understood today?
I think the people that have I am doing it for a long time and I know I mean to me I have had to rely on a lot of these resources because it was some wasn't something that came like first nature to me, and so I have talked to a lot of customer marketers some that have been only been doing it for, you know, two or three years and some that have been doing it for 15 or 20 years.
So there is people in larger companies usually is where you see it you know you like the IBM's of the world and you know, HP things like that.
Like they have had customer marketers.
Ever.
Have they been focused on different things and can customer marketing like should they build a customer Advisory Board?
Should they be focused on just driving, you know, reviews or something?
Should they be strategizing?
I think it's evolved a lot over the years for sure.
And I have always as a marker to talk to customers.
I can't I guess yo tell how important that is as a marketer, that you should be talking to customers and not just talking to them taking what they're saying and actually doing.
Do something about it, but to create programs, specifically built around retention and expansion upsell opportunities has been newer for me.
And I feel like I have done a lot that has made an impacted short time because I don't want to live, like, could I retention rate?
Be better.
Absolutely right now, 100%.
And I think everyone realizes that.
And so the programs that we're putting together is hopefully making an impact on that.
And I can already see a lot of The result even within the last five months, and it's trending, like, kind of like hockey stick style up.
So, alright, so let us go back a little bit.
Rewind, I would love to dive into your story into just even how you got to becoming the Evangelist customer marketing, Guru that you are today.
Take us back a little bit.
And how did you get into B2B marketing?
Yeah, so completely by luck to be honest with you, so I went to school for sports management.
Like I said, I played baseball, all my life played in high school, played in college and I went for sport management.
And when I got out, I said I am going to be a big shot athletic director at a D1 school, or I am going to be a sports agent or something like that, and when I got out turned out, none of those were true.
I could go sell tickets for the Red Sox making $10 an hour, and I was like, oh, that doesn't sound.
Very fun.
Like why did I go to college for that?
But to be honest, I wasn't also a great student.
I cared more about baseball and I feel like being a marketer actually relates really well, the baseball and Sports in general, I feel like it's being someone.
Athletic is kind of made me a better marketer because kind of you know teamwork everything plays together really well, but I said okay, well, this isn't going to pay the bills.
My parents told me I needed to get like a real job.
And, so I said, all right, I am going to go into sales inside sales.
It was as for a tooling company, and let me just tell you like, that was boring.
Like I hated I was doing inside sales and I had to show up at 7 AM and work till 5 PM in sit at like an old computer.
It wasn't even a laptop.
It looked like it was from like the 80s, and this was like in 2000, like 12.
So, it wasn't even like that long ago and like I sat there and just took calls from basically General Foreman construction workers about like, industrial tools.
And like, I would go pick them out back and like, basically sell them and I had upsell them and all these different things.
So I never did sales for Tech, but I did sales for them and then I moved into Motorola actually.
And so, I ran Channel sales for Motorola after their AT&T account.
So at the time I was going up against the iPhone, every release for September, and we were trying to outsell them, and I had to come up with creative ways to get their dealer channel to want to do that.
And then I moved to like a channel marketing role which was still working within the same.
I had the whole East Coast for a Titi ta Titi indirect dealers and I would just work with them to kind of figure out spiff, programs and incentives.
Contest trainings.
All of those.
Things.
And I was like, oh, this is cool.
I don't have a quota hanging over my head, but I get to do all these fun things and travel, and I was young at the time, so I was like, oh, traveling is great.
And then I went to another company, I moved into another Channel marketing role and then that allowed me to move into my first field marketing role in B to B Tech.
And it was the first true role that I ever really did.
I remember?
It was a company called Simplicity.
They were in the hyperconvergence space just outside of Boston years ago, a lot of EMC.
CMC people for people that know, EMC out there.
And I was like, this is so fun, like we get to do all these crazy things and at the time our CEO is telling us don't buy your yacht yet like we reached a billion dollar valuation in 23 months fastest in the it space to reach a billion dollar valuation.
And I remember all the sudden we had an immediate like all hands meeting and it was like HP bought us for 600 million and be.
I felt bad because I was Only there for like a year and a half of people that were there for four five, six years, basically, they were getting nothing for their time because everything was under water at that point and then that was kind of like my I just kind of didn't look back at allowed me to start to do field marketing for a lot of these other B2B companies.
And that's kind of what I have done for the last eleven ten or eleven years now.
Wow.
Okay.
So walk us through how you got into evangelism and customer marketing specifically, yeah, so the It was in pieces, is interesting to me.
I have always, you know, looked up to people like sangram when he was at Terminus Ethan.
Buuck, who's that, bom, bom, Randy from Uber flip.
Like these people that have Chief evangelist titles, and I was like, wow, they're like out there evangelizing for a product and Company and in the it space I always saw Advocates as kind of like evangelist but I feel like it was developers.
Like it was very interesting like I couldn't fit that because I was not a developer But I said, you know what?
I said, Mar Tech in sales Tech is lacking this type of role from a non-executive standpoint.
And so when my boss came to me and said, hey would you be open to doing this?
And I said, yeah, but I want this.
I am going to tell you exactly why I said I feel like I have already been doing a lot of these things of, you know, helping be the face for the brand doing all these events, the podcasts, the prospect calls and customer calls.
I said I want to actually help Leave the path for what it looks like for non-executives to take to do these types of roles.
And I can tell you like, he was like, absolutely.
Let us pitch it to the leadership team.
So, I got on a call with the CEO, ocfo like everyone and I pitched it.
I said, this is why I think I should do this role.
And I said, B2B companies and more Tech and sales Tech don't have it yet.
You want to be at the Forefront of this.
I am telling you, and there was no pushback.
They're like, yeah, absolutely.
Like you're a perfect fit that role, And now you're seeing more and more people start to get these types of roles.
I mean, I think of people like Jen Al, and she was at the Challenger, she did just leave, but like her, you know, will Akin Nick Posey, Arthur Castillo from Chile, Piper?
Like, you're seeing more and more non-executives take on these evangelists /, like Creator type roles and I think from an evangelist perspective, your kind of mixture of things.
So like you're a subject matter expert you are out.
Are evangelizing on behalf of the product and communities wherever your ICP is meet them where they are, but you're also a Creator in a lot of regards.
If you look at a lot of people that have these types of roles, they're regularly creating content on LinkedIn on Tick-Tock, on all these other social media platforms.
And I think when you go to a company, say, hey, by the way, I have, you know, 40,000 followers on LinkedIn.
You know, all these on Tick-Tock, we should create this.
Type of role.
It's a lot more appealing, especially in the more Tech world.
And I do think, as we move into 2023 you're going to see more B2B companies start to either create these types of roles in Elevate people internally or start to externally bring people in.
Because I do think the Creator economy is going to blast off in B2B in 2023.
That makes total sense.
When do you think the chief evangelist?
Like this whole role really started to take traction?
How many years ago months ago?
Yeah, I mean I think the chief evangelist role has been around.
Like I think I like saying I am from even like I mean, I don't know how long he's been doing it but like he's been doing it for a while like I feel like Randy from Uber flips.
Been doing it for a while.
Ethan like you have these types of people that have done these roles for a while.
However, I do think The like the outcomes that you're looking to achieve from these roles are very different.
Like in, I could tell you no one really has figured it out because I have asked probably about 20 to 30 people how they view, this specific role in everyone is very different from like how do they track it?
And measure it to what are the actual like objectives that they're looking to complete?
Yeah.
Could you walk us through?
What?
Some of those objectives looks like look like even for yourself and then What are you tracking?
Yeah, so I think it's, you know, a big piece of it is external community building and participation.
So, like if you're a martyr tech company, for example, you want to be active where your prospects and customers hang out.
If it is in, let us just say Peak Community or rev genius or Pavilion.
Or I mean there's so many slack communities out there and Discord communities.
Now like just being active there.
You want to join the events and sessions to better network with your I see.
You're not selling them anything, you're just building those relationships so that when the time comes, they keep you top of mind, you just want to be in that conversation, ultimately from there.
The product has to do everything that you want it to and live up to the standards and the hype and all that.
But that's the first thing.
The second thing is internal employee advocacy and I feel like this is an important one because if you think about it and I will just give you an example.
So in 2020 to my content on LinkedIn.
Alone will drive about 12 million views.
So about a million views.
A month is what my content is driving on LinkedIn.
Now, you take, I post on Tick-Tock, I post on Instagram reels, YouTube shorts.
You take that, you amplify all that.
Now, cool, you have one Nick now, what about all these other employees that are creating content or want to create content?
Think about that.
There's no cost associated with this.
It's just time.
And getting people to better understand how you like what are the outcomes that you actually want to achieve from that all of a sudden, say LinkedIn?
For example, you get 15, 20 employees creating their own content.
You're driving 15, 30 40, 50 million views a year.
Think about what you would pay an ad spend for that, it's through the roof.
Especially as ad spend continues to go up.
So, employee advocacy is a huge piece of it and I think that there are companies out there that kind of produced Like software and products to help support that.
I have been doing everything just from a manual standpoint myself because it's more.
So educating and people who are afraid to click post for the first time.
But if you just get them to share their stories and you don't want them to talk about the company.
If the come someone wants to hear about your company, they're going to go to your website.
They're going to go to other channels corporate handles.
They're not going to LinkedIn to hear me talk about Alice for example, they I go and I try to Share value But ultimately When I am getting, you know, 15,000 views to my profile, every 90 days, and they're clicking.
And they're saying oh by the way, he works for Alice, let me go see what Alice does.
Oh they're gifting company huh?
We use a gifting company we're up for Renewal I am gonna go check them out and submit a demo in how did you hear about us?
I am going to put that, I heard Nick on LinkedIn or from this podcast, so we can use self-reported attribution to tie everything back.
So that's that piece side.
The third piece is influencer marketing.
So again, I think this is you can look at it as like the Creator economy, influencer marketing, whatever it is, but it's working with the key people in your industry that you want to have promoted your company, your product, your mission, everything through that and yeah, you know, one off, engagements are cool and stuff.
But if you can build long-term engagements and ultimately create an in-house type of environment, we have creators that you eat that, you know, they work for the company.
Benny, But ultimately they're doing their own thing and you just have all these people that are going out there and doing their own thing, it can do some serious damage and I think that's going to be another huge Topic in 2023 is influencer marketing and how to B2B companies leverage it.
Because b2c has a figured out really well.
B2B is still lacking behind there, the other ones, a prospect calls and customer calls.
So I joined seven to ten calls a week between Prospect or customer calls.
Yeah.
And it's not just sitting there at a no value like, Like I am leading these calls through strategy, through brainstorming sessions, and that's where I think the customer marketing piece plays into it as well.
It's like, great helping current customers retain them figure out if they're a makes any sense for upsell or anything for prospects.
And that's where from a customer marketing standpoint, those relationships should start at the prospect level and you should be working your all the way through.
Don't just take that hand off after they close a deal and when CS gets it, jump in.
Start to build Advocates from there.
You should be building Advocates from Way Beyond that, so that's that piece the external speaking and networking.
So for me, that's a big one.
So, like I in the last two years I have done about 90 podcast as a guess.
And so that has helped me kind of again, Drive awareness for, for the company.
And so Alice like I will single-handedly this year, do a million dollars in pipeline myself, just from organically creating content, and I am proud of yourself.
Reported after best nap for that just for a moment there.
That's pretty amazing.
Yeah, how much of that do you think we will close?
So probably about 60% base.
Yeah, it's I mean, I did 500k the year before in 250 close, so 50%, and our win rates are up and I feel like everything is better products in a better spot than it was a year ago, so I can see 60 to 70 percent closing easily and that's just again literally zero cost you.
No nope.
Pay two heads were run or anything from that.
It's just solely people coming in from self-reported attribution.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
And then the last thing that I was going to say is just from an evangelist and point.
Like you want to take these insights and learnings in figure out how to infuse them back into the business.
Because if you're out there and you're hearing all these things and you're not relaying this information or if you're not taking action on them.
What's the point?
It's like any marketing rule like you could hear all these things from a customer, you understand, the issues.
But if you just sit on it and do nothing, you're not going to win.
So to walk me through what that looks like?
Yes.
You're going across all of these different channels and opportunities and getting the word out there.
You're getting insights.
What does that look like tactically and sharing with your team?
Yes.
So it's quarterly presentations on kind of the learnings, from calls from events, from what the General market says, in its data to back it up as well on top of that.
And so we can see specifically how the market is trending.
How people are thinking about?
It in.
Fortunately, I have a lot of friends that work at competitors, and so I am a lot of friends that are customers at competitors.
And, so I am able to kind of triangulate a lot of this information, so it helps make that roadmap better.
Because again, if you're hearing all these things in XYZ product feature is in on your road map.
Well, these 40 people said it should be, and they're choosing these competitors because of it.
You would think you want to get that.
That on your road map ASAP.
And so those are a lot of the things in.
So I usually put out a deck every quarter, that kind of highlights all these things plus a video and I usually presented in person, I mean virtually as well.
And this is with your team at Alice.
Yeah, exactly.
So it goes like, there's two different versions.
There's a leadership, like SLT like senior leadership version and then there's a marketing like version.
And there's a general company version, like just slightly changing the talking points and things like that, and kind of what's being shown.
But yeah.
What are some of the key things you highlight at each of those levels?
So to senior level because that gives me an idea of like the outcomes of what success look like.
So what do you present at that?
Your level.
Yeah.
So I think it's the ability on how are people thinking about the brand Affinity.
It's like, you know, great, are you increasing Revenue per quarter?
Are you engaging a certain percentage of customers per quarter or are you increasing customer satisfactions, which ultimately Drive higher MPS, surveys in scores?
Are you kind of getting a you can you showcase your attribute like a positive association with in the Brand and that's engagement things like that?
I mean, the senior leadership's, like numbers, you know, they're like, Yay, why would I invest in something like this?
If it doesn't produce Roi, but I feel like a lot of what I do 80% is tied to revenue programs and 20% is brand or experimental.
And I feel like this evangelist type role is somewhat experimental because some of the things that you could do, like, let us just take this me and you talk right now.
Now, you cut this up, there's micro-content.
You start tagging me.
All these people.
See it.
They click my name.
They go see what Alice does cool.
You just help me drive a ton of pipeline.
Thank you.
And like yeah, we can attribute some of that.
But what if people don't specifically you know say they heard about me from you or self-reported attribution just doesn't fall in a way that you wanted to.
I think the second piece is dark social or word of mouth or however you think about it and like if I go Tell ten people after this?
Hey I just did a session on welcome and you should go check it out.
If you're looking for a virtual event platform, that's not directly attributed but it's me telling 10 people.
And I feel like my word would hopefully hold a lot of weight with those 10 people.
That's good.
Wow.
Okay.
There is a question from Jeanette that we can pull up here.
How are you measuring self-reported attribution and how do you gather the data?
Yeah.
So basically, I am pulling Salesforce reports of anyone that has mentioned my name specifically and so it's been a little bit easier because I will see about two to three inbounds come in per week with, with my name, and we drive.
I mean, how we drive about 160 demos per month right now.
So it's a sizable amount, and I am seeing people start to put my name and Tick Tock next to it as well.
Which is a little bit newer because funny enough, I actually don't talk about Alice, it all in my Tick Tock, it's just, it's not an ALICE page, it's my own personal page.
But what I am doing is repurposing a lot of content that I create on LinkedIn and then creating videos of that and then posting it on tick-tocking Instagram rails.
And it's a completely different audience because not so many people from B to B, you're on there yet.
But the organic reach is absolutely like through the roof.
So really just pulling it down.
Yeah.
Really pulling Salesforce reports for people that are using that specific field which we make it a requirement in our demo form.
On how did you hear about us?
So I was just going to ask about that.
Yeah so you have to fill it out and there's a couple other questions as well, and we have been tweaking some things to see how it works.
If people at answer more favorably, if we do things, but we had the drop down box for so long and it was like as marketers.
We like to put people in boxes and when you hit when You go to a demo page and you hit that drop down box, more than likely you're in a click that first thing and it's usually like Google or something like that and like that's why everything gets attributed wrong and that's another whole conversation, honest.
That's right.
But yeah, Wow, that The Tick Tock point is so interesting to me because I am just curious.
Like, are those actually qualified leads that come through, are they B2B?
And yeah, I think I can tell you, I can tell you in the last two weeks, there's been, there's been two.
And one is from a 20,000 person company in our ICP.
In one is from a 4500 person company.
So for those people in Executives out there that say that Tick Tock is not for be I call BS and it's an absolute lie because I can prove that B2B should be on Tick Tock and should be producing content.
There.
Mmm.
That's really interesting.
What are your thoughts on Instagram?
Facebook Twitter, so, so Instagram.
All I am really doing with Instagram.
I am using Instagram, reels to repurpose, Tick-Tock content over there, and again, it's a different audience.
So, like the people that are following my Instagram reels have been Went from Tick-Tock have been different from LinkedIn, so it's cool.
It's like three different platforms.
I don't put anything on Twitter and Facebook.
I don't mess with anything with their either.
But the interesting thing is let us just say LinkedIn decides to kick us all off tomorrow, and we all go to LinkedIn.
Jill.
What happens?
You don't own the audience on any of these social media platforms, that's the issue.
Mark, like just every anyone thinks that like they own that audience.
So If LinkedIn kicks me off tomorrow, my 41 thought a thousand followers goes by, like I have nothing and so that's why I am now creating an email list because that is the one thing that you do own you create that email list which feeds into a newsletter which feeds into all these other channels for me personally and yeah, like I mean, it's my personal thing, not an ALICE thing but ultimately the brand still is associated with who I am.
That makes sense.
Wow, okay, so that's a ton of content creation.
I am on your side.
Do you have?
Like are you the one man Agency or how are you getting all the editing, the shooting, the writing previously done.
So it's all just me outside of the podcast.
The podcast, I do have a company that's been with me in Partnership for two years now.
But as far as like the LinkedIn creation, then taking that, and all I am really doing is say, I write a, I will get used today is an example.
I Needed, a text post around, 20 23 ideas.
For events that are in person ways that you could use product tours, things like that.
All I did was take my phone record myself repeating.
What that text post was?
Which takes me about five minutes maybe less than that.
It took me five minutes to write that post.
Five minutes to shoot the video.
I throw it into an app called captions, which will automatically put captions into it and then I just hit post on tick tock.
On Instagram rails and post on YouTube shorts.
In the whole thing.
Takes me 15, 20 minutes, max, nice.
Okay.
And then you have, like, a way of calendaring these out.
Like, how do you organize your content right now?
Yeah, I don't do it very well.
I can tell you that, I have always been the type of person that doesn't write anything down.
Like, I hate taking notes, like any of my And it's / like spur of the Mind type thing, like I will be usually in the shower and I will try to remember what it was.
By the time I got out of the shower to my phone, but I don't schedule anything out.
I don't write anything in advance unless I know I have to like post something specifically about ass like certain topic but like 99% of the time, it's just whatever comes to mind in.
Like, for me I am a very out overanalyze, and I am very indecisive, so, if it takes me longer More than five minutes to create any type of content.
I just won't do it because then I start to overanalyze, is this going to actually make sense?
And I am just like, who cares?
Like, if you read my stuff, like this, grammatical errors.
Luckily grammarly saved me a bit but like, I don't, yeah, I run on sentences all the time.
I don't care.
It's all about, just getting it out there.
That's a really key point of advice.
I think for Content creators anyone out there interested in getting into evangelism is like the analysis paralysis.
Cisco.
I think that happens.
So often with content creators where you're like, getting really nitpicking and then it's like, I don't know if I should even put this out.
And by that time, you have already over, thought the whole thing?
Yeah.
But it's so true and it's like, you start to hit backspace and like you write the same thing as 10 times and then 45 minutes passed and then you're like I am not even gonna post this time to frustrated right now, but like who cares?
Sometimes you just gotta send it.
Like whom, you know one thing I noticed the first time I am I posted content, is this always going to be people who don't like it and who cares?
That's why I made this hat.
That's why I made this.
I have a merch line and specifically around the creation.
Yeah, it's like haters hate creators create that's, there's always going to be people who hate what you do in this going to be people that tear you down, trolls that are out there.
Who cares?
Like don't let them get in your way and like that's what a lot of people.
There's so many mental barriers that people need to overcome, and they're afraid that people are going to not like what they say.
And that's okay.
Your content isn't going to be for everyone.
Just like yo Alice is content isn't going to be for everyone but it doesn't matter because it's going to reach the right people and that's what matters at the end of the day, so where can I go to get that hat, I will have to link you.
It's yeah, I have got hats, I have got hoodies.
It's I wear this everywhere.
Now drop the link in chat, so we can all get our hats and Sport your swag.
Absolutely, that's awesome.
So talking about content.
If we go into your content strategy as an evangelist, like, how do you balance the content strategy that you work on?
Like, how do you think about that from a, like, a Content pillar perspective?
You know, Alice has its core product Services offerings and there's a key, you know, direction for that brand, but then there's your brand.
So how does that all work?
In determining prioritization.
And what Is like what's going to hit the mark with your audience's.
So I think you know the benefit are a fortunate thing is that the Alice brand is kind of like out there.
It's a fun brand like people like we're not like robots like even like when you look at the stuff from our corporate handle it's value-add it's like fun.
It's Christina.
Does a great job with like are like social media but like there's we don't try to be stuffy or something that were not and I think that's why it.
Me so well because that's how I am.
It's authentic.
And if you can't be authentic in the content that you create, people are going to see right through it.
Same as marketers.
It's like when someone prospects me, it hits a copy and paste job that anyone could see from a million miles away and then gets mad that you're not going to take a 30-minute meeting with them.
Like come on, do a little bit of research on me.
I give you all of this information on my LinkedIn and yet people still don't do research like in the last.
I would say two weeks.
I have gotten about 45.
Five prospecting emails and Linkedin.
DM's guess, how many of those have been personalized one?
And it's crazy because I give those all this information is in my LinkedIn profile.
If you just took five minutes of your time to check some things out, you know, I love baseball.
You know that I have a daughter, you know, I love New England Sports and that I am devastated about the Red Sox right now but people aren't doing that.
And so for me like the content that I create, it's all about authenticity.
Nicely.
And so, you know, good example, when I have been doing this for three years.
So, when I started three years ago, I only talked about field marketing, and I was the only one on LinkedIn.
The talked about field marketing on a consistent basis and what it actually meant to a revenue organization.
So think about that one person out of 650 million users at the time.
Crazy.
And then I started my podcast at the time, which was on personal branding and I started to talk more about that and I lost being associated with the marketer.
People would reach out to me and want to talk personal branding building an audience, but they didn't want to talk marketing.
And I was like, oh, man, that kind of devastates me because like, I feel like the content I want to create is really around marketing.
And so a couple months ago, I said, you know what, I feel like personal branding.
Yeah.
You should absolutely do it, but I said, I feel like it's so played out, like, you can't scroll LinkedIn more than five minutes without seeing a post around it.
And so, I said, I said to my production team that does my podcast.
I said, I want to end the podcast.
I want to create a new one.
I want to get back to being known as a marketer, and I said, I am going to start to create content around customer marketing influencer marketing, Creator economy, interest Marketing, in general.
And I said, this will help me get back to being associated to a marketer.
And the new podcast is a marketing podcast.
And I feel like all of these things, it's starting to tip the tables a little bit more, and it's going to take a little bit of time.
But like I am trying to avoid talking about personal branding and building an audience, like, at least first.
I want it to be marketing first that second, mmm.
That's good.
Thanks for breaking that down.
We have a question that's relevant to this.
Let us pull up.
Spencer's, question, what's the best way to generate authentic content?
Whoo, yeah, conversations is definitely important.
Like, I feel like we're all working on projects and ultimately the best LinkedIn.
Is when you're sharing your experiences Lessons, Learned things that you're doing in your everyday life.
So that me as a marketer, if I see what you're doing, and I am like, who like and you talked about a failure or something like that.
I try to avoid those steps so that I am not making the same mistake.
Or if you're having a huge success, you're sharing that I am trying to replicate it myself to whatever process that I need.
And I feel like that is the most authentic content.
Like when people are sharing hey these are the five things that At I did that resulted in XYZ cool and I will give you another good example, cute.
I think it was cute to aq3.
I drove a bunch of G2 reviews, I think it was like, 83 that ultimately drove and I drove with 70 something in two days, and I am credible.
Thank you.
Yeah.
And I posted the entire Playbook on a LinkedIn post.
I said, this is the exact email I sent.
This is how I segmented the audience.
This is how I got the MPS.
This is literally the email and everything and it blew up.
It had almost 2,000 likes on it.
Hundreds of comments on it.
I got a lot of hate from G2 competitors.
Actually, people that tried to Blackmail me and like, tell me that I was doing like illegal that it was crazy, but ultimately that drove over 100,000 views with just one post.
Well, I feel like those types that type of content is something that I personally love to put out there in any role that I go building and public is incredibly important to me and like having a company support that.
And yeah I am not out there.
Sharing are you know, growth numbers or anything like that, but I am sharing exactly what I am working on and sharing it as much as I can.
Because I feel like that's going to help the next marketer, hopefully be in a better spot than they are today.
Wow, that's great.
You will have to share that g to review.
LinkedIn's post with us early, so we can pull that Playbook.
Wow, this is incredible.
So evangelism works as a channel for you and the, and we're seeing some direct Roi.
Direct Revenue come through.
Let us talk a little bit.
I know we have only got 15 minutes left, believe it or not.
Let us talk about customer marketing.
A little bit more.
You touched it at the beginning of our conversation.
And when you and I spoke prior to this convo, you're really unpacking some of the processes and like, how you work with the customer success team and how your structured organizationally with them?
Can you give us a little double?
Click into the customer marketing strategy?
Yeah, absolutely.
So I guess kind of little bit of background, so we went through a layoff a couple weeks ago and so marketing was a 10-person team down.
On 24.
So we have basically dissolved marketing and I report to our VP of Cs now.
So I am incredibly aligned on the retention side of the business, the other members of the marketing team report to our VP of sales.
And that's another whole conversation.
I don't know if I personally believe with it, but it is what it is.
So, I am incredibly aligned to the programs that customer success is running.
I understand the process is, I understand I am literally, A huge part of their team.
And like, we all work really, really well together.
And so, for me, I try to break down what I am working on through three different things.
Really?
So customer communication emails and I, so I send them out from our VP of CS2, all yet.
End users on a bi-weekly basis.
I create the email for her, and I am really trying to keep these short and concise with the video from her and then kind of little bit about product updates or features or Things like that or things that they should know about.
I am actually I just wrote one today that's going out next week that kind of is like a year in rear interview, talks about all the Integrations, all the donations that we did, things like that.
So I am really excited about that and the feedback from customers has been through the roof one, the part of the issue is you can use in-app messaging which is awesome.
However, with our product specifically, we if you are using Integrations, you We don't need to go into Alice which means that in at messaging is only getting the 30 to 40% of our users.
Which what happens to the rest of them?
We weren't actually emailing anyone before that.
We were just relying on in-app messages.
So them hearing from us is a huge win.
The other piece is g 2 reviews.
Understand, social proof is incredibly important.
Plus all these gold nuggets that you can then pull out and start to use for the sales team for the Cs team start to figure.
Out what features in what use cases are more prevalent than not has been huge?
And, so I mean in the last two quarters I think I have about 140 reviews into quarters.
That has given us tremendous feedback in tremendous results and it comes specifically for me.
So I record a video that says, hey I am I am asking for a GT review in exchange.
I am going to send you a gift, not a gift card because I think things should be But Power of Choice, you can use it if you exchange it for a gift card, if you want and I say email me back, if you want to give me feedback on the product, hop, on call, whatever.
And I can't tell you how many customers want to hop on a call, want to talk through things wanting to just get better insights, we were able to up sell a bunch of companies.
We were able to retain earlier in the contract companies that maybe we wouldn't have I have done till like later.
So that's another huge thing and then the third thing is the customer stories.
So again, we had customer case studies, I feel like they were fluffy, and I am going to give you a good example because I like giving examples, Sixth Sense is a customer of ours, and so we released a story last fall and it said 6 and sees five hundred and thirty-seven percent ROI increase.
And as a marketer, I read that headline.
Is it click baby?
Maybe I didn't come up with it but I want to know exactly.
We how they did that.
What is the Tactical like step-by-step that they did to get that Roi because we serve a similar audience like I want to replicate that and it didn't talk about that.
And I said, you know what, when I took this rollover I said I want to redo these stories and I want to focus on the Tactical aspect, and so we have released four of them so far.
I am redoing the six cents, one, it's actually just in production right now should be coming out next week, but I can tell you it is very, very tactical, goes into their secrets.
Sauce, how they do everything, and I feel like these stories have been tremendous, because we're running paid ads around them.
Now, we're running them for our sales team in Cadence's.
It rbdr team RCS.
Team is leveraging them.
Our website, traffic has been through the roof.
Oh, no.
Did I disappear?
You did?
Hold on.
Sorry, it's all good.
It's your fancy setup over there.
I think I am that you could try refreshing.
That's weird.
Hold on, I don't know what that's never happened before.
There's your little Avatar.
Oh, most there, there you are.
That's weird.
That's never happened before.
Sorry about that.
Oh, it's all good.
Cool.
But yeah, that's, you know, that's, that's the base of what I am doing.
I am actually building on a customer Advisory board right now as well, because again, why be reactive in the feedback that you're getting, why not be proactive and seek this information out from your top customers.
So I have uh, I built a few versions of decks, and we're going to start to explore that as a 2023 initiative as well.
Love that there are some definite actionable strategic tactical points you offered here.
We have got about nine minutes left.
I did want to answer Janet's.
Got a question here.
And it has to do with employees.
How do you give your employees the parameters for posting content?
What do you think of AI for generating content?
So I don't think you should give parameters to employees for posting content honestly.
Because why would you want 30 employees saying the same exact thing that's just copy and pasted?
And I can tell you I did an in a vent and I started to get tagged the other day.
From about 20 employees that must have used some type of software and just clicked repost because it was literally the same wording from all of them in the same video clip and like yeah like that's cool but like you know there's no authenticity behind it's like you know someone's basically telling you.
This is what you have to post whereas with no parameters.
Hey like everything is fair game like yeah, talk about things that you're passionate about.
Ultimately, it's still going to impact the business.
I am not saying like don't go out and like, Not talk about the company to share cool stuff because ultimately people buy from people, and if you can showcase that and build relationships with people, that's going to be awesome.
On the AI side, I have been playing around with the chat G PT, 3 things, and it's interesting because I actually wrote I wrote anything.
I said, what does evangelism and be to be mean to you.
And I must have stumped it because I got like a blinking cursor.
That came back at me, and I was like, oh yeah, this thing is Going to steal my job.
I am not, I am not too worried so, but yeah, I mean, it's honestly it's way better than anything that's out there right now.
I can tell you that, like, I have used it for I am seeing like Tick Tock videos that Engineers are using it to basically like figure out like coding and all it just basically writes code for you and like all these other things, I think it's going to be really cute cool.
But I don't think you should 100% rely on it because it goes back to your point of authenticity, right?
And at some point, I mean, the challenge is some of these AI generated content pieces to feel authentic.
But then, at some point you can start to see, like, oh, is this a?
I generated like, as a person, consuming the content, I will question it.
You know, actually so awesome.
All right, well, I would love to close our time with a point of advice or encouragement that you have for the B2B community.
Yeah.
It's you know, I would say going back to my new pad podcast, which is called the anonymous marketer people submit questions anonymously, like the it's not about the right or the wrong answer.
It's about starting a conversation for the B2B marketing community and I would say, don't be afraid to ask these questions.
I feel like so many people when the pandemic happened, they turned to communities, and they were asking questions in there because they didn't want to be judged by the companies.
They worked for now.
There's so many of your colleagues in bosses that are in these communities as well.
People are still feeling uncomfortable.
So I wanted to start something that allows people to create anonymous questions and hopefully myself and a guest can dive into this.
And a good example, I am releasing the first episode next week, but it's around career growth.
And one of the questions I got was it's so hard to find a mentor if, especially, if you're not in a big city, like Boston, New York or San Francisco.
How do I go about?
Out.
Finding a mentor because I feel like I need one.
And it was like, that's so many people are dealing with that as a marker.
It hits home because I haven't had a mentor up until a couple few years ago.
I didn't know where to turn.
No one told me where to go, find him our mentor and then the second question was around.
I actually feel like I know more than my boss at this point.
What do I do?
I could sit here in Coast for another year, but I feel like I am doing myself a disservice by doing that and I feel like that's again.
I mean I have been in That spot where I feel like I knew more than my boss but like what do you do?
If there's no other ways to go around like you're just kind of stuck there.
Yeah you could Coast but it's we go deep on to these types of questions and I think it's going to be really helpful for B2B marketers to kind of explore like hey this is impactful for me.
In this does help me in my career.
Disappear again.
Right, next.
We lost your video again, but we could still hear you say, okay, your podcast is coming out.
Is it next week?
Yeah.
Next Wednesday.
Yep.
The 14.
Hey, okay.
So we will be looking out on your LinkedIn for any updates or whoa.
That's, I don't know.
Fact, Got to get it.
Get some of that techno music going.
Yeah, all right.
Well we're at time anyway, Nick.
So I thank you so much for your nuggets of wisdom and gold.
We are grateful for your contribution and investment back to the B2B marketing Community as well.
So, thank you for everything that you're doing all the thought leadership that you are offering out to us, it's extremely helpful and it means a lot.
So, thank you so much for your time.
Nick, thank you for having me.
I definitely appreciate it.
Awesome.
All right, so with that, thank you for joining our time.
We have our next event taking place this coming Wednesday actually.
And Nick is going to be on again.
We're really on this customer marketing topic.
You were pulling this thread, very deep.
We have also got Serena director of customer Stammer marketing from qualified will be joining.
It's gonna be a rich discussion so definitely join us then and then Thursday I don't have a screen up.
We have got an interview Spotlight with Kevin Lee who's the SVP of marketing at oyster, and he's got a lot to share on plg brand strategy as well as leading remote teams.
Well going into 2023 have a wonderful rest of your day.
We will catch you next time.
I played my drum for would invite my bumper, I played my best for him.