Did a full 180 crazy?
Walk away, you know how don't talk and don't you good?
Anything could stop me.
The ox and lamb kept time for the rubber bumper.
I played my drum for him but I played my best for him.
Hello, everyone.
It's great to be with you today, and nice to see you tuning in from all over the world.
Literally, we got folks from Puerto Rico to Colombia, to Cape Cod Seattle, and I am here in Ewa Beach Hawaii.
It's a beautiful day to be alive today, so I am really excited about today's panel.
I have got some of the best customer marketers.
Who will be talking today about customer retention and why this is such a critical thing?
You know, there was a recent stat that came out from Bain & Company research that a 5% increase in customer.
Retention can actually increase profits by 25 to 95% what a mind-blowing stat right there.
So, especially as we're moving into 2023, we know, budgets are getting tighter, we have to be better.
Better stewards of the business overall.
It makes sense to double down.
And so we have got the best here and I would love to introduce to our stage.
Nick Bennett director of evangelism and custom marketing analysis and Serena director of customer marketing at qualified.
Hi.
Hi, everyone.
How's it going?
Good to see you, both.
How are you doing well, doing?
Well, happy holidays.
Happy holidays.
So, just to get a quick check here, we're all tuning in from just want to put up this map where Serena year.
Okay, you're an Oakland.
I am an England.
Yeah.
Right.
Outside of San Francisco.
In the East Bay.
Nice and Nick.
We see your tuning in from Boston.
Yes, yes, it's cold like that.
Oh, it's freezing.
It's actually snowed the other day, and I was not ready for that.
Okay.
Gotcha.
Serena, how's the weather for you?
You know, it's a little warmer not snowing here but yeah, probably in the 50s.
So staying warm.
Nice.
I can't complain.
It's run 70 over here.
So Contrast temperatures.
Awesome.
Well, before we kick off, you know, would love to talk just a little bit about each of you and get to know each of you a little more with our fun facts.
So I am going to start off with my fun fact.
It's not exactly me.
But it's my husband who actually used to do a doo-wop group with Bruno, Mars.
So the two in the middle right there.
Bruno, Mars is in the middle left.
And my husband Duane is to the right of him.
And this was their doo-wop group base is seeing all around the Honolulu hotels, and they say, do Ops with Boys to Men and all these other tracks.
But yeah, I am gonna hand it over to you, Nick.
What's your fun fact?
Yeah, for me it's I still play baseball competitively, so I am 35 and I can still hang with a lot of those 18 year olds.
Nice.
Where?
What?
Position.
Do you play?
I am a picture.
I am a lefty pitcher, and I actually come out of high school.
I used to throw almost 90 miles an hour, and I was on the way to a D1 scholarship and I blew out my arm.
Unfortunately.
And, so I was told I needed Tommy John surgery and for anyone that knows like, I am not going to the pros.
I was like, you know what, I am just ready to go to school.
Play some baseball with a weaker arm and get my degree and move on.
WOW.
Wow, didn't know you're moving towards.
Do you want?
And that's pretty big deal.
All right, handing it over to you.
Serena.
What's your fun fact?
So my fun fact is I am a twin I have got a twin sister named Karina.
Yes, those names.
Rhyme just closer to you and Nick she's over in New York but that's a photo of us at dreamforce.
We're hugging Astro, love, love me some Astro.
And then I think you have got another photo.
Figured I would YouTube since we're Twins and given of course this season, you have got little Serena and Karina in matching snow attire because twin parents love doing that.
So, yeah, speaking of twin parents got a call it out Nick, I am.
Yeah, I am actually having twin girls and I already have a four-year-old daughter, so I am going to be officially really outnumbered in a couple more months.
So congrats.
Well, they have natural rhyming names.
Nick know I will, so we're at the point now where we're trying to see my daughter's name is Reese, and we're trying to say, do we do now go all our names but like, we're just like a whatever.
It's like at this point we're just taking it day by day.
That's awesome.
We got the twinsies connections all around here.
Cool.
Well, jump diving right into our discussion here.
So, as I mentioned earlier, customer marketing is going to be a huge priority for a lot of teams, moving into 2023.
But there's a lot of questions still around processes and like how do you define it?
So I just wanted to hear from each of you, how do you define customer marketing and What are some of those pillar programs?
Awesome.
I will go first.
So, how I Define customer marketing is really understanding our customers stories, how they're leveraging our products.
And then, of course, how we bring those stories to life, across our different marketing channels, they think that's sort of the core of it.
Yeah, and I would say, for me, you know, and I am not a customer marketer per se.
Like, I have been doing this for like, five months, but I am a traditional field marketer and ABM marketer.
And, so I have always understood the customer for me, the way that I view it is, how can customer marketing support retention, and for us, we call it t TV.
So, time to value, and the board has put so much pressure on us to deliver High retention numbers from a net revenue.
Tension.
And so all the focus is there right now and honestly it's been really interesting to think about it for someone that has not specifically run customer marketing programs for years.
And I have relied so much on the customer marketing Community to bounce ideas.
Off of, it's been really refreshing.
And when you each describe, like just some basic pillar programs of what can customer marketing can consist of what does that look like for qualified and Alice?
Yes, I do.
Oh God, go ahead make.
I was going to say, you know, so I break it down into like five buckets and so when I think about like, how can we actually support that?
So internal enablement, how do we enable and educate our csm's?
And so that's a big one because they're the ones that are on the front lines that are talking to the customers every day and being a failed marketer.
I always partnered really close with the sales team.
I was the closest member of marketing to the sales team and it was a very much, a two-way street so internal.
Moment.
Huge, especially when you don't have an enablement resource to when I think of like new customers again.
It's like how do you reduce time to Value?
So like for us we are gifting company.
How do we get that time for them to send their first 20 gifts within a 30-day window?
Because if you're signing a one-year contract and it's taking you three months to get out of onboarding, you really only have nine months to see value and then who knows, these things that pop up and then renewal time And it's like, well on.
I didn't even get as much value out of this.
I need longer.
So reducing time to value for new, customers from all customers.
It's how do you increase?
The use case adoption.
So for me, it's like, how do I Inspire and educate customers on how to use gifting and creative ideas?
And it's probably why I join so many calls to ideate, and there's strategize with customers and Prospects.
But the customer side, those relationships should really start at the prospect level and Then you will at risk.
So obviously churn is Big right now, budget concerns from a marketing perspective.
How can we identify customers that risks way earlier, how can we run?
Proactive Outreach to them and then high-performing customers on the flip side, how do you actually turn those into Advocates?
So that they are the ones that are ultimately driving a ton of inbound business, on the acquisition side, Yeah, right.
So I would say on the qualified side you touched on a lot of the pillar programs that we offer as well.
So we're thinking about website content so that's in the form of case studies.
We Do videos, we do a lot of Photography along with quotes and stats were thinking about sales enablement, constantly.
I think that's a big portion of my job as well as making sure that our reps are knowledgeable about the stories that we have and are able to communicate those stories to prospects, as well as customers.
So that's usually in the form of story, slides, we have quote slide It's we do slide recordings, email, templates, all of that.
And then I would also say social is a big channel for us.
We're promoting these stories, these quotes these successes on organic as well as paid.
And we're also doing a lot of events and webinars like this webinar.
But yeah, we also are just starting to kick off an MVP program.
So really elevating.
Those customers that are considered true Champions really making sure that they're understanding how to use the product inside and out so that we can help too.
Scale, our CSM team, that's great.
Thanks for breaking that down.
If anybody has questions, feel free to drop it in Q&A, and we will be sure to pull those up.
So that's really helpful to understand the breakdown of each of these pillars.
Now we talked when we think of the actual onboarding experience after the post sale with a customer.
What does that process look like of hand off with customer success?
And when Does customer marketing come in and get introduced.
How do they get introduced?
Like what can you walk me through that introduction point of customer marketing with the customer?
Yeah, no.
I am happy too.
So for us something that we like to do is we like to include a publicity Clause within the contract.
So we know right off the bat whether or not this is a customer that's open to doing co-marketing.
So I think that's a really important first step for us and then I would say just as we're signing, a customers, something that we like to do is what we call a win announcement.
So, you know, we have got this great customer.
They have decided to partner with us.
Let us make a big splash about that.
I think that's a really sort of nice way to start the relationship and then from there, we generally partner with customers that are seeing success.
So whether that's after 6 months, time frame were checking in with dark USA.
Team to understand which customers are seeing success, which customers are really leveraging.
Our platform to the Max and understanding who those true Champions are getting those introductions.
And then meeting with those customers, doing those kickoff calls, understanding their stories understanding In what marketing opportunities they're interested in.
I think that's a really important step as well because you want to make sure these relationships are mutually beneficial.
So understanding what opportunities they get excited about.
Whether that's speaking whether that's sharing their story in the form of a case, study or a video.
Those are things we like to cover.
And then of course, in that same conversation, understanding their use case and really getting into the nitty-gritty of their story.
And then from there, being able to leverage that content in a lot of different ways.
And do you generally meet with a customer right upon within the first 30 days of their onboarding, or what's like a good amount of time from the point of post-sale onboarding?
Yeah, I think they're interested in doing when announcements where generally getting introduced within the first 30 days.
But, typically, I would say it's after, after they were seeing value, so for us, that's anywhere from for six to eight months.
Nick.
Any thoughts to add?
So I actually report to our VP of Cs which is interesting.
So like, I actually don't report to marketing right now per se, but I am incredibly aligned to our customer success team and it's actually the team that has grown most out of any team within the last.
I would say six months.
Or so, we have actually moved a lot of people in the acquisition side over to the CSI.
In our account management side as well.
And you know we so for us it's a little bit easier because we're marketing to marketers, and so we're marketing to people that are exactly like me that have been looking to solve these pain points for the last you know 10 years of my career.
So I can relate, and I am usually connected to them, or we been in different like same circles.
It's easier to have those conversations which usually for us happen even before they become a customer.
Um, because I probably talked to them at the prospect bubble, I probably sent them some type of gift made them feel kind of like, you know, vip-style specially to our Target accounts.
Now, it's a closed deal.
So again I am usually jumping on in having strategy calls around like a b x.
How do we like they want to go gifting in their outbound strategy for a VM?
And I talked about that, or I was actually on a call yesterday with the customer that is rolling out a brand-new customer marketing.
Ting program that utilizes gifting into their entire flow.
And so it was more so like, hey, like how do you do this internally?
And then how can I replicate that?
And so, it's jumping on a lot of those calls.
The customer stories is huge for us, as well.
I actually went through the process of redoing these, so I am calling them more playbooks now where it's a very tactical.
Hey you drove five hundred percent ROI increase using a How did you actually do it?
What are the programs you ran?
What are the screenshots from your dashboards?
And we get super tactical into delivering that, which not only uses us, or benefits us from a retention side for other customers.
It actually drives a ton of acquisition growth as well.
So we're using a kind of from both sides and for me, you don't my hundred percent of my focus isn't on customer marketing, it's also on the evangelism piece.
So I would say that there's really nice parallels between the two Lee because ultimately, you want to create your customers to be Advocates and evangelist for you out in the community and dark, social and word-of-mouth.
And all those beautiful things, your customers are kind of speaking about the experience that they had.
But yeah.
So you know, I am doing a lot of these different pieces that ultimately happen before the handoff and then through the handoff as well.
I feel like I have the beauty to be able to see it across the entire Journey.
Hmm.
What would each of you say?
As far as your programs that you have mapped out?
What's like the one thing that's really working right now, who I can jump in on this one.
So for us, it's G2 reviews, social proof is huge in.
I went through the process, I wrote a LinkedIn post about this couple months ago, but I was able to drive it was ultimately 83 reviews and like two weeks but I throw I drove 73.
In two days and it was incredible and I basically gave my playbook away for free of how I did this.
So, how did you do that?
Yeah, and it was, it was more.
So again it was a video in message coming from me.
Marketed a marketer that was talking about.
Hey listen, you're always being you know, gifted like why don't I gift you something in exchange for this?
Now, people are going to be like, well, listen, you're incentivizing people for review.
Absolutely.
If you're, if you're a marketer and you're not doing this, you're an Idiot.
But it's Pete.
You're not incentivizing people for a positive review.
You're incentivizing people for feedback and I think that's the piece that gets missed, because I got a lot of hate because people are like, you're incentivizing people.
Yeah, absolutely.
I want to thank someone for their time for giving feedback on how we can improve our roadmap for the future and it was honestly, one of the biggest things that we saw.
When the G2 some reports came out, We saw like number one ranking in so many reports, and it was something where I was like, cool.
I can just replicate this process now, month, over month versus waiting till the last month of the quarter when they're like, hey, you need to get all your D2 reviews in by this time.
And it's been a huge driver for us because then what I did was I took all those G2 reviews and I bucketed them into use cases.
So ABM events, customer marketing.
And I really kind of took out the gold pieces from those quotes and I fed it to the sales team to the Cs team.
So now they have all these use cases that they can use when they're talking to additional people as well.
That's awesome.
Serena any thoughts to the one thing that's really working?
Yeah, I think one thing, we're doing that's a little more out of the box is something.
We're calling customer appreciation day.
So these are days of the year that we actually bring customers into our office.
We did this during dreamforce and it worked really, really well because we had so many of those Mutual customers in San Francisco and our office just happens to be two blocks from us.
Coney.
So we were able to bring I think close to 30 customers in over the course of those three days.
We captured quotes from those customers.
During that time we captured We have them in our studio as well as video interviews.
And so, coming out of that, we had just all these fantastic assets.
We were able to repurpose and feature across our website across social many different places.
And I think it was just fantastic.
Not only from the content production perspective but also being able to meet with all those customers in person.
We got to meet them build those relationships in person, we got to introduce them to folks in our office as well as our Executives.
And we Also use that day as an opportunity to host executive briefing Center beings with our Executives.
So there was a lot of excitement in the office.
There was a lot of great energy so it was just fantastic and so much so that we're now doing those on a quarterly basis.
Oh wow, whatcha do you both also have customer advisory boards and is that experience woven into an in-person experience like that or virtual experience Yes.
I would say it's something we have talked about it's not necessarily something we have done yet, something we are playing around with is something we call our early adopter program.
So that's rolling out new features to a select group of customers and having them play around with it, give us feedback that then we feed into our product team.
I would say, that's probably the extent of that type of strategy at this point.
Yeah, we're similar, we actually don't have an actually just created version.
One of like a customer Advisory Board deck for 2023 and mapped out.
What that exactly.
Looks like the benefits who I think should be included based on, like all of the data that we have, but we are targeting to kind of it would be a quarterly thing but it would be a virtual component in April and then in person component, in September at something yo, really bringing everyone together to do something like a really elevated experience.
But again, we haven't done it before and I think these customer advisory boards.
Help you become so much more proactive versus reactive when it comes to the roadmap and establishing those relationships that it's honestly, it's, I wish we did it earlier.
Gotcha.
Wow.
Okay, question, I have next is around attribution and kpis.
How are each of you reporting back?
The, the kpis what does attribution look like for customer marketing?
Woohoo.
Yeah it's a good question because I feel like we're still like looking at it or trying to look at it a certain way.
So we use you know, we don't really have an upsell version of our product but that is part of it, it's more influence Revenue that comes from it.
I am more measured on like the Evangelist side as well for like you know hey self-reported attribution What specifically comes in that is mentioning my name or additional pieces that we can tie back to the efforts that I am driving on social media or in person events, or if someone comes and fills out a demo today, they say, hey, I saw you on this welcome event.
Awesome, cool.
We can report that back and again that starts the relationship, ultimately, bridging out into the customer side of things but I do.
Look at like hey I have I wanted to get a certain number of playbooks out before the end of the year.
Certain number of G2 reviews, certain number of MPS surveys, things like that.
Like, you know, it's we do look at it but it's not as scrutinized as you know, some of the other roles.
Yeah, I would say that's probably the piece of most customer marketing programs, that folks struggle with the attribution piece of it just because it is so difficult to sort of map out.
I would say, you know, it's next Point, there's a lot of things that were measured on in terms of output in terms of performance, you know, number of pieces of content that we produce across case, studies videos slides Etc.
But yeah, the attribution piece is less obvious and it's one that we're actually just starting to tackle.
And so what we're doing is we're starting by building out campaigns within Salesforce where then attaching those two part at retarget.
Links, I am then going to get those links into the hands of sales, so that when they do start to share case studies, slides videos with customers and Prospects that we're able to then track who's actually opening those links and who's viewing that content and then being able to Target those folks directly because we have got all that living in Salesforce.
But yeah, beyond that I think you know the one place where we Really start to get some, some good progress there was that Salesforce and what sort of model we set up was you know if there was an introduction that was made through someone within customer marketing where we got connected to a customer and then you know, as a result of them attending an event or you know, doing some type of co-marketing with us, you know?
We could say okay great that was a relationship that marketing had started and if they were attached to a future opportunity than that was something we could.
Claim credit for.
But I would say that was sort of the one place where we had a pretty strong model in place.
Now, as far as pipeline influence or anything that, you know, you currently are seeing.
Like Nick, I have heard you talk about the significant pipeline influence that even your evangelist evangelism side has had, could you each of you speak to just how the performance is as far as just from an influence standpoint for each of your Despite efforts?
Yeah, I can kick things off so it's, you know.
So again, self-reported attribution.
So we make it a required field.
When you fill out our demo for movies movie, made that switch back in October of 2021.
Insights that we got into, which communities, we should be partnering with which channels are actually working organic was actually our biggest driver of all pipeline in 2022.
It's by a staggering number and marketing actually.
70% of the pipeline right now for what we have done through November of 2022.
Now, you know, when I use self-reported attribution and people specifically call out my name, I pull, I have a report in Salesforce that I can pull and kind of get this info, and so I will do.
I am on track to do a million dollars in pipeline myself this year, with about a 60 maybe a little bit higher than 60% close rate on top of that.
So just think about that one person.
And it's why I think that at the Creator economy.
As we move into 2023, it's going to be so crucial because ultimately we know people buy from people.
And if you can be a relatable person, someone that people want to build relationships with and get in, you provide value through the content that you create.
They may not have a need right now, but I can guarantee you when there is a need, they're going to remember you and they're gonna be like, hey, I am gonna at least put you in the conversation.
Then it's up to the sales team and product and all those other things to make it happen.
But it's about being That conversation to just get there because again, like Mar Tech.
It's so crowded right now in sales Tech as well and budgets are being cut.
Layoffs are happening every single day.
Why should someone say I am going to spend 20,000 dollars on Alice when I could go by Amazon gift cards off?
Amazon, just send it to people?
Like, why do I need a platform?
And so again, it's building those relationships, both virtually in person through content.
And again, I create intent on a lot of different platforms through events to podcast.
I just released my first episode of my new podcast today, that is a marketing podcast and so all these channels will amplify everything else that we're running internally as well.
So that's just kind of some thoughts.
I have the I think it's going to be, I think short form content is going to be huge in 2023 and then the Creator economy and B2B is going to be another thing.
Great points Bill and Chad is asking for your link to your podcast.
So please drop that when you get a moment Serena handing it over to you, any thoughts?
Yeah.
So I think it's really taking advantage of those opportunities when we meet with our customers.
So when we're bringing them into the office, and we're doing those customer appreciation days.
You know, they also have the opportunity to meet with our product team.
And so we have had a number of those conversations happen in person where they're actually getting Live demos of different products they haven't seen before.
And, so I think that's really been a great way to spike that interest.
Also, I mentioned the edc's, it's another opportunity to kind of understand like where the gaps are within the different products.
They're leveraging on our platform and then getting them into a room to actually speak with the products, you would be Executives and help them paint that vision and get those demos.
So, so powerful and then I think also, another great opportunity is dreamforce.
You know, we were sponsors this year.
We had sessions, we had a Both within the campground.
And so again, when we're able to just meet with those people in person and really show them how it works.
I think that's really the eye-opening piece of it.
And of course, in each of those sessions, we had our customers, tell their stories, you know, shared the stage with our speakers and it was just fantastic because you know, I think it's one thing when qualified says we're able to do something, but when you hear it from the mouth of our customers, it's so much more meaningful.
So we found those strategies to work very well.
Common denominators, I am hearing from both of you.
Is just the value of the relationship building opportunities that you're having as we're moving into this Creator economy with short-form content bite-sized.
So on so forth.
What's going to sustain and keep bringing people back to your brand, is ultimately that relationship and Richard, you're calling it right here in chat where it's the reinforcement of the importance of brand relationships on sales and marketing.
So I think each of you guys are describing that going into Q&A, here we go.
Some questions trickling in Norma Hogan, is asking, Nick said he's under CS.
What about Serena is this a marketing role or a cs1?
Good question, a great question, I would say, you know, having done customer marketing at 5 plus companies.
Now generally sits under product marketing and when you think about that, it makes a lot of sense.
You know, you want your customer marketer to be able to understand the product to help customers explain the product in a way that's meaningful.
All that inspires others.
And so yeah it's typically been product marketing for me.
Yeah, I was I was going to add something to that.
So you know we actually just went through a reorg probably about a month or so ago.
So I actually did sit under our VP of marketing but it's now got shifted, where some of the members of marketing that are left report to our VP of sales and growth or revenue or whatever, they're calling it now.
And then I because I am so focused on retention so under the VP of Cs but it was under marketing as well before.
Uh, so I just wanted to call that out.
Alright, another question here from Andrea do either of you have customer events planned in 2023 in person?
Roundtables product, service training series, customer appreciation dinners, Yes, 100%.
We have got incredible events, team.
Shout out to Jackie and Amy.
They're fantastic.
We just given our customer base and our product.
We partner very closely with the Salesforce events.
So, we're at dreamforce.
We're at the world tours, you will find us there.
And with each of those events were doing dinners the night before typically before the event.
And we're inviting, you know, key prospects and customers to those dinners to meet in person to be able to have Roundtable.
Shins around product and challenges.
They're seeing out there that hopefully we can help address.
So that's one thing we're doing.
We also have a series called Taste of qualified where we invite prospects and customers virtually to join us for wine.
Tasting, will usually have a featured winery.
That's pouring, the wine.
And we have shipped them, the wine in advance.
That's a lot of fun as well.
I would say, that's more on the event side and then, of course, the events that I am running from the, the customer marketing side is those customer appreciation days.
We talked about We're also just kicking off our MVP programs, so we will be going quarterly to meet with those MVPs in person, we have identified the top cities, they're based in, so we will be hosting those in person.
Meetups to do some product education, as well as some customer marketing.
So we will be doing photography, photography video, as well as interviews and two out of four of those events are aligned with Salesforce events Amazing.
Yeah, any thoughts Nick to add?
Yeah, I mean we definitely plan to do some things.
We are very limited team right now with four people down from 10.
So we're cutting back on a lot of our efforts mostly from a like bigger event standpoint.
However, I am a big believer in small curated elevated experiences, both VIP experiences for your customers but also from The prospect level because I think that the amount of micro content short-form content that you can ultimately create from that and repurposing redistribute at scale is incredibly important.
So it's something that I definitely plan to do it.
Just it's going to be a lot less than what we initially expected.
And that's real.
It's probably real for a lot of companies right now.
So I appreciate both perspectives there.
Richard has a question for us.
The number one, Pitfall you see in today's customer marketing World, whether that is over or under prioritizing certain initiatives and ideas.
Yeah, I mean, I feel like it's for us like we're trying to do less honestly, it's tough when you are a Very stretched team.
Why do 10 different things?
Like, there's like 10 15, 20 different things.
I want to do, but they're going to be half asked if I do them because we don't have the resources to be able to support that.
So, why not do 567 things?
Really, really well, and be proud of that, and so I think for me like I am okay with doing less and it sounds weird saying that because like I am not usually that type of person, but I think the quality over quantity.
A station starts to come in and it becomes a lot more imperative to be like, listen, I did these six things but honestly, they drove tons of business, tons of renewals early, renewals all these things and you feel really proud of it versus saying, I did these 15 different things and seven of them flopped.
So that's just a couple of my thoughts.
Yeah, I would say for me it's you know now that we have got sort of this content engine built, we were pumping out case studies were pumping out videos.
I really want to start focusing on the next phase of that so it's focusing on how sales is actually using the content is that's making a difference.
I want you know, we talked about attribution that's something I really want to figure out next year.
And so, for me, something I am starting to do is actually go into Salesforce.
We're running reports.
We're seeing all the opportunities in stage 3 looking at The notes within those opportunities and actually proactively suggesting case studies, and slides, that they should be leveraging those conversations.
So that's sort of something I hadn't had the time to do before that.
Something I want to focus on more now and moving forward.
And then again, yeah.
Figuring out, you know, how are these stories traveling?
Which stories are working?
Well, how do we produce more stories like that?
You know what, what are we missing as far as our inventory of stories?
I want to start diving more into those numbers.
You know I know Top my head, there's certain sub industries that we don't have as much representation as we should.
So that's something else.
I want to get my hands around as well as you know any stories were missing in terms of product so you know we just launched qualified meetings.
So that's something I want to be focused on is getting those stories of customers that are successfully using that piece of our product.
So good, thanks for sharing Bill's.
Got a question here.
Nick.
It sounds like you're generating a lot of content across.
A lot of channels though.
You did mention Focus right now, which is great?
What have you found?
Most effective?
What do you think will be effective even if it's not yet, driving metrics?
Yeah, I mean, for me, LinkedIn is my number one channel so, and I was able to fortunately build up a pretty decent sized audience there.
I have almost 42 thousand followers currently And, so I have been able to initially I Niche down really, really hard on field marketing at the start of the pandemic and it was I was the only one talking about it on all of LinkedIn.
Like how does it actually contribute to a revenue organization and so people were interested in that and then I branched out to ABM then I branched out to a lot of different topics.
And now more recently, I am talking about like, the customer marketing piece in its.
It's honestly, it's been really, really great.
And if you look at the content that I create, I actually Talk about Alice in 98% of that content and Leadership internally isn't happy about that, by the way.
But I think it's important because if I know that for 2022, I am going to drive about 15 to 20 million views on my content alone, organically on LinkedIn, think about how many people are clicking my profile.
So you know on LinkedIn where it says, every 90 days you can see how many people click your profile.
So I have about 15,000 people that view my profile.
Every 90 days on a rolling thing.
So the first thing that they do when they cook their profile, my profile is they see.
Oh cool.
He's at Alice.
Oh, what's a Liz?
Oh, they're gifting platform.
Oh, we use a competitor.
Oh, oh, we're thinking of budgeting for that, for 2023, they click it.
That's where the self-reported attribution standpoint comes in and all I am trying to do is share learnings of things that I am working on different types of projects like nothing is off limits for me.
And again, it's probably something that leadership isn't always happy about but I don't share anything that's negative.
You know numbers that I shouldn't be.
I just share projects that I am working on lessons, learn successes failures because people don't like to talk about failures because they feel judge.
I will talk about failures all day long because it's about the learnings that you do from those failures to move you forward.
And that's all I have really tried to do.
It's been in March of twenty 20, 30 be three years of me, creating content on LinkedIn, and so I have now doubled down on Tick, Tock and Instagram rails.
And all I am doing is taking my written LinkedIn content and recording myself on video talking about what that text post was, and then Distributing it on, you know, YouTube shorts, rails, and Tick-Tock.
So it actually doesn't take me a ton of time to get this content out there.
It's more time, actually engaging in replying to every single person that comments on my stuff.
But that's how you build those real relationships.
That's how you get in those conversations when someone's thinking about your product, or service, or whatever it is, it's the relationships that you build in the Mint section that ultimately moved to DMS.
Ultimately move to inbound.
Requests ultimately remove the comes to like job offers down the road as well.
Like it can do a lot from you from a branding perspective in like building an audience, but you have to deliver value versus being that person that just is out there, pitching their company every day.
Such good, call-outs, tons of gems.
There.
I am curious are both of you?
So you mentioned, Nick, you're using Tick-Tock and these other social channels for customer marketing and other things.
Serena are you finding that successful as well wear for qualified?
Are you all exploring other social channels is linked in a good channel for qualified?
Yeah, so I would say LinkedIn is definitely our number one.
Channel.
And we're thinking about paid and organic.
And what we do is we will always promote our stories as well as our videos customer content on LinkedIn and will encourage our customers to do the same because, of course, we have got our audience, they have got theirs and so if we're able to package that up for them, they were able to share out on their channels and even you know within the folks then the story if they share out, you know, that's just amplifying the story.
So I would say that's definitely our number one channel.
That's great.
So you all actually create the customer testimonial and then you quip your customer with that content with the asset so that they can amplify.
Exactly.
It's a great tactic.
Okay, awesome.
Well, I have got one other question here, and then we can start wrapping this up.
If anybody has any other questions, please drop them in the tab.
One question I have got is around just budget and headcount for customer marketing.
How do you justify the budget?
The head counts if you want to do a campaign or some sort of program that requires a budget.
How do you justify this?
Maybe this is tied to that attribution.
Note that we talked about earlier but just curious how it works for you all.
Yeah, I think the budget conversation aligns with the strategies, so it's kind of going into each quarter and understanding like what programs do we think need to be a priority this quarter?
What have we noticed?
That moves the needle from the previous quarter.
What do we think?
We have done enough of that?
We can kind of put a pause on and then, of course, understanding all the numbers that align to them.
So for me, a big Focus for us this year was producing content, so we made the budget ask for Like building out our own Studio within our obvious.
So, we got a lot of photography equipment.
We got a lot of video equipment, but being able to set all of that up.
We have now hosted three photo shoots, and we have captured 50 plus customers.
So I think for us that's been a huge win.
A lot of people might be thinking, well, you know, she's mentioned photography a lot.
You know, why is that so important for us?
If you go on our website, you're not going to see stock photography.
You're going to see beautiful smiling.
Happy customers and those are real.
Real people, real stats, real quotes, real videos, and I think that's just so much more meaningful, it's so much more authentic.
And I think that's made a really, really big difference for us.
So, yeah, I think it's just really trying to get your hands around.
Like, what is going to be the priority figuring out what those numbers look like and then making the case for it.
So that's been my Approach.
Yeah, I love, I love that.
That idea, honestly, we don't have it on office unfortunately anymore, but like, I would absolutely like, if anyone that's listening, like, go steal that idea because like, I have also thought about that, and because we do use stock images on her website, but like it's such a brilliant idea and I love that and I will always remember that now.
But for me, like, I am a one-person team.
Like, again, we are like super like strap.
From a budget standpoint from a resource standpoint to like usually what I have to do is provide kind of like a business justification for what I am looking to do, and I am usually borrowing money honestly from our acquisition, acquisition side of the business.
So like maybe I am taking some from Paid search or yo are paid spend or maybe I am taking it from our event budget.
It's been up until I switched over to the customer marketing side.
We actually didn't have anyone in cusp of marketing.
Everyone was focused solely on acquisition up until like I would say like five or six months ago.
So it's also you know I think 2023 will change it will have its own budget line item and thing but for this year I have just been like stealing from people left and right when I need money.
Love about those notes and just the realistic also situation Nick that you're communicating because I think that's something you know it's like what can we do when you have a budget when you don't have budget, you got to get really creative right?
So I appreciate that a ton.
All right, well we're going to be wrapping up here and I would love to end with just a note of any advice or encouragement that you have for all of Us as we're going into 2023, we're going to get into the holidays.
What's something that each of you would leave with us?
I would say double down on content creation, like with your customers with, with anyone.
Like I think that.
Yo and I qualified like does a fantastic job with this?
Because again, like I see them everywhere, I see the content that they create everywhere, I spoke at their event, you know, not too long ago, Aunt insulin on content.
Yeah.
So like I think, I think if anything like, you know, figure out how to create content, whether it's through customer stories, whether it's do organic, Nick paid whatever like utilize all these things and then double down on like the short form aspect of it and then like figure out how to distribute that at scale.
Yeah, that's really good.
I think something having done customer marketing for a while.
Now that I am constantly challenging myself to think about is, how do we do it different, you know, there's, we're so used to seeing case studies.
We're so used to videos, you know, and all those things sort of the standard pillars, which aren't bad, they're fantastic, but I want to spend more time next year, thinking about like, what is that?
Next big idea that we can offer our customers, that gets them really, really excited.
So, We have got some ideas, we have been throwing around internally, you know, customer appreciation day was one of them.
Revamping our customer page is going to be one of them, but, you know, now that we have got all this great content, you know, can we put it in the form of this incredible customer campaign that we do next year in?
Does that look like out-of-home?
Does that look like an event presence?
Does that look like a customer only event where, you know, to your point, Nick, your stories aren't talking about your product but it's, you know, could be just the customer sharing their stories.
So giving them the ability in the For me to do that.
I think would be really exciting.
So that will be a challenge I take on for next year.
So good.
Wow, thank you so much.
Serena Nick, it's been a pleasure to have you here.
Thank you so much for everything that you're doing and the knowledge and wisdom, you have shared with us today.
All the best happy holidays to both of you.
All right, so thank you everybody for joining today's session.
We have an interview tomorrow with Kevin Lee.
He is the SVP of marketing for oyster, and we're going to dive into another topic, that's very relevant.
In to 2023 the power synergies of brand building and actually team building, and they're oftentimes two sides of the same coin, and so he's going to dive into that.
Don't miss it we have the link right above so go ahead and click on that and until then have a wonderful rest of your day or week.
If I don't see you stay positive, stay bright, take care.
Did a full 180 crazy?
It's me.
Don't show up.
Anything could stop me.