Did a full 180 crazy?
Don't come out.
Anything could stop me.
Hi everyone.
Happy Wednesday, it's great to be here.
It's great to see some of you trickling, in feel free to drop in what city you're tuning in from.
I am here in Ewa Beach, Hawaii, and this is about 30 minutes away from Honolulu in Oahu.
Can't complain about the weather right now.
It is, it is chillier.
But, you know, it's still probably around high 60s or so.
So, anyway, I am so excited today.
We have got Alex Kelly director of digital marketing at serous joining us today, and we're going to be talking about attention-grabbing B2B Marketing in a very noisy Market.
There's a lot of efficiencies and different things that marketers are thinking about, as we're moving into 2023 and things, got to change the way that we Market.
The way that we work the way that we Singe and meet our buyers, across the buying Journey need to change.
And So within the constraints of 2023, it breeds creativity.
And I think this is the opportunity where we can hear from Alex on some of the Innovative approaches and ways in which he is able to Foster creativity and thinking with his team's.
So with that, I would love to invite Alex to the stage.
Please join me.
Hello, thank you.
Hello.
Thanks so much.
For having me.
I am doing well.
It's been a pretty slow roll to the week, but excited to kick things up in the middle here.
Nice.
Right.
Right before the holidays.
So, right, before everything just shuts down again.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Thanks for even just showing up really, really appreciate it.
And I am really excited about the conversation that we're going to dive into today.
But before we jump in, there's a few fun facts that I would love to jump right into And you know, all I will start with my fun fact, and then we will go into yours but I have got a different way of getting your fun facts notified.
So this is Allyson Felix and I basically played basketball with her.
We went to the same high school and it was funny because like, she literally could not make any basketball shot, like it would go straight off the backboard, but she was the fastest one down on each side.
I would have offense and defense to the end of the court.
So that's my fun fact for you.
Alex, we got some fun facts and you're a musician.
I am yes I study music in college and then I thought that's what I was going to do with my life and then you know, decided maybe I wasn't a hundred percent cut out for that life.
And when I moved back to New Jersey, I sort of fell into what I am doing now, which is very different but kind of similar in some ways.
Nice, nice.
And I know we were hoping to get a life singing session, but maybe another time.
Yeah, it wasn't quite feeling up to it after the last week and a half that I have had but I would have loved it all good.
All good.
Okay, so I have got another fun fact, sort of poll that we can do here.
It's called to it's will be three truths and One Lie and if we could pull that up on stage.
So there're these facts which some of these you just mentioned that are true about you?
But if you all want to vote, which one is not true about Alex, Go ahead and drop your votes.
Majored in music in college takes on graphic design.
Gig has twin boys, just got married.
So go ahead and drop in your votes.
This is where the Jeopardy music comes in doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo, doo-doo-doo-doo-doo.
Okay.
All right, we got votes so just got married.
What's not true?
Alex.
I definitely do not take on graphic design gigs.
Nobody wants to pay me for that.
That would be, that would be an Abomination.
We're kind of playing.
We're splitting hairs here.
I got we had our wedding on Saturday, but it was after several covid.
Delays.
We were supposed to get married back in March of 2020, right?
When the world shut down, and we pushed it one year, which ended up not being nearly long enough.
So we ended up having to delay it.
It once again, and we decided to do it in December of this year.
So we legally got married in 2021 but it was very small thing and only our parents are there.
And so we finally had our wedding this Saturday, which is also why I am feeling not quite up to destroying my vocal cords.
Even more from all the singing and dancing we were doing.
Wow.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
What a big deal?
Yeah, and the we do have twin boys.
We have identical twins who are one-year olds, and they were able to come for a little bit.
So they we they got pushed down the aisle by our nephew which was definitely a highlight for both of us.
Well, I hope you get a ton of rest and recovery coming out of that.
Thank you.
Yeah.
So let us Jump Right In to know you even more.
I would love to dive into your story.
Getting into B2B marketing.
And you know why, why beaten we have marketing wide Tech.
You probably could have gone to the b2c direction but walk us through your journey and how you got to serous.
Yeah, well everybody grows up.
Definitely wanted to be a B2B marketer when they're a child, they dream about it right now.
I studied music in college.
I thought that's the route that I wanted to go is The only thing I was really all that passionate about and spending a lot of my time, just performing and writing and doing all the things that I just found a lot of joy in and creatively and in school and all throughout college.
And when I graduated in started writing more and thought, that's what I wanted to go.
I was still living down in Virginia and I kind of hit this point where I was either going to move to Nashville and really make that a concerted effort or I would already been From home in New Jersey for seven or so years.
A few years after college and I kind of wanted to go back for a bit and just see everybody that I had grown up with that, that was back in the area and my family was nearby.
And so when I, when I came back, I kind of fell into working with a really close friend of mine, doing some project management work at a mortgage company and it was a lot of requirements Gathering.
It was helping to organize their projects and keep them on task and just kind of help out wherever I could.
And some of the things that we ended up taking on.
We're very much in the digital marketing realm.
It was you know we were helping to build this new retail forward website.
They had Marketo install, but nobody really knew how to administrate it or use it.
So I just kept raising my hand and saying, yeah, sure, I will try to teach myself how to do this, or we just got more involved in some of these kinds of projects because we were fairly fresh out of college and willing to take on some of these more.
Tech, heavy task and I really just enjoyed it.
I liked it, the things I was I was taking on I liked the challenge of it.
It was, it was also really fun to just try to learn as much as I could and teach myself what I needed to know, to do the job on the day, and it was a lot of, you know, reading Hub, spots blog and all that kind of stuff and just trying to learn as much as I because I never took any marketing courses and in college.
And, you know, after a few years there and you know, through that time I was given the opportunity to take on more direct ownership over these things.
I hired some folks and got to learn from a couple of others who are in the marketing realm.
And I really wanted to try to make that my core focus and moved over to working at an agency for a time.
It was a hotspot partner, inbound marketing agency and great way to learn a lot really fast working with a ton of different types of clients, but it was not exactly for me that kind of model.
Where you're, you know, a team of one or two taking on eight or nine, clients in all these different Industries and doing everything for them, including all the account management and the strategy and the content creation, and the implementation and all that stuff.
So I after that, I was lucky enough to get connected with the team of data dog.
And, you know, I joined the demand generation team there which was just a really phenomenal sort of solidification of My understanding of B2B marketing and how a business like that can run and how a marketing team at a business like that can run.
And, you know, I worked with a team of really awesome marketers across all the different teams that we're supporting that business.
And it was just a really, really awesome experience being there at the time that I was there and that was, you know, somewhere around the range of 250 to 600 plus employees and it Just under a year and a half that I was there.
So it was rapid growth.
There was a lot of success.
It was, it was just really fascinating to see how they ran.
And I kind of found myself missing a little bit of that chaos from the agency days when I was just getting my hands on everything and trying things out and seeing what worked, and I got introduced to the VP of marketing at serous through somebody that I had worked with and at data dog.
And, and just really liked what he had to say, and they were a smaller, team, smaller organization, really high appetite for experimentation.
And how the product is there were just over 100 maybe just a hair over 100 people, and they were not all in New York.
It was, you know, the entire product organization was remote.
There was a handful of people starting to start an in the UK and the rest of us were in New York City.
Office wasn't even nearly 100 people, so it felt a lot smaller and it felt Very contained in that way.
And I really liked that and then marketing team was pretty small.
We were with the VP maybe you know, five people or so.
And then we had an editorial team that was maybe three or four or think at the time.
And so there was just a lot of going on.
You're trying to figure a lot of things out and I like that energy about it and it was also just the last four and a half years that I have been here, just been a great learning experience and really great growing.
You know, experience to opportunity to grow and stretch myself and a bunch of different ways.
And, you know, now we're a little over 400 employees and, you know, a lot more people in the UK and now we're fully distributed and a global team which is just really, really interesting Evolutions over that time.
But yeah, not exactly what I thought it was going to do, but I have loved the, the Journey of it's been really, really fascinating plus I still The do creative things, but I love.
Hmm.
So tell us about what you do at serous.
Yeah.
So I head up the digital Bob bit of a misnomer, but I am the director of digital marketing, which started as purely taking ownership, over the digital team, which, you know, we had events and digital, which is kind of everything non-event.
And right now, I had up a team or help manage a team of around 10 marketers that is everything from digital, which is are always on digital programming or growth engine for inbounds coming in through the website.
It's email marketing and have an inbound SDR.
That's a part of that team, but we also that the team is also making up a demand generation more campaign, specific or account-based efforts to help support particular verticals.
I now lead our field marketing team, which is our event strategy across book, North America, and a Mia.
As well as customer marketing.
So all of our sort of enablement and dissemination of engaging content and materials for our existing customers as well.
So it's a bit broader than it started.
It's quite a bit broader than it started but it's, you know, it's kind of grown organically over that time, and we try to make it feel really cohesive as much as we can and really tie these different areas of the team together to make sure that we're all sort of capitalizing on what we're able to.
To do in tandem with each other not just individually as separate groups, how is your current marketing team structured?
So I helped oversee that, that part of the organization, which is those marketing functions.
The more I would say campaign or Channel specific execution arms, digital demand generation field marketing and customer marketing as well as a web developer that helps oversee our various marketing web properties.
And then Of in parallel to us.
Next to us our VP of content oversees, all of the content and editorial social and design and creative resources.
So we partner really closely with that part of the team, and we are very dependent on them for a lot of the creative decisions and execution to help facilitate the programs that we're trying to run.
But I tend to focus mostly or at least I hope much heavier on the new business growth of the organization.
And a lot of the programs to help support that growth.
Wow, that's a lot of responsibility on your side.
It's been fun.
It's certainly been challenging especially over the last few years but the challenge has been you know really rewarding part A lot has changed over the last, you know, three or so.
Years going remote, you know, pretty much the entirety of the team.
One person on the team today on my side of the team today was here.
In the office with us everything.
Everyone else has been brought into the team since which is just sort of fascinating change to see.
But yeah, it's been, it's been a lot of stretching myself.
A lot of trying to learn and trying to learn as much as I can and take on some of these bigger challenges but that's what also keeps it really interesting.
That's awesome.
Well, jumping into the topic today, of attention-grabbing B2B marketing.
How are you thinking about this?
Especially going into 2023?
This is going to be more important than ever.
At the same time we don't want to just be noise, right?
As marketers, how can we create meaning and really that differentiated unique type of messaging, So what are your thoughts?
You know, in this topic going into 2023?
Yeah, it's it is a challenge for everybody.
It's challenge for every Organization no matter what you're selling, what your who your customer is.
We as consumers are inundated with countless messages and marketing campaigns.
And, you know, just information overload across every channel.
Not even.
At, but our expectations have changed dramatically as consumers.
It's not even just the noise.
It's also, you know, we consume information and media so (differently) than we were even a handful of years ago in some of these cases.
But if you look at what Netflix and the streaming model is done for our consumption of media, if you look at how organizations are trying to adapt to that, you know, you can look at the changing landscape of how, you know, entertainment and movies are created and distributed it.
Its it is monumentally different from the experiences that we sought out as consumers, you know in the Years prior and our expectations of how we consume information and find information has changed.
Because of that we expect a very similar type of experience and delivery model from the businesses that were looking to consume from.
You know, as marketers, we create a lot of content, we are creating a lot of information, and we are looking to distribute that across all the Channels.
And we're always trying to find the ones that are connecting with our audience or where our audience is engaging.
But that landscape changes really rapidly and the I guess we look back you know, since the early 2000s that inbound marketing model of sort of owned media and these creating these platforms have content awareness and distribution where your you will create gated content offers.
And you will surround that with blog, Posts and you will rank for specific keywords and you will bring in this organic traffic and grow some more sustainably over time.
There's a lot of really good ideas in that are just a lot more challenging today because of the changing algorithms of what actually ranks and what Google is going to reward over other content.
It also is challenging because every organization is following the same Playbook.
We're all trying to do the same kinds of things, which means we're all creating the same articles for the same words in the same phrases, and We're always trying to outrank each other for that same traffic.
But Google is also sending less traffic back to your website.
Then they were in years prior because they want people to remain in their platform and every social media, platform acts, the same way, they're prioritizing the things that keep them there.
Because that eyeball in, that platform, is more valuable to them than some of the ad dollars or whatever the case is that you're creating for your audience, they don't, they don't want to prioritize your value, they want to prioritize their own, so they will charge you for the same amount of awareness and an activity than they otherwise would have organically.
So all of these things are making it a lot harder to not just get the attention of your audience but to deliver information in a way that they actually care about and that they actually want to consume and interact with.
So what we have spent a lot of time, you know, doing and really it's very important parcel with what our platform kind of does, and we try to eat our own dog food as much as we can, which is We create content that we find incredibly interesting and, and more eye-catching and interactive, and then we find ways of refactoring that for whatever that Channel or the median is.
Because at the end of the day, your product message can be really compelling.
But if you don't have the eyeballs of that audience, they're never going to get there.
They're never going to find it.
So you need to get their attention first.
And then, you could start to translate that into ways of really understanding what your product, and what your ultimate.
You is to them as a consumer but it's really an attention economy at the moment.
And we're really just trying to figure out.
How do we, how do we combat the competition, which is not just the people that we compete with, on a product basis?
It is competition in the forms of people would rather spend their time scrolling through social media, then engaging with your business.
How do you play in that space?
They'd rather be looking at videos that are entertaining.
I am versus videos that might be relevant to what your product offers.
So how do you make your product messaging more entertaining and more like the things that they actually want to seek out all?
These things are sort of converging into this very difficult space of his digital competition.
So some of the things that we're trying to do our take our editorial Direction, and we have been doing this for quite some time, in the team is creating some really interesting.
Arresting interesting stuff, but our editorial direction is much broader.
It's not fully rooted in our buyer.
It's not fully rooted in our product.
It is just interesting stories told visually and through interactive lenses that is also sort of passive showcase for what our product can do.
So if they find that interest, and we're able to connect that interest it with the Right audience, then there're ways of us, re-engaging them with things that are more and more relevant to the business and the product further On the cycle, but we're always trying to lead with that eye-catching moment, that interactive element, that just gets them to lean in just a little bit.
Even though it's through a, through a screen in a digital channel, thank you.
I think you explained the landscape really well and the challenges of a very noisy attention-grabbing type of landscape that we have to deal with today.
What process are you working with your team to get to that?
Type of messaging that's differentiated and meaningful entertaining.
You know, I don't think the mechanisms there are two dissimilars What is ultimately necessary?
In all cases is to understand the customer and understand what they care about and what they're interested in, as it relates to their role.
But also expanding that lends to what they just find interest in and what they engage with in there, they're sort of day-to-day lives.
You know, the, the feedback loop sort of insight Gathering process is very much.
Still, a research based effort, it's having conversations with people.
Trying to observe them in their natural habitat, it's just taking conversations in a more natural Direction versus it being purely.
Well, how would you solve this problem and what do you feel when you experience that problem?
And it's not 100% around?
What is your product?
How to understand?
How your product can solve for a problem?
It's also just, you know, what are you interested in?
What are you seeing today?
That is really catching your eye.
What do you where do you go for information?
Where do you turn to that?
You trust who Are the people that you really perk up when they're speaking about a topic that's related to the things that you care about.
And if you can kind of converge, those topics of Interest with the people of influence and the channels of connectivity.
That's really where the magic happens but you really can't get there.
Unless you're either having direct conversations or trying to, you know, find that research out and more mass-market ways of either existing research or conducting your own Roan on a more broad basis but it's got to come from your audience.
Otherwise, you're going to be led astray by the time, the tactics and strategies that got us to where we are today which is not going to get us through the next, you know, three five ten years as the landscape continues to evolve and change.
So we were to get a little more tactical on how you go about to gather the research and the insights.
Are you regularly doing customer interviews, or what are ways in which you are able to get those insights?
Yeah, couple of ways either direct conversations were its it is sort of structured more than a fact-finding mission.
We are, we want to speak with, you just about your behaviors, and we want to understand what makes you tick.
We want to understand, you know what you do in your day-to-day, both inside work and out and how we can use that to start a triangulate as we interview more, more people, you can also create content anchors that help to capture those insights on a more ongoing basis.
You know, we're doing it right now, you're having a conversation with me.
I am a director of marketing or digital marketer at an organization of a particular size and profile.
I am talking about the things.
I am doing and what I find interesting and what got me to where I am, these are all things that we can you could feed back into your overall strategy of.
Okay.
Well how do I use that to change?
How I distribute a message to somebody like Alex in his role at as organization?
And so when these mechanisms exist and you're constantly speaking with and recording and Gathering insights from people that you ultimately are looking to engage with all of that.
Is it accessible.
Information.
All of that becomes fodder for each change in the strategy or change in the message or a change in the tactic.
Also, going directly to the sales organization listening to a ton of gone calls and you know, hot trying to look for certain keywords or phrases or things that topic areas that are of interest and to see what kinds of organizations are speaking about things or, you know, not trying to gain Insight through a game of telephone but going right to the source.
What are they?
On these calls that you could use in your own messaging more, you're using their words the, you know, the better off things are going to be as long as you're able to figure out how to package those things up.
So, you know, there's I would say, existing mechanisms in kind of all businesses to gain those insights.
Somebody in the company is having regular conversations with your audience and it's really figuring out how to tap into that or as a marketing organization, create platforms.
Like this, that allow you to speak with people that are, you know, Know your target audience or subject matter experts in your area that you can, then start to sort of feed those insights back into the broader team in a way that is more accessible or more.
Distributable.
So okay, II.
Love this.
And thank you for validating that.
Even this opportunity right now is sort of fact-finding.
B2B marketers is one of our targets, right?
So just to ask you a question, what type of messages resonate with you?
What type of going into 2023, again, you're probably getting hit up, DMS and Linkedin.
Emails are inundated.
I mean, that's the world of what a lot of Experience of beauty marketing.
But what's going to touch you differently?
What's going to grab your attention?
Alex, it is so difficult.
It's so hard.
And I know, I know full, well, I my attention to my inbox or, you know, the amount of phone calls that I get in a day, my attention can't always turn to those things and, and full transparency, I think a lot of folks, you know, A lot of folks know inherently know this and feel it in their personal lives and just generally we know this, and we also know that the tactics work but I have a hard time getting connected to a message in those mediums where it's somebody picking up the phone and calling me directly where it.
There's no sort of Preamble or there's no pre-existing awareness of what it is.
We're actually trying to The phone down to talk about or same thing in my inbox, my I think like most people, my email is a disaster site and it is so hard to find the things that are irrelevant.
Let alone, the things that are not what works for me personally.
And I can't say that's the same for anybody else is things like this.
When there is a platform of information that is Really high quality that I am able to go out and seek information from rather than it being pushed in front of me when I connect with a source more than I connect with a single episode or a single topic and I come back time and time again, more often than not, I am going to go to them.
I am going to, I am going to reach out when I have a need or a challenge or something.
That I think they can help me with because they have already proven that they can help me with it because Hi, I have listened to or watched or engaged with things over the course of several months.
It could be several years.
We think brought on drifts for first ballot early on, in my time at saris and I had been listening to their, their, their stuff and an engaging with their content for years prior to that.
And I just really had a sort of I wanted to be able to check it out in a way that was more advantageous to them.
But I was never to Into until I was.
And then when I was, I went directly to them, it wasn't a sales call, and there's, there're countless examples of that.
We're usually when I get to the point of making a decision of being able to solve a problem, there's already a short list in my mind and that short list is probably pretty short because there're names that I recognize there's people that I feel like I can trust even if I have never spoken to them because I have spent the time and I put in the time to engage and consumed as much as I can, which is ultimately how I got to where I am I learned from others, I didn't, I didn't know any of this before I started, it's here.
It's all in service of engaging with others.
So, the more I am able to do that or sort of put out a bat signal in a community of people that I feel like I can trust, their opinions, it starts to narrow down the list.
So the message is really difficult.
The more that it's led by sort of entertainment and education and a Spurt.
He's the better off.
It, it lands with me but it takes a lot of time, and we don't always have time as marketers or especially not of the sales professionals which makes it all the harder.
So the more you can invest early on the better off you're going to be you know a year or two years from now but it's that's really the challenge that everybody is up against.
It's good.
All right, so if anyone's got questions for Alex, feel free to drop them in QA looks like a has one question.
What are some tactics you have used to build brand awareness, especially at a time when budgets are getting tighter, yeah.
Our CEO has said this a couple of times in different contexts and there's this mentality of, you know, champagne results for beer money.
We're just because budgets tighten, doesn't necessarily mean that the, the execution of something needs to suffer, right?
On.
In most cases, when constraints are added into a process, it actually breathes a higher level of creativity because you have to be really creative.
Native.
And in some cases Scrappy to solve a problem.
And that's where a lot of the really robust and sort of meaningful ideas can come out of.
So the tactics might be the same in essence, but the way in which you execute, those things might just have an added layer of creativity added into that and I guess some examples of that.
We had a We had thrown a an event a few years ago for a product launch and you know, we weren't trying to do something so astronomically expensive, but we were trying to do something really meaningful, and we were trying to do something that really helps to play into the message of the day and the message of the day was all about creating experiences and that experience ultimately is what matters, right?
It's the things that we experience are what make them real the experiences that we seek out in The world are meaningful, the difference between a good experience in a bad experience, is so Monumental.
But both of those things stick out in our mind for different reasons, and the team spent a countless amount of time and putting their heads together, really?
Trying to figure out how to nail this thing?
And some of it was, was not thrown together.
It was, it was just done in such a way that Illustrated that concept, it was, you know, a bad experience entering into this venue versus A sort of red carpet experience.
The bad experience was just Solo cups and, you know, Gruff looking people and a dingy coat rack and a bat back kitchen.
But that helped illustrate exactly what we were trying to go for without having to spend even more money to help.
Really, you know, gussied up that part of the experience.
We also had thrown together a stand-in for a DMV to help illustrate the sort of antiquated ways that people create content.
And it's just like, brought this space to light, but it was all, you know, is, you know, rope and pipes and stuff that would kind of pull together in a really crafty way.
And we threw up a web page for that.
Using Sarah's in like an hour.
The designer did an awesome job, making it look purposefully bad.
But we just had a really fun afternoon trying to do that as quickly as we could.
Because they realize, hey we put a URL in the back.
Is this thing that were printing out?
Can you throw something up on the website?
Yeah, we could do that.
So, I mean it's finding ways of just having fun with it and creative executions on tight, constraints, actually make things feel like they're more meaningful as much as they as much as these flashy things people kind of they can see through the, the shine in a lot of cases and it just doesn't feel quite as real, you know, I think other ways to build awareness are just your content doesn't have to look and feel premium for it to be really meaningful and to be really authentic, and Be really entertaining.
I mean, look at any book.
It's just words on a page, but the feelings that generates are so varied that it's, it's insane.
I have a stack of books on my desk right behind my monitor.
That would be really, really sad to show people, but it's just, that is a mechanism.
That is very Lo-Fi in a lot of cases, but it's such a, it's still building a meaningful connection.
So, you know, there're ways of doing events, there're ways of doing virtual events in a really cost effective way.
And just having conversations with people, one-on-one to breed really creative ideas is a good place to start and say That's great.
Thank you for that.
I, you know, I wanted to dive a little bit into.
I remember you talking about your collaboration with design and how you can work with different parts of the marketing org, that maybe you wouldn't normally do like a strategy brainstorm with or something like that, but you were talking about how its arrows, you all have done that and have had great outcomes results come out of it.
So could you describe your creative process to get to some of the ideas that you were even sharing?
Yeah.
It's fun because it's always evolving but it's, you know, I think it's marketing organizations for marketers and marketing teams we can think about things in a really linear fashion where we might have a sort of primary message that we're going for we create this long document of narrative, or We create this, Google doc with all of our messaging and maybe it's a blog post, maybe it's something longer, and we send that over to a designer when it's all said and done, we have created the strategy.
We have created the we know who the audience is, we have done all the research, we have created all the copy, and we send it over to somebody to essentially produce off of that.
Where it's just taking, you take this thing that I have already decided I am doing.
And can you make it look better?
It's and presentable, and we have found Time and time again, that the earlier in the process is that we Engage The Design Team.
The, the more involved, they are in the actual strategy development in the, the investigation of ideas the better off the end result is, you know, its it just opens up the conversation and ways that we might not have expected.
They will ask questions that we didn't think about.
They will ask us why a lot, and we More you ask the world.
Why?
And really dig into that.
Sometimes you don't always have an answer and maybe that's telling, right?
And then we need to kind of go back to the drawing board and figure some stuff out.
But having them involved.
From day one before it's, you know, really a solidified idea before it's something that is more concrete.
It is just a problem to solve designers and visual thinkers.
They think about solving problems in a very different way.
So instead of it being a very linear production, Yes, we try to make it more cyclical, we try to make it more collaborative from the beginning where that brief is put together.
There's a lot of iteration on just even the sort of underlying needs and you know feelings that we're trying to evoke or audiences that we're looking to go after what do we know about them?
How do we put all of that into this, this sort of shared understanding and this brief and from there, you know, the copy and the wireframe?
The design all feed off of each other and there's a lot of going back and refactoring things that aren't working.
There's a lot of sparking new ideas throughout the process, and then we ultimately end up in a place that's just more fun and more interesting and that shines through to the audience more.
(So) than even the team that's creating it, you know, an example of that is, we recently were trying to create essentially, create more use case content.
We were trying to Showcase more or of how, you know, content created in Sarah's helps to solve for very particular pain points in the in these certain kinds of Industries, and we have examples from clients, we have a lot of examples of things that were created, and we just wanted to find a different way of presenting it, so we, it was pitched to us, as this idea, to essentially create a fake business, a fake brand with fake brand guidelines, with a very outlandish product, and they had the very same challenges that a lot of (Is) have and here's exactly how they did it.
And what that piece of content looks like and what their messaging looks like in context and it allowed us to create this really fun story and really Branch off of that in very different ways but the end result is the same.
We connect it to a pain point, that a very real business will have and it's very much also shows what exactly they can do to solve for this problem and ultimately connect that back to a product value.
This product is called the, the ripe So detector, so that you always get to that.
Exact ripe avocado before it goes, starts to go bad in your drawer and I think people just had fun with it.
We had fun creating it and the team just had a lot of fun ideas to bacon at this, and we would never have come up with that on our own.
We just wouldn't have we would have gone a little bit more traditional, which ultimately wouldn't have really felt like saris.
And we're thankful to have partners that really push us to think outside of the box on that.
So good.
All right, we have a couple of more questions that have come through saline is asking, what is top of mind for you go into 2023?
What are some things you will be doubling down on ya.
We have spent a lot of time over the last few months thinking about our event strategy.
And you know what has been working for us?
What hasn't necessarily been working quite as well?
So we are spending a lot of time.
Time thinking through.
How do we take that same ethos of creating really interesting digital experiences and make those come to life in a physical space as well?
Or at least make sure that the same things are true.
That the same constraints are there that the same, the same sort of guiding principles are there?
And, you know, as we have been sort of rebuilding and building out our field marketing team and thinking through our representation and Different markets and sort of building the plan for next year.
I find there's just so much opportunity for us to think about the in-person representation of the brand.
And how does that lead to the conversations that we want to have?
Yes, the operational sort of underpinnings to that is something.
I have spent personally a lot of time on to make sure that we're buttoning, things up in the right ways and that the strategy is more sound.
But you know, the creative execution of that is so important to it is the first People see when they're walking by, they see your booth.
They see the representation of the product they see touch screens or you know, just visual cues makes them want to come and speak with you.
And that is really important in an in-person event.
So it's a strategy that's worked really well for us.
And we're trying to find ways of making it work, exponentially better in the years to come.
And then I think what's really top of mind for me is just how do I ensure as the team is executing and really focused on The objectives and the goals that we are tying all these things together as best we possibly can.
How is the digital engine, helping to support the demand generation campaigns, that are very specific to an audience?
How does that tie into the content strategy and our editorial planning?
What are some of these really interesting out their stories that are still really hyper relevant to the audience's that we care about on the downstream effect and in our sales and marketing Pipeline?
And how do we make sure that it's just, we're, we're amplifying, the things that we can amplify, and we're making sure that the all of these components are working together to build this much bigger representation of what we want to be seen as a known for and it all helps to showcase the power of the platform in different ways.
So that's really top of mind for me, as we enter into next year because it will last couple of years have really been, how do we just navigate, what's in front of us?
And it's just, we're sort of, you know, riding the waves to some And that's not going to change, but there's a lot that we can do in that.
I can focus on to help ensure that at the very least, the team has solid foundation and structure as possible to just collaborate as best we can, that's huge.
I think that alignment and collaboration and the currency of the trust and structure that you're providing is going to be really critical going into 2023 as far as events.
So that's interesting that you all are looking at in-person events in particular.
What conferences Summits in person events?
Are you all looking at for next year?
Yeah, there's a number we have had a lot of success at, you know, going back to HubSpot.
We have had a lot of successes in bounds and it's, it's a, so I was there in September in person.
And first time, I would been since 2019, I think it's the first time we as an organization have been and it was just the, I think it was also unique to that.
Here.
Everyone was so happy to be there and the energy level of people being in person and talking to their co-workers.
And the people that are in a very shared similar space was pretty electric and people were really interested in.
And what you know, the organization's had to say the sessions were really compelling and I also think they just did a really incredible job of to refactoring the layout of the space to account for just the reality of what today actually needs versus, you know, a few years ago.
But you know that's a pretty big one for us.
We're looking at the Adobe, you know, Summit and Adobe Max to connect with, you know, the marketing and design audiences in different ways where there's a number of other events that have started to come onto the scene for us more.
So in the last couple of years obviously is everything is shifted virtually or did shift virtually entirely for a couple of years.
There's a number of vendors that do really high quality meeting setting, like one-to-one conversations that are happening both in person and virtually that had just been incredible pipeline builders for us and any organization.
And we're going to make sure to continue to do those as we get back to some of these bigger conferences, just to be able to show off the brand more.
Those are really about just in connecting the product story, as deeply as we can to people that have a very particular need and challenge.
So we're trying to find the right mix.
That's great.
All right.
Spencer has a question here.
This will probably be our last question.
That will take you mentioned.
That one of the most effective ways of marketing to you is to be a respected resource.
How would you justify and monitor an approach like this?
That would likely take a while to see results from?
Yeah.
It's especially if you're a small team, it's a hard thing.
It's because there's such immediate needs to help bolster the business.
Des and it does, it takes a lot of time, you know, I think like anything.
There's there needs to be pretty clear expectations set up front around what you believe it is ultimately going to take and that's going to take time, it's going to take resources is going to take a little bit of patience, may be a lot of patients in some cases but just because it is going to take a lot of time.
Doesn't mean that it's not going to show some promise earlier on and that promise might be not might not be in.
The form of pipeline that might not be in the form of closed, one business.
It might not even be in the form of, you know, people coming to you and saying explicitly, they want to use your solution, or they're interested in learning more about your product.
But if you are getting the right, personas the right organizations, the right kinds of individuals, engaging with that, Clark property or that content or that, you know that particular you know, series whatever that format is and you're getting some qualitative feedback that's really helping to bolster the effectiveness of it.
That can be enough to go on in the early days it can be enough to show that you were saying the right kinds of things.
The right kinds of individuals are finding it and now it is about how do you iterate on that strategy?
How do you build more Foundation underneath it to hell?
A pre engage and bring them back to learn more about the product because one effort and one tactics, not going to do it all, it's not going to help solve this Big Brand Story and help build a point of view and also showcase the product in a really compelling way.
It's really hard to do that.
All on through one, through one mouthpiece, or one lens.
So the expectations and the, the ways that you measure that need to be different and it's likely going to be pretty qualitative.
Especially in the early days but you know if you have the right, you know, the right c-level executive of the right company saying like well that was really interesting there and all they're doing is leaving a comment on a social post that might be enough.
It might be enough to show, you know, show your boss to say people are engaging in the right people are engaging.
We need to figure out a way to make this more sustainable or maybe a little bit more efficient or, you know, pump a little bit more into this to figure out how we you know, broaden that mouthpiece to really capitalize on what's working, but it is.
It's a journey and it can be a really difficult one.
When the pressure is on for that in quarter, pipe line objective.
That is also staring you down, so it's not easy.
But that's what I would look.
For is whatever early signals.
You can possibly find that show that you're moving in the right general direction, because you're never going to get it right the first time.
That's good.
So for the teams we need to determine those early signals and you said it could be as simple as like a third-party solicited message.
You know, from our targeted buyer or something like that.
That's not necessarily an mql conversion but you know an early detector like you said.
So that's good to know.
Awesome.
All right, Alex.
Well thank you so much.
For taking the time with us today to just drop your wisdom and knowledge for us.
Could you leave us with one word of encouragement or advice for the B2B marketing community?
Yeah.
As you join any organization, it can be very overwhelming to learn the business and the buyer and the things that are working or not working.
And all of the things that you, you just need to absorb as somebody in an organization.
But I think anywhere you go, it's important not to lose you and your individuality, and the things that make you unique because they hired you, they hired you for a reason, the way that you present yourself the way that you see the world, the way that you know, just the way that you approach the work, whatever, whatever the case might be, there're things that make us who we are, that, that are valuable to any organization.
And when you can figure out a way to make your individuality mesh with the company objectives and those big picture goals, that's really where the magic happens.
You know, I am I fancy myself a musician, I have not spent nearly enough time investing in that over the last few years.
Especially with twins but the things that I find Value in our those creative Pursuits.
And even though I am a much more Revenue focused Market or today, I still make sure that I am engaging in Creative Pursuits, either in the office or outside of, or having these conversations that feel fulfilling in that vein because it's important to me.
And when it's important to me and I feel more fulfilled by that, then I give more to the organization that I am a part of, so I think that's just so important just, you know, not to Lose Yourself to the big, the big machine around us, and they will be better off for it when they're able to find ways of enabling that as well.
Wow, such a powerful Point.
Thank you so much.
I mean, I think that is right on about not losing yourself because it's you can get overwhelmed.
Not just even with the business needs.
But you go on LinkedIn and it's like Doom, scroll with how many layoffs taking but like all these different Marketplace factors and the economy and all these things.
But at the end of the day, there is a special magic that each person brings to an organization.
And we need to hold onto that if anything double down on that, going into 2023.
Exactly amazing.
All right.
Alex will, it's been a pleasure.
Thank you so much for your time.
If any of you want to get in touch with Alex, I find them on LinkedIn and yeah, feel free to I am opening it up.
Feel free to message him directly and connect with me as well.
Awesome.
All right, so We're moving into the holidays and our next event is going to be in January, and we're going to be doing an interview with Meghan at tulip.
She leads demand generation over there and seventy percent of her pipeline is actually generated through webinars, and she's going to walk us through some of her Special Sauce of what are those different types of webinars that she's fighting.
Really effective at every step of the buying cycle.
So we hope to see you then if I don't see you, you know, have a wonderful happy holidays.
Enjoy your time with your loved ones, and we will catch you in the new year.
Take care.
She told me, she loved me.
You got me out here doing my tattoo me up but can't nobody, stop the movement, let us go.
Left Foot Right Foot levitate pop stars, do Aleppo in the baby.
I had to let my son's father blesses.
I would say if I ever slip out into a better situation, so catch up, go put some cheese on it, get out and get your bread up, they always leave you barbecue run together, weight of the world on my shoulders.
I kept my head up now baby stand up because girl, you Your mama saw, like I need you all night.