I am still levitated a medicated ironic.
I gave him love, and they end up hating on me.
She told me she loved me, and she didn't wake been fighting hard for your love, and I am running thin on my patients.
Need someone to hug, even took it back to the base and see what you got me out here.
Doing my tattoo me up but can't nobody, stop the movement.
Let us go Left Foot Right Foot levitate Start doing leap with the baby.
I had to let my son's father blesses.
I would say if I ever slip out into a better situation, so catch up, go put some cheese on it, get out and get your bread up, they always leave you barbecue run together, weight of the world on my shoulders.
I kept my head up now baby stand up because girl, you More like your mama saw.
Like I need you all night.
So you are honor him parents.
The ox and lamb kept time.
Burner of a, I played my drum for you but I played my best for him.
I am feeling those holiday Vibes.
Are you Pentatonix?
Bringing it to us.
Hey, everyone.
It's so great to see you here.
We have got Janet tuning in from North.
No Cal, Kevin Lee.
Our speaker from Boise, Idaho and K Berg from Seattle.
It's great to be here.
It's another wonderful day.
And today, I am so excited to be able to have this interview with Kevin Lee.
He is The SVP of marketing with oyster and boy.
He's got a lot of deep knowledge and experience in B2B marketing and leading remote teams.
And today we're going to dive into a very great tap topic as it relates to going into 2023.
A lot of teams need to be thinking about their brand and on the flip side of that building healthy phenomenal, remote team culture, they go hand-in-hand, is brand ties to your values, your vision.
Your mission and how that gets communicated externally and internally.
So, with that, I would love to invite Kevin to the stage.
Hello.
Hi everyone.
So good to be here.
Thanks for having me.
Oh, yeah.
It's a pleasure to have you here.
Kevin.
I am such a big fan of you, and just everything that you have invested into the B2B marketing Community.
You have got a quite, you got quite a following, and you have your own news.
Newsletter.
How long have you been maintaining your own database of marketers?
Yeah, it's interesting.
So I number all my newsletters, I think this week's, I said, when every week this week's is 350 or something, which is not to say I have sent 350 of them, but I put the year number at the start and then number each week.
And so this is my third year, on some stuck, the 50th week of the year.
So three or sometimes doctor I have been doing it a bit before then too.
Wow, God Gotcha and there's such Rich information in there.
If people wanted to check it out.
What's the website link again?
Yes, he can get there through my personal website, which is Kevin Lee.com and then the direct subject link is Kevin Lee dotsub stack.
That qasim okay?
Yeah, definitely check it out, if you're interested.
So you're tuning in from Boise Idaho.
I know there's some fun facts that we want to learn to get to know you a little bit more.
So I put together this little pole and basically it's three truths and One Lie.
So if we could Pull that pull up on stage here.
Okay, so we have got these four different answers which of these is not true about Kevin one teaches marketing at a college to be a newspaper.
Reporter reads three reads 50 to 100 books each year or for has an MBA.
So go ahead and drop your votes.
And then we will see which one is not true.
Okay, I tried to vote myself.
This is, these are good.
I don't think people believe that you actually could potentially Read 50 to 100 books each year.
That's a lot.
That is a lot.
It's a lot bigger.
Alright though.
So yeah.
Okay.
So let us reveal the answer drumroll and the answer Kevin which one of these is not true.
I do not have an MBA, okay.
So you actually read 50 to 100 books.
Each year I do.
Yeah, I was lucky when I worked at buffer which is a B2B SAS social media company.
One of our perks was a free Kindle and as many Kindle books as you wanted and so that got me hooked into reading and I have carried that habit with me ever since.
So yeah, I read a mix.
I try to read short one so that I can get the number up and feel good about like hitting a milestone, but that is the range I try for each year.
That's awesome.
So what are some of your more recent books that you are reading and that you would recommend?
Yeah.
So I just published my best of books to my newsletter list for like the full.
I think it was 50 or 60 this year that I read and I didn't read by many marketing books this year which I don't know if that's like what that means.
Maybe I am burnt out on marketing books or something like that.
But the one that I love this year that was somewhat marketing related was called the sea.
We In.
It was all about storytelling and the importance of Storytelling for Branding, for marketing, for politics, for culture, like for so many different reasons.
And so you probably wouldn't find it in the business section of a Barnes Noble or library.
But for me, it had a lot of interesting takeaways from marketing.
And then one of my favorite marketing books of all time is a book called Alchemy.
It's written by one of the executives at the Ogilvy advertising agency.
It is just such a mind-blowing blend of science and art within marketing which I believe there is both a lot of science.
But also a lot of art that you can't really explain with what we do on marketing side.
And so that's been a really influential book for me, and put words to a lot of the feelings that I had with how I go about marketing.
Love that.
That's a classic right there, agreed.
Yes.
Wow.
Okay.
Well, thank you for sharing that and you know, I wanted to dive a little bit more into, just your story getting into B2B marketing.
And why, how did you get into it?
And why did you choose B to B?
Because you probably could go beat his see, as well, you know?
So why B to B Tech totally?
Well, I kind of stumbled into it.
I don't even know if I consciously like knew what B2B stood for when I started like down this.
And so, for me, it was wanting to join, wanted to join.
A start-up, was one of my primary motivations and even the reason for joining a start-up was because I had a really high belief in remote work and the ability to like, do work that you're passionate about and like results-based.
Work environments, I came from a very traditional marketing background with, you know, office and suit and tie and show up to work every day and sit in meetings, and it was just like a very stereotypical experience.
I thought But I want something different.
So that led me toward toy startups.
I love the optimism of startups.
I love the scale of startups but I had no concept of what the difference between B2B and b2c was, which is maybe can partially explain how I do marketing today in some ways?
So the company that really caught my eye was buffer, which was a company that was mission first, really cared about culture and values and that was all I needed to hear like they had a An opening for writer.
And I was brought up into in newspaper, reporting and journalism and all these different written communication fields.
And so, I was like, I would love to write for a full-time job, and I want to do it at a place that cares, as much as I do about culture and values.
That was my start buffer happened to be a B2B company.
And so gained a lot of experience there.
And I haven't looked back since Wow, that's awesome.
How many years ago was that?
That was about ten years ago.
Guy trans I had some exposure into like New Media and startups before that through my time at vaux and that was eye-opening as well.
Now that was I was there for five years of as well.
So like 15 years total in Canada, startup and texting.
Wow.
Okay so tell us a little bit about like what were some of the most challenging the moments that you experienced in your startup, especially the early stages of just, like, learning about what is B2B and you know, what were some of those challenges Yeah.
Yeah, it was interesting because I think I because I don't have an MBA as we learned in the poll earlier, and I am not formally trained and educated in marketing.
So much of the marketing that I knew was either from my core discipline of content or was from the marketing that I experienced when Brands and products are being marketed to me.
And so, I think I have always had some of that like user first DNA, into my B2B marketing plans like b2c DNA Within The world that B2B marketing.
It's that was really helpful.
I think as a starting foundations like how would I like to be marketed to let me make sure that is true of the marketing that I do and then my team is doing so that was I think a useful Foundation to start from, but then like my education and to B2B marketing was it was like super steep.
Like I woke up every day at work thinking, today was going to be the work that I did.
Today would be the day.
I get found out is an impostor and I don't know anything about what I am doing, and I am sent packing.
You're thinking, so there was always that like, underlying fear of, I am not qualified or not cut out for this.
And so that motivated me to stay curious to learn as fast as I could.
The, the things that I had gaps in and to be very self-aware of where I knew, I didn't like understand the certain acronym in a meeting or understand certain phrase like rather than try to avoid like ever being close to that phrase again.
Like I would go out and research it understands what am I missing here was the context?
And so I think that Like early days.
I know my curiosity and my drive to succeed.
We're really important in learning as fast as I could.
I was really fortunate to be at a place like buffer, that was like, very transparent in the information that they shared internally.
I had a wonderful boss who was patient with me and, you know, showed me kind of the ropes of what we were doing.
And then a company, that was okay, thinking differently about how we could grow and how we want to show up as a business in the market.
And, so I think a lot of it was very serendipitous.
That I started where I did.
That's awesome.
I think all those feelings and emotions learning curves that you mentioned are so real.
And I think so often, you know, especially B2B marketers, just getting into the game.
I appreciate your transparency about that process because I think a lot of marketers could feel the way that what you conveyed and learned through.
So yeah, they're not alone.
It is a universal feeling in a lot of ways and it's a very isolating job to because like I work, Work.
I work remotely and so these things, I am feeling them in my office here.
I am not feeling the next to someone at also having those feelings and it's just a it's a feeling that you need to say out loud as much as possible.
So that people know, it's true of other people than just yourself.
Are there communities that you have joined?
I mean, you have created your own.
Are there others that you participate in as well?
Yeah, I think that's partially what motivates me to run the newsletter that I run into the present where I am present online, as a way to give back as a way to show folks.
Like I didn't I don't really know much about anything, but this is what I do know.
And if it's helpful for you, like, please, please take it.
So that's yeah, that's been helpful for me.
There have been some slack communities.
I have been part of Those tend to come and go.
But it's always nice to just, I tend to be more of a lurker than a valuable contributor but just being able to lurk and see the same of the conversations in there are similar to the things that I am thinking about and wondering about it makes me feel more connected, I guess to the broader marketing community.
And then I took some courses early on like reforge is one of my favorite, my favorite programs and that was really helpful to understand like oh I now know.
Like what, the, what the current way of thinking is, and it's not very far off from how I am thinking today, or it was far off, but now I am caught up to where it was, so it was just like a very validating experience and so kind of build some of that into my, my ritual has been helpful.
Love that thank you for sharing, so I would like it out Dives Right into our panel or panels are interviewed topic here on brand strategy and how that goes hand in hand, really with the remote team culture, that you are building and you have established.
So, let us start with the brand strategy topic.
I know that you're very well versed in experienced in this area.
You have built differentiating brands in Tech yourself, just curious.
But what brands do you admire, and why?
Yeah, I love b2c brands in general.
And so like I am very drawn to, you know, from some really big Brands like Nike to even like the deed is see direct to Consumer space.
Like there's so many unique and interesting things happening there, in terms of how they're using storytelling and data to really connect with the very A very late clear picture of who their customer is.
I think that's what strikes me about some of the brands that I find appealing as like they are speaking.
Such a very clear and direct way to a very clear and direct type of person I think that's really admirable and something that I am always striving to do better at, and so I often look outside of tech for inspiration in that regard but when I do like inside of teca, there're things, you know, endless examples of great Brands and Tech to some of the big ones that I have, as kind of North Stars for me, and my teams are Brands like web flow or figma.
But then there's also like really, you know, early stage startups, a seed stage or series either doing some cool things to, as I am always on product hunt to understand like what is, what is the newest and greatest like tool and Technology.
But also how are these tools and Technologies branding themselves, and how they show up in the market?
So that's may be cheating.
I think I said I Find inspiration everywhere.
Essentially, but I, those are where I start when I am looking for, what makes those Brands differentiating to you?
Why are they iconic?
Yeah, you know, it's I think of brand as a sum of all the experiences that someone has with your company and so what differentiates them are makes them, iconic is It will sound like beating around the bush with my answer, but I think what's true for me is that it's the experience of these brands that resonates most with me and then experience is hard to like, pinpoint in 2000.
It is this exact thing they're doing with their visual identity, like I am over when, when Pitch came out as like this new slide presentation software, like they were using.
What was it?
Like 3D shapes or something, and their visual identity, which is very new and differentiated But that alone wouldn't have really sunk in with me.
Like it had to be grounded in a brand strategy and a brand personality and to permeate everything else that pitch does which they do really well.
So that's what draws me, more to a brand, like pitch, its kind of the sum of all the experiences.
But usually, the entry point is something may be small in particular, like a visual identity, some copy on a website, maybe some user-generated content, or Word of Mouth that people are talking about this.
And or the space.
So that's usually like the hook.
And then to really resonate with me, it needs to be like a full, a fully-realized experience.
Mmm.
And that takes time to be able to get there and resources.
Yes, it's a big Endeavor, you sure?
Yeah.
Because it's not, it's probably not even just marketing building out that experience.
It's with the product.
It's with the sales, cuz it's the whole company being Be able to adopt and fully capture the brand experience from your perspective.
Like, what has that look like with some of the brands that you have built when you have worked with other team members?
And how do you get that established brand strategy?
And then the alignment across from executive leadership to the org?
Yeah, you're exactly right.
It really is.
Those two phases.
Its can we align on?
What our brand is, what we stand for, how we want to show up in the world.
And then it's the second phase of how consistent are we being in actually following through on this and applying it.
So, you know, they're both very difficult phases.
They're different difficult for different reasons.
I think the first phase of defining that brand is needs to be highly collaborative.
It needs to be No, ambitious.
It needs to be grounded in like some very core visceral, feelings, and values.
And those things take time to discuss and to hash out with the, with your internal team with market research, or just a lot of different inputs, you need to go into refining that.
And so, I have done that work at buffer and an oyster and for other companies and kind of advisory capacity.
And it's may be as fast as it could be.
Is a 62 10-week process, that is maybe being a bit ambitious, even in like a six-week timeline.
And so more often, it's a quarters worth of work to really get to the details into that and get something that you can be confident in as well.
If you don't want to rush out a brand that you don't feel fully bought into either.
So that works really important.
I think, for me, it comes down to, you know, starting with the why, why does our company exist and that's often the question that gets answered by the founding team.
Ideally, they had a, why?
When they started out.
And so, hopefully, that why is compelling enough?
Otherwise, I am happy to come up with a different why that makes sense to so, starting with that Y, and then marrying that to a tension that you find out in the culture and the market at large.
And I think that's where a brand can really come to life and resonate in a powerful way when you're connecting this Y, which is often, you know, a personal need or a personal problem that you're solving to this broader.
Cultural tension that applies to many other people and can have like some natural scale and resonance to it.
So that's, you know, not an easy thing to figure out, but it the closer you get to the heart of your brand and like what your Brand's best self is the easier.
It is to start to notice where those overlaps might be.
So that's the first phase and the second phase is.
Yeah.
The once we figure all this out, how do we make sure we're being consistent about it?
That am I mean that is an ongoing process.
I think I have been very lucky that Bufferin at ways to maybe I will share a waster is example.
Oyster, we are very aligned on what type of mission we have as a company and how that relates to our brand.
So it's very clear alignment and obvious alignment for everyone of what we're trying to do as a company in the short medium, and long term, a twister.
And that's a great place to start from.
So then my challenge is a marketing leader as well.
How do I make sure that We are all consistently applying that brand to are our internal experience, our external communication?
Like there's so many different layers of this that permeate every single team within the business.
And if you're not careful about it, as time goes on, you will start to notice.
Some people starting to interpret this brand from a slightly different shade and then all of a sudden, you know, six months later, it is an entirely different narrative that you not, you can hardly recognize from where it started with.
And so, I have to keep reminding myself.
I need to be Overly communicative, I need to share more than I think.
I need to share any to repeat.
What might seem very obvious to me just, you know, I think you have to say something seven times before it sinks in.
So I have to say something seven times every month because I think it you know, you lose it after every month to you, need to keep refreshing.
And so it just becomes a very much an always-on process for us.
And we're kind of working through that toy store at the moment.
Wow, so even after that first quarter of getting the strategy, Get outta line with executive leadership, communicating out launching it out, even thereafter years after you're still continuing to bring alignment communication.
And I am guessing the brand also evolve May evolve.
And how do you handle that?
Yeah, I definitely evolved anywhere in one of those Evolution stages that oyster, at the moment, we're very much about Global Employment today, but we see a path in the future where from More expansive, even Beyond Global Employment into many different aspects of future of work.
And I think it's both a question of how do you, how do you make that transition?
But also, when do you make that transition?
When is the sequencing and timing right to go from A to B?
And I mean, the fortunate thing is there's no, there's no like Playbook to follow.
And so, they're in a sense.
There's no wrong answer to some of this.
I think a lot of it is going into it with eyes wide open and acknowledging.
Like, yes, this is the Trajectory, we need to be on and the steps that need to happen.
And let us I think it's always unique for every company.
And so let us look at the circumstances and understand what makes the most sense for us today.
And so for us, that waster, for instance, we haven't had our employment brand.
I mean, oyster is a two-and-a-half-year-old company in general.
And so the brand hasn't had a lot of time to bake fully yet.
Since I think that reason, like, it makes sense to keep going on the employment side, a bit more before you switch gears to something else.
But then also, I think you want to do it in a way that isn't jarring for the market as well.
Like, there's a total Rebrand, which is almost like a single point in time we were this thing.
And now we're this thing, there's almost like a, like, an ICP, or Persona change where we were about these people and now we're about these people but there's more of like the underlying brand values brand strategy piece, which is maybe not as evident right away to the market.
But over time you start to get at this shift into what people are expecting, sometimes that can happen with, you know, we're going to expand our product line from.
We used to sell this thing to we're going to sell it to other thing.
You see that a lot with like d to C brands that are selling like I think Obama is the socks company.
Like, I know them as a sock company, but they sell t-shirts, and, and underwear and all these different things now, and like, over time, my understanding of that brand is going to evolve, but it wasn't like a single point in time when bomb was like, was like socks from the website.
We're going to go all in on this thing instead.
Like I think is a very natural progression that a lot of brands have to undertake.
And it's not something you want to.
You want to feel like a very abrupt shift if it doesn't have to be in.
So it's an interesting process of.
How do you work through design and that way where you're making tweaks, rather than complete overhauls through copy through voice and tone through the images that you use, like there's just a lot of different components that you can kind of sequence, each of those in and of themselves, too.
So it's almost like I think about change management and kind of take some of those same principles of how you manage change with people and orgs with your brand as well because things can't be too abrupt or, you know, you can't just say like, all right we're going to rear and tomorrow you know, there's a lot of sequencing, a lot of things involved.
So yeah, thank you for walking us through so going into 2023.
I am seeing some folks talk about investing into their brand.
How do you see it?
Because I know budgets are getting tighter.
We have to show, you know, Roi with smaller amounts of spend and you know, hopefully deliver 10x even like 20x out of like less spend is sometimes the pressure that some folks have been communicating.
But what's your sense?
Ahow brand strategy and investing into your brand, can help.
Play into next year's prodigies.
It's an interesting topic.
One of the things I often think about with marketing, is its marketing job to be two to three years ahead of the company and that is something that I hope, I hope pretty dire.
In terms of that long-term thinking, long-term strategy, and that often gets lost in moments like this, where you're so focused on the near term and You know, next quarter's revenue, or next quarter sleeve volume and is very real-time metrics, essentially.
And so, as a market leader, I try to find ways to ensure that I am still including long-term planning into my plans and advocating for that.
And brand is one of those very significant long-term plays for our team and for many marketing teams.
And so that's like the broader lens that I think of it through brand is our greatest.
What's going to help us differentiate and way in a long term and I think it's really important that companies.
These are aware of what their long-term strategy is for this for winning, or for growth, whatever the case may be.
And so that doesn't necessarily help like, when you get your resource and budget number, and it's smaller than what you expected me have to make some really hard trade-offs.
And so, for me, when I am in those conversations, it's become a shift from Brand, being a brand awareness play.
Like, that's get as many people to know about oyster or buffer or welcome as possible and it becomes More about how can our brand, how does our brand influence, the sales funnel or the marketing funnel, or the self-serve funnel, like, whatever funnels, you have, because brand does have an influence on that.
Oftentimes, it's hard, it's harder to measure than like a direct Roi type measure of Performance Marketing or conversions, things like that, but if you take brand out of that, you will see a lot of your numbers change.
And when you put Brandon to it, you will see all of your numbers improve.
And like if you can get more clarity into what those numbers are, what those are.
Facts are I think it makes the case a little bit easier to invest in Grand.
And so that's one of the ways that we have been thinking of it, specifically tying brand to metrics like our LTV or tying it to metrics like our yield on, how much we spend on ads versus how much pipeline we generate or even something like sales velocity.
Like in theory, if someone knows and loves your brand, the first conversation is going to be easier than be more likely to move.
The second conversation closing.
It will be easier because whoever they have to get approval from may already know about you and I feel good about you.
So that's where Branch shows up for me and moments like this.
And this is one of the places where I point others to, when I am advocating on behalf of grand.
Hmm, that's really good.
Thanks for sharing that.
So for you all, when you get into these planning modes for thinking about the next one year to three years.
What's that process?
Like are you first having the conversation with your leadership and then do you have like a team?
Team, what does the team look like on marketing to be able to execute on a brand strategy?
Yeah.
So ideally we have a three to five-year company strategy, which would come from a CEO, or a founding team, or her c-suite leadership team.
And that's really helpful to know, like, where do we want to be as a company in three to five years now, because that obviously will dictate what we want, our brand to be three to five years from now, I think what where it gets really challenging as if no one's thinking, three to five years ahead.
And he was a market leader of the only one thinking, three to five years ahead, then all of a sudden I know, I have been in places like that where I am putting up strategies together and like is anyone actually going to agree with me about this direction?
I am saying we should go in 23 years and so that is a challenge.
I, so I say if you don't have that definitely push for it or ask for it within your team and Company to have that company long-term Vision to ground your brand strategy.
And but then from there is its a lot of going back to that company strategy is doing market research.
And understand like where are the trends today?
And how they evolved over the past two to three years and almost like projecting out where you think they could be two to three years.
Now, it's important to bring as many data in as you can, but there's always going to be a pretty hefty dose of qualitative input into like a three to five-year Vision document for brand.
And then involving your team is really helpful to like, can you get insights from your product marketing team since they know the markets so well, and they know customers.
While can, you get inside some growths team on what channels are I am the best and even how Channel performance has evolved over the past couple of years, and they evolve into the future.
Once you have all those inputs, usually a brand strategy becomes a bit more clear to see Mmm, that's good.
Okay.
And if anybody has any questions, feel free to drop them in the Q&A tab.
I would love to transition our conversation.
Speaking about teams talking about how you are building a pretty awesome, team culture from what I have heard from your teammates.
So, you know, just FYI, you have got that good third-party feedback, coming out your leadership and the team Dynamic that you have built over at oyster.
Currently, how many team members do you have on the marketing team?
What is, what is your org look like?
And yeah, how do you manage them a week to week?
I would love to hear about just your, you know what?
What does workflow look and feel like?
Yeah.
So, we're a 50-person marketing team today 50, and we have, I guess, where you can consider a matrix marketing organs.
So, we have Pillars of brand marketing, product, marketing, and growth marketing.
And then we have to supporting layers of content and design and then as we have kind of scaled to the team size right now, we were able to carve out a group called strategic projects that which works on most like startup within a start-up kind of ideas as well as business operations, which has helped us a lot and of organizing ourselves and our processes, and they're hoping everything runs smoother and so it's been a steep learning curve for me like T people is a lot of wonderful people to get to work with.
So I learned a lot about how to I am still learning a lot about how to manage, all that.
I guess like to get people moving in the same direction.
I think has been a really interesting puzzle to solve, and so we have a number of different rituals that we use to.
I hope a good effect.
I don't know what the word of mouth would be on my team's feelings about the rituals, but I have enjoyed putting them in place, and if I don't know if this complicates it or makes it easier, I often think this makes it a bit easier, but it might not sound that way, but we are a very asynchronous call.
Our oyster and so we don't spend a lot of time in synchronous meetings discussing strategy or checking in like a lot of that happens in a Google Document or in slack or in the ocean.
And so that for me has helped because I am able to document a lot of the thoughts that come out of my head or come out of my chats of the marketing leadership team or come out of different parts of the business document that and then put it in a place where people can access it on their own terms at their own time and kind of on demand.
Moving forward, and so I think that helps when you get to a certain scale where you have information easily accessible for people whenever they need it and want it.
So that's been a help I think as we have scaled, and we have also been very deliberate about putting our strategy down on paper working in a sauna for project management is that we start from strategic planning to move all that into a sauna for project management.
We also use a sign up for goal tracking, then we have a biweekly live stand up.
We all get together to discuss performance to date but also use that time to connect as a team to highlight other voices on the team, so they can share like work in progress or deep dives into their areas and feel like we're again moving in the same direction.
Honestly, I am really grateful for the leaders that I have on my team because so much of managing a 50-person team happens when I am not there.
And when I have no idea what's going on in.
So, like in the individual departs, like sub departments within marketing.
There's so much good work.
That happens with those.
Dividual teams and their cultures in terms of moving in the same direction, communication team building.
And so, it becomes especially important to be a good manager of managers when you get to the scale because you won't have direct contact with the majority of the folks in your organic more.
That's great.
And I am curious like what are some of those challenges that you have run into where you have had to problem solve and figure it out?
Yeah, we have a few, there's always a few.
So one of the ones is I think it's due to this concept that I have called push-and-pull.
So we have a cremation.
We're very, very many documentarians with an oyster.
And so, a lot of information is available for folks to look and see and I will probably incorrectly often come to the assumption that.
Well, it's in the here.
So of course, people know to look here and you know, people probably don't know to look there.
They No, they don't look somewhere but there's so many places to look at so many things to read it just doesn't get read or doesn't get seen.
It doesn't get like fully integrated into their plans and strategies and so that's one of the risks that we have as an asynchronous culture.
And as a team of our size is that we have important things that we are putting in a synchronous document that might not resonate or even be seen by as many people as we think they're being feeling consumed by plus one on one when risk, another thing that's popped up.
Recently.
Is that during the planning phase?
We have a concept of these are, you know, the five to 10, big projects that we want to do as a team over the next quarter.
But, you know, for a 50-person team, you can do 5 to 10 big projects that still have a ton of, you know, either always on work.
That's happening.
Anyway or additional work.
Like there's lots of bandwidths to do some really great stuff.
And so how do you prioritize almost like the second layer priorities?
Beneath the 5210, big things and often times when the It's about is in the production areas, like content or design or marketing operations, or lifecycle or website, like these creative units that are needing to build infrastructure or create assets and things like that.
And so, we felt some crunch there to have, like, it's clear with the big things that we're working on.
What does that mean for everything else that we can work on and want to work on and maybe should be working on as well?
And so, we haven't necessarily solve that puzzle yet, but we're aware.
It is a puzzle.
How to solve at the moment, I think it's huge that your team members can even bring these things up and there's that trust and transparency to.
It sounds like quickly surface any challenges and you know even if it's not resolved ASAP like we're working together to figure it out.
So how have you have established that level of collaboration transparency See, you know, how did you create that kind of culture?
That is a good question.
I think I should ask him my teammates at what they think was successful to get there.
Like I do believe that Like, I always try to build teams with trust respect and affirmation is some of the core values of the teams that I am building.
So the fact that trust is so front and center for me, I think does kind of work through a lot of the different connection points that I have with my team?
Whether it's consciously or subconsciously, as I am doing it.
And so, as an example, the way that I lead and manage people is very, very open.
It's very, I give a lot of autonomy to folks.
I am often asking for feedback or very receptive to feedback when it's shared.
I think that builds a certain amount of safety in sharing your feedback with No, with your boss or manager or team Lee.
Like, I think that psychological safety is really important.
So I do that a lot to the, the way that I manage those, I try to do that through the way that I manage.
We also have regular surveys that we do both at the company level.
But then we're also often asking the team for feedback at like, a stand-up or in stock, and then the important thing is to ask, but then to return the results to people, so they see that, oh, this person asked this saw the results, and this is the action that you're From them.
So we just did our queue for employee engagement survey as the company and marketing's results were sent to me in the market leadership team, and we kind of had a chance to talk about all this, but then we were like, well let us ask the team what they think about these results to, and so we share the results with the team.
And then ask them, these are the themes that we noticed from your feedback.
Did we get it right?
And if not let us know, but if so like what do you think you would like to see happen?
Next, as a result of this and take their thoughts into Duration with that.
And, so I think those I guess those processes and systems really do help to build that psychological safety in the build a culture where it's okay to give feedback you know, up down or horizontal, and so we're lucky that has been the case for us so far, that's awesome.
Thanks for sharing.
All right we have got a couple of questions actually coming through.
So let us go ahead and pull up and question.
What are some marketing tactics you have used too successfully?
Bring awareness to Brand you worked on?
And is there anything you tried?
That didn't work like you thought it would.
Yeah.
So the ones that have worked really well for us at waster, have been our PR and our thought leadership and our social media work.
And we have seen some really impressive scale from those channels.
So specifically, when it comes to getting placements in Tier 1, Yeah, that's four different stories that we want to tell and then using our either our own profile.
So like our oyster LinkedIn profile or using the profiles of some of our most influential people within the company, like our CEO or a founding team or some of our leaders and thinking of them, almost as brand ambassadors and putting together content strategy and thought leadership behind them.
We have seen some really powerful scale for the brand to that one of the next steps.
There's then to tie that into like a full, I guess you could think of it as an employee.
Agassi the strategy.
And so, how do you get the hundreds of people who work at oyster?
Also, sharing on LinkedIn or Twitter or Tick, Tock, or whatever the case may be on behalf of your brand and the things in the stories that are important to you.
And so, that's, that's kind of really large scale, sustainable way to move the brand.
We have also spent money on the brand and so events is a really big lever for us to being very targeted to which events resonate most with your target audience, or which events resonate with Because the way you want to be perceived in the market.
And so the difference for us in that case is we want to show up at HR events because we are an HR Tech platform.
I always stir, and so we have a presence there, but then we also want to be known as Innovative.
We want to make kind of splash in the Silicon Valley seems.
So we're showing up at Tech events, likes a stir or web Summit as well because it connects our brand with kind of has this bigger Zeitgeist around Tech.
So those have been helpful for us, I would say on the side that hasn't worked as well.
We have done some, some very initial testing and out-of-home advertising which I think can work.
Well if you get the strategy right but it requires a certain amount of investment to really an investment and belief and time like to really let that sink in and to get it to work the way you want to, when we did it, we advertised on some Billboards in San Francisco and the primary benefit of that for us is we could take a picture of it and share it on LinkedIn.
It was almost like a social proof thing more so than an actual brand Impressions or brain consideration kind of play.
So that would be.
I would be somewhat careful about that.
But otherwise, it's, you know, I think for us it's a lot of, it depends on what is the goal of your brand?
Like, if you're going after brand impression doesn't number, then yes, channels like PR social media.
Make a lot of sense because of the scale, if you After more of like a brand consideration aspects that may be something like a podcast, which is a bit more intimate than maybe doesn't scale, to as many eyes or ears in that case.
I think you can be very, very specific and targeted based on what outcome you want to drive for your brand.
It's great.
We have got another question from Spencer in this time of justifying marketing, spend improving Roi.
How do you show the value of brand marketing?
Great question.
It's it gets tricky and I think a lot of it depends on what is most important to.
What is most important to the people who are most important that your company is?
So that's probably the CEO but in some cases it might be like a Chief Financial Officer clo or just whatever the hierarchy looks like it company like what are the things that matter the most to those folks and how do you connect brand to them?
And so it has a general rule.
I would say connecting Brands to any sort of efficiency metric today is going to be really helpful.
Like I mentioned earlier, that could be something like LTV or yield sale.
Lost city is another example.
So connecting it back to these metrics that help you get more efficient with your spend, with your acquisition.
That's one way that I have seen it.
Be really effective, but I have also seen it be effective with kind of broader company's strategic decisions.
Like if you want to go after category, creation is like your one long-term strategy that you have a high belief in.
Then how do you connect your brand work to category creation that case?
Maybe it is the organic search volume for a particular keyword.
Word or maybe it is the number of reviews you get in this certain review website on this certain category term.
And so, I think you can marry it to whatever the company strategy is or whatever is most important to the company.
At a time, when I would probably default to an efficiency metric in the meantime.
Some of the, like, always on brand goals that we have for, for us, a twister is, what is are aided recall?
So running an aided recall survey on brand awareness out the market.
What is the free traffic to our Website?
And so how many people are coming direct to our website?
How many people are being referred to our website?
So clicking on a link that someone else said about Western coming here or what is like or organic.
Search volume both for like any relevant search term, but it's even more specifically for Brandon Search terms like how many people are typing oyster?
Oyster HR oyster Global Employment into a search engine and finding us that way.
So those are kind of like the always on one side.
We look at as well as share a voice which is more of a market, share kpi.
Those arms are kind of always on.
There we go.
For the next one.
Yeah, it's a tricky one.
We use Blended share of voice for the market, share one.
And so we're measuring across paid search, social PR in organic search.
And this shirt like the specific percentage of she avoids, very some differently, across all four of them.
So we're trying to find a way to blend them into like one metric.
But in general, we usually based it on how many competitors we have their space.
And so we have two main competitors in our space and so if you think of if All equal.
We should all have 33 percent share of the market.
So we want more than 33 percent is the way we would goal ourselves in that case.
That's great.
Alright wow, like I need to play back.
This recording is there so much that you shared with us and believe or not.
We only have like five minutes left before we wrap up, Kevin.
I know that you have got a job board and you have got resources.
And so we have got some links here.
Your palate.com or can I go ahead and share?
Sure.
That it is there.
Anything else that as a marketing Community we could learn benefit from with the resources you currently have.
Yeah, that's a great one.
Yeah, you're welcome to share that link.
So this is a jobs board for remote.
Jobs in particular, remote marketing jobs.
You're welcome to just check out the link there and look at the jobs and hopefully it's helpful for you or someone in your network if they're looking for work.
But also, if you want to apply to be part of what's called a Within that transport, it just helps me make introductions or connections to hiring companies as well.
If you're currently in the job market or looking for your next opportunity.
So would love to support you in that way.
If that's helpful for you, if you do, subscribe to the newsletter, you will get to hear from me once a week.
You can unsubscribe anytime.
If you get tired of hearing from me once a week, but you can get some resources there.
I am often sharing their stories from oyster or buffer, sharing resources that were using sharing Ideas that are on my head and so, it's very much like a real time look into the stuff that matters to me at the moment.
And then there is a paid app head section of that newsletter, which gives you access to my personal notion workspace, which has a bunch of different templates and play books and things.
They're all the proceeds from that newsletter, go to a non-profit that's helping to bring more or folks of underrepresented groups into Tech.
So, if you're welcome to subscribe there and get access to notion as well, That's amazing.
All right.
Kevin with the wrap up, is there one word of encouragement or advice that you could leave the B2B a community with Yeah, I probably tie it back to where we started, which is, I came from a very non-traditional background into Tech.
And I think that non-traditional background is something that can resonate very deeply in a very crowded and noisy B2B marketing space.
And so embrace the non-traditional, think outside the box, go big, go wild.
Like we have a saying, like, we celebrate moonshots and roof shots.
So, as long as you have some moonshots in addition to all the Roof shots the validating the stuff that you're doing.
Like, I think that is that makes for a really good mix and then just feel free to be bold with it.
I think that's where a lot of great performance comes from, a might be harder to measure.
Might be harder to tie directly back to some sort of Roi, but it's worth it to get your brand and your product heard out in the market today.
Love that.
Thank you so much.
Kevin, we appreciate you.
We're so grateful for everything you're investing into the community and so all the best to you and your team your endeavors.
Wonderful, thank you, Gina.
Thank you.
Everyone was great to be here today.
Awesome.
All right.
Well with that, our next event is taking place next week, so we are going to be interviewing Alex from Saros.
He is the director of digital marketing, and it's going to be a great conversation on really looking at content and figuring out.
What is that attention-grabbing Marketing in a noisy market?
And he's going to talk, especially about the collaboration with design, And so, definitely check it out.
Come on down.
Have a wonderful rest of your week and weekend until then.
Take care.
Bye.
Again, is the greatest thing?
No, debating on.
I am still levitated, I am Evelyn medicated ironic, I gave him love, and they in the painting on me.
She told me she loved me.
And She'd been waiting fight hard for your love, and I am running thin on my patients.
Need someone to hug, even took it back to the bank and see what you got me out here.
Doing my tattoo me up but can't nobody, stop the movement, let us go Left Foot Right Foot levitate pop stars Duality between the baby.
I had to let my shoes father blessed.
As I was saying, if they ever slip and fall into a better situation, so catch up, go put some cheese on it, get out and get your bread up, they always leave you father you run together, weight of the world on my shoulders.
I kept my head up now baby stand up because girl you Don't you baby?
I want you baby sugar.
Boo.
I got you more like your mama saw.
Like I need you all night.